<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="abcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:55:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>See Where Pope Francis Changed for Mass</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/pope-francis-mass-bolivian-burger-king/story?id=32336679</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis changed in a burger King in Santa Cruz Bolivia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis Changes for Mass in a Bolivian Burger King
Jul 9, 2015, 3:48 PM ET
By DAVID WRIGHT in Santa Cruz, Bolivia
Pope Francis stands outside the Burger King franchise that served as a makeshift sacristy for today's open air mass in Santa Cruz, Bolivia.
David Wright/ABC News
The Pope had it his way.
Just before todays open air mass in Bolivia , the leader of the Roman Catholic church stopped by a nearby Burger King  not to eat but to prepare for mass.
The restaurant, draped with white curtains and surrounded by plainclothes Swiss Guard, served as the sacristy for todays huge open air mass in Santa Cruz. The sacristy is where the priest dresses, saying prayers as he dons each item of clothing.
He had been riding around in the Popemobile for about a half hour when his entourage pulled up to the Burger King, which had been reserved three days ago for the event because the restaurant is so close to the stage for the mass.
David Wright/ABC News
PHOTO: Pope Francis stands outside the Burger King franchise that served as a makeshift sacristy for open air mass in Santa Cruz, Bolivia, July 9, 2015.
Throughout his trip to South America, Pope Francis has been stressing the need for social justice , preaching hard against a culture where money rules, rather than service.
Francis has called for people to look beyond the pursuit of profit and look out for one another instead.
Its a message that resonates in Bolivia, South Americas poorest country, where 60 percent of the population lives below the poverty line.
By late afternoon, the Burger King had reopened for business, but the altar and the papal throne from the mass were still inside.
Christian Vaca, the assistant manager of the Burger King, is hoping the popes visit to his franchise will be good for business.
Business has been hopping since he was here, he said. Its really a blessing.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:29:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Don't Be a Dummy': Driver Caught in HOV Lane With Mannequins</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/toronto-driver-ticketed-hov-lane-mannequins-passengers/story?id=32333711</Link>
        <Description>A driver in Toronto was ticketed after he was caught using the HOV lane with two mannequins as his passengers, according to police. </Description>
        <MainBody>Toronto Driver Ticketed After Using HOV Lane With 2 Mannequins as Passengers
Jul 9, 2015, 2:11 PM ET
A Toronto driver used two dummies in an attempt to use the HOV lane.
Toronto Police Department
Copy
"Don't be a dummy!"
That's what the Toronto Police Service is telling the public after an unnamed driver was caught in the HOV lane on with two dressed mannequin dummies, according to a statement from the department.
"As a result, the driver was subsequently charged with the appropriate HOV offense," Toronto police said. "On a positive, note, everyone in the vehicle was wearing a seatbelt," including the mannequins.
Dear ABC News Fixer: Driving Solo in the Carpool Lane
The driver was stopped on Wednesday on the Gardiner Expressway after an officer noticed that the front-seat passenger in the Dodge pick-up truck "did not appear to be life-like," according to police.
The dummy in the front passenger seat was was wearing a baseball cap over a long, black wig of hair and was dressed in a floral top, according to the photo the cop snapped. The dummy in the back seat was wearing a black cap over a shorter black wig of hair and sported a yellow t-shirt, police said.
The photo was shared on the department's Twitter account with the caption, "Are you hangin' with dummies?"
It has been favorited over 500 times and retweeted over 300 times in less than 24 hours.
"The Toronto Police Service and the Integrated Security Unit would like to thank the motorists who continue to help us keep the region moving by carpooling, re-routing, re-timing, and taking transit whenever possible," police added in a statement.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:00:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What Kerry Is Saying Now About Iran Nuclear Deal </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/secretary-state-john-kerry-iran-nuclear-talks-sit/story?id=32332707</Link>
        <Description>Secretary of State John Kerry briefed reporters in Vienna today on the latest updates with the Iranian nuclear talks.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy
Speaking for less than five minutes outside the Palais Coburg Hotel here in Vienna, Secretary of State John Kerry told eager reporters that "tough issues remain unsolved" in the Iran nuclear talks, now nine days past the June 30 deadline.
"As I have said many times, we are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever," Kerry said. "We also recognize we shouldnt get up simply because the clock strikes midnight. We will not rush, and we will not be rushed."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:39:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brits: Terror Attack in Tunisia ???Highly Likely???</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/brits-terror-attack-tunisia-highly/story?id=32333209</Link>
        <Description>British government tells citizens to high-tail it out of north African nation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy
Saying another terrorist attack is highly likely, the British government today urged its citizens in Tunisia to get out of the north African nation.
Although we have had good cooperation from the Tunisian government, including putting in place additional security measures, the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably, reinforcing our view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely, the British Foreign Office said online today. On balance, we do not believe the mitigation measures in place provide adequate protection for British tourists in Tunisia at the present time and we have therefore changed our travel advice accordingly.
Editor's Picks
ISIS Claims Responsibility for Tunisia Attack That Killed 39
If youre in Tunisia and you dont have an essential need to remain, you should leave by commercial means, the statement says.
Late last month 38 foreign tourists were killed, including 30 Britons, at a popular beach resort in Tunisia when a gunman pulled a Kalashnikov rifle from under an umbrella and opened fire on the vacationers. The terror group ISIS later claimed responsibility for the attack.
Tunisia Attack: Gunman Kills at Least 39 at Beach Resort, ISIS Claims Responsibility
Today's advisory went on to say that "tourist resorts" could be targeted "by individuals unknown to the authorities whose actions may be inspired by terrorist groups via social media."
"The Tunisian authorities have increased their security measures but have also acknowledged the limitations of their ability to counter the current terrorist threat," the advisory said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:41:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syrian Refugees Pass 4 Million Mark, According to UN</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/syrian-refugees-fleeing-strife-civil-war-pass-million/story?id=32327149</Link>
        <Description>Fleeing a civil war, Syria's refugees have nearly doubled in the past year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syrian Refugees Fleeing Strife and Civil War Pass 4 Million Mark, According to UN
Jul 9, 2015, 11:28 AM ET
By EVAN SIMON
Syrian refugees gather at the Turkish border as they flee intense fighting in northern Syria between Kurdish fighters and Islamic State militants in Akcakale, Turkey, June 15, 2015.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
Copy
The number of Syrians fleeing their war-torn homeland for neighboring countries has passed the 4 million mark, according a United Nations report released today. The report comes just ten months after the U.N.'s refugee agency reported the number of Syrian refugees passed the 3 million mark.
"This is the biggest refugee population from a single conflict in a generation. It is a population that needs the support of the world but is instead living in dire conditions and sinking deeper into poverty," said U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees Antnio Guterres in a statement today.
The majority of Syrian refugees, just over 1.8 million, have fled to Turkey , according to the report, while other neighboring countries such as Lebanon , Jordan , Iraq , Egypt and other north African countries have also registered high numbers of refugees seeking asylum. Meanwhile, an additional 7.6 million people are still displaced inside Syria, many of them unable to get out, the report states.
Boris Grdanoski/AP Photo
PHOTO: Migrants from Syria and Afghanistan board a train to Serbia at the railway station in the southern Macedonian town of Gevgelija, June 22, 2015.
"The factor that is most important at this point is the ability of people to cross borders into neighboring countries," Bill Frelick, Human Rights Watch's director of refugee program, told ABC News.
Frelick pointed to restrictions that neighboring countries have placed on refugees fleeing Syria's civil war, such as Lebanon's visa restrictions and Jordan's unofficial closing of crossing points. Such neighboring countries, often unprepared economically and politically for an influx of Syrian refugees, have slowed the ability for refugees to cross their borders, Frelick said, arguing that it was up to the international community to provide the support necessary to keep them open.
"We have to recognize that the international community has a moral responsibility to support these countries and enable them to keep their doors open," Frelick said.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
PHOTO: Syrian refugees cross into Turkey from Syria over and through a hole on the border fence in Akcakale, Sanliurfa province, southeastern Turkey, June 14, 2015.
Last year's U.N. appeal calling for financial assistance to countries facing an influx of Syrian refugees was only half met, according to the UNCHR. Halfway through this year's appeal, funds received to date only reach 24% of the agency's more than $4.5 billion goal.
"This is a problem that is going to mushroom," Frelick said, noting that without the support of the international community, neighboring countries risk "becoming destabilized and a year so from now could produce even larger refugee populations."
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:02:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Check Out This Great White Photobomb</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/great-white-launches-sea-photobombs-shark/story?id=32309726</Link>
        <Description>A great white shark breached the surface for "no apparent reason."</Description>
        <MainBody>Great White Launches Out of the Sea, Photobombs Other Shark
Jul 8, 2015, 4:28 PM ET
By KAYLEE HECK
A great white shark is seen in this undated file photo.
Getty Images
Copy
Even sharks can be great at photobombing.
A boat -- on a dive tour with White Shark Africa -- was near Seal Island in Mossel Bay, South Africa when everyone on board got a memorable surprise.
Shark Attack Surge in North Carolina: What Could Be Behind It
Six divers were in the cage below the water and the camera was rolling Monday on a great white shark that was next to the vessel when another shark wanted some camera time, spokesman Dan Abbott told ABC News today.
Sometimes sharks will jump to get out of each others way, but there were no sharks below this one, he said.
The shark launched itself into the air and it was all caught on GoPro footage.
Abbott said it was a breach for no apparent reason since there wasnt bait in the water around them, but that it surprised everyone on board.
Great whites are the only sharks that spy hop to see around above the surface, he said. But I also like to think that, just like whales, great white sharks get some sort of joy from breaching like this."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Whether the Pope Samples Coca Plant a Burning Question</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/pope-francis-samples-coca-plant-burning-question/story?id=32306512</Link>
        <Description>The leaf is used in local teas in Bolivia, where he was headed this afternoon.</Description>
        <MainBody>Whether Pope Francis Samples Coca Plant a Burning Question
Jul 8, 2015, 1:47 PM ET
People take pictures with their phones as Pope Francis departs from the San Francisco Church aboard the Popemobile, in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
AP Photo
Copy
Millions of people have been following Pope Francis during his tour through Ecuador , but his actions this afternoon in Bolivia will be even more carefully watched.
The question on many minds today is "will he or won't he" after Francis is likely offered coca leaves to chew or tea brewed from the plant.
The plant is seen as a local delicacy that is regularly used to help treat altitude sickness in the town of La Paz, Bolivia, which is about 12,000 feet above sea level.
Pope Heads to Bolivia Amid Church-State Tensions
While those uses are widely accepted there, coca is known more globally as the plant that is the main ingredient in cocaine.
Coca was declared an illegal substance there in 1961, but that hasn't stopped dignitaries from trying it while on Bolivian soil, according to the Catholic News Agency .
Pope John Paul II drank tea made from coca during his 1988 visit to Bolivia, CNA reported.
AFP/Getty Images
PHOTO: Pope John Paul II blesses Bolivian faithful May 13, 1988 at Tajira airport.
The "will he or won't he" debate for Pope Francis, 78, started when Bolivian culture minister Marko Machicao said the Argentina-born pontiff "specifically requested" to chew coca, according to the BBC .
Vatican spokesman the Rev. Federico Lombardi remained non-committal in a statement to CNA when asked about the pope's verdict ahead of this afternoon's visit, saying he "wouldnt be surprised because the pope likes taking part in popular customs. The pope will do as he sees fit."
Lombardi added: "Well see if he follows local customs.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:02:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I Thought I Was Going To Die,' London Bombing Survivor Says 10 Years Later</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/thought-die-london-bombing-survivor-10-years/story?id=32280438</Link>
        <Description>Sajda Mughal, 33, was on the Underground that morning when a bomb exploded in the front car of her train in London.</Description>
        <MainBody>'I Thought I Was Going To Die,' London Bombing Survivor Says 10 Years Later
Jul 7, 2015, 7:26 PM ET
By LOUISE DEWAST
Sajda Mughal, 33, was on the Underground that morning when a bomb exploded in the front carriage. She survived, unhurt. But the memories of that day remain painful.
ABC News
Copy
Ten years ago, 52 people were killed and more than 700 injured in multiple terrorism attacks across London.
Sajda Mughal, 33, was on the Underground that morning when a bomb exploded in the front car. She survived, unhurt. But the memories of that day remain painful.
"I started thinking about my loved ones, thinking I hadn't said goodbye, that I hadn't gotten married and hadn't had kids. I was getting ready for death, but I was hoping this wouldn't be the end," Mughal said.
After 45 minutes in the darkness, emergency services rescued Mughal along with hundreds of others. Twenty-six people were killed and 340 were injured on her train.
Around the same time, bombs exploded on two other London Transport trains, killing eight and injuring 171 in one, killing seven and injuring 163 in the other. Nearly an hour later, a bomb exploded in a bus in central London, killing 14 people and injuring more than 110.
Today, commemorative events were held at St Paul's Cathedral in London and at a dedicated memorial in Hyde Park to remember the victims.
Mughal says her experience have changed her life. After several months of counselling she had gone back to her old job, but quickly realized that she was haunted by unanswered questions.
"I wanted to know who had brainwashed these four men, with a wrong ideology, and why," said Mughal, who is Muslim. "I couldn't accept that they had done this because I know that in the Koran it says that killing an innocent person is like killing humanity."
Since 7/7, Mughal has dedicated her time working for her non-profit organization, Jan Trust, which helps and educate Muslim mothers who are worried that their sons are being radicalized. She was awarded with the prestigious Order of the British Empire in 2015, a royal recognition to "distinguished service to the arts and sciences, public services outside the Civil Service."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:08:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>See 3-Year-Old's Reaction to Getting 'Parking Ticket'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/year-biker-parking-ticket-halifax-police-canada/story?id=32283240</Link>
        <Description>A 3-year-old was exasperated when he got his first ticket after "illegally" parking his red plastic motorbike at a ferry terminal in Halifax, Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>"Remember, no motorcycle parking in the circle by the ferry terminal," the Halixfax Department wrote on Twitter. "This ruthless biker was caught yesterday!"
Currie, who issued the "ticket," added that it's nice to show a softer side of police.
"We're not always making arrests and hauling people away," he told CTV News . "We like to have fun."
The photograph of the kid's reaction to getting an illegal parking ticket has gotten over 9,000 likes and over 2,000 shares on Halifax Regional Police's Facebook page .
Lisa Tramley, the ticketed toddler's mom, told CTV that her young bad boy has been a good sport about his ticket.
"He loves his ticket," she said. "He tried to go bed with his ticket."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:49:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Iran Negotiating Team Fuels Up With Twizzlers</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/twizzlers-iran-nuclear-talks/story?id=32283578</Link>
        <Description>As U.S. and Iranian nuclear talks drag on, Twizzlers fuel the negotiators.</Description>
        <MainBody>Twizzlers and String Cheese Fuel US Team in Iran Talks
Jul 7, 2015, 5:06 PM ET
By JESSE KIRSCH
US negotiators on the Iran nuclear deal have been eating a lot of Twizzlers during the talks.
Getty Images
Sweet.
The Iran nuclear talks may be dragging on in Vienna, but the U.S. team has a solution -- sugar and lots of it.
While there might be sticking points on a potential deal, U.S. negotiators can agree on one thing, their love of Twizzlers, string cheese and other goodies.
The 15-person U.S. delegation and their staff have, since June, scarfed down 10 pounds of strawberry Twizzlers, 30 pounds of mixed nuts and dried fruit, 20 pounds of string cheese and more than 200 Rice Krispies treats, a senior official said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:53:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Venezuela to Stop Buying Rice From Guyana Amid Dispute</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/venezuela-stop-buying-rice-guyana-amid-dispute-32341974</Link>
        <Description>Venezuela to stop taking oil payments in rice from Guyana amid escalating border dispute</Description>
        <MainBody>Venezuela to Stop Buying Rice From Guyana Amid Dispute
GEORGETOWN, Guyana  Jul 9, 2015, 5:52 PM ET
By BERT WILKINSON Associated Press
Venezuela has decided to stop buying much of Guyana's rice crop amid an escalating border dispute between the South American neighbors, the Guyanese finance minister said Thursday.
Finance Minister Winston Jordan said Venezuelan officials informed him during a visit to Caracas that they will be acquiring rice from other suppliers, including Suriname, by the end of the year.
Venezuela has in the past four years purchased about 40 percent of Guyana's rice production, or about 200,000 tons, paying for it with oil that amounts to about half of Guyana's daily supply needs.
"It will be a significant blow to us," said Peter DeGroot, president of the Rice Millers Association.
The exchange of rice for oil was done under the Petrocaribe program, a Venezuelan initiative that provides fuel at generous financial terms to Caribbean and Central American countries. Guyana remains a member of Petrocaribe and will continue to buy oil from Venezuela, Jordan said.
Jordan said Venezuela did not disclose the reason for its decision, but the long-running border dispute has been heating up following the recent disclosure of a major oil discovery off Guyana in waters that Venezuela also claims. Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro announced Monday that he was recalling his ambassador in Guyana for consultations and would review relations between the countries.
Venezuela has long refused to recognize a boundary drawn in 1899 and it claims about two-thirds of Guyana's territory as its own. Venezuela published a new map in May that expanded its maritime territory to essentially leave Guyana landlocked.
Guyana Prime Minister Moses Nagamootoo said the timing of the rice announcement made it at least appear that it is connected to the border fight.
"It will have to be considered whether Venezuela's position of the non-renewal of the Petrocaribe barter agreement is indeed an act of economic sanction against Guyana," he said in a statement.
President David Granger told Parliament on Thursday that Guyana does not have the military capacity to challenge Venezuela and his government would seek an international judicial settlement over the border issue.
"Guyana has never used aggression against any state," said Granger, a retired army general. "In as much as we are a peace loving state we will not allow our territorial integrity to be violated and threatened."
The finance minister said Venezuela did not rule out future purchases of rice. He also said that Venezuela had previously informed Guyanese officials of the plans to discontinue the bulk purchase of rice but the government of President Donald Ramotar, which lost May elections, did not disclose the information.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:49:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Offers Sweeping Sales Tax Hikes, Pension Cuts in New Proposals to Creditors</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/greece-offers-sweeping-sales-tax-hikes-pension-cuts-32341808</Link>
        <Description>Greece offers sweeping sales tax hikes, pension cuts in new proposals to creditors</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece Offers Sweeping Sales Tax Hikes, Pension Cuts in New Proposals to Creditors
ATHENS, Greece  Jul 9, 2015, 5:49 PM ET
Greece offers sweeping sales tax hikes, pension cuts in new proposals to creditors .
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:45:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mexican Journalist Robbed at Gunpoint While Webcasting</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/mexican-journalist-robbed-gunpoint-webcasting-32341779</Link>
        <Description>Mexican journalist robbed by gunman while webcasting from car, records part of incident</Description>
        <MainBody>Mexican Journalist Robbed at Gunpoint While Webcasting
MEXICO CITY  Jul 9, 2015, 5:45 PM ET
Mexican journalist Pedro Ferriz says he was robbed at gunpoint while webcasting and he kept recording, taping part of his own robbery.
Ferriz was speaking into a cellphone app in a car in Mexico City when he was robbed of his watch and phone by an assailant with a pistol.
In the video, which was posted on local websites, Ferriz is seen taping himself when suddenly a scuffle ensues. He can be heard saying, "I'm on air!"
The assault occurred on a street in an upscale neighborhood just blocks from the presidential residence.
The robbery drew attention to Mexico City's problem with persistent crime, despite the fact the capital has been largely spared the large-scale drug cartel violence affecting some regions of the country.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:40:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British American Tobacco Is Ending Operations in Chile</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/british-american-tobacco-ending-operations-chile-32341778</Link>
        <Description>British American Tobacco says it's ending operations in Chile due to law</Description>
        <MainBody>British American Tobacco Is Ending Operations in Chile
SANTIAGO, Chile  Jul 9, 2015, 5:40 PM ET
British American Tobacco is closing its operations in Chile because of changes to the country's tobacco law, the company announced Thursday.
The world's No. 2 cigarette maker, which produces brands like Dunhill, Lucky Strike and Pall Mall, objects to changes that include banning additives like menthol and adding larger warnings to cigarette packs about the risks of smoking.
The Chilean unit of the company called the toughening of Chile's tobacco law "unconstitutional and arbitrary."
"We deeply regret what has been approved by the Senate, a decision that will affect thousands of Chileans who were working legally and responsibly for more than 100 years," the company said in a statement.
British American Tobacco says the modifications approved by Chile's Senate this week would affect its business and hurt a "significant number of farmers and workers" who produce and sell tobacco in the country.
The company, which has operated in Chile since 1909, says it'll start the phase-out by firing 20 percent of its nearly 1,000 employees. It estimates about $400 million could be lost with the menthol ban and warning label changes.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:40:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saud Al-Faisal, Former Saudi Foreign Minister, Dies</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/saud-al-faisal-saudi-foreign-minister-dies-32336939</Link>
        <Description>Saud al-Faisal, former Saudi foreign minister with 40 years in the post, dies</Description>
        <MainBody>Saud Al-Faisal, Former Saudi Foreign Minister, Dies
RIYADH, Saudi Arabia  Jul 9, 2015, 5:39 PM ET
By ABDULLAH AL-SHIHRI and LEE KEATH Associated Press
Saudi Arabia's Prince Saud al-Faisal, who was the world's longest-serving foreign minister with 40 years in the post until his retirement this year, has died, the ministry spokesman said Thursday. He was 75.
The tall, stately Prince Saud was a fixture of Mideast diplomacy, representing the oil-rich Gulf powerhouse as it wielded its influence in crisis after crisis shaking the region  from Lebanon's civil war in the 1970s and 1980s, through multiple rounds of Arab-Israeli peace efforts, the 1990 Iraqi invasion of neighboring Kuwait and the subsequent Gulf War, al-Qaida's Sept. 11, 2001, attacks in the United States, the 2003 U.S.-led invasion of Iraq to the current day's tensions between the Arab Gulf bloc and Iran, Arab Spring uprisings, Syria's civil war and the spread of Islamic State group extremists.
The country's government-owned media announced Saud's death after midnight Friday. The official announcement, carried by state television, did not state the cause of death. The prince had undergone multiple surgeries in recent years for his back, which left him walking with a cane, and for other ailments.
Word of his passing first emerged late Thursday when Saudi Foreign Ministry spokesman, Osama Nugali, wrote on his official Twitter feed, "The eye tears, the heart saddens. We all are saddened to be separated from you."
The prince, who took the ministry post in 1975, retired on April 29, citing health reasons. At the time, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry hailed him, saying he "has not just been the planet's longest-serving Foreign Minister but also among the wisest." He was succeeded in the post by Adel al-Jubeir, who before that was Saudi Arabia's ambassador in Washington.
From Washington, Kerry expressed his condolences to Saud's family and friends, King Salman and to the people of Saudi Arabia , saying the prince was "a man of vast experience, personal warmth, great dignity, and keen insights who served his country loyally and well."
"I personally admired him greatly, valued his friendship, and appreciated his wise counsel," Kerry added. "His legacy as a statesman and diplomat will not be forgotten."
Saud was the son of Saudi Arabia's third king, Faisal, who ruled from 1964 until he was assassinated in 1975. Prince Saud, who had a bachelor's degree in economics from Princeton University and had been deputy petroleum minister, was soon after appointed to the foreign minister post, which his father had held during his reign. The young prince, fluent in English and French, brought an air of sophistication and charisma, whether in crisp suits or in the traditional Saudi white robe and gold-trimmed black cloak with a red-checkered head piece. Soft spoken, he often showed a sense of humor not often seen among the publicly stolid royal family.
He was father to six children, three boys and three girls. King Salman's son, Prince Sultan, is married to one of Prince Saud's daughters. The late prince's brothers are also known as highly educated and eloquent, with Prince Khaled al-Faisal serving as the governor of Mecca and another brother, Prince Turki al-Faisal, heading a research center and think tank after decades as the head of intelligence.
Mamoun Fandy, author of Saudi Arabia and the Politics of Dissent, said his death marks the end of an era as the elder royals move to shift power to younger princes.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:36:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Yemen Al-Qaida Leader Says US Is His Group's Only Rival</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/yemen-al-qaida-leader-us-groups-rival-32341771</Link>
        <Description>New Yemen al-Qaida leader says United States remains his group's only rival</Description>
        <MainBody>New Yemen Al-Qaida Leader Says US Is His Group's Only Rival
CAIRO  Jul 9, 2015, 5:36 PM ET
The new leader of Yemen's al-Qaida branch says his group's main enemy remains the United States and is urging Sunni militants to keep up their war against America, which he claims is "reeling" from terror attacks.
Qassim al-Raimi assumed the leadership of Al-Qaida in the Arabian Peninsula after a U.S. airstrike last month killed his predecessor, Nasir al-Wahishi, who was also the global terror network's second-most important figure.
In an audio message Thursday on social media, al-Raimi eulogized his predecessor, saying al-Wahishi got his wish to die fighting. The recording was posted by the AQAP's media arm.
Al-Raimi, who previously was the Yemeni branch's military commander, praised al-Qaida affiliates' recent victories in Syria and elsewhere.
Yemen's al-Qaida branch is widely seen as al-Qaida's most dangerous offshoot.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:19:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hopes for Greek Deal Rise as Creditors Open to Debt Relief</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/greece-racing-finalize-reforms-remain-euro-32321232</Link>
        <Description>As Greek government sends through reform proposals, creditors open to easing debt terms</Description>
        <MainBody>Hopes for Greek Deal Rise as Creditors Open to Debt Relief
ATHENS, Greece  Jul 9, 2015, 5:19 PM ET
By DEREK GATOPOULOS and RAF CASERT Associated Press
Pensioners wait outside the main gate of the national bank of Greece to withdraw a maximum of 120 euros ($134) in central Athens, Thursday, July 9, 2015. With a deadline just hours away to come up with a detailed economic reform plan, Greece... View Full Caption The Associated Press
Pensioners wait outside the main gate of the national bank of Greece to withdraw a maximum of 120 euros ($134) in central Athens, Thursday, July 9, 2015. With a deadline just hours away to come up with a detailed economic reform plan, Greece requested a new three-year rescue from its European partners Wednesday as signs grew its economy was sliding toward free-fall without an urgently needed bailout. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti) Close The Associated Press
Share
Copy
Greece finally met a deadline that counted on Thursday and made a series of proposals that its creditors needed by midnight to set off a mad rush toward a weekend deal to stave off a financial collapse of the nation.
It raised hopes that Greece can get the rescue deal that will prevent a catastrophic exit from the euro after key creditors said they were open to discussing how to ease the country's debt load, a long-time sticking point in their talks.
After months of foot-dragging despite impending chaos, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras sent the proposals to the country's international creditors late Thursday, and the spokesman for eurogroup President Jeroen Dijsselbloem tweeted that it was "important for institutions to consider these in their assessment" of the Greek situation.
Finance officials from the European institutions and the International Monetary Fund were to fine-comb through the proposals on Friday before the 19 eurozone finance ministers assess them on Saturday.
In ideal circumstances, a summit of the European Union's 28 members would be able to approve them on Sunday.
While creditors are now assessing whether Greece will offer the full range of economic measures they have asked for, Donald Tusk , who chairs the EU summits, indicated that European officials would make an effort to address Greece's key request for debt relief.
"The realistic proposal from Greece will have to be matched by an equally realistic proposal on debt sustainability from the creditors. Only then will we have a win-win situation," Tusk said.
Greece has long argued its debt is too high to be paid back and that the country requires some form of debt relief. The International Monetary Fund agrees with the premise, but key European states like Germany have resisted the idea.
On Thursday, German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble said the possibility of some kind of debt relief would be discussed over coming days, though he cautioned it may not provide much help.
"The room for maneuver through debt reprofiling or restructuring is very small," he said.
Making Greece's debt more sustainable would likely involve lowering the interest rates and extending the repayment dates on its bailout loans. Germany and many other European countries rule out an outright debt cut, arguing it would be illegal under European treaties.
The comments on Thursday boosted market confidence that a compromise will be found. The Stoxx 50 index of top European shares was up 2.4 percent in late afternoon trading.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras met with finance ministry officials and was holding a cabinet meeting Thursday afternoon to finalize his country's plan, a day after his government requested a new three-year aid program from Europe's bailout fund and promised to immediately enact reforms, including to taxes and pensions, in return.
The last-minute negotiations come as Greece's financial system teeters on the brink of collapse. It has imposed restrictions on banking transactions since June 29, limiting cash withdrawals to 60 euros ($67) per day to stanch a bank run. Banks and the stock market have been shut for just as long.
The closures, which have been extended through Monday, have led to daily lines at ATM machines and have hammered businesses. Payments abroad have been banned without special permission.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:19:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain Tells Tourists to Leave Tunisia Over Terror Risk</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/uk-government-tells-tourists-leave-tunisia-32332663</Link>
        <Description>British government tells UK tourists to leave Tunisia because of terror risk</Description>
        <MainBody>Britain Tells Tourists to Leave Tunisia Over Terror Risk
LONDON  Jul 9, 2015, 5:18 PM ET
By JILL LAWLESS Associated Press
The British government on Thursday told all U.K. tourists to leave Tunisia because a terrorist attack is "highly likely" and the North African country's government has not done enough to enhance security.
The Foreign Office advised against all but essential travel to Tunisia, a popular holiday destination for Britons. It said British tourists on package holidays should contact their travel agents, which will arrange flights to bring them home.
Thirty-eight tourists, 30 of them British, were killed on June 26 when a gunman stormed the Tunisian beach resort of Sousse. In March, 22 people died in an attack at the National Bardo Museum outside Tunis.
"While we do not have any information suggesting a specific or imminent threat, since the attack in Sousse the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably leading us to the view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely," British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said.
In a statement, his office said the travel advice had been changed because "we do not believe the mitigation measures in place provide adequate protection for British tourists in Tunisia."
On Saturday, more than a week after the Sousse attack, Tunisian authorities announced a state of emergency and enacted new security measures such as sending more than 1,300 security forces to patrol hotels, beaches and other tourist sites.
Hammond, speaking on the sidelines of talks about Iran's nuclear program in Vienna, said British authorities were in close contact with tour operators, who were arranging to get their customers home "as quickly as possible."
"To those travelling independently, our advice is to return on commercial flights which are operating normally," he added.
Travel company Thomas Cook, which has about 2,000 British customers in Tunisia, said it would be bringing customers back on its 10 scheduled flights this weekend, and use other airlines if needed. Spokesman Ian Benjafield said the company would get people home "whatever way we can."
Thomas Cook, along with firms Thomson and First Choice, canceled trips to Tunisia through Oct. 31. The 30 Britons who died in Sousse were Thomson and First Choice customers and the operators  both owned by TUI Group  have no travelers in Tunisia.
Michelle Ayres, a British tourist in Sousse, said she and other travelers had not received any information other than what they found online.
She wondered "if us Britons are at risk why put us all on the same buses to remove us from the hotels? Surely, that is the risk that they want?"
?"We all feel perfectly safe within the hotel," she told Channel 4 News. "They have been amazing."
The U.K. decision amounts to a major new blow to Tunisia's tourist industry. Hundreds of thousands of British tourists visit Tunisia each year. Many Britons left after the Sousse attack, but some 3,000 are still in Tunisia.
Germany's Foreign Ministry said it was observing the situation very closely and adjusting travel advice regularly. There was no immediate change to its travel advice, last updated five days ago. Two Germans were killed in the Sousse attack.
France's Foreign Ministry on Wednesday renewed its recommendation for French nationals in Tunisia to be "particularly vigilant" in the wake of the Sousse attack.
It stopped short of advising French nationals to return home. A ministry spokesman was not immediately available for comment following the British statement.
Tunisia's hospitality industry has already felt a major impact.
At the Riu Palace Hammamet Marhaba in coastal Hammamet, southeast of Tunis, receptionist Hamdi Mohsen said that since the attack in Sousse, business is down like he's never seen before in his 34 years working at the resort.
"It's all because of Sousse," he said. He noted that the hotel now has only about 100 visitors, far short of the 800-850 person capacity  and no Britons at all. The hotel, which was nearly full in early June, tends to host about 300 Britons a day at this time of year, he said.

Jamey Keaten in Paris contributed to this report.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:12:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Threatens to Quit Nuke Talks; Iran Blames West for Divide</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/iran-nuke-talks-lurch-deadline-32320555</Link>
        <Description>US threatens to quit nuke talks as they head into 14th day; Iran blames West for impasse</Description>
        <MainBody>US Threatens to Quit Nuke Talks; Iran Blames West for Divide
VIENNA  Jul 9, 2015, 5:11 PM ET
By BRADLEY KLAPPER and MATTHEW LEE Associated Press
European Union High Representative Federica Mogherini talks to media in front of Palais Coburg where closed-door nuclear talks with Iran take place in Vienna, Austria, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Mogherini said that negotiations will continue for the next couple of days despite hitting some tense moments. (AP Photo/Ronald Zak)
The Associated Press
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry threatened Thursday to walk away from nuclear talks as he signaled that diplomats won't conclude an agreement with Iran over the coming hours  another delay that this time could complicate American efforts to quickly implement any deal. The Iranians immediately fired back, accusing the U.S. and its European allies of causing the deadlock.
Kerry and other Western officials said Iran still hadn't made the tough political decision to roll back its nuclear program. But a senior Iranian official said it was the Americans and their partners who were backtracking on several key commitments related to Iran's permitted level of nuclear activity and definitively ending economic sanctions against Tehran.
"This is not open-ended," Kerry told reporters outside the 19th-century Viennese palace hosting the negotiations. "We can't wait forever for the decision to be made. If the tough decisions don't get made, we are absolutely prepared to call an end to this process."
It was the strongest indication yet of U.S. frustration with Iran, and vice versa, coming two days after President Barack Obama vowed a similar response to Iranian intransigence and suggesting patience was running out as the current round of talks headed into its 14th day.
Thursday's latest delay for a comprehensive deal is significant. Iran is demanding prompt easing of economic penalties for nuclear concessions, and the longer it takes world powers to make good on their promises, the longer they'll have to wait for the Iranians to scale back their nuclear program.
Under U.S. law, the seven nations negotiating in Vienna have to complete the accord before the end of Thursday in Washington to avoid invoking a 60-day congressional review period during which President Barack Obama cannot waive sanctions on Iran. If they meet the target, the review would only be 30 days.
The specter of prolonged public relations campaigns for and against the pact also may not work in Obama's favor. The delay could imply that the U.S., Iran and other negotiating powers may end up having to push off the talks until September when any deal would again only amount to a 30-day review period.
"We will not rush and we will not be rushed," Kerry said.
"We would not be here continuing to negotiate just for the sake of negotiating. We're here because we believe we are making real progress toward a comprehensive deal," he said. But, he added: "We are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever."
Kerry spoke after discussing the state-of-play with other world powers for almost an hour Thursday evening. That conversation followed a flurry of other closed-door meetings, including a 45-minute session between Kerry and his Iranian counterpart.
"We're working hard, but not rushed, to get the job done," Zarif tweeted.
A senior Iranian official, who briefed foreign reporters covering the talks on condition no one quote him by name, declared the West's reluctance to ease economic penalties the biggest obstacle. The U.S. is "obsessed" with sanctions, said the official, adding that the deadlock could prove a major setback.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said he would remain in Austria's capital for negotiations into Friday morning, citing "good things, but there is still work to do."
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:06:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Indigenous Group in Bolivia Frustrated</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-pope-francis-celebrate-mass-bolivia-32325269</Link>
        <Description>The Latest: Indigenous group in Bolivia frustrated that not invited to meeting with pope</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Indigenous Group in Bolivia Frustrated
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia  Jul 9, 2015, 5:06 PM ET
Pope Francis greets the crowd in Santa Cruz, Bolivia, Thursday, July 9, 2015. The pope is heading to his first public event of the day in Bolivia, an open-air Mass in Santa Cruz's Christ the Redeemer square. (AP Photo/Rodrigo Abd)
The Associated Press
Here are the latest developments from Pope Francis' trip to South America:

5 p.m.
A top leader of one of Bolivia's largest indigenous groups is expressing frustration for not getting accredited to attend a social summit with Pope Francis on Thursday evening.
The Guarani has been at odds with the government of President Evo Morales ' government over its decision to open up the country's 22 protected wilderness areas to oil and natural gas exploration.
Guarani leader Celso Padilla says: "The summit is strictly controlled by people from the government. The government has only accredited people close to it. We've been left out."
Bolivia's deputy minister for coordination with social movements says the Guarani would have been welcome had they actively sought participation.
Xavier Albo, a Jesuit priest, author and leading authority on Bolivia's indigenous, says it's curious the pope is not holding any separate meetings with indigenous groups on his entire eight-day visit in South America.
He says: "There isn't a single act that is explicitly for the indigenous, but rather they are included within encounters with social movements together with other sectors."

4:30 p.m.
The pope is scheduled to give a late-afternoon speech to delegates at the second World Meeting of Popular Movements, a colorful gathering of Latin America's dispossessed and groups  including the Catholic charity Caritas  who advocate for them.
The first such meeting was held at the Vatican in October. Its Justice and Peace council organized this meeting with Bolivia's government, which chose the more than 1,500 delegates.
Inside a Santa Cruz sports hall, land rights advocates from Peru swapped experiences with people displaced by hydroelectric projects in Brazil, Bolivia's main labor federation and of mining collectives were prominent, along with Brazil's CUT labor federation.
Prominent, too, are delegates from CONAMAQ, Bolivia's main highlands indigenous organization, representing the dominant Quechua and Aymara ethnicities.
And then there are the truly poor, including nearly a dozen collectives of trash-pickers, "cartoneros," from Argentina , organizations especially dear to the pope.

2:45 p.m.
The Vatican is seeking to explain the "Communist crucifix" given to Pope Francis by Bolivian President Evo Morale, saying it's a symbol of dialogue and not an offensive melding of faith and ideology.
Morales gave the crucifix carved into a hammer and sickle to Francis when they met Wednesday upon Francis' arrival in Bolivia.
The Vatican wasn't expecting the unusual gift and it immediately raised eyebrows.
It turns out, the crucifix was originally designed by Jesuit activist Luis Espinal, who was assassinated in 1980 by suspected paramilitaries during the months that preceded a military coup. Francis is a fellow Jesuit and he stopped to pray at the site where Espinal's body was dumped.
The Vatican spokesman is the Rev. Federico Lombardi, and he said Thursday the pope had no idea that Espinal had designed such a crucifix.
Lombardi said Espinal's fellow priests said he had designed the crucifix as a symbol of dialogue and commitment to freedom for Bolivia during a turbulent time.
Many church theologians have bitterly denounced the Marxist influences on Liberation Theology, but Francis has tried to rehabilitate the movement  without the Marxism.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:26:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Kerry on Iran Nuclear Negotiations: 'We Will Not Rush'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/kerry-iran-nuclear-negotiations-rush-32340356</Link>
        <Description>Sec. of State John Kerry says negotiators are making progress, but warns "we will not sit at the negotiating table forever."</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Kerry on Iran Nuclear Negotiations: 'We Will Not Rush'
Another deadline in the Iran nuclear negotiations is apparently going to come. And go without a final deal won't let ourselves rushed through any aspect of this nine days after the original deadline secretary Kerry insists negotiators are making real progress. But says the US will not hesitate to walk away if their conditions are not met we are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever. Earlier this year negotiators outlined a tentative framework that would allow unprecedented inspections of Iran's nuclear facilities reduce Iran's existing supply of nuclear fuel and limit its ability to make highly enriched uranium in exchange economic sanctions that have crippled Iran's economy would be lifted but he's sticking points remain including how to limit and monitor Iran's nuclear program. And the pace at which those sanctions on Iran would be lifted. We are gonna need to see concrete verifiable progress. Toward living up to their commitments. On a part of the Iranians. Both for sanctions relief related to nuclear weapons. Is get it but critics are still skeptical a deal can be reached a ram by all accounts those announcer it's about abandoning its nuclear weapons program. When the president news. When will the president and his negotiators. Stand strong. After today's miss deadline lawmakers here in Washington will now have an extra 3860. Total to review any final deal and the more time lawmakers have the more time the opposition. We'll have to rally support against any final agreement. Mary Bruce ABC news Washington.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Toronto Man Ticketed for Mannequin Passengers in HOV Lane
Now Playing: Kerry on Iran Nuclear Negotiations: 'We Will Not Rush'
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Extended Again
Now Playing: Official Photos From Princess Charlotte's Christening Released
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Wimbledon Fans See Fantastic Tennis but Hear Loud Grunts
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32340356,"title":"Kerry on Iran Nuclear Negotiations: 'We Will Not Rush'","duration":"1:40","description":"Sec. of State John Kerry says negotiators are making progress, but warns \"we will not sit at the negotiating table forever.\"","url":"/International/video/kerry-iran-nuclear-negotiations-rush-32340356","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Iran Nuclear Talks Extended Again</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/iran-nuclear-talks-extended-32335545</Link>
        <Description>Secretary of State John Kerry says tough issues are still on the table and negotiators will not be rushed</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Iran Nuclear Talks Extended Again
Under. Developments today in the Iran nuclear talks another deadline fast approaches negotiators from six countries including the US turning the screws on Iran to get a deal. Right now the international hot spots. Vienna Austria hello I'm Packard. Hear from secretary Kerry who you just not just a moment with an update on the negotiations. And it's time they let the negotiations are delayed again it could set things back two months or more. ABC's Molly hunter is in Vienna Austria. Bus Molly still no deal there. Still not yelled I that we are standing by now we have the low impact that June 30 deadline nine days pat that June 30 deadline. And are waiting for acting from secretary of eight carry right now we have heard positive things but cautiously positive things in recent days and secretary Kerry we did this morning at that the teens are working diligently that they are working hard and they are continuing to talk. But work nine dean's path that deadline and there's speculation here that they may just. Keep talking actually as long as talks remain productive. They may faint that he will be hurt as much from the packed Press Secretary earlier this week. And we heard from the Iran audience to that as long as progress is being made that the are protected conversations at that table. They may just stay at that table even longer and I can tell you. The media spam in the journalists behind art. Really hoping that's not the case. What are the main sticking point among negotiators at this point. Nat US delegation and other delegations it's that they will get quieter as we get closer and they often said that they had never. Bank closer. Add in the last years as these negotiations have been going on but we can tell you dared to add. Pretty important sticking point that have yet to be ironed out. And sanctions now that sanctions and tricky since the beginning and they remain tricky at the eleventh hour now Iran infant strapped. And a simultaneous. Action so did David the Iran and start to chip away at that nuclear programs start to at neat does technical requirements. They want to see a framework in place from the so called. At for the permanent members of the Security Council and two of which the US is a maverick and they want to see a framework in place. That will lift all the sanctions so tight by the time that act. The Iraq and have actually finished and that all of those technical requirements. There are also those sanctions and have been lifted now money will flow back and if that economy albeit slowly but that is what Iran instant watch. Now the second sticking point that is being talked about a lot in this eleventh hour. Is the arms embargo and I can play that rush. I'm a member of that. Isn't really keen to get that arms embargo lifted there is an arms embargo on Iran and you Ronnie that said for years now that actually. A conventional weapons program and having ballistic missiles and shouldn't be part of this new nuclear negotiation and shouldn't be restricted now the US that. They actually that our arms embargo and the ban on ballistic missiles. And in conventional weapon is a direct result of this nuclear program at so we have not. Heard whether those two issues and have been ironed out. But they're going to be have to I got if there's going to be a deal on the table. All right Mike thank you so much for joining us ABC's Molly hunter in Vienna Austria. And right now I US secretary of state John Kerry updating the ongoing nuclear negotiations with Iran in yen up let's listen. Look good evening everybody let me start by thanking all of you for your remarkable patience. I know in fact all of us involved in this know that. There's been a very difficult couple of weeks for that many journalists. Who are here in Viet without us. But let me assure you. We would not be here are continuing to negotiate. Just for the sake of negotiating. We're here because we believe we're are making real progress toward. A comprehensive deal. But as I have said many times and as I discussed with President Obama last night. We are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever. We also recognize. That we shouldn't get up and leave simply because the clock strikes midnight. And I emphasize. Given that the work here is incredibly technical and that the stakes are very very high. We will not rush. And we will not be rushed. And we won't let ourselves be rushed through any aspect of this. All that we are focused on is the quality of the agreement. And that is what will continue to define our work. If in the end we are able to reach a deal. It has to be one that can withstand the test of time. Does not a test of a matter of days or weeks or months. To test for decades. That's our goal here. The simple fact is that despite all of the progress that we have made and it's real. Some of the tough issues remain un resolved. We know that difficult decisions. Don't become easier over time. One way or the other. Those decisions must be taken very soon. That is precisely why all of our delegations remain hard at work here in Vienna. And that's why a number of my counterparts returned last night that are here now. So that we can't continue to push. Through on the tough issues. And ultimately see whether or not the good deal that we have been working for so hard. As possible to achieve. That's what we're working on. That's what we'll continue to work thank you all very much. How long are you willing to Spain. Acting I just said this is not open ended. Pres Obama made it very clear to me last night. You can't wait forever for the decision be made we know that if the tough decisions don't get made. We are absolutely prepared. To call an end to this process. Thank you all very very much thank you. The president said it's less than 5050 that he get a deal that's when he told the Democrat well under. Thank you all very much appreciate it. Sykes. Secretary of state John Kerry they're leaving the podium we're gonna bring in ABC's merry Bruce in Washington area noted deal. No no timeline but. This is an open ended he'll be returning home soon if there is no progress made what is this all mean. You heard secretary carry their state very clearly. That they will not be rushed that they are still going to try and work through some of these remaining very. Large sticking points that are still on the table but that this is not going. To simply be some open ended process now the Obama administration and especially secretary Kerry have worked in recent days tick to dismiss suggestions that. Desperation will somehow prompt the president to rush to sign a deal that is in a good deal and you heard again secretary Kerry saying. That they are going to make sure that they stick. Today it the framework that was originally outlined that they are only going to accept a good deal and that they remain optimistic that that can be achieved. But it they simply aren't going to negotiate this forever that they will at some point. Call it quits if that good deal cannot be achieved. So best case scenario we come away with the deal what happens. Well once the deal if a deal is achieved then US lawmakers will have an opportunity to pick over and that's actually one of the reasons why thinking deadline. About one of many self imposed deadlines that now will be blown through was so critical had reached a deal. By midnight tonight and US lawmakers would have had thirty days to review of the deal but since they will miss that deadline lawmakers' will now have. Sixty days to review a deal and as you can imagine the more time lawmakers have the more time. The opponents of the deal have to try and rally against state and so the longer supporters will have. It's it's it today in theory be at risk of losing a deal. So there are high key stakes here and in fact we jester white house Press Secretary Josh Earnest once again say that any deal. Will be verifiable Nicholas. Well it. I'm confident there will be critics of the deal who will say that they would like to have additional time to try and criticize the agreement. That said we continue to have confidence. That the terms of the political agreement that were reached in Los on. Will be the parameters of a final agreement if one can be reached India. And the reason for that is that since that's essentially what the president has established as his bottom line. And to the president. Continues to be confident that. An agreement like that would effectively shut down every pathway that are on test a nuclear weapon. And it would put in place the most intrusive set of inspections and have been imposed on the country's nuclear program. To verify Iran's compliance with the agreement now this final agreement has not been reached yet they're still continue to be some. Obstacles to reaching that final agreement but that's the only kind a final agreement. At present Obama and the American negotiating team will sign off on the good news is that this is the only kind of final agreement that our international partners will sign off on as well so. That the president has succeeded over the last several years in building and unanimous international front. To compel Iran to come to the negotiating table and make serious commitments and concessions. That will ensure that it any sort of nuclear activity that exists in Iran exists solely for peaceful purposes. But what the or run ins have sought and what is the essence of the negotiation. Our how would. The a Ronnie and stick specific steps to. Should never happened after the nuclear weapon in an exchange would nuclear. Sanctions nuclear weapons related sanctions. Be. Relieved in exchange for those steps. What we have said is that. We are gonna need to see concrete verifiable progress. Toward living up to their commitments. On the part of the Iranians. Both for sanctions relief related to nuclear weapons. Is get. And but exactly how to structure that is the essence of the ongoing negotiations and. So Mary we heard initially with the initial framework of this deal so much optimism but with all the time it is pass and the deadlines misses the White House. Scaling back on its expectations for a deal. I think they are a little bit you still hear optimism but it is a cautious optimism clearly. You heard secretary Kerry come out and say that there is still enough hope here that it's worth them staying. In the candidate trying him around and of these remaining sticking point but again he said they are not going to just stay at the negotiating table for ever and to put that into some broader contacts. The president earlier in the they have this week reportedly told senate Democrats that he now what's the chance of a deal at less. And 5050. Time all right not great odds that considering BM out of hope the White House expressed just some months ago NBC's Mary Bruce with us from Washington thank you so much. For joining us and the word from Vienna no deal yet and no new timeline for a deal is negotiations for Iranian nuclear program. And limiting that program. Continues you can keep up with the story in real time I downloading the ABC news app and starting this story for exclusive updates on the go out. This is an international hot spot on ABC news digital anti Hernandez in New York thanks for watching.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: High Stakes Negotiations With Iran
Now Playing: Toronto Man Ticketed for Mannequin Passengers in HOV Lane
Now Playing: Kerry on Iran Nuclear Negotiations: 'We Will Not Rush'
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Extended Again
Now Playing: Official Photos From Princess Charlotte's Christening Released
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Wimbledon Fans See Fantastic Tennis but Hear Loud Grunts
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32335545,"title":"Iran Nuclear Talks Extended Again","duration":"12:17","description":"Secretary of State John Kerry says tough issues are still on the table and negotiators will not be rushed","url":"/International/video/iran-nuclear-talks-extended-32335545","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:13:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Great White Launches Out of the Sea, Photobombs Other Shark</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/great-white-photobombs-other-shark-32325271</Link>
        <Description>Six divers were in a shark cage off the coast of South Africa when it happened.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Great White Launches Out of the Sea, Photobombs Other Shark
Hilly hike sharply well underway now to mark the UK general we show you this from South Africa. That is diet great white devouring a piece of Tony you see that but then. That would decide to another sharp jump suddenly out of the water in the back. Dependent that it would oppose that there fishermen on the boat insisted he did nothing to war the second star kid. We've heard sharks are Smart but do they were hip to photo Bob same news. Amazing shot that as a fantastic but.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Great White Launches Out of the Sea, Photobombs Other Shark
Now Playing: Man Flies Balloon-Powered Lawn Chair Over Canada
Now Playing: Baby Pygmy Hippo Goes for One Adorable Swim
Now Playing: Watch This Aunt Totally Freak Out at Baby News
Now Playing: This TV Reporter Is Really Bugged by Cicadas
Now Playing: Man Calls 911 Over Stuffed Tiger: 'It Seems Pretty Dangerous'
Now Playing: Florida Woman's Toilet Clogged by Iguana Intruder
Now Playing: Man Calls 911 Over 'Aggressive' and 'Mad' House Cat
Now Playing: Man Caught Dancing to 'Rich Girl' Atop Patrol Car
Now Playing: Raccoon Uses Umbrella to Stay Out of Rain
Now Playing: See Man's Body Covered With 1.1 Million Bees
Now Playing: Kids Captivated by Gator on Front Lawn
Now Playing: Python's Taste for BBQ Tongs Leaves It Hospitalized
Now Playing: Koala Wanders Into Hospital Waiting Room
Now Playing: Honolulu Food Festival Showcases Spam
Now Playing: 'Van Goat': Meet Bodie, the 4-Year-Old Goat That Paints
Now Playing: California Hills Are Alive With Mystery Piano's Music
Now Playing: What This Leopard Kitten Does Will Make Your Day
Now Playing: Little Girl Scolds Aunt for Using 'Bad Word'
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32325271,"title":"Great White Launches Out of the Sea, Photobombs Other Shark","duration":"0:29","description":"Six divers were in a shark cage off the coast of South Africa when it happened.","url":"/International/video/great-white-photobombs-other-shark-32325271","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:31:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/nyse-trading-resumes-united-airlines-flights-grounded-hours-32313271</Link>
        <Description>NYSE trading resumes after technical glitch; United Airlines Flights Grounded for hours, causing heavy delays; Facebook makes subtle change to icon. </Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
The closing bell sounds odd it's great game. I'll speak in New York Stock Exchange trading vaulted from most of the big hit with technical college officials are able to get it back running. 4050. Sort of makes it means is you know one of the big venues and how many venues were retrained stocks went out. And just just. The vulnerability. The F eight lifting the nationwide ground stop on United Airlines flight plot. Out of the travelers still waiting in long lines for more than an hour tonight on all of its planes here in the US QQ what they called me. Network connectivity issues computer problems that they couldn't get checked and pathos. The rope line. Let's sell off in China continues. Stocks in Shanghai welcome to bear market territory within 66%. Sell off today. Well this is something that has been going on now for three weeks to market China selling off more than 30%. Two and a half trillion dollars in wealth just wiped out in that span of time. I think battle today over encryption technology in our Smartphones and computers and cracking down on terror plot. A law enforcement officials including FBI director came on the Capitol Hill arguing the right to privacy must be weighed against public safety interim. Law enforcement officials. Are trying to make the case agent sent to congress today that they need legislation that. To force these companies to make products that can be tapped into with portals. I'm faithful to the friends icon is getting his make over. The new icon is on the right you can see the woman is no longer in the man shot up. They're equal partners there the FaceBook designer who brought the woman silhouettes the forefront. Similar changes were made in the FaceBook groups I kinda new icon on the right showing a woman. In fruits. That doctor Doolittle of the dump more on this Golden Retriever is content to outlaw act of lives with these experts at camps here and it is safe today. They're I'll be at that. Bob add hoses and hang out with his Brothers and sisters from the other mother. Get him to take pictures where there thankfully it's human powers.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:45:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/nyse-halts-trading-due-technical-glitch-sc-house-32311470</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 7.8.15.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: South Carolina Senators Vote to Remove Confederate Flag From Capitol Grounds
Now Playing: NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI, 'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon
Now Playing: Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies, U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day, Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon
Now Playing: C-130 Plane Crashes In Medan Indonesia, Gov. Chris Christie Announces Presidential Bid, President Obama Meets With Brazilian President
Now Playing: Obama Signs Fast-Track Trade Bill, NBC Cuts Ties With Trump, Wimbledon Begins
Now Playing: 3rd Suspect in Boston ISIS Terror Arrested; House Rejects Obama's Trade Bill; Boeing Shows Off New Dreamliner
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 6/9/15
Now Playing: Colorado Tornado Damage, American Pharoah Practice Run, Hong Kong MERS Screening
Now Playing: Sen. Graham Enters Presidential Race, Caitlyn Jenner Revealed, Nadal Wears $775k Watch At The French Open
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Hillary Breaks Her Silence With Reporters, Fatal Flooding In Columbia, 'Blue Alert Act' signed
Now Playing: Amtrak Derailment Debris Cleaned Up, Mississippi Officer Remembered, Search for Missing US Marines Helicopter
Now Playing: Deadly Amtrak Crash in Philadelphia, Nepal Earthquake Aftermath, Indy 500 Car Flips During Practice
Now Playing: Second Earthquake Strikes Nepal, Arkansas Tornado Victims Cleanup, 'Jetman' Soars Above Dubai
Now Playing: Attorney General Announces Baltimore Investigation, NYPD Officer Mourned, Obama at Nike Headquarters
Now Playing: Oklahoma Tornado Aftermath, Quake Victims Remembered In Nepal, Air Force Football Meets Obama
Now Playing: Philadelphia Honors Fallen Officers, Sir Elton John Fights For HIVAIDS Funding, SpaceX Tests Astronaut Abort System
Now Playing: Gen. Dunford Nominated Joint Chiefs Of Staff, Huckabee Announces 2016 Bid, Cinco De Mayo
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 5/04/15
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32311470,"title":"NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match","duration":"0:46","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 7.8.15.","url":"/International/video/nyse-halts-trading-due-technical-glitch-sc-house-32311470","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:58:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/london-bombings-survivor-thought-die-32286347</Link>
        <Description>Sajda Mughal remains in pain 10 years after surviving the 2005 London bombings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'
Or. Asked about those three as oh among. Kenyon to day I was working in the sixty of London. They means. That was. It. I wasn't that makes. Says that issues on the big ticket. Am happy that she's I should've looked on silently. I ended up getting that you. Ten seconds. Into the tunnel obviously took office when it was aimed not at which time out that was its base. Train and let's not act but it felt like. Show. Life went house. Waxman stops and a carriage. Compete and it actually. Then act signed. Went. Into screen. Trying. People buying the tools. People crying. Yeah. But for me I remained in the east still. And I remember going to shall. Win and I had a crush of fools. And I stopped to remember my loved ones. And I honestly feel that. I was going to die that day. Basically I was complete city covet. A black smoke my hands face. My suit I remember but having its takeoff in the carriage might they send it to you wrapping it around my face. Could let it starts to suffocate me. Eventually. What happened was. He mentions he says it's came down. To rescue us. We need to clear now roses well. Please on the evening yeah. Came in the carriage is escort us out onto the tracks. Back to king's books I've talked corn up on I couldn't get through on the net that network systems without. And I had to make my way high one book exactly what I did I won't back. It took me Alice. Took how is that eventually went liked it now I'm and I remember when I was on my right I just ran past Boston like it's my. According to the house bill that dual shock that since shuffled lines that TV and radio an amendment. Just cutting off from the safe. This needs to isn't crying weight problems come. I was compete job I though the UK would Napa -- for bombing. And often on the national and stand. And then stuck in. That it will they were bombings carried out ice cream. I'm not shocked me even mall the attacks that they could eat eat and can you don't want to overcome that and. I don't. Because that job she.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: British Remember 7/7 Bombings
Now Playing: London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'
Now Playing: Law Enforcement on Heightened Alert Ahead of July 4th
Now Playing: Pres. Obama Announces Embassy Openings in Cuba; Dozens Killed in ISIS Sinai Attack; Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: Iran Hostage Crisis Survivor Protests Obama Nuclear Deal
Now Playing: A Year of Sleepless Nights for Boy Who Survived Deadly Beach Attack
Now Playing: ISIS in Mosul 1 Year Later
Now Playing: Meet the 8 Young Musicians of NYC's Harmony Program As They Take the Stage with the NY Philharmonic
Now Playing: Inside the Horse Barns at Belmont Park
Now Playing: A Day in the Life: How Music Helps Get One Girl Into One of NYC's Top Public Schools
Now Playing: A Day in the Life: Music Helps Change the Life of a Boy From an Underserved Community
Now Playing: The American Dream: Music Helps An Immigrant Mother's Wishes Come True for Her Daughter
Now Playing: Retaliation for Military Sexual Assault Reporting Rampant
Now Playing: Wildlife Parkgoers Defy Rules After Lion Kills American
Now Playing: First Look Inside the Dizzying Heights of the New World Trade Center
Now Playing: Watch: Texas Flash Flooding, May 2015
Now Playing: Here's The Military-Style Gear President Obama Banned Local Police From Using
Now Playing: Biker Gang Shootout Leaves 9 Dead in Texas
Now Playing: Moscow's Subway Is An Underground Palace
Now Playing: How 5 Possible White House Hopefuls Answered the Iraq Question
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32286347,"title":"London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'","duration":"3:47","description":"Sajda Mughal remains in pain 10 years after surviving the 2005 London bombings.","url":"/International/video/london-bombings-survivor-thought-die-32286347","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:56:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/year-boy-issued-parking-ticket-32286252</Link>
        <Description>Halifax police constable Shawn Currie jokingly issued a citation for Declan Tramley's illegally stopped red plastic motorcycle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
It's a familiar sight and sound on the Halifax waterfront. All too familiar for constable Sean Currie part of my job in the water premise public safety and part of it was just keeping the circle clear for emergency vehicles. While the motorcyclist like combat partner here. It's a big reason you'll spot three year old decked him scrambling cruising the boardwalk it's one of his favorite places to explore. There's people to meet shops to check out but its favorite attraction is the motorcycles. Accompanied by his parents Jacqueline loves to ride down on his bike. Toss on his leather jackets even mingle with his fellow bikers. Is that mores are brings in to see the bikes and stuff. You know once every couple weeks that's when Jacqueline had his first run in with the law he practiced by dislike the other more cycles. He walked away and we thought it would be funny by went over in just pretend to read architect police officer went over it and they're pretending to read him a ticket and it is certificates and and equipment parent. Once sequins father snapped the picture sent it to the Halifax regional police who jumped at the opportunity to posted on social media so far reaction to the picture's been overwhelming. I never die. It would explode I mean. As looking like different radio stations FaceBook pages and everywhere insist. Every night this shows the different sides of please. You know we're not always the ones making arrests and hauling people away were just normal like everybody else in the the picture received hundreds of re tweets and favorites on Twitter. And the H or. 440000. People closes ticket. The outside nervously as you can actually it's safe to say though that. He won't be so pleased years from now when he receives his first actual parking ticket and has to dish out the cash to pay for it Matt Woodman CTV news Halifax.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Toronto Man Ticketed for Mannequin Passengers in HOV Lane
Now Playing: Kerry on Iran Nuclear Negotiations: 'We Will Not Rush'
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Extended Again
Now Playing: Official Photos From Princess Charlotte's Christening Released
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Wimbledon Fans See Fantastic Tennis but Hear Loud Grunts
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32286252,"title":"Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket","duration":"1:51","description":"Halifax police constable Shawn Currie jokingly issued a citation for Declan Tramley's illegally stopped red plastic motorcycle.","url":"/International/video/year-boy-issued-parking-ticket-32286252","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:57:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons  </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/fighter-jet-small-plane-collide-fbi-searches-subway-32285611</Link>
        <Description>Two killed after fighter jet and small plane collide over South Carolina; FBI searches Subway spokesman Jared Fogle's home; Man ties himself to helium balloons to advertise business. </Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
The mid air collision involving a military F sixteen fighter aircraft and he's definitely one that people were now. Carolina and that crash scene is looking at about eleven miles north of Charleston as the fighting. Aircraft the prop plane colliding with a supersonic F sixteen. Air force fighter. The FBI they think Indiana we'll look at Pittsburgh and U ovals this morning. We'll go out just after weak case attorney for fifty fully cooperating with authorities. Working screen and vet almost 7000. Volunteers. To ensure that they are committed to fighting Neitzel as of July 3 partner currently training about sixty fighters. This number is much smaller than we hope for us. Startling revelations about bill can't be today in a deposition from a sexual -- federal ten years ago the comedian admitted to obtaining waiting weeks for women keep going to have sex. Very very blog. From a legal point of view him as well as from an emotional. For many the election. New clot on cape Florida State freshman cornerback Dionte Johnson. Punching a woman at a bar last month the incident caught on surveillance camera and released yesterday by prosecutors had met the teen to cut ties. With a heartbeat. Really what's going on across Paul sports. Right now since the rate video blame someone you know is charged with something more there arrest. On something at what point do you cut. Today topping it with an official gathering in brothels for an emergency summit for Greece's new finance chief arrived without a proposal. Greece is expected tonight to put out a letter to other Euro zone members asking for assistance from what's called DS and European stability mechanism. That would give them a medium. And short term loans. If you want to up your advertising game called this guy at 26 year old man soared over Calgary to appetite for cleaning product. He used more than 100 helium balloons and a lawn chair in the active parachute down after. Flew off of course police are not happy the man arrested for mr. causing danger through life. Oh.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home Searched by FBI
Now Playing: Toronto Man Ticketed for Mannequin Passengers in HOV Lane
Now Playing: Kerry on Iran Nuclear Negotiations: 'We Will Not Rush'
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Extended Again
Now Playing: Official Photos From Princess Charlotte's Christening Released
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Wimbledon Fans See Fantastic Tennis but Hear Loud Grunts
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32285611,"title":"Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons ","duration":"2:32","description":"Two killed after fighter jet and small plane collide over South Carolina; FBI searches Subway spokesman Jared Fogle's home; Man ties himself to helium balloons to advertise business. ","url":"/International/video/fighter-jet-small-plane-collide-fbi-searches-subway-32285611","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:27:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI,  'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/subway-spokesman-home-searched-fbi-running-bulls-begins-32284441</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 7.7.15</Description>
        <MainBody>Brown shocked crowds as he dominated his match with 2-time Wimbledon champ Rafael Nadal.
Now Playing: Dustin Brown Becomes Wimbledon's Breakout Star
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home Searched by FBI
Now Playing: NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI, 'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon
Now Playing: Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies, U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day, Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon
Now Playing: C-130 Plane Crashes In Medan Indonesia, Gov. Chris Christie Announces Presidential Bid, President Obama Meets With Brazilian President
Now Playing: Obama Signs Fast-Track Trade Bill, NBC Cuts Ties With Trump, Wimbledon Begins
Now Playing: 3rd Suspect in Boston ISIS Terror Arrested; House Rejects Obama's Trade Bill; Boeing Shows Off New Dreamliner
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 6/9/15
Now Playing: Colorado Tornado Damage, American Pharoah Practice Run, Hong Kong MERS Screening
Now Playing: Sen. Graham Enters Presidential Race, Caitlyn Jenner Revealed, Nadal Wears $775k Watch At The French Open
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Hillary Breaks Her Silence With Reporters, Fatal Flooding In Columbia, 'Blue Alert Act' signed
Now Playing: Amtrak Derailment Debris Cleaned Up, Mississippi Officer Remembered, Search for Missing US Marines Helicopter
Now Playing: Deadly Amtrak Crash in Philadelphia, Nepal Earthquake Aftermath, Indy 500 Car Flips During Practice
Now Playing: Second Earthquake Strikes Nepal, Arkansas Tornado Victims Cleanup, 'Jetman' Soars Above Dubai
Now Playing: Attorney General Announces Baltimore Investigation, NYPD Officer Mourned, Obama at Nike Headquarters
Now Playing: Oklahoma Tornado Aftermath, Quake Victims Remembered In Nepal, Air Force Football Meets Obama
Now Playing: Philadelphia Honors Fallen Officers, Sir Elton John Fights For HIVAIDS Funding, SpaceX Tests Astronaut Abort System
Now Playing: Gen. Dunford Nominated Joint Chiefs Of Staff, Huckabee Announces 2016 Bid, Cinco De Mayo
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 5/04/15
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32284441,"title":"Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI, 'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon","duration":"0:39","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 7.7.15","url":"/International/video/subway-spokesman-home-searched-fbi-running-bulls-begins-32284441","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 23:46:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Greece's Financial Crisis Affects Citizens, Store Owners</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/greeces-financial-crisis-affects-citizens-store-owners-32282647</Link>
        <Description>ABC News??? Alexander Marquardt talks to businesses that are losing money due to the economic situation in Greece.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Greece's Financial Crisis Affects Citizens, Store Owners
This is something you see all across Athens all across streets here behind me two different yeah. Hands would long lines at each of them. People lining up to take out that maximum daily allotment of sixty euros. Or 67 dollars and that number could quickly go down to zero this country running out of cash. If it doesn't get an emergency injection sued all of these ATMs will soon be empty. We've been coming every day you know at sixty euros every day. You immediately spend that are you sitting at home in case congressman's not only then there's me the first needs. Who eat something. But what. My soul. Only case. Just days is the basic experience on a strong note to his house tops five years ago. This is the central market map and still bustling with customers who come here to buy meat and fish. But this flow of customers could quickly dry up if the cast does. And the vendors here telling us it's getting harder for them because they buy these fish directly from the fisherman. Who now multi sided anymore. Accepting only cash. Where he seems crisis. It every day. To have gone down and welcome to this. But once people are afraid what more. It's been so volatile fight whatever they need. We'll fight game he's really want a man who's so no one enjoys life. It's happening in Williams smiled. Your customers are just dropped almost ten days the period there's a deficit of 9%. We just bluster yes because. And human Mohammed mom does and they can be six to use today. So both of that do. So the by pollutants of buy food. Steve reverend. Abuse and amp. Author today Hager will be able to be brought together as a because it is.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Great White Launches Out of the Sea, Photobombs Other Shark
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Extended Again
Now Playing: NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Greece's Financial Crisis Affects Citizens, Store Owners
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI, 'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon
Now Playing: London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: Int'l Hotspot: Dozens of Egyptian Soldiers Killed by ISIS Suicide Bombers
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32282647,"title":"Greece's Financial Crisis Affects Citizens, Store Owners","duration":"3:00","description":"ABC NewsAlexander Marquardt talks to businesses that are losing money due to the economic situation in Greece.","url":"/International/video/greeces-financial-crisis-affects-citizens-store-owners-32282647","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:30:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  GMA 07/09/15: Some Wary of 'Coincidences' in Computer Glitches</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/gma-070915-wary-coincidences-computer-glitches-32327573</Link>
        <Description>Ariana Grande Apologizes for 'I Hate America' Comments; How Your Insurance Could Pay to Help You Lose Weight</Description>
        <MainBody>GMA 07/09/15: Some Wary of 'Coincidences' in Computer Glitches
01:07:07 07/09/15 NR
Ariana Grande Apologizes for I Hate America Comments; How Your Insurance Could Pay to Help You Lose Weight
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:32:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 07/08/15:  Shark Attack Surge in Carolinas: What Could Be Causing It</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-070815-shark-attack-surge-carolinas-causing-32319994</Link>
        <Description>How 'Dude Perfect' Pulls Off Epic Trick Shots; Misty Copeland's Hard-Fought Journey to Ballet Stardom</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 07/08/15:  Shark Attack Surge in Carolinas: What Could Be Causing It
17:52 07/08/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 07:46:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  WN 07/08/15: United Airlines Grounds All Flights Across the Country</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WNT/video/wn-070815-united-airlines-grounds-flights-country-32317775</Link>
        <Description>The NYSE shut down for hours; Baltimore's police commissioner fired by mayor.</Description>
        <MainBody>WN 07/08/15: United Airlines Grounds All Flights Across the Country
20:14 07/08/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 22:35:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  This Week 07/05/15: Donald Trump's Impact on the 2016 Campaign Trail</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/ThisWeek/video/week-070515-donald-trumps-impact-2016-campaign-trail-32234897</Link>
        <Description>Guests: Rick Perry, Yanis Varoufakis, Bob Goodlatte, Tom Cole, Bill Kristol, Joaquin Castro, Anne Gearan</Description>
        <MainBody>This Week 07/05/15: Donald Trumps Impact on the 2016 Campaign Trail
48:52 07/05/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 09:03:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  20/20: Bruce Jenner: The Interview - Encore Presentation</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/2020-bruce-jenner-interview-encore-presentation-32235522</Link>
        <Description>Bruce Jenner shares an exclusive and wide-ranging conversation with Diane Sawyer.</Description>
        <MainBody>20/20 07/04/15: Bruce Jenner: The Interview - Encore Presentation
01:20:00 07/04/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
