<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="abcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:41:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Check Out This Great White Photobomb</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/great-white-launches-sea-photobombs-shark/story?id=32309726</Link>
        <Description>A great white shark breached the surface for "no apparent reason."</Description>
        <MainBody>Great White Launches Out of the Sea, Photobombs Other Shark
Jul 8, 2015, 4:28 PM ET
By KAYLEE HECK
A great white shark is seen in this undated file photo.
Getty Images
Even sharks can be great at photobombing.
A boat -- on a dive tour with White Shark Africa -- was near Seal Island in Mossel Bay, South Africa when everyone on board got a memorable surprise.
Shark Attack Surge in North Carolina: What Could Be Behind It
Six divers were in the cage below the water and the camera was rolling Monday on a great white shark that was next to the vessel when another shark wanted some camera time, spokesman Dan Abbott told ABC News today.
Sometimes sharks will jump to get out of each others way, but there were no sharks below this one, he said.
The shark launched itself into the air and it was all caught on GoPro footage.
Abbott said it was a breach for no apparent reason since there wasnt bait in the water around them, but that it surprised everyone on board.
Great whites are the only sharks that spy hop to see around above the surface, he said. But I also like to think that, just like whales, great white sharks get some sort of joy from breaching like this."
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Whether the Pope Samples Coca Plant a Burning Question</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/pope-francis-samples-coca-plant-burning-question/story?id=32306512</Link>
        <Description>The leaf is used in local teas in Bolivia, where he was headed this afternoon.</Description>
        <MainBody>Whether Pope Francis Samples Coca Plant a Burning Question
Jul 8, 2015, 1:47 PM ET
People take pictures with their phones as Pope Francis departs from the San Francisco Church aboard the Popemobile, in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
AP Photo
Copy
Millions of people have been following Pope Francis during his tour through Ecuador , but his actions this afternoon in Bolivia will be even more carefully watched.
The question on many minds today is "will he or won't he" after Francis is likely offered coca leaves to chew or tea brewed from the plant.
The plant is seen as a local delicacy that is regularly used to help treat altitude sickness in the town of La Paz, Bolivia, which is about 12,000 feet above sea level.
Pope Heads to Bolivia Amid Church-State Tensions
While those uses are widely accepted there, coca is known more globally as the plant that is the main ingredient in cocaine.
Coca was declared an illegal substance there in 1961, but that hasn't stopped dignitaries from trying it while on Bolivian soil, according to the Catholic News Agency .
Pope John Paul II drank tea made from coca during his 1988 visit to Bolivia, CNA reported.
AFP/Getty Images
PHOTO: Pope John Paul II blesses Bolivian faithful May 13, 1988 at Tajira airport.
The "will he or won't he" debate for Pope Francis, 78, started when Bolivian culture minister Marko Machicao said the Argentina-born pontiff "specifically requested" to chew coca, according to the BBC .
Vatican spokesman the Rev. Federico Lombardi remained non-committal in a statement to CNA when asked about the pope's verdict ahead of this afternoon's visit, saying he "wouldnt be surprised because the pope likes taking part in popular customs. The pope will do as he sees fit."
Lombardi added: "Well see if he follows local customs.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:02:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I Thought I Was Going To Die,' London Bombing Survivor Says 10 Years Later</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/thought-die-london-bombing-survivor-10-years/story?id=32280438</Link>
        <Description>Sajda Mughal, 33, was on the Underground that morning when a bomb exploded in the front car of her train in London.</Description>
        <MainBody>'I Thought I Was Going To Die,' London Bombing Survivor Says 10 Years Later
Jul 7, 2015, 7:26 PM ET
By LOUISE DEWAST
Sajda Mughal, 33, was on the Underground that morning when a bomb exploded in the front carriage. She survived, unhurt. But the memories of that day remain painful.
ABC News
Copy
Ten years ago, 52 people were killed and more than 700 injured in multiple terrorism attacks across London.
Sajda Mughal, 33, was on the Underground that morning when a bomb exploded in the front car. She survived, unhurt. But the memories of that day remain painful.
"I started thinking about my loved ones, thinking I hadn't said goodbye, that I hadn't gotten married and hadn't had kids. I was getting ready for death, but I was hoping this wouldn't be the end," Mughal said.
After 45 minutes in the darkness, emergency services rescued Mughal along with hundreds of others. Twenty-six people were killed and 340 were injured on her train.
Around the same time, bombs exploded on two other London Transport trains, killing eight and injuring 171 in one, killing seven and injuring 163 in the other. Nearly an hour later, a bomb exploded in a bus in central London, killing 14 people and injuring more than 110.
Today, commemorative events were held at St Paul's Cathedral in London and at a dedicated memorial in Hyde Park to remember the victims.
Mughal says her experience have changed her life. After several months of counselling she had gone back to her old job, but quickly realized that she was haunted by unanswered questions.
"I wanted to know who had brainwashed these four men, with a wrong ideology, and why," said Mughal, who is Muslim. "I couldn't accept that they had done this because I know that in the Koran it says that killing an innocent person is like killing humanity."
Since 7/7, Mughal has dedicated her time working for her non-profit organization, Jan Trust, which helps and educate Muslim mothers who are worried that their sons are being radicalized. She was awarded with the prestigious Order of the British Empire in 2015, a royal recognition to "distinguished service to the arts and sciences, public services outside the Civil Service."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:08:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>See 3-Year-Old's Reaction to Getting 'Parking Ticket'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/year-biker-parking-ticket-halifax-police-canada/story?id=32283240</Link>
        <Description>A 3-year-old was exasperated when he got his first ticket after "illegally" parking his red plastic motorbike at a ferry terminal in Halifax, Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>"Remember, no motorcycle parking in the circle by the ferry terminal," the Halixfax Department wrote on Twitter. "This ruthless biker was caught yesterday!"
Currie, who issued the "ticket," added that it's nice to show a softer side of police.
"We're not always making arrests and hauling people away," he told CTV News . "We like to have fun."
The photograph of the kid's reaction to getting an illegal parking ticket has gotten over 9,000 likes and over 2,000 shares on Halifax Regional Police's Facebook page .
Lisa Tramley, the ticketed toddler's mom, told CTV that her young bad boy has been a good sport about his ticket.
"He loves his ticket," she said. "He tried to go bed with his ticket."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:49:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Iran Negotiating Team Fuels Up With Twizzlers</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/twizzlers-iran-nuclear-talks/story?id=32283578</Link>
        <Description>As U.S. and Iranian nuclear talks drag on, Twizzlers fuel the negotiators.</Description>
        <MainBody>Twizzlers and String Cheese Fuel US Team in Iran Talks
Jul 7, 2015, 5:06 PM ET
By JESSE KIRSCH
US negotiators on the Iran nuclear deal have been eating a lot of Twizzlers during the talks.
Getty Images
Sweet.
The Iran nuclear talks may be dragging on in Vienna, but the U.S. team has a solution -- sugar and lots of it.
While there might be sticking points on a potential deal, U.S. negotiators can agree on one thing, their love of Twizzlers, string cheese and other goodies.
The 15-person U.S. delegation and their staff have, since June, scarfed down 10 pounds of strawberry Twizzlers, 30 pounds of mixed nuts and dried fruit, 20 pounds of string cheese and more than 200 Rice Krispies treats, a senior official said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:46:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Extremely Rare' White Humpback Whale Spotted </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/extremely-rare-white-humpback-whale-makes-spectacular-appearance/story?id=32280688</Link>
        <Description>An "extremely rare" white humpback whale recently made researchers' jaws drop when it surfaced above Cook Strait waters in New Zealand. </Description>
        <MainBody>'Extremely Rare' White Humpback Whale Makes Spectacular Appearance in New Zealand
Jul 7, 2015, 3:37 PM ET
A white humpback whale with a normal black humpback whale on July 5, 2007 in Cook Strait, New Zealand.
New Zealand Department of Conservation
An "extremely rare" white humpback whale recently made researchers' jaws drop when it surfaced above Cook Strait waters off New Zealand .
The white whale was photographed on Monday swimming side-by-side with a buddy, a more common black humpback whale, the New Zealand Department of Conservation (DOC) said in a statement today.
"Only four white humpback whales have been reported in the world," said Nadine Bott, the leader of the boat's survey team counting whales passing through Cook Strait.
Tracking the Elusive, Super Intelligent Sperm Whale
They survey is assessing humpback whale recovery since commercial whaling ended in 1964 in New Zealand and aims to estimate the size of the humpback population in our waters. Bott said there is a promising indication humpback whale numbers are increasing in our waters.
New Zealand Department of Conservation
PHOTO: The white whales distinctive dorsal fin
The DOC added it believes the spotted white whale is Migaloo, which literally means "white fella" in an aboriginal Australian language.
"Migaloo is the most famous" of white humpback whiles from Australia , Bott explained adding that he "is thought to have fathered two white calves which have been making appearances along Australia's eastern coast. One has been named MJ, short for Migaloo junior."
New Zealand Department of Conservation
PHOTO: The white humpback whale's head.
Researchers said they will do a DNA test from a skin sample they got from the whale to confirm whether the whale is in fact Migaloo.
The analysis will also reveal whether the whale is albino or whether its whiteness is due to color variation.
"This is so unique," said marine mammal scientist Carolos Olavarria, who was with Bott during the sighting. "I have never seen anything like this in New Zealand."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 22:39:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A Pair of Iron Fists: 'Lenin' and 'Stalin' Come to Blows in Red Square</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/lenin-stalin-blows-moscows-red-square/story?id=32263735</Link>
        <Description>See what sparked the fight. </Description>
        <MainBody>'Lenin' and 'Stalin' Come to Blows in Moscow's Red Square
MOSCOW  Jul 7, 2015, 2:51 PM ET
By PATRICK REEVELL
In this Jan. 2009 file photo, lookalikes of two Vladimir Lenins, left, and a Josef Stalin, right, speak near Red square in Moscow.
Alexey Sazonov/AFP/Getty Images
Stalin and Lenin came to blows not far from Moscows famed Red Square on Monday evening. At least thats how Lenin tells it.
Two impersonators who dress up as the former Soviet leaders to entertain tourists were in a subway station when Stalin fell upon Lenin with his umbrella, Lenin, also known as Igor Gorbunov, told the tabloid TV station LifeNews.
Other Russian media initially reported that Lenin had accused Stalin of working with another Lenin impersonator and that Stalin took it so badly he hit Lenin on the back with his umbrella.
But the injured Lenin told LifeNews that the two had fought over money -- with Stalin underpaying him for his days work impersonating the Soviet Unions founder.
Stalin, however, has denied everything.
Its a set up! Stalin, whose real name is Latifa Valiyev, told ABC News as he stood at his usual spot near Red Square.
Theyve set me up. Its my competitors, you understand? he said, waving his pipe. Pulling a copy of the days paper from his uniform, Stalin said other Stalin impersonators on the square had made the story up to sabotage him.
Im going to lodge a complaint, Stalin said, although he did not elaborate.
Both men, and two or three other Lenins and Stalins, are normally seen standing happily together, charging tourists money for photos with them.
However, this is not the first time the two erstwhile Communist leaders have come to blows.
Last summer, a different Stalin went to the police, accusing a Lenin of punching his wife, Russian state TV reported. Lenin, for his part, said hed been defending himself from Stalin.
The impersonators are a city institution, with the same men playing the leaders for years. But with more and more Stalin and Lenin impersonators encroaching on each others turf on Red Square, the business seem to have become cut-throat.
Hes creating a mafia atmosphere here, a Lenin told Russian state TV last summer, pointing at a Stalin who was smoking a pipe.
And besides that, theres his Napoleon-like plans, he added.
The real-life Stalin succeeded Lenin in the 1920s as leader of Soviet Russia , despite Lenins attempts to prevent it, warning Stalin was dangerous for the country.
This time though, the offended Lenin said they had patched things up, telling LifeNews he had forgiven Stalin and they had decided to remain friends.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 20:36:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Falling Short of Mission to Train Syrian Fighters</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/60-syrian-fighters-trained-us-military-falling-short/story?id=32273598</Link>
        <Description>Defense Secretary Ash Carter made a shocking admission today about just how slowly the strategy against ISIS is unfolding, saying that the U.S. is currently training only 60 Syrian fighters to combat ISIS.  

When the strategy to defeat ISIS inside Syria was announced last year the Pentagon said it aimed to train 5,000 moderate Syrian rebels per year over three years. No Syrian forces have yet to graduate from any training program. 

Now 11 months later, that cadre of 60 trainees is ???much smaller than we'd hoped for at this point,??? Carter said during testimony in front of the Senate Armed Services Committee, which is holding a hearing on the counter-ISIS strategy.

"We'd like to see more, and we're trying to get better at training them, because the number 60 is, as you all recognize, is not an impressive number."  Carter blamed a difficult process of vetting viable candidates.

Last month Carter also spoke about falling short of goals to train the Iraqi military, saying of the 24,000...</Description>
        <MainBody>Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, Gen. Martin Dempsey, right, looks to Defense Secretary Ash Carter, left, as he testifies at the Senate Armed Services Committee hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington, D.C. on July 7, 2015.
Carolyn Kaster/AP Photo
Defense Secretary Ash Carter made a shocking admission today about just how slowly the strategy against ISIS is unfolding, saying that the U.S. is currently training only 60 Syrian fighters to combat ISIS.
When the strategy to defeat ISIS inside Syria was announced last year the Pentagon said it aimed to train 5,000 moderate Syrian rebels per year over three years. No Syrian forces have yet to graduate from any training program.
Now 11 months later, that cadre of 60 trainees is much smaller than we'd hoped for at this point, Carter said during testimony in front of the Senate Armed Services Committee, which is holding a hearing on the counter-ISIS strategy.
"We'd like to see more, and we're trying to get better at training them, because the number 60 is, as you all recognize, is not an impressive number." Carter blamed a difficult process of vetting viable candidates.
Last month Carter also spoke about falling short of goals to train the Iraqi military , saying of the 24,000 it had hoped to have training theyd only received enough recruits to train 7,000.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 18:47:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  10th Anniversary of The London 7/7 Bombings</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/remembering-victims-10th-anniversary-77-bombings-london-32266782</Link>
        <Description>London mourns on the 10th Anniversary of the 7/7 attacks </Description>
        <MainBody>Remembering the Victims on the 10th Anniversary of the 7/7 Bombings in London
+

A man and woman stop to look at floral tributes left at Aldgate underground station in memory of the victims of the July 7 bombings exactly 10 years after London's transport network came under attack, July 7, 2015, in London.
Daniel Leal-Olivas/PA Wire/Getty Images
A man and woman stop to look at floral tributes left at Aldgate underground station in memory of the victims of the July 7 bombings exactly 10 years after London's transport network came under attack, July 7, 2015, in London.
Daniel Leal-Olivas/PA Wire/Getty Images
Buses pass by as family members attend a remembrance ceremony at the spot where 13 people were killed in the London bombings, July 7, 2015, in London.
Peter Macdiarmid/Getty Images
A flower lies on a plaque bearing the names of victims at the 7/7 memorial, on the 10th anniversary of the attacks, July 7, 2015, in Hyde Park, London.
Matt Dunham/ AP Photo
Police officers carry candles bearing the names of the bombed sites during a service in St Paul's Cathedral to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the London Bombings, July 7, 2015, in London.
Frank Augstein/AP Photo
A person lays flowers at the 52 steel pillars memorial to the victims of the 7/7 London bombings in Hyde Park, July 7, 2015, in London.
Dan Kitwood/Getty Images
Police officers line up to observe a minute's silence for the victims of the 7/7 bombings, on the 10th anniversary, at the All England Lawn Tennis Championships, July 7, 2015, in Wimbledon, London.
Tim Ireland/AP Photo
The Bishop of London Richard Chartres stands with representatives of the world's religions during the service to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the London 7/7 bombings at St Paul's Cathedral, July 7, 2015, in London.
Richard Pohle/ Getty Images
British Prime Minister David Cameron, right, and London Mayor Boris Johnson lay wreaths during a wreath laying ceremony in London's Hyde Park , July 7, 2015, in memory of the 52 victims of the 7/7 London attacks.
Steve Parsons/AFP/Getty Images
Poppy petals lie on the floor during a service in St Paul's Cathedral to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the London Bombings, July 7, 2015, in London.
Frank Augstein/AP Photo
A woman cries at the memorial plaque in London's Hyde Park, July 7, 2015, in memory of the 52 victims of the 7/7 London attacks.
AFP/Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 23:13:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN Chief Calls for Inquiry Into Dag Hammarskjold Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/chief-calls-inquiry-mysterious-dag-hammarskjold-plane-crash/story?id=32262632</Link>
        <Description>United Nations Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon believes further investigation is necessary to uncover the truth behind a 1961 plane crash in which Dag Hammarskjold died.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN Chief Calls for Inquiry Into Mysterious Dag Hammarskjold Plane Crash
Jul 7, 2015, 3:19 AM ET
Dag Hammarskjold is seen in a 1957 file photo.
MPI/Getty Images
United Nations Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon believes further investigation is necessary to uncover the truth behind a 1961 plane crash in which Secretary-General Dag Hammarskjold and 15 others died.
Questions remain about a possible aerial attack or other interference, Ban said.
But Ban said in a letter to the U.N. General Assembly circulated Monday that an independent review of new information about the mysterious crash put to rest claims that Hammarskjold was assassinated after surviving the crash.
Editor's Picks
The Note: Notes On A Rope
Ban called for countries to disclose relevant records related to the crash.
Hammarskjold's plane, a DC-6 known as the Albertina, crashed Sept. 18, 1961, in the African bush in Northern Rhodesia , today's Zambia , during a peace mission to newly independent Congo .
Topical Press Agency/Getty Images
PHOTO: Dag Hammarskjold is seen leaving the Claridges Hotel in London in this file photo.
The crash has long been shrouded in mystery. The lone survivor reported that there were explosions aboard the plane before it hit the ground, and speculation has raged that the plane was shot down, or that Hammarskjold was the subject of an assassination plot.
Pilot error has also been thought to have ontributed to the accident.
Hammarskjold devoted his life to diplomacy and public service. He was born in 1905, the son of Swedish prime minister Hjalmar Hammarskjold, who pushed for neutrality during World War I .
After attending college and receiving a doctorate from Stockholm University, Hammarskjold served as a professor and held various government roles. He joined the United Nations in 1949, and was approved as secretary-general in 1953.
ullstein bild/Getty Images
PHOTO: Dag Hammarskjold is seen in a 1955 file photo.
His tenure was marked by his diplomatic entreaties: face-to-face communication between various heads of state, pursuing peace, seeking accord.
He probably knows more state secrets than any man alive, Parade wrote of Hammarskjold in a 1960 profile. He hides what he knows behind a cloud of diplomatic double-talk. Like a baseball umpire, he is aloof, almost icy, and does not fraternize with the players. Also, he is criticized by both sides, and respected for his integrity.
After his death, Hammarskjold was awarded a posthumous Nobel Prize , one of three people to earn the distinction. A foundation was also established in his name, and his journal was published as Markings, a collection of insights and spiritual reflections.
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:52:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Morales Has Politically Charged Gifts for Pope</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-pope-wrap-time-ecuador-fly-bolivia-32299851</Link>
        <Description>The Latest: Bolivia's president gives Pope Francis some politically loaded presents</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Morales Has Politically Charged Gifts for Pope
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia  Jul 8, 2015, 8:52 PM ET
Here are the latest developments from Pope Francis' trip to South America:

7:25 p.m.
President Evo Morales has given Pope Francis some politically loaded presents during the traditional exchange of gifts between heads of state.
Chief among them: A crucifix carved into a wooden hammer and sickle, the Communist symbol uniting labor and peasants. The image also appears on a medallion Morales gave to Francis that he wore around his neck.
Another politically charged gift: A copy of "The Book of the Sea," which is about the loss of Bolivia's access to the sea during the War of the Pacific with Chile in 1879-83. Bolivia took its bid to renegotiate access to the Pacific to the International Court of Justice in 2013, while Chile has argued the court has no jurisdiction because Bolivia's borders were defined by a 1904 treaty. The court is expected to rule by the end of the year if it has competence to decide the case.
Francis, for his part, gave Morales a mosaic of the Madonna and a copy of his recent encyclical on the environment.

6:10 p.m.
Pope Francis stopped the popemobile briefly on the way to the presidential palace in La Paz, Bolivia, near where the body of a fellow Jesuit priest was dumped in 1980 after a military dictatorship had him killed.
The priest, Luis Espinal, was an outspoken defender of the poor, like Francis. He was also unorthodox. A skilled communicator, he used film and journalism as tools. His body was found with 12 bullet holes.
The pope got out at the roadside site, laid flowers and led the waiting crowd in a minute of silence and then prayer.
Francis said that Espinal was, in the pope's words, "our brother victim of interests that did not want him to fight for Bolivia's freedom."
It was the second time in as many months that Francis has recognized a priest slain by the far right in Latin America during a period in which the United States backed dictatorships. In May, Archbishop Oscar Romero of El Salvador was beatified 25 years after he was killed.

5:45 p.m.
In his welcoming remarks to the pope, Bolivian President Evo Morales said Francis is working toward the same goals as his government by advocating for "those most in need."
In Morales' words: "He who betrays a poor person, betrays Pope Francis."
The president recalled how the Catholic Church many times in the past was on the side of the oppressors of Bolivia's people, three-fourths of whom are of are indigenous origin.
But Morales said things are different with this pope and the Bolivian people are greeting Francis as someone who is "helping in the liberation of our people."
Bolivia's government does have its differences with the church, however. In recent weeks, various senior officials have engaged in a heated war of words with a Spanish priest who demands that the Morales administration devote more funds to public health.

5:30 p.m.
Pope Francis has praised Bolivia for taking important steps to include the poor and the marginalized in its political and economic life, but insists that the Catholic Church also has a "prophetic" role to play in society.
In his arrival speech, Francis recalled that Catholicism took "deep root" in Bolivia centuries ago and said the church "has continued to contribute to its development and shape its culture."
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:46:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Insists on Church Role in Bolivia After Limits Imposed</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/pope-wraps-ecuador-leg-samerica-trip-stop-bolivia-32290664</Link>
        <Description>Pope insists on church role in Bolivia amid efforts by Morales to limit Catholic influence</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Insists on Church Role in Bolivia After Limits Imposed
LA PAZ, Bolivia  Jul 8, 2015, 8:45 PM ET
By NICOLE WINFIELD and CARLOS VALDEZ Associated Press
Pope Francis arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday on the second leg of his South American tour and immediately insisted that the Catholic Church continue to play an important role in society amid efforts by the government of President Evo Morales to curb its influence. He later called for dialogue between Bolivia and Chile over their longtime border dispute.
Morales hugged the pope as he descended from the Boliviana de Aviacion plane and hung a pouch around his neck of woven of alpaca with indigenous trimmings. It is of the type commonly used to hold coca leaves, which are chewed by people in the Andes to alleviate altitude sickness. It wasn't known if Francis chewed any leaves, though he was served mate tea made with coca leaves, chamomile and annis on the plane from Quito, Ecuador.
La Paz stands at 4,000 meters (about 13,120 feet) above sea level, and the Vatican decided to keep the pope's stay to just four hours to limit any problems for the 78-year-old pontiff, who has only one full lung. Francis though seemed in fine form, bundled against the cold and wind by a white shawl that he donned for his popemobile ride into town past thousands of people who came to greet him, waving handkerchiefs and singing songs of welcome.
At an airport welcome ceremony with Morales by his side, Francis praised Bolivia for taking "important steps" to include the poor and marginalized in the political and economic life of the country, South America's poorest.
Morales came to power championing Bolivia's 36 indigenous groups and enshrined their rights in the constitution, and under his leadership Bolivia's economy has boomed thanks to high prices for its natural gas and minerals. But Morales has roiled the local church by taking a series of anti-clerical initiatives, including a new constitution that made the overwhelmingly Catholic nation a secular country.
In his speech, Francis noted the Catholic faith took "deep root" in Bolivia centuries ago "and has continued to shed its light upon society, contributing to the development of the nation and shaping its culture."
"The voice of the bishops, which must be prophetic, speaks to society in the name of the church, our mother, from her preferential, evangelical option for the poor," he said.
Morales, for his part, recalled how the Catholic Church in the past was on the side of the oppressors of Bolivia's people, three-quarters of whom are of indigenous origin. But Morales, an Aymara Indian known for anti-imperialist and socialist stands, said things have changed with this pope and the Bolivian people are greeting Francis as someone who is "helping in the liberation of our people."
"He who betrays a poor person, betrays Pope Francis," Morales said.
He later gave Francis some politically loaded gifts. Chief among them: a crucifix carved into a wooden hammer and sickle, the Communist symbol uniting labor and peasants.
Another politically charged gift was a copy of "The Book of the Sea," which is about the loss of Bolivia's access to the sea during the War of the Pacific with Chile in 1879-83. Bolivia has taken its bid to renegotiate access to the Pacific to the International Court of Justice , arguing that its poverty is due in part to being land-locked. Chile has argued the court has no jurisdiction since Bolivia's borders were defined by a 1904 treaty.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:30:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boko Haram Offers to Swap Kidnapped Girls for Detainees</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/boko-haram-offers-swap-detainees-kidnapped-girls-32299173</Link>
        <Description>Negotiator: Boko Haram asks Nigerian government to swap detainees for kidnapped Chibok girls</Description>
        <MainBody>Boko Haram Offers to Swap Kidnapped Girls for Detainees
LAGOS, Nigeria  Jul 8, 2015, 8:30 PM ET
By MICHELLE FAUL Associated Press
Nigeria's Boko Haram extremists are offering to free more than 200 young women and girls kidnapped from a boarding school in the town of Chibok in exchange for the release of militant leaders held by the government, a human rights activist has told The Associated Press.
The activist said Boko Haram's current offer is limited to the girls from the school in northeastern Nigeria whose mass abduction in April 2014 ignited worldwide outrage and a campaign to "Bring Back Our Girls" that stretched to the White House .
The new initiative reopens an offer made last year to the government of former President Goodluck Jonathan to release the 219 students in exchange for 16 Boko Haram detainees, the activist said. The man, who was involved in negotiations with Boko Haram last year and is close to current negotiators, spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to talk to reporters on this sensitive issue.
Fred Eno, an apolitical Nigerian who has been negotiating with Boko Haram for more than a year, told the AP that "another window of opportunity opened" in the last few days, though he could not discuss details.
He said the recent slew of Boko Haram bloodletting  some 350 people killed in the past nine days  is consistent with past ratcheting up of violence as the militants seek a stronger negotiating position.
Presidential adviser Femi Adesina said on Saturday that Nigeria's government "will not be averse" to talks with Boko Haram. "Most wars, however furious or vicious, often end around the negotiation table," he said.
Eno said the 5-week-old administration of President Muhammadu Buhari offers "a clean slate" to bring the militants back to negotiations that had become poisoned by the different security agencies and their advice to Jonathan.
Two months of talks last year led government representatives and Eno to travel in September to a northeastern town where the prisoner exchange was to take place, only to be stymied by the Department for State Service intelligence agency, the activist said.
At the last minute, the agency said it was holding only four of the militants sought by Boko Haram, the activist said.
It is not known how many Boko Haram suspects are detained by Nigeria's intelligence agency, whose chief Buhari fired last week.
The activist said the agency continues to hold suspects illegally because it does not have enough evidence for a conviction, and any court would free them. Nigerian law requires charges be brought after 48 hours.
Thousands of suspects have died in custody, and some detainees wanted by Boko Haram may be among them. Amnesty International alleges that 8,000 detainees have died in military custody  some have been shot, some have died from untreated injuries due to torture, and some have died from starvation and other harsh treatment.
In May, about 300 women, girls and children being held captive by Boko Haram were rescued by Nigeria's military, but none were from Chibok. It is believed that the militants view the Chibok girls as a last-resort bargaining chip.
In that infamous abduction, 274 mostly Christian girls preparing to write science exams were seized from the school by Islamic militants in the early hours of April 15, 2014. Dozens escaped on their own in the first few days, but 219 remain missing.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:48:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Seeks 3-Year Aid Program, Rushes to Detail Reforms</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/greece-seeks-year-aid-program-rushes-detail-reforms-32307343</Link>
        <Description>Greek government asks for 3-year aid program, races to submit suitable reforms proposal</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece Seeks 3-Year Aid Program, Rushes to Detail Reforms
ATHENS, Greece  Jul 8, 2015, 7:48 PM ET
By ELENA BECATOROS and JAMEY KEATEN Associated Press
With a deadline just hours away to come up with a detailed economic reform plan, Greece requested a new three-year rescue from its European partners Wednesday as signs grew its economy was sliding toward free-fall without an urgently needed bailout.
As its banking system teetered near the edge, the government extended bank closures into next week, while international creditors were in open disagreement over whether to award the country debt relief  with Germany at odds with the International Monetary Fund.
Without a deal, Greece faces an almost inevitable collapse of the banking system, which would be the first step for the country to fall out of the euro.
As Thursday's deadline loomed, the government sought to reassure its European creditors that it would enact tax and pension reforms quickly in exchange for loans from Europe's bailout fund, the European Stability Mechanism.
In a formal request that was filled with vague promises but short on details, the Greek government pledged to "immediately implement a set of measures as early as the beginning of next week"  but did not specify what these were.
After months of fruitless negotiations with the Greek government, the skeptical eurozone creditor states have said they want to see a detailed, cost-accounted plan of the reforms by Thursday. That is meant to give enough time to review the plan before all 28 leaders of the full European Union meet on Sunday in what has been termed as Greece's last chance to stay in the euro.
But Greece's major creditors were hardly in lock-step over what path to take in dealing with the struggling but defiant EU member nation.
IMF chief Christine Lagarde reiterated Wednesday that Greece's massive debt would need restructuring, something that Germany  Greece's largest European lender  has resisted.
Speaking in Washington, Lagarde said Greece needed to continue cost-cutting reforms, but added: "The other leg is debt restructuring, which we believe is needed ... for debt sustainability."
"It well may be that the numbers may have to be revisited, but our analysis has not changed," she said of the need for granting Greece better repayment terms.
U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew added pressure on the European lenders, arguing debt relief was needed for a deal  and describing a Greek euro-exit as a "geopolitical mistake."
"I don't think any prime minister of Greece could sell all the additional fiscal measures, plus the structural reforms that are needed without some sense of what the debt sustainability looks like," he said in Washington.
Earlier Wednesday, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said his country was seeking a deal that would bring a definitive end to his country's financial crisis. Greece has had two bailouts from its European partners and the International Monetary Fund since May 2010, totaling 240 billion euros ($260 billion).
"We need to ensure the medium-term funding of our country with a development and growth program," Tsipras told lawmakers at the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France.
Applause rose from left-wing lawmakers in the turbulent chamber when Tsipras said aid to Greece has only helped banks, not ordinary Greeks, as some held up "No" signs to back Greek voters' rejection of more austerity.
Tsipras insisted he has "no hidden agenda" to drive Greece out of the euro and that last Sunday's referendum in which Greeks roundly rejected more belt-tightening reforms does not mean a break with Europe.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:28:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Feds: 3 Indicted in Las Vegas in $1.5B Investment Fraud Case</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/feds-indicted-las-vegas-15b-investment-fraud-case-32314343</Link>
        <Description>US officials say 3 people indicted in Vegas-based Ponzi fraud preyed on Japanese investors</Description>
        <MainBody>Feds: 3 Indicted in Las Vegas in $1.5B Investment Fraud Case
LAS VEGAS  Jul 8, 2015, 7:28 PM ET
By KEN RITTER Associated Press
Authorities in the U.S. are seeking the arrest of the chief executive of a Las Vegas investment company and two of his former Asia-based executives on an indictment alleging they headed a $1.5 billion Ponzi-style fraud scheme, officials announced Wednesday.
Edwin Fujinaga of Las Vegas, and Junzo Suzuki and Paul Suzuki, both of Tokyo, were each indicted on eight counts of mail fraud and nine counts of wire fraud in a scheme that prosecutors and the FBI said operated through Las Vegas-based MRI International Inc.
Thousands of unsuspecting Japanese investors were victimized, Assistant U.S. Attorney General Leslie Caldwell said.
Fujinaga, 68, also is charged with three counts of money laundering, and the indictment filed in U.S. District Court in Las Vegas seeks from the three defendants the forfeiture of the proceeds of their alleged crimes. They could face decades in prison if they are convicted.
Attorneys listed in federal court records as having represented Fujinaga; Junzo Suzuki, 66; and his son, Paul Suzuki, 36, in other cases didn't immediately respond to telephone and email messages seeking comment.
The indictment was announced by Caldwell and two top federal law officials in Nevada , U.S. Attorney Daniel Bogden and FBI Special Agent in Charge Laura Bucheit in Las Vegas.
It identifies Fujinaga as former president and chief executive of MRI, Junzo Suzuki as the firm's Asia Pacific executive vice president and Paul Suzuki as general manager for Japan operations.
Bogden said they told thousands of overseas victims that their investments would be safely held and managed by an independent, third-party escrow agent in Nevada.
Meanwhile, Fujinaga and the Suzukis are accused of using investors' funds to pay for gambling, travel by private jet and other personal expenses.
The scheme operated for at least four years before it was exposed in April 2013, according to the charging document.
Investments were primarily sold through the company service center in Tokyo, promising high returns and low risk through a technique dubbed "factoring." The company promised high returns buying accounts receivable from medical providers at a discount, then attempting to recover more than the discounted amount from the debtor.
The government alleges the Ponzi scheme defrauded victims by using money from new enrollees to pay early-stage investors and persuade others to take part.
The largest Ponzi-style fraud in U.S. history, involving New York financier Bernard Madoff , bilked investors of an estimated $20 billion. Madoff was convicted in 2009 and sentenced to 150 years in prison.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:14:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guinea's Ex-Junta Leader Indicted for More Than 156 Deaths</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/guineas-junta-leader-indicted-156-deaths-32314427</Link>
        <Description>Lawyer: Guinea's ex-junta leader indicted for deaths of more than 156 people at 2009 rally</Description>
        <MainBody>Guinea's Ex-Junta Leader Indicted for More Than 156 Deaths
OUAGADOUGOU, Burkina Faso  Jul 8, 2015, 7:13 PM ET
By BRAHIMA OUEDRAOGO Associated Press
Guinea's ex-junta leader was indicted Wednesday for the deaths of more than 156 people gathered at an opposition rally in 2009, his lawyer said.
Moussa "Dadis" Camara and his lawyer met behind closed doors with two Guinean magistrates who came to Burkina Faso , where Camara is in exile. They met for about three hours.
"I can confirm that my client has been indicted," said the lawyer, Jean Baptiste Haba. "There is a hearing on the matter in more depth for the moment, and it is in secret."
The indictment could not be independently confirmed.
Camara seized power in a 2008 military coup, hours after the death of longtime despot Lansana Conte. In September 2009, the presidential guard opened fire on thousands of protesters who had gathered in the national soccer stadium to demand that Camara resign, killing at least 156. Over 100 women were gang-raped by soldiers, according to rights groups.
Camara was shot in the head a few months later by a top aide, and went to Burkina Faso as part of a peace deal.
International Criminal Court prosecutor Fatou Bensouda said in a statement during a visit to Guinea last week that numerous high-ranking individuals have been indicted, and hundreds of victims and key witnesses have been interviewed, as part of Guinean judicial investigations into the September 2009 events.
Haba said Camara's hearings with the magistrates could continue into next week, and it was unclear what Guinean authorities would choose to do.
In May, Camara declared he was moving into politics, heading up a new political party and saying he would be a candidate for Guinea's presidential elections later this year.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:00:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nicaraguan Police Beat Protesters and Harass Journalists</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/nicaraguan-police-beat-protesters-harass-journalists-32313018</Link>
        <Description>Nicaraguan police beat and arrest opposition protesters, harass journalists at demonstration</Description>
        <MainBody>Nicaraguan Police Beat Protesters and Harass Journalists
MANAGUA, Nicaragua  Jul 8, 2015, 6:59 PM ET
Police beat and detained government opponents and harassed journalists Wednesday at a protest outside Nicaragua's top electoral council.
The protesters were attending a weekly demonstration in the capital of Managua to demand fair election rules and a change of electoral magistrates ahead of the 2016 presidential election.
Police initially tried to block them from reaching the electoral council offices, but they grabbed a police barricade and tried to use it to force their way past a police line.
Officers roughed up several photographers and broke the lens of an Associated Press photographer.
Police also detained but later released nine lawmakers from the opposition Independent Liberal Party.
Government opponents contend the ruling Sandinista party has skewed electoral rules and oversight in its own favor.
Augusto Valle, a Liberal Independent legislator in the Central America Parliament, suffered a wound to the face in the fracas.
"This is repression. I am exercising my right to protest," Valle told local media. He claimed police took his cellphone and hit him in the legs and stomach.
Liberal Independent leader Eduardo Montealegre said his party "will continue demonstrating for transparent elections and for changes in the electoral branch."
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:58:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Some Progress in Quelling Wildfires Raging in Canada</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/progress-quelling-wildfires-western-canada-32309776</Link>
        <Description>Officials report some progress in quelling wildfires raging across large swaths of Canada</Description>
        <MainBody>Some Progress in Quelling Wildfires Raging in Canada
LA RONGE, Saskatchewan  Jul 8, 2015, 6:57 PM ET
Firefighters made some progress Wednesday in quelling hundreds of wildfires raging across western Canada that are threatening thousands of people and triggering air quality warnings across the country and in the U.S. West and Midwest, authorities said.
Steve Roberts, a Saskatchewan wildfire management official, said better visibility has allowed aircraft to dump water on the flames there. Several hundred Canadian soldiers were involved in firefighting efforts and the military said another 500 troops from Manitoba were on standby. Fire-fighting crews from across Canada and from South Dakota have been helping out.
But even as progress was being made in Saskatchewan, wildfires burned in parts of British Columbia and northern Alberta and authorities were forced to seek help from around the country and other countries, including Mexico and Australia .
"As we started down the road with these fires, Alberta and British Columbia fire hazards escalated, the numbers of fires increased and they had community evacuations as well," Roberts said. "That has stretched the availability of resources across the country."
Karen Hill, a spokeswoman for Saskatchewan's provincial emergency services, said an estimated 10,000 to 12,000 people in the province have been forced to leave their homes in recent days. The evacuations are mostly from more than 50 communities in the northern part of the province.
The Canadian Interagency Forest Fire Centre, which co-ordinates firefighting services for the provinces and territories, said Canada may have to seek more help from the U.S. and abroad.
The latest report on the agency website said the wildfire hazard is extreme and major wildfires "have the potential to exhaust agency fire resources nationally."
Alberta said Wednesday that it was bringing in 62 firefighters from Mexico to help battle 92 wildfires burning in the province, including 33 listed as out of control.
British Columbia, with more than 180 fires, was bringing in crews from Australia.
Environment Canada continued to issue special air quality advisories for parts of British Columbia, Saskatchewan, Manitoba and northwest Ontario due to wildfire smoke.
Smoke from the wildfires has also led to air quality advisories in the U.S., including Washington state, North and South Dakota and Colorado .
Wildfire expert Mike Flannigan said tinderbox conditions in the Western provinces set the stage for the wildfires. "Our weather this year has been very hot, dry and windy," said the University of Alberta professor.
"This is consistent with what we expect with climate change. I'm not saying every year is going to be a bad fire year, but we are going to see a lot more fire on the landscape."
Kerry Anderson, a research scientist with the Canadian Forest Service, said the weather pattern known as El Nino, which is caused by the warming of the Pacific Ocean off the coast of South America, is responsible.
He expects weather conditions will settle down in Saskatchewan in the coming weeks, but warmer than normal temperatures will likely persist for a while in B.C. and Alberta.
Anderson said even if crews bring the Saskatchewan fires under control, they may not actually be put out until the fall.
"The large fires that are burning there will continue to burn until they are contained or until a fire-ending event may occur, and that may just end up being the first snowfall."

Associated Press writer Charmaine Noronha in Toronto contributed to this report.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:14:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Yemen Truce Talks See Disagreement Over Terms, but Continue</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/yemen-truce-talks-disagreement-terms-continue-32314121</Link>
        <Description>Yemen's government, Houthi rebels disagree over terms of truce in UN-sponsored talks</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen Truce Talks See Disagreement Over Terms, but Continue
SANAA, Yemen  Jul 8, 2015, 6:13 PM ET
By AHMED AL-HAJ Associated Press
The spokesman for Yemen's exiled government says it has informed the United Nations that a truce to halt more than three months of fighting would hold if guarantees are in place to ensure Shiite rebels withdraw from major cities and release prisoners  demands the rebels have rejected.
Rebel leader Zeifullah al-Shami told The Associated Press late Wednesday those conditions are "unacceptable" because they don't address the country's humanitarian crisis.
Despite the disagreements, al-Shami says the U.N.-sponsored talks that began Sunday are continuing in the capital, Sanaa.
Government spokesman Rajeh Badi says any truce should be observed by the U.N.
More than 3,000 people have been killed since March, when a Saudi-led and U.S.-backed coalition began launching airstrikes against the rebels and their allies.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:03:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NYC City Council Speaker: Washington Must Help Puerto Rico</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/nyc-city-council-speaker-washington-puerto-rico-32310215</Link>
        <Description>APNewsBreak: NYC City Council Speaker Mark-Viverito says Washington must help Puerto Rico</Description>
        <MainBody>NYC City Council Speaker: Washington Must Help Puerto Rico
NEW YORK  Jul 8, 2015, 6:03 PM ET
By JONATHAN LEMIRE Associated Press
New York City Council Speaker Melissa Mark-Viverito, who is arguably becoming one of the nation's most influential Puerto Rican politicians, is urging Congress and the Obama administration to step in and help the island commonwealth struggling under the weight of its debt.
Mark-Viverito, who was born in Puerto Rico , said Wednesday that the situation in her native land was "a fiscal crisis" that required help from the superpower that sits 1,000 miles from its shores.
"My mother still lives there, my family still lives there. I hope to retire there someday," Mark-Viverito told The Associated Press in her first comments on the matter. "This is very personal to me to see Puerto Rico in this situation."
Puerto Rican Gov. Alejandro Garcia Padilla said last month the island's $72 billion public debt is unpayable given the current level of economic growth. He is seeking a payment moratorium from bondholders  including the United States  as the commonwealth attempts to emerge from a nearly decade-long economic slump.
Mark-Viverito, a Democrat who was elected to the speakership last year, urged quick action to address the situation, which has become a popular debate topic among the 2016 presidential candidates in recent days.
She advocated Congress allowing Puerto Rico to restructure its debt, giving the U.S. territory the same ability as cities and public corporations under the bankruptcy code. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Rodham Clinton advocated a similar strategy earlier this week.
"Congress is not a very friendly place these days," said the liberal Mark-Viverito, "but we can't wait."
She also urged the Obama administration to issue executive orders that would ease the costs of shipping and health care on the island, which is mired in a prolonged economic slump.
"Young people are leaving year after year because there are better opportunities elsewhere," said Mark-Viverito, who owns property in Puerto Rico and returns several times a year to visit the island where she lived before moving to Manhattan at age 18. "The big picture needs to change."
Mark-Viverito, whose political clout has grown in recent months as she has become an outspoken voice on immigration and police reforms, said her team has spoken to Sen. Charles Schumer, D-N.Y., and leaders in other U.S. cities with large Puerto Rican populations to rally support and lobby Washington to help.
The White House has said it is not considering a federal bailout of Puerto Rico. Legislation allowing Puerto Rico to use Chapter 9 bankruptcy laws is pending in the House. In the Senate, Schumer and Sen. Richard Blumenthal , D-Conn., are planning to propose companion legislation.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:31:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/nyse-trading-resumes-united-airlines-flights-grounded-hours-32313271</Link>
        <Description>NYSE trading resumes after technical glitch; United Airlines Flights Grounded for hours, causing heavy delays; Facebook makes subtle change to icon. </Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
The closing bell sounds odd it's great game. I'll speak in New York Stock Exchange trading vaulted from most of the big hit with technical college officials are able to get it back running. 4050. Sort of makes it means is you know one of the big venues and how many venues were retrained stocks went out. And just just. The vulnerability. The F eight lifting the nationwide ground stop on United Airlines flight plot. Out of the travelers still waiting in long lines for more than an hour tonight on all of its planes here in the US QQ what they called me. Network connectivity issues computer problems that they couldn't get checked and pathos. The rope line. Let's sell off in China continues. Stocks in Shanghai welcome to bear market territory within 66%. Sell off today. Well this is something that has been going on now for three weeks to market China selling off more than 30%. Two and a half trillion dollars in wealth just wiped out in that span of time. I think battle today over encryption technology in our Smartphones and computers and cracking down on terror plot. A law enforcement officials including FBI director came on the Capitol Hill arguing the right to privacy must be weighed against public safety interim. Law enforcement officials. Are trying to make the case agent sent to congress today that they need legislation that. To force these companies to make products that can be tapped into with portals. I'm faithful to the friends icon is getting his make over. The new icon is on the right you can see the woman is no longer in the man shot up. They're equal partners there the FaceBook designer who brought the woman silhouettes the forefront. Similar changes were made in the FaceBook groups I kinda new icon on the right showing a woman. In fruits. That doctor Doolittle of the dump more on this Golden Retriever is content to outlaw act of lives with these experts at camps here and it is safe today. They're I'll be at that. Bob add hoses and hang out with his Brothers and sisters from the other mother. Get him to take pictures where there thankfully it's human powers.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:45:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/nyse-halts-trading-due-technical-glitch-sc-house-32311470</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 7.8.15.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: South Carolina Senators Vote to Remove Confederate Flag From Capitol Grounds
Now Playing: NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI, 'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon
Now Playing: Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies, U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day, Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon
Now Playing: C-130 Plane Crashes In Medan Indonesia, Gov. Chris Christie Announces Presidential Bid, President Obama Meets With Brazilian President
Now Playing: Obama Signs Fast-Track Trade Bill, NBC Cuts Ties With Trump, Wimbledon Begins
Now Playing: 3rd Suspect in Boston ISIS Terror Arrested; House Rejects Obama's Trade Bill; Boeing Shows Off New Dreamliner
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 6/9/15
Now Playing: Colorado Tornado Damage, American Pharoah Practice Run, Hong Kong MERS Screening
Now Playing: Sen. Graham Enters Presidential Race, Caitlyn Jenner Revealed, Nadal Wears $775k Watch At The French Open
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Hillary Breaks Her Silence With Reporters, Fatal Flooding In Columbia, 'Blue Alert Act' signed
Now Playing: Amtrak Derailment Debris Cleaned Up, Mississippi Officer Remembered, Search for Missing US Marines Helicopter
Now Playing: Deadly Amtrak Crash in Philadelphia, Nepal Earthquake Aftermath, Indy 500 Car Flips During Practice
Now Playing: Second Earthquake Strikes Nepal, Arkansas Tornado Victims Cleanup, 'Jetman' Soars Above Dubai
Now Playing: Attorney General Announces Baltimore Investigation, NYPD Officer Mourned, Obama at Nike Headquarters
Now Playing: Oklahoma Tornado Aftermath, Quake Victims Remembered In Nepal, Air Force Football Meets Obama
Now Playing: Philadelphia Honors Fallen Officers, Sir Elton John Fights For HIVAIDS Funding, SpaceX Tests Astronaut Abort System
Now Playing: Gen. Dunford Nominated Joint Chiefs Of Staff, Huckabee Announces 2016 Bid, Cinco De Mayo
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 5/04/15
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32311470,"title":"NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match","duration":"0:46","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 7.8.15.","url":"/International/video/nyse-halts-trading-due-technical-glitch-sc-house-32311470","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:58:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/london-bombings-survivor-thought-die-32286347</Link>
        <Description>Sajda Mughal remains in pain 10 years after surviving the 2005 London bombings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'
Or. Asked about those three as oh among. Kenyon to day I was working in the sixty of London. They means. That was. It. I wasn't that makes. Says that issues on the big ticket. Am happy that she's I should've looked on silently. I ended up getting that you. Ten seconds. Into the tunnel obviously took office when it was aimed not at which time out that was its base. Train and let's not act but it felt like. Show. Life went house. Waxman stops and a carriage. Compete and it actually. Then act signed. Went. Into screen. Trying. People buying the tools. People crying. Yeah. But for me I remained in the east still. And I remember going to shall. Win and I had a crush of fools. And I stopped to remember my loved ones. And I honestly feel that. I was going to die that day. Basically I was complete city covet. A black smoke my hands face. My suit I remember but having its takeoff in the carriage might they send it to you wrapping it around my face. Could let it starts to suffocate me. Eventually. What happened was. He mentions he says it's came down. To rescue us. We need to clear now roses well. Please on the evening yeah. Came in the carriage is escort us out onto the tracks. Back to king's books I've talked corn up on I couldn't get through on the net that network systems without. And I had to make my way high one book exactly what I did I won't back. It took me Alice. Took how is that eventually went liked it now I'm and I remember when I was on my right I just ran past Boston like it's my. According to the house bill that dual shock that since shuffled lines that TV and radio an amendment. Just cutting off from the safe. This needs to isn't crying weight problems come. I was compete job I though the UK would Napa -- for bombing. And often on the national and stand. And then stuck in. That it will they were bombings carried out ice cream. I'm not shocked me even mall the attacks that they could eat eat and can you don't want to overcome that and. I don't. Because that job she.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: British Remember 7/7 Bombings
Now Playing: London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'
Now Playing: Law Enforcement on Heightened Alert Ahead of July 4th
Now Playing: Pres. Obama Announces Embassy Openings in Cuba; Dozens Killed in ISIS Sinai Attack; Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: Iran Hostage Crisis Survivor Protests Obama Nuclear Deal
Now Playing: A Year of Sleepless Nights for Boy Who Survived Deadly Beach Attack
Now Playing: ISIS in Mosul 1 Year Later
Now Playing: Meet the 8 Young Musicians of NYC's Harmony Program As They Take the Stage with the NY Philharmonic
Now Playing: Inside the Horse Barns at Belmont Park
Now Playing: A Day in the Life: How Music Helps Get One Girl Into One of NYC's Top Public Schools
Now Playing: A Day in the Life: Music Helps Change the Life of a Boy From an Underserved Community
Now Playing: The American Dream: Music Helps An Immigrant Mother's Wishes Come True for Her Daughter
Now Playing: Retaliation for Military Sexual Assault Reporting Rampant
Now Playing: Wildlife Parkgoers Defy Rules After Lion Kills American
Now Playing: First Look Inside the Dizzying Heights of the New World Trade Center
Now Playing: Watch: Texas Flash Flooding, May 2015
Now Playing: Here's The Military-Style Gear President Obama Banned Local Police From Using
Now Playing: Biker Gang Shootout Leaves 9 Dead in Texas
Now Playing: Moscow's Subway Is An Underground Palace
Now Playing: How 5 Possible White House Hopefuls Answered the Iraq Question
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32286347,"title":"London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'","duration":"3:47","description":"Sajda Mughal remains in pain 10 years after surviving the 2005 London bombings.","url":"/International/video/london-bombings-survivor-thought-die-32286347","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:56:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/year-boy-issued-parking-ticket-32286252</Link>
        <Description>Halifax police constable Shawn Currie jokingly issued a citation for Declan Tramley's illegally stopped red plastic motorcycle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
It's a familiar sight and sound on the Halifax waterfront. All too familiar for constable Sean Currie part of my job in the water premise public safety and part of it was just keeping the circle clear for emergency vehicles. While the motorcyclist like combat partner here. It's a big reason you'll spot three year old decked him scrambling cruising the boardwalk it's one of his favorite places to explore. There's people to meet shops to check out but its favorite attraction is the motorcycles. Accompanied by his parents Jacqueline loves to ride down on his bike. Toss on his leather jackets even mingle with his fellow bikers. Is that mores are brings in to see the bikes and stuff. You know once every couple weeks that's when Jacqueline had his first run in with the law he practiced by dislike the other more cycles. He walked away and we thought it would be funny by went over in just pretend to read architect police officer went over it and they're pretending to read him a ticket and it is certificates and and equipment parent. Once sequins father snapped the picture sent it to the Halifax regional police who jumped at the opportunity to posted on social media so far reaction to the picture's been overwhelming. I never die. It would explode I mean. As looking like different radio stations FaceBook pages and everywhere insist. Every night this shows the different sides of please. You know we're not always the ones making arrests and hauling people away were just normal like everybody else in the the picture received hundreds of re tweets and favorites on Twitter. And the H or. 440000. People closes ticket. The outside nervously as you can actually it's safe to say though that. He won't be so pleased years from now when he receives his first actual parking ticket and has to dish out the cash to pay for it Matt Woodman CTV news Halifax.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Wimbledon Fans See Fantastic Tennis but Hear Loud Grunts
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32286252,"title":"Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket","duration":"1:51","description":"Halifax police constable Shawn Currie jokingly issued a citation for Declan Tramley's illegally stopped red plastic motorcycle.","url":"/International/video/year-boy-issued-parking-ticket-32286252","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:57:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons  </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/fighter-jet-small-plane-collide-fbi-searches-subway-32285611</Link>
        <Description>Two killed after fighter jet and small plane collide over South Carolina; FBI searches Subway spokesman Jared Fogle's home; Man ties himself to helium balloons to advertise business. </Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
The mid air collision involving a military F sixteen fighter aircraft and he's definitely one that people were now. Carolina and that crash scene is looking at about eleven miles north of Charleston as the fighting. Aircraft the prop plane colliding with a supersonic F sixteen. Air force fighter. The FBI they think Indiana we'll look at Pittsburgh and U ovals this morning. We'll go out just after weak case attorney for fifty fully cooperating with authorities. Working screen and vet almost 7000. Volunteers. To ensure that they are committed to fighting Neitzel as of July 3 partner currently training about sixty fighters. This number is much smaller than we hope for us. Startling revelations about bill can't be today in a deposition from a sexual -- federal ten years ago the comedian admitted to obtaining waiting weeks for women keep going to have sex. Very very blog. From a legal point of view him as well as from an emotional. For many the election. New clot on cape Florida State freshman cornerback Dionte Johnson. Punching a woman at a bar last month the incident caught on surveillance camera and released yesterday by prosecutors had met the teen to cut ties. With a heartbeat. Really what's going on across Paul sports. Right now since the rate video blame someone you know is charged with something more there arrest. On something at what point do you cut. Today topping it with an official gathering in brothels for an emergency summit for Greece's new finance chief arrived without a proposal. Greece is expected tonight to put out a letter to other Euro zone members asking for assistance from what's called DS and European stability mechanism. That would give them a medium. And short term loans. If you want to up your advertising game called this guy at 26 year old man soared over Calgary to appetite for cleaning product. He used more than 100 helium balloons and a lawn chair in the active parachute down after. Flew off of course police are not happy the man arrested for mr. causing danger through life. Oh.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home Searched by FBI
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Wimbledon Fans See Fantastic Tennis but Hear Loud Grunts
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32285611,"title":"Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons ","duration":"2:32","description":"Two killed after fighter jet and small plane collide over South Carolina; FBI searches Subway spokesman Jared Fogle's home; Man ties himself to helium balloons to advertise business. ","url":"/International/video/fighter-jet-small-plane-collide-fbi-searches-subway-32285611","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:27:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI,  'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/subway-spokesman-home-searched-fbi-running-bulls-begins-32284441</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 7.7.15</Description>
        <MainBody>Brown shocked crowds as he dominated his match with 2-time Wimbledon champ Rafael Nadal.
Now Playing: Dustin Brown Becomes Wimbledon's Breakout Star
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home Searched by FBI
Now Playing: NYSE Halts Trading Due to Technical Glitch, SC House Debates Confederate Flag, Federer Wins Quarterfinals Match
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI, 'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon
Now Playing: Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies, U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day, Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon
Now Playing: C-130 Plane Crashes In Medan Indonesia, Gov. Chris Christie Announces Presidential Bid, President Obama Meets With Brazilian President
Now Playing: Obama Signs Fast-Track Trade Bill, NBC Cuts Ties With Trump, Wimbledon Begins
Now Playing: 3rd Suspect in Boston ISIS Terror Arrested; House Rejects Obama's Trade Bill; Boeing Shows Off New Dreamliner
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 6/9/15
Now Playing: Colorado Tornado Damage, American Pharoah Practice Run, Hong Kong MERS Screening
Now Playing: Sen. Graham Enters Presidential Race, Caitlyn Jenner Revealed, Nadal Wears $775k Watch At The French Open
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Hillary Breaks Her Silence With Reporters, Fatal Flooding In Columbia, 'Blue Alert Act' signed
Now Playing: Amtrak Derailment Debris Cleaned Up, Mississippi Officer Remembered, Search for Missing US Marines Helicopter
Now Playing: Deadly Amtrak Crash in Philadelphia, Nepal Earthquake Aftermath, Indy 500 Car Flips During Practice
Now Playing: Second Earthquake Strikes Nepal, Arkansas Tornado Victims Cleanup, 'Jetman' Soars Above Dubai
Now Playing: Attorney General Announces Baltimore Investigation, NYPD Officer Mourned, Obama at Nike Headquarters
Now Playing: Oklahoma Tornado Aftermath, Quake Victims Remembered In Nepal, Air Force Football Meets Obama
Now Playing: Philadelphia Honors Fallen Officers, Sir Elton John Fights For HIVAIDS Funding, SpaceX Tests Astronaut Abort System
Now Playing: Gen. Dunford Nominated Joint Chiefs Of Staff, Huckabee Announces 2016 Bid, Cinco De Mayo
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 5/04/15
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32284441,"title":"Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI, 'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon","duration":"0:39","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 7.7.15","url":"/International/video/subway-spokesman-home-searched-fbi-running-bulls-begins-32284441","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 23:46:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Greece's Financial Crisis Affects Citizens, Store Owners</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/greeces-financial-crisis-affects-citizens-store-owners-32282647</Link>
        <Description>ABC News??? Alexander Marquardt talks to businesses that are losing money due to the economic situation in Greece.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Greece's Financial Crisis Affects Citizens, Store Owners
This is something you see all across Athens all across streets here behind me two different yeah. Hands would long lines at each of them. People lining up to take out that maximum daily allotment of sixty euros. Or 67 dollars and that number could quickly go down to zero this country running out of cash. If it doesn't get an emergency injection sued all of these ATMs will soon be empty. We've been coming every day you know at sixty euros every day. You immediately spend that are you sitting at home in case congressman's not only then there's me the first needs. Who eat something. But what. My soul. Only case. Just days is the basic experience on a strong note to his house tops five years ago. This is the central market map and still bustling with customers who come here to buy meat and fish. But this flow of customers could quickly dry up if the cast does. And the vendors here telling us it's getting harder for them because they buy these fish directly from the fisherman. Who now multi sided anymore. Accepting only cash. Where he seems crisis. It every day. To have gone down and welcome to this. But once people are afraid what more. It's been so volatile fight whatever they need. We'll fight game he's really want a man who's so no one enjoys life. It's happening in Williams smiled. Your customers are just dropped almost ten days the period there's a deficit of 9%. We just bluster yes because. And human Mohammed mom does and they can be six to use today. So both of that do. So the by pollutants of buy food. Steve reverend. Abuse and amp. Author today Hager will be able to be brought together as a because it is.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Greece's Financial Crisis Affects Citizens, Store Owners
Now Playing: London Bombings Survivor: 'I Thought I Was Going to Die'
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: Subway Spokesman Home Searched by FBI, 'Running Of The Bulls' Begins, Rain Delay At Wimbledon
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Now Playing: Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies, U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day, Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon
Now Playing: Pres. Obama Announces Embassy Openings in Cuba; Dozens Killed in ISIS Sinai Attack; Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: Int'l Hotspot: Dozens of Egyptian Soldiers Killed by ISIS Suicide Bombers
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32282647,"title":"Greece's Financial Crisis Affects Citizens, Store Owners","duration":"3:00","description":"ABC NewsAlexander Marquardt talks to businesses that are losing money due to the economic situation in Greece.","url":"/International/video/greeces-financial-crisis-affects-citizens-store-owners-32282647","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 22:42:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/eu-foreign-policy-chief-announces-flexibility-iran-nuclear-32278571</Link>
        <Description>Federica Mogherini discusses taking the needed time in order to finalize the negations taking place in Vienna between Iran and six world powers. </Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
We are moving forwards. We entered into the most say they singled and sensitive. Content that told us we do not stigmatizing those things. This summer thanks fateful night meetings innings against CNN news. So I'm not talking about an extension until you know taking that I wasn't any news. I try to completes our way it is that it looks we always feel it was going to be difficult. But we aren't continue to learn to see if we managed to finalize agreements. Saying in the next hours a couple of days. That's what they're doing using the time we have an inflexible way. Knowing that's we have to lose in this fight I came here a couple of days ago Sunday saying the time is now sealed the times now. So it's so we know that we are using the maximum. But we're not closing the window and then opening another window at another time we are using the time out.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Wimbledon Fans See Fantastic Tennis but Hear Loud Grunts
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32278571,"title":"EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline","duration":"0:59","description":"Federica Mogherini discusses taking the needed time in order to finalize the negations taking place in Vienna between Iran and six world powers. ","url":"/International/video/eu-foreign-policy-chief-announces-flexibility-iran-nuclear-32278571","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 21:17:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/camping-attend-papal-mass-32277947</Link>
        <Description>An estimated 1 million pilgrims gathered in Quito's Bicentennial Park, many sleeping overnight in pouring rain, to hear Pope Francis give mass during his trip to Latin America.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
You can contact thank you sandy million dollars or miss so when I. As well no it was and the whole night yeah. We look. At my limited green you. You know we couldn't eat. They're. They it is subject to be here again. How long have you been. We've been camping anything about him that night and we thought part. For the lottery amount and how much of this category. We have but both have all been taken down out of me worth B. And even the lot of then. You guys are from Chicago and yet and you can't just to see the vote. This man is being held on what you're giving the airport you're OK don't. Look up book that's still control tower. And these are the runway. Pat let me. And crowded me. It's interesting because sometimes it's you know the ticket which you had the most. Barton is the easiest thing isn't it that range but it's not about the honorary doctorate and sacrificed again and who have suffered that they haven't given us. Thanks for them.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: NYSE Trading Resumes; United Airlines Flights Grounded for Hours Nationwide; Facebook Makes Subtle Change to Icon
Now Playing: Wimbledon Fans See Fantastic Tennis but Hear Loud Grunts
Now Playing: Why a 3-Year-Old Boy Was Issued a Parking Ticket
Now Playing: Fighter Jet and Small Plane Collide; FBI Searches Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle's Home; Man Ties Himself to Helium Balloons
Now Playing: EU Foreign Policy Chief Announces Flexibility With Iran Nuclear Deadline
Now Playing: Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: No New Bailout Plan for Greece at Eurozone Summit
Now Playing: Pope Greeted by Millions in Tour of Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32277947,"title":"Camping Out to Attend a Papal Mass","duration":"1:25","description":"An estimated 1 million pilgrims gathered in Quito's Bicentennial Park, many sleeping overnight in pouring rain, to hear Pope Francis give mass during his trip to Latin America.","url":"/International/video/camping-attend-papal-mass-32277947","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 21:12:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/us-training-60-fighters-syria-32277333</Link>
        <Description>In a shocking admission by the Pentagon, Defense Secretary Ash Carter revealed the U.S. was only training about 60 Syrian opposition fighters to battle ISIS, well below the 5,000 that officials had originally estimated.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
We're also nearly stages of our train and equip mission in Syria. Three months into our program training is under way and we are working to screen and vet almost 7000. Volunteers. To ensure that they are committed to fighting Beisel pass to Keller intelligent screening. And meet standards prescribed by US law. Regarding the law for conflict. And necessitated by operations. As of July 3 we are currently training about sixty acres this number is much smaller than we know for at this point. Partly because of the vetting standards I justice. Right. Now you mentioned we are currently training about sixty fighters. I gotta tell you after four years from secretary that's not a very impressive number. Hello everyone I'm all of the carry New York shocking admission by the Pentagon their Defense Secretary ash Carter admitting that the US with only training about. Sixty Syrian opposition fighters to battle ice is well below expectations. Joining me now with more on these revelations it's ABC news pick on digital journalist booby Martinez. Louis good afternoon to you and first off again a startling admission by ash carver and there so why is this strategy unfolding so slowly in Syria. Well it is unfolding very slowly Elizabeth as you say it kind of a startling admission their Press Secretary defense ash Carter. That it's only about sixty east moderates hearing rebels are currently undergoing training. The plant had been to train as many as fine thousand of these rebels within the first year this program they're not even close to that. We've all known at this has been a very slow roll of very slow process to gated under way. Partly the reason that ash Carter is citing the main reason is that because of the vetting process this is the screening process that is currently under way. To you. Go through the year in the backgrounds of as many as 7000 volunteers are 7000 buzz Syrians who have stepped forward saying they want to be part of this program. They want to fight nicest they also want to fight the aside regime. But it's a very slow process for American officials to look into the backgrounds these rebels of these individuals to determine number one if they are going to be. Oh not willing to be fighting rice's number two whether they are treatable number three most importantly I would say. Is to make sure that the aid will not pose a threat to their trainers to their American trainers what is called the green on blue threat. That once they're screened and that they might pose a threat here trainers that something that is of major concern is another major concern is that these. What where the loyalties of these individuals it once they're trained in re inserted back into Syria they really gonna fight. Prices or are and will they continue. With working with the US or will they turn over and become. Extremist themselves so that is those are the reasons that ash Carter is citing for the useful role. And why we're hearing this very surprising number I mean we're China under a hundred people here. And in a training program that was supposed to have pumped out 5000. Warned that first year. Very interesting and we should note here we heard briefly from Senator McCain off the top their but he went ought to push ash Carter further cleaning that the defense department's lack of support in fighting Bashar Al side was the reason why the fighters were not joining. Is he correct. He's partly correct that it that is because McCain is a very freaking critic of the Defense Department in particularly of the administration's strategy in Iraq and Syria. One of the terms that he used at today's hearing lies that if president strategies quote delusional. A minute not mincing words when it comes to criticizing. But what he sees the lack of smaller number of American troops inside Iraq where there presently 3500. Of them. But also the it would he says it why aren't we doing more to support the Iraqis why aren't they are Forward Air controllers calling in strikes. Air strikes would along with its alongside. Iraqi troops Y arena viewing more inside Syria he is a frequent critic of the operations of US operations inside Syria which so far. Had a limited to the airstrike campaign against ices and supporting the Syrian Kurds and also with is very very slow rule process. Of training moderate Syrian rebels. Eyes sale McCain laying into. The president's strategy just yesterday route you'll recall a President Obama was here at the Pentagon. Citing some of the progress that. Has been made against the basis in both Iraq and Syria. And that was what McCain was referring to when he said that it was the lesion now. How much time are gonna get this I mean this is the president made it clear yesterday this is going to be yes a little process. And so the fact that there are only slow numbers small numbers. The Syrian stepping forward is to actually go go undergo this training program. And does not speak. About the effectiveness of it right now but that comes to the cautions have been from officials say. This is going to be a multi year effort against crisis we need to be patient. And we need to listed programs develop over time. I think Katie ash Carter himself has not been satisfied he told the committee today that he was not satisfied with the pace of the change. But that he had been assured by the senior commander in charge of the program. That adds more betting gets underway and has Morse individual step forward more individuals will eventually get into the pipeline. But for now they're saying we have 87000 volunteers we just have to get through them. And then get them into the actual training program and general re insert them into Syria so they can take on crisis. And finally we just mentioned the president visited the Pentagon yesterday and that he noted this is going to be eighth low and long campaign. But have you learned anything about any new change in this strategy and that's coming. For them to fight and defeat crisis. Elizabeth they strategy. The administration of clean out these three people number one it is contained crisis inside Iraq Hugh used to train. The Iraqi military so that they can take on ices. And push them out of Iraq have pushed him out of the cities that gave it go taken over like Mosul. And then the third part of the strategy is in Syria to contain prices it's his ability support itself and support operations. In two. Iraq in the do that by conducting airstrikes and by training this moderate force. What we did hear from the president yesterday is that wanted to things that is Guyanese has been happening. It is likely to continue on is an intensification. Of the support against vices inside Syria. One of their key phrases that we keep hearing from ash Carter from general Martin Dempsey the chairman of the joint chiefs. Is that about supporting local ground forces effective local ground forces. Insight Syria and Iraq in Syria in particular what they're referring to you right now. Are the Syrian Kurds. You know they initially the idea was that the US and Iran but this training program that he's moderate Syrians this force a five pounds would eventually be fighting inside Syria. And that they are going to be cannery in size is on the ground. There but what has happened over the last six months is at this. Grassroots operation Syrian Kurds in northern Syria that pushed the ice is out of cook Bonnie. Hayes man had other battle through congress in northern Syria along the border with Turkey. They have become the dip back to go force this local ground force. That the US has been talking about and the US has been providing them with air support. And providing them and other means to combat prices well what we saw over this weekend is holiday weekend was a large number of airstrikes over crisis is the facto capital of rock in Syria. We saw XT six senior strikes in one day. And would the reason they did this later on we learn from Defense Secretary Carter was it they wanted to support these Kurds by preventing crisis from leaving Iraq. Where they could counter them up north east Kurdish forces are currently about thirty miles north of rock so the area pose a threat to them. The US doing everything it can. It's just stated they're supporting a force that they had not not envisioned being there mean combat force Tory there's a proxy inside Syria. And instead this moderate training program moving very slowly and eventually officials being optimistic that it will ramp up but. We're seeing right now screen format colors comments affairs slovo. As slow roll indeed once again ABC's Willie Martinez joining us from the Pentagon thank you so much. And you can keep up with the story in real time by downloading the ABC news happened storing this story for exclusive update on the go. I'm Elizabeth her in New York.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
sident Obama, in a rare visit to the Pentagon, delivering remarks on his strategy to defeat ISIS after receiving a briefing from his military brass.
Now Playing: President Obama on Fight Against ISIS
Now Playing: Martin Dempsey Releases 2015 National Military Strategy for the US
Now Playing: NYSE Halts All Trading
Now Playing: United Airlines Flights Cleared for Takeoff After Early Morning Computer Glitch
Now Playing: US Markets React to China Stock Slide
Now Playing: FBI Raids Home of the Subway Sandwich Pitchman
Now Playing: U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria
Now Playing: More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador
Now Playing: North Carolina's Shark Threat: 7th Victim Attacked
Now Playing: Toxic Train Accident Forces 5,000 Residents Out of Maryville, TN
Now Playing: Obama Embraces Campaign Mode in Overtime Push
Now Playing: Shooting Scare at Washington, D.C. Navy Yard
Now Playing: New Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: US and Cuba to Normalize Diplomatic Relations
Now Playing: 100+ Killed in Military Cargo Plane Crash in Indonesia
Now Playing: Gene Palmer, Guard Charged in NY Prison Escape, Appears in Court
Now Playing: NBC to Donald Trump: 'You're Fired!'
Now Playing: Manhunt Continues for Surviving Escapee
Now Playing: Manhunt Continues for David Sweat, Public Reacts to SCOTUS Decision
Now Playing: Supreme Court Ends Same-Sex Marriage Ban
Now Playing: Reaction to Supreme Court Ruling on Obamacare
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32277333,"title":"U.S. Only Training 60 Fighters in Syria","duration":"9:02","description":"In a shocking admission by the Pentagon, Defense Secretary Ash Carter revealed the U.S. was only training about 60 Syrian opposition fighters to battle ISIS, well below the 5,000 that officials had originally estimated.","url":"/International/video/us-training-60-fighters-syria-32277333","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:47:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  GMA 07/08/2015: Flash Flood Emergencies Lead to Multiple Rescues</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/gma-07082015-flash-flood-emergencies-lead-multiple-rescues-32302488</Link>
        <Description>LAPD May Open Investigation Into Bill Cosby After Court Revelation; 'The Lego Movie' Directors Sign On for Han Solo Spinoff Movie</Description>
        <MainBody>GMA 07/08/15: Flash Flood Emergencies Lead to Multiple Rescues
01:07:00 07/08/15 NR
LAPD May Open Investigation Into Bill Cosby After Court Revelation; The Lego Movie Directors Sign On for Han Solo Spinoff Movie
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 12:01:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 07/07/15:  San Francisco Shooting Suspect Raises Immigration Questions</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-070715-san-francisco-shooting-suspect-raises-immigration-32291803</Link>
        <Description>Fashion Icon Beverly Johnson Speaks Out on Cosby Court Filings; Searching for Monstrous Sharks Near Cuba, Caribbean's Final Frontier</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 07/07/15:  San Francisco Shooting Suspect Raises Immigration Questions
18:14 07/07/15 NR
Fashion Icon Beverly Johnson Speaks Out on Cosby Court Filings; Searching for Monstrous Sharks Near Cuba, Caribbean's Final Frontier
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 11:18:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  WN 07/07/15: Down to the Wire in Iran Negotiations</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WNT/video/wn-070715-wire-iran-negotiations-32290413</Link>
        <Description>New study on why women outlive men; ticker tape parade for US Women's Team World Cup Champions.</Description>
        <MainBody>WN 07/07/15: Down to the Wire in Iran Negotiations
20:08 07/07/15 NR
New study on why women outlive men; ticker tape parade for US Womens Team World Cup Champions.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 22:35:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  This Week 07/05/15: Donald Trump's Impact on the 2016 Campaign Trail</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/ThisWeek/video/week-070515-donald-trumps-impact-2016-campaign-trail-32234897</Link>
        <Description>Guests: Rick Perry, Yanis Varoufakis, Bob Goodlatte, Tom Cole, Bill Kristol, Joaquin Castro, Anne Gearan</Description>
        <MainBody>This Week 07/05/15: Donald Trumps Impact on the 2016 Campaign Trail
48:52 07/05/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 09:03:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  20/20: Bruce Jenner: The Interview - Encore Presentation</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/2020-bruce-jenner-interview-encore-presentation-32235522</Link>
        <Description>Bruce Jenner shares an exclusive and wide-ranging conversation with Diane Sawyer.</Description>
        <MainBody>20/20 07/04/15: Bruce Jenner: The Interview - Encore Presentation
01:20:00 07/04/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
