<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="AP">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 01:03:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US threatens to quit nuke talks; Iran blames West for divide</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-09-Iran-Nuclear-Talks/id-bc80501d1bf540e9a77ba8d5bfc3d167</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (AP) — U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry threatened Thursday to walk away from nuclear talks as he signaled that diplomats won't conclude an agreement with Iran over the coming hours — another delay that this time could complicate American efforts to quickly implement any deal. The Iranians immediately fired back, accusing the U.S. and its European allies of causing the deadlock.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video
Buy AP Photo Reprints
VIENNA (AP)  U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry threatened Thursday to walk away from nuclear talks as he signaled that diplomats won't conclude an agreement with Iran over the coming hours  another delay that this time could complicate American efforts to quickly implement any deal. The Iranians immediately fired back, accusing the U.S. and its European allies of causing the deadlock.
Kerry and other Western officials said Iran still hadn't made the tough political decision to roll back its nuclear program. But a senior Iranian official said it was the Americans and their partners who were backtracking on several key commitments related to Iran's permitted level of nuclear activity and definitively ending economic sanctions against Tehran.
"This is not open-ended," Kerry told reporters outside the 19th-century Viennese palace hosting the negotiations. "We can't wait forever for the decision to be made. If the tough decisions don't get made, we are absolutely prepared to call an end to this process."
It was the strongest indication yet of U.S. frustration with Iran, and vice versa, coming two days after President Barack Obama vowed a similar response to Iranian intransigence and suggesting patience was running out as the current round of talks headed into its 14th day.
Thursday's latest delay for a comprehensive deal is significant. Iran is demanding prompt easing of economic penalties for nuclear concessions, and the longer it takes world powers to make good on their promises, the longer they'll have to wait for the Iranians to scale back their nuclear program.
Under U.S. law, the seven nations negotiating in Vienna have to complete the accord before the end of Thursday in Washington to avoid invoking a 60-day congressional review period during which President Barack Obama cannot waive sanctions on Iran. If they meet the target, the review would only be 30 days.
The specter of prolonged public relations campaigns for and against the pact also may not work in Obama's favor. The delay could imply that the U.S., Iran and other negotiating powers may end up having to push off the talks until September when any deal would again only amount to a 30-day review period.
"We will not rush and we will not be rushed," Kerry said.
"We would not be here continuing to negotiate just for the sake of negotiating. We're here because we believe we are making real progress toward a comprehensive deal," he said. But, he added: "We are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever."
Kerry spoke after discussing the state-of-play with other world powers for almost an hour Thursday evening. That conversation followed a flurry of other closed-door meetings, including a 45-minute session between Kerry and his Iranian counterpart.
"We're working hard, but not rushed, to get the job done," Zarif tweeted.
A senior Iranian official, who briefed foreign reporters covering the talks on condition no one quote him by name, declared the West's reluctance to ease economic penalties the biggest obstacle. The U.S. is "obsessed" with sanctions, said the official, adding that the deadlock could prove a major setback.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said he would remain in Austria's capital for negotiations into Friday morning, citing "good things, but there is still work to do."
However, U.S. Energy Secretary Ernest Moniz, who has been leading the American negotiating team alongside Kerry, was to leave for Portugal for most of Friday to discuss climate change matters with the president, prime minister and other senior officials.
The current round of talks has already been extended twice since it started on June 27, as has an interim nuclear accord with Iran that these negotiations are meant to finalize. The preliminary deal was due to expire on June 30, then July 7 and then Friday. It would have to be renewed a third time if the talks go beyond Friday.
At an economic summit in Russia, Iran's President Hassan Rouhani said his nation was preparing for a "post-sanctions" era, suggesting a deal may be in sight to curb Iran's nuclear program in exchange for the lifting of economic sanctions.
Kerry spoke by phone with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, who was also in Russia and voiced optimism, saying he was prepared to return to Vienna.
And in what was widely seen as a hint that the talks might soon wrap up, the White House late Wednesday issued a brief statement saying President Barack Obama had conferred with the U.S. negotiating team through a secure video call.
The last time Obama held a secure conference call with his negotiators on the road was shortly before the framework for a final accord was reached on April 2 in Lausanne, Switzerland.
Kerry, nursing a broken leg, has been in Vienna since June 26, while Zarif has made one short trip to Tehran for consultations. Other foreign ministers have come and gone. All but the top diplomats from Russia and China were present at Thursday's meetings.
When the talks missed their second deadline it raised new questions about the ability of world powers to cut off all Iranian pathways to nuclear weapons through diplomacy.
Long-standing differences persist over inspections of Iranian facilities and the Islamic republic's research and development of advanced nuclear technology.
New difficulties also have surfaced over the past few days. Iran is pushing for an end to a U.N. arms embargo on the country but Washington opposes that demand.
Russia's Lavrov took Tehran's side.
"Our Western partners, who did not support a draft resolution entirely acceptable to the other parties, are at fault, not Iran," he tweeted.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 01:03:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Greece offers sales tax hikes, pension cuts</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-09-EU--Greece-Bailout-The%20Latest/id-b5a7d77b2d6b441bb80f5e2d036c5d43</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS, Greece (AP) — The latest from the Greece's financial crisis (all times local):</Description>
        <MainBody>ATHENS, Greece (AP)  The latest from the Greece's financial crisis (all times local):
___
12:53 a.m.
Greece's government has agreed to longstanding demands by creditors to impose sweeping sales tax hikes and cuts in state spending for pensions.
In the text of proposals sent by Athens, and seen by The Associated Press, the government concedes to demands it had previously resisted, mostly on moving various categories of goods and services to higher sales tax rates.
The proposals were sent in a last-ditch effort to reach a deal with rescue lenders after the country's previous program expired and missed repayments to the International Monetary Fund, and Greece was forced to close banks to prevent their collapse under the weight of mass withdrawals.
___
11:20 p.m.
The head of the eurogroup has received the proposals of the Greek government that are necessary to discuss a deal by Sunday to stave off financial collapse in the nation.
Beating a midnight deadline by almost two hours, the spokesman for Dutch eurogroup President Jeroen Dijsselbloem tweeted that the proposals were received and that it was "important for institutions to consider these in their assessment" of the Greek situation.
Eurogroup finance ministers are meeting on Saturday to discuss them and prepare a Sunday summit of European Union government leaders, widely seen as the decisive meeting on the Greek bailout crisis.
___
10:00 p.m.
Greece's energy minister is urging the government not to sign a third bailout, despite the risk of the country being forced out the euro.
Energy Minister Panagiotis Lafazanis told a business conference Thursday that "the choices we have are tough ... but the worst, the most humiliating and unbearable is an agreement that will surrender, loot and subjugate our people and this country."
He said Greece had voted 'no' in last weekend's referendum "and that will not be turned into a humiliating 'Yes.'"
___
7:20 p.m.
Greek Defense Minister Panos Kammenos says the Greek government's economic reform proposals will be submitted "in the next few hours."
Athens must submit the proposals by midnight Thursday Brussels time, so they can be reviewed by the country's creditors ahead of a summit of European leaders on Sunday.
European creditors have described this as Greece's last chance to produce a credible and realistic list of reforms in order to receive bailout cash and prevent the country from crashing out of the euro.
Athens on Wednesday requested a third bailout, and promised to "immediately" implement reforms including to taxes and pensions.
___
6:20 p.m.
German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble has rejected the notion that Germany should take the lead in solving Greece's debt woes because his country itself benefited from debt forgiveness in the past.
Germany's debts were written down by more than half in 1953, a step which helped launch the country on the path of growth after the destruction of World War II. Greece was among the countries that signed the agreement forgiving Germany.
Schaeuble said the situations "are not comparable" and the comparison "misleading," in response to a question from Harvard University's Benjamin Friedman at an economic conference in Frankfurt.
Schaeuble said Greece's economy was not competitive and that Greece's economic institutions "did not correspond to the minimum requirements" even before the debt crisis broke out in 2009.
___
6:10 p.m.
A prominent lawmaker from Greece's opposition conservative New Democracy party says there is enough support in parliament to approve any bailout deal that the government strikes with its creditors.
Dora Bakoyannis said after an hour-long meeting with European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker she's hopeful a deal can be reached that prevents Greeks from having "to pay the price for amateurishness, obsessiveness and egotism."
Another New Democracy lawmaker Kostas Hatzidakis said the overwhelming majority of Greeks want to stay in the EU and the eurozone.
Greece faces a midnight deadline  Brussels time  to send euro partners detailed economic reform proposals that will accompany any bailout loans. On Wednesday, Greece submitted a request for a three-year bailout.
European leaders meet Sunday in Brussels to decide whether the Greek government has done enough to get the bailout. Without the money, it faces bankruptcy and falling out of the euro.
___
5:45 p.m.
German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble says the possibility of some kind of debt relief for Greece will be discussed over coming days but he doesn't see much room for maneuver.
Germany is ruling out an outright debt cut, arguing that it would be illegal under European treaties. It's also resisted calls for any debt relief for Greece unless the country undertakes serious economic reforms.
The International Monetary Fund has argued that Greece's debt needs restructuring, if not by a so-called haircut then through other means, such as lengthening the time the country has to pay its debts.
At a conference in Frankfurt, Schaeuble noted that a private-sector debt restructuring was carried out in 2012, which went further than IMF proposals at the time.
Schaeuble said "the room for maneuver through debt reprofiling or restructuring is very small."
___
4:55 p.m.
Germany's Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble says Greece could start rebuilding trust with its partners in the 19-country eurozone by taking immediate actions to reform its economy.
Schaeuble said at a conference in Frankfurt that "we have always said there need to be prior actions, actions meant to build trust, and I don't see any prior actions."
Schaeuble, who has been skeptical of the Greek government's commitment to reform, conceded the chance of such actions before Sunday's European summit on the Greek crisis was "rather limited."
However, he did say that new Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos was "more conventional than his predecessor"  the confrontational Yanis Varoufakis.
Greece's euro partners are awaiting a last-chance proposal from Greece for bailout loans to keep it from running out of money and possible leaving the euro.
___
4:20 p.m.
Olivier Blanchard, director of research at the International Monetary Fund, says Greece's troubles pose little threat to the broader global economy.
In a statement Thursday, Blanchard said the world economy has "withstood the stress tests of the last two weeks fairly well."
Blanchard noted that Greece makes up just 2 percent of the 19-nation eurozone's economy and less than 0.5 percent of the world's economy.
"We continue to hope for and work toward a positive solution by which Greece remains in the eurozone," he says. "There is little question that Greece is suffering and may suffer even more under the scenario of a disorderly exit from the Eurozone. But the effects on the rest of the world economy are likely to be limited."
___
4 p.m.
Chancellor Angela Merkel has reiterated that Germany opposes an outright debt cut for Greece.
Merkel said during a visit Thursday to the Bosnian capital, Sarajevo, that "a classic haircut is out of the question for me. That hasn't changed between the day before yesterday and today."
Greece has to produce a finalized reform plan by the end of the day. Merkel says she isn't in a position to assess whether that plan will meet creditors' expectations.
Greece is seeking debt relief and the International Monetary Fund argues that the country's massive debt does need restructuring. Germany, though, has resisted calls for debt relief before Greece announces economic reforms.
___
3:35 p.m.
The eurozone's 19 finance ministers are set to meet on Saturday to assess Greek proposals to secure another financial bailout, which would ease the pressure on the country's economy and avoid its potential exit from the euro.
The afternoon meeting in Brussels will also prepare the ground for Sunday's summit of the 19 eurozone leaders, which will be followed by one of the wider European Union, which will involve all 28 leaders, officials said.
Sunday has the feel of being a make-or-break date for Greece. Without a deal, Greece could effectively be left to its own devices by Monday morning. And that could mean the collapse of its banks and the return of the country's ancient currency, the drachma.
In the run-up to the weekend meetings, the mood music surrounding Greece appears to be getting more positive. Markets certainly think so, with the Stoxx 50 index of leading European shares up 2.1 percent Thursday.
___
3:10 p.m.
Irish Finance Minister Michael Noonan thinks it's probable that Greece can strike a third bailout deal with European partners this weekend.
He credits Athens' switch of finance minister for improving the negotiating mood and repairing trust.
Speaking to Newstalk radio in Dublin, Noonan said this week's surprise replacement of Yanis Varoufakis with Euclid Tsakalotos has encouraged others at the table to believe that Athens wants a realistic deal, not endless brinkmanship.
For months, Noonan said he and his peers in the 19-country eurozone found Varoufakis evasive and difficult to pin down on specifics.
On the other hand, Noonan said he found Tsakalotos, at his first eurogroup meeting Tuesday, straightforward and "interesting," citing his background as a wealthy Marxist economist.
"It seems now they are serious," said Noonan, who now rates the chance of a deal with Greece at "better than 50 percent."
___
2:50 p.m.
European stock markets pushed higher after a leading official indicated that discussions over Greece's debt burden should be on the table in Sunday's summit of the European Union's 28 leaders.
The Stoxx 50 index of leading European shares was up 2 percent.
The advance came after Donald Tusk, who will chair this Sunday's meeting in his capacity as European Council President, said any Greek deal should include proposals from creditors over how to make the country's debts sustainable.
In a tweet, Tusk said Greece's reform proposals, due later, need to be "matched by (a) realistic proposal from creditors on debt sustainability to create win-win situation."
___
1:55 p.m.
Donald Tusk, who will chair this Sunday's meeting of European leaders, says any Greek deal has to be matched with realistic proposals from creditors over how to make the country's debts sustainable.
In a tweet, Tusk said Greece's reform proposals, due later, need to be "matched by (a) realistic proposal from creditors on debt sustainability to create win-win situation."
Tusk's call echoes comments from Christine Lagarde, the International Monetary Fund's managing director, on Wednesday.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras has insisted that debt relief should form part of any resolution to the Greek crisis at Sunday's summit of the European Union's 28 leaders. Germany, though, has resisted calls for debt relief without reforms.
Tusk also said in a tweet he expects, following a telephone call with Tsipras, to receive "concrete, realistic reform proposals today" from Greece.
___
1:30 p.m.
Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov says it would be wrong to say his country is enjoying the spectacle of Europe struggling to deal with Greece's debt crisis.
He said Russia has no interest in "throwing kindling onto this fire," and wants to see a quick resolution acceptable to all sides.
Russia, he said, is interested in a "strong, functioning, economically growing European Union.
Any idea that Moscow is rubbing its hands over the crisis European partners is wrong, he added.
"It is a distortion of our position and our interests," he said.
Relations between the European Union and Russia are at a low ebb as both sides have exchanged sanctions over the crisis in Ukraine.
There has been talk in recent weeks that Russia may help Greece out financially but that has been dismissed by the Kremlin.
___
12:50 p.m.
European markets are posting solid gains amid hopes Greece will finalize a plan of reforms and following a rebound in Asia.
Among major indexes, Germany's DAX was up 1.4 percent while France's CAC 40 rose 1.6 percent. The euro, however, was down 0.4 percent at $1.1035. The Athens stock market remained closed, alongside the banks.
The Greek government has until the end of the day to submit a plan of economic measures it will take in exchange for a new three-year program of loans. The creditors will review the measures before European leaders convene Sunday to decide on Greece's fate.
"Signs of unhappiness at the proposed deal could easily reverse the good feeling ... but for now markets just appear to be pleased that negotiations are underway once again," said Chris Beauchamp, senior market analyst at IG.
___
11:15 a.m.
A German member of the European Central Bank's governing council says Greek banks should not get more emergency credit from the central bank unless a bailout deal is struck.
Jens Weidmann said in a speech Thursday it's up to eurozone governments and Greek leaders themselves to rescue Greece.
Weidmann said the central bank "has no mandate to safeguard the solvency of banks and governments."
The ECB capped emergency credit to Greek banks amid doubt whether the country will win further rescue loans from other countries. The banks closed and limited ATM withdrawals because they had no other way to replace deposit flight.
Weidmann said he welcomed the fact that central bank credit "is no longer being used to finance capital flight caused by the Greek government."
___
10:45 a.m.
EU Economics Commissioner Pierre Moscovici is hopeful that a new Greek bailout deal is possible, in exchange for "concrete, complete" reform proposals from Greece's government.
Moscovici said Thursday on France-Inter radio that Thursday is "a decisive day" for Europe, as Greece's creditors await a detailed economic reform plan from Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' government before a midnight deadline.
Moscovici said, "I have the sense that the dialogue is established, or restored, and that there is a way out." Failure to reach a deal could be the first step toward Greece leaving the shared euro currency.
Greece requested a new three-year rescue from its European partners Wednesday. International creditors disagree over whether to award the country debt relief. Moscovici said that is not currently under discussion.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 01:03:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Amid detente with Hamas, Israel says 2 citizens held in Gaza</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-09-ML--Israel-Palestinians/id-02b58dcf4f904846a98f6c7407453f7b</Link>
        <Description>JERUSALEM (AP) — Israel on Thursday said that two of its citizens are being held captive in the Gaza Strip, an announcement that brought back bitter memories of the case of an Israeli soldier who was captured and imprisoned for five years by the Hamas militant group.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video
Buy AP Photo Reprints
JERUSALEM (AP)  Israel on Thursday said that two of its citizens are being held captive in the Gaza Strip, an announcement that brought back bitter memories of the case of an Israeli soldier who was captured and imprisoned for five years by the Hamas militant group.
But circumstances have changed dramatically since Gilad Schalit's release in a 2011 prisoner swap, and the case announced Thursday could provide an important test of a new fragile detente that has emerged between Israel and Hamas since their devastating war last year. A relatively subdued reaction in Israel reflected the new reality, though Hamas is likely to push for a new round of prisoner releases by Israel before it returns the two men.
Israeli defense officials identified one of the men as Avraham Mengistu, an Israeli of Ethiopian descent in his late 20s.
According to COGAT, the defense body that handles civilian issues with the Palestinians, Mengistu disappeared after he "independently" crossed the border fence and entered Gaza on Sept. 7, two weeks after the end of last year's war.
It gave no further details on why he had crossed into Gaza, though Israeli media said he had been distraught at the time of his disappearance.
COGAT said the second man was a Bedouin Arab citizen from southern Israel. It refused to identify him or say how long he had been in Gaza or how he got there. Officials also would not say which group had him in custody.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said he held Hamas, which has ruled Gaza since seizing control of the territory in 2007, responsible for the fate of both men. Netanyahu said Israel was working to free them and that he had appointed a representative to deal with the matter.
"Yesterday I spoke with the parents and siblings of Avraham Mengistu and I told them that from the moment the incident became known, we have spared no effort to return him to Israel," Netanyahu said, urging the international community to "issue a clear call" for their release.
But there were no threats of action against Hamas, in contrast to a bruising military campaign that followed Hamas' capture of Schalit in a 2006 cross-border raid  or more recently, the arrests of scores of Hamas supporters after the deadly abduction of three Israeli teens in the West Bank last year.
The kidnapping set off a string of events that culminated in a 50-day war that killed more than 2,200 Palestinians in Gaza and 73 people on the Israeli side. It was their third war since the Hamas takeover.
Since then, Israel and Hamas have largely honored a cease-fire and even reached some unspoken understandings to preserve quiet, a reflection of the shared threat to both sides by Gaza's Salafi militants inspired by the Islamic State extremist group.
Notably absent on Thursday were also the type of celebrations in Gaza that had accompanied previous kidnappings of Israelis. A Hamas spokesman, Salah Bardawil, said he had no information about the two missing Israelis.
"Even if it is true, we don't have instructions to talk about it," he said.
The different circumstances also contributed to the subdued reactions. Where Schalit and the teens were captured in military-style operations, the latest disappearances appeared accidental.
"It's a completely different situation," said Gershon Baskin, an Israeli activist who helped mediate the Schalit exchange deal, in which Israel freed more than 1,000 prisoners.
"They're not dealing with a valuable asset" like a captured soldier, Baskin said. "It's not the same high-value bargaining card."
Still, a protracted round of negotiations appears likely.
A senior Hamas official said that as a precondition for negotiations, the group would seek the release of nearly 60 militants released by Israel in the Schalit deal and then re-arrested last year after the three Israeli teens were kidnapped.
Hamas will also seek the release of some of the thousands of Palestinians held by Israel, he said, speaking on condition of anonymity because he was discussing the group's internal deliberations.
While Israel said nothing about the Bedouin man held in Gaza, the Hamas official claimed he had served in the Israeli military and was considered a prisoner.
Mkhaimar Abusada, a professor of political science at Gaza's Al-Azhar University, said a possible deal could include steps to strengthen the cease-fire. "I think the swap would be part of a long-term truce, five years or more," he said.
One of the first issues could be determining the fate of Mengistu. The Hamas official said Mengistu had walked into Gaza and appeared to have "psychological" problems. He said Mengistu told interrogators in the coastal strip that he did not want to go back to Israel and then left Gaza through a smuggling tunnel into Egypt in hopes of ultimately returning to Ethiopia.
COGAT, however, said it had "credible intelligence" that Mengistu was being held "against his will" by Hamas.
Israeli Channel 2 TV said Mengistu arrived at an Israeli beach near the Gaza border on the evening of Sept. 7, left his bag behind and crossed into Gaza through a breach in the border fence that was apparently made by Israeli tanks during the 2014 war.
"This is a difficult humanitarian matter, because my brother is not in the best of health," Ilan Mengistu told reporters. He did not elaborate, but Israeli Channel 2 TV said Mengistu was distraught following the death of another brother.
Israeli Channel 10 broadcast an interview with a man it identified as Mengistu's father. "They didn't do anything," Haili Mengistu said. "Where is my son?"
While Mengistu's disappearance had been well known inside Israel's Ethiopian community, Israel had barred publication of the incident for several months.
Israeli media had lobbied hard for permission to publish details on the case, putting pressure on the government to release information.
Khaled Mashaal, the head of Hamas' political bureau, also may have forced Israel's hand by telling a London newspaper this week that Israel had asked Hamas through a European mediator to release "two soldiers and two bodies." Israeli officials have said that the remains of two soldiers killed in combat last summer are held by Hamas.
Israeli lawmaker Yaakov Peri, a former director of the Shin Bet intelligence agency and an ex- government coordinator for prisoner of war issues, said that going public may have hurt the negotiations but that talks could nonetheless succeed in the current climate.
"Calculations are a little bit less emotional. And it's good. It's good for the negotiations, and I am sure it will affect the outcome," he said.
___
Associated Press writers Daniel Estrin and Tia Goldenberg in Jerusalem, Mohammed Daraghmeh in Ramallah, West Bank, and Fares Akram in Gaza City, Gaza Strip, contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 01:03:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Indigenous group in Bolivia frustrated</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-09-LT--Pope-The%20Latest/id-06f092c0076847f9a1e5858ed117eb9c</Link>
        <Description>SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia (AP) — Here are the latest developments from Pope Francis' trip to South America:</Description>
        <MainBody>Buy AP Photo Reprints
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia (AP)  Here are the latest developments from Pope Francis' trip to South America:
___
5 p.m.
A top leader of one of Bolivia's largest indigenous groups is expressing frustration for not getting accredited to attend a social summit with Pope Francis on Thursday evening.
The Guarani has been at odds with the government of President Evo Morales' government over its decision to open up the country's 22 protected wilderness areas to oil and natural gas exploration.
Guarani leader Celso Padilla says: "The summit is strictly controlled by people from the government. The government has only accredited people close to it. We've been left out."
Bolivia's deputy minister for coordination with social movements says the Guarani would have been welcome had they actively sought participation.
Xavier Albo, a Jesuit priest, author and leading authority on Bolivia's indigenous, says it's curious the pope is not holding any separate meetings with indigenous groups on his entire eight-day visit in South America.
He says: "There isn't a single act that is explicitly for the indigenous, but rather they are included within encounters with social movements together with other sectors."
___
4:30 p.m.
The pope is scheduled to give a late-afternoon speech to delegates at the second World Meeting of Popular Movements, a colorful gathering of Latin America's dispossessed and groups  including the Catholic charity Caritas  who advocate for them.
The first such meeting was held at the Vatican in October. Its Justice and Peace council organized this meeting with Bolivia's government, which chose the more than 1,500 delegates.
Inside a Santa Cruz sports hall, land rights advocates from Peru swapped experiences with people displaced by hydroelectric projects in Brazil, Bolivia's main labor federation and of mining collectives were prominent, along with Brazil's CUT labor federation.
Prominent, too, are delegates from CONAMAQ, Bolivia's main highlands indigenous organization, representing the dominant Quechua and Aymara ethnicities.
And then there are the truly poor, including nearly a dozen collectives of trash-pickers, "cartoneros," from Argentina, organizations especially dear to the pope.
___
2:45 p.m.
The Vatican is seeking to explain the "Communist crucifix" given to Pope Francis by Bolivian President Evo Morale, saying it's a symbol of dialogue and not an offensive melding of faith and ideology.
Morales gave the crucifix carved into a hammer and sickle to Francis when they met Wednesday upon Francis' arrival in Bolivia.
The Vatican wasn't expecting the unusual gift and it immediately raised eyebrows.
It turns out, the crucifix was originally designed by Jesuit activist Luis Espinal, who was assassinated in 1980 by suspected paramilitaries during the months that preceded a military coup. Francis is a fellow Jesuit and he stopped to pray at the site where Espinal's body was dumped.
The Vatican spokesman is the Rev. Federico Lombardi, and he said Thursday the pope had no idea that Espinal had designed such a crucifix.
Lombardi said Espinal's fellow priests said he had designed the crucifix as a symbol of dialogue and commitment to freedom for Bolivia during a turbulent time.
Many church theologians have bitterly denounced the Marxist influences on Liberation Theology, but Francis has tried to rehabilitate the movement  without the Marxism.
___
1:15 p.m.
Argentina's government is mounting an extensive operation to provide health services for more than a million Argentines expected to flood across the border to neighboring Paraguay for a Mass celebrated by their countryman, Pope Francis.
The Health Ministry says it's creating temporary health stations at points along the border with Paraguay, where the pope is to arrive on Saturday.
The effort includes extra ambulances, helicopters and specially outfitted airplanes, as well as military hospital tents and portable bathrooms.
Many Argentines have already set off for Paraguay because Thursday is a national holiday.
The pope is skipping Argentina on this visit, in part because the Vatican tries to avoid countries where a presidential election is imminent.
___
12 a.m.
With a vast crowd and a temporary altar, Pope Francis needed someplace to change before saying Mass. The closest place at hand was a Burger King.
So the famously unpretentious pope used the fast food restaurant before walking to the altar. The restaurant was closed for business due to the Mass, in which the pope denounced consumerism.
___
11 a.m.
Celebrating his first Mass in Bolivia, Pope Francis is calling on the faithful to reject consumerism, which he says only creates barriers between people.
Francis is addressing hundreds of thousands in Christ the Redeemer square in Santa Cruz.
He says consumerism includes a logic in which everything becomes an object that can be consumed and negotiated. He says that excludes people, but the contrary is necessary for a fulfilling life.
Francis said: "A memorable life needs (the participation) of others."
After the Mass, Francis' main event of the day is a keynote speech to a summit of grass-roots groups whose advocacy for the poor and marginalized has been championed by history's first Latin American pope.
___
10:15 a.m.
Pope Francis has begun celebrating an open-air Mass in the Bolivian city of Santa Cruz.
Hundreds of thousands have packed into Christ the Redeemer square and the streets beyond. Overnight, several thousand slept in square to get a spot close to the front.
Francis arrived in the Andean nation late Wednesday after three days in Ecuador.
___
9:30 a.m.
Pope Francis is out and about on the popemobile heading to his first public event of the day in Bolivia, an open-air Mass in Santa Cruz's Christ the Redeemer square.
Francis' bodyguards jogged alongside his popemobile at a fast clip as the pope waved to the crowds. His motorcade route was lined by flag-waving Bolivians held back by a human chain of police.
After the Mass, Francis' main event of the day is a keynote speech to a summit of grass-roots groups whose advocacy for the poor and marginalized has been championed by history's first Latin American pope.
Overnight, several thousand slept in square to get a spot close to the front.
Francis arrived in the Andean nation late Wednesday after three days in Ecuador.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 01:03:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saud al-Faisal, former Saudi foreign minister, dies</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-09-ML--Saudi-Obit-Prince%20Saud/id-d64b0cb0844d4eb5ba6c788bdb2689f4</Link>
        <Description>RIYADH, Saudi Arabia (AP) — Saudi Arabia's Prince Saud al-Faisal, who was the world's longest-serving foreign minister with 40 years in the post until his retirement this year, has died, the ministry spokesman said Thursday. He was 75.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video
Buy AP Photo Reprints
RIYADH, Saudi Arabia (AP)  Saudi Arabia's Prince Saud al-Faisal, who was the world's longest-serving foreign minister with 40 years in the post until his retirement this year, has died, the ministry spokesman said Thursday. He was 75.
The tall, stately Prince Saud was a fixture of Mideast diplomacy, representing the oil-rich Gulf powerhouse as it wielded its influence in crisis after crisis shaking the region  from Lebanon's civil war in the 1970s and 1980s, through multiple rounds of Arab-Israeli peace efforts, the 1990 Iraqi invasion of neighboring Kuwait and the subsequent Gulf War, al-Qaida's Sept. 11, 2001, attacks in the United States, the 2003 U.S.-led invasion of Iraq to the current day's tensions between the Arab Gulf bloc and Iran, Arab Spring uprisings, Syria's civil war and the spread of Islamic State group extremists.
The country's government-owned media announced Saud's death after midnight Friday. The official announcement, carried by state television, did not state the cause of death. The prince had undergone multiple surgeries in recent years for his back, which left him walking with a cane, and for other ailments.
Word of his passing first emerged late Thursday when Saudi Foreign Ministry spokesman, Osama Nugali, wrote on his official Twitter feed, "The eye tears, the heart saddens. We all are saddened to be separated from you."
The prince, who took the ministry post in 1975, retired on April 29, citing health reasons. At the time, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry hailed him, saying he "has not just been the planet's longest-serving Foreign Minister but also among the wisest." He was succeeded in the post by Adel al-Jubeir, who before that was Saudi Arabia's ambassador in Washington.
From Washington, Kerry expressed his condolences to Saud's family and friends, King Salman and to the people of Saudi Arabia, saying the prince was "a man of vast experience, personal warmth, great dignity, and keen insights who served his country loyally and well."
"I personally admired him greatly, valued his friendship, and appreciated his wise counsel," Kerry added. "His legacy as a statesman and diplomat will not be forgotten."
Saud was the son of Saudi Arabia's third king, Faisal, who ruled from 1964 until he was assassinated in 1975. Prince Saud, who had a bachelor's degree in economics from Princeton University and had been deputy petroleum minister, was soon after appointed to the foreign minister post, which his father had held during his reign. The young prince, fluent in English and French, brought an air of sophistication and charisma, whether in crisp suits or in the traditional Saudi white robe and gold-trimmed black cloak with a red-checkered head piece. Soft spoken, he often showed a sense of humor not often seen among the publicly stolid royal family.
He was father to six children, three boys and three girls. King Salman's son, Prince Sultan, is married to one of Prince Saud's daughters. The late prince's brothers are also known as highly educated and eloquent, with Prince Khaled al-Faisal serving as the governor of Mecca and another brother, Prince Turki al-Faisal, heading a research center and think tank after decades as the head of intelligence.
Mamoun Fandy, author of Saudi Arabia and the Politics of Dissent, said his death marks the end of an era as the elder royals move to shift power to younger princes.
"The history of Saudi foreign policy is al-Faisal, both him and his father," he said. "It's how the world knew Saudi Arabia, through al-Faisal."
Arab League Secretary General Nabil al-Arabi said the world lost a "noble" diplomat who defended his nation with "courage and valor." Iyad Madani, the secretary general of the Organization of Islamic Cooperation, the world's largest body of Muslim nations, said the prince fought major political battles in his career for the sake of his country and for the Muslim world.
He led Saudi diplomacy over a period that saw the kingdom  once better known for behind-the-scenes influence  become more overt in throwing its weight in affairs across the Mideast. Tending to the alliance with the United States was a major part of that. Saddam's invasion of Kuwait brought U.S. troops to Saudi Arabia, a deployment that raised some opposition among Saudis.
Al-Faisal played a key role in patching ties with the United States which were strained by the Sept. 11, 2001 attacks, in which 15 of the 19 hijackers were Saudi nationals. He insisted in public speeches that Islam and Muslims are not the enemy, saying in 2004 in an address at the European Policy Center in Brussels: "You just cannot dismiss a 1,400-year-old culture and civilization by stigmatizing it as merely a hatchery for terrorism."
After the 2003 U.S.-led invasion of Iraq ousted Saddam, Saudi Arabia often bristled over the consequences  the rise of Shiite power in Baghdad and the growing influence there of Shiite-led Iran, the kingdom's top rival. Saud "had to explain to the world how they hated Saddam Hussein, but objected handing over Iraq to Iran," Fandy said.
Al-Faisal was not seen as a hawk toward Iran, but was part of the leadership that saw the Shiite powerhouse across the Gulf waters as the main challenge to Sunni-led Saudi Arabia. Last year, he invited Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif to visit Saudi Arabia, but later accused Iran of fomenting unrest throughout the Middle East. Zarif ended up visiting shortly after King Abdullah's death in late January and expressed hopes of greater co-operation with the Sunni-ruled kingdom.
Among the stories shared about the prince by Western diplomats in Riyadh is that at one point, he had approached King Abdullah to ask to retire as foreign minister, saying he was tired and needed to rest. The monarch declined his request, telling him, "So I should be the only one to die in office?"
In one of his last public appearances as foreign minister in March, he helped rally efforts for Saudi Arabia to lead a coalition of Arab countries to bomb Yemen's Shiite rebels who had taken over the capital there. "We are not warmongers, but if the drums of war call for it, we are prepared," Saud said in a speech to the kingdom's consultative Shura Council, arguing that Yemen was integral to overall Gulf security and that Iran was behind the rebels.
__
Keath reported from Cairo. Associated Press writers Aya Batrawy in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, and Ellen Knickmeyer in San Francisco contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
