<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="AP">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:44:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece seeks 3-year aid program, rushes to detail reforms</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-08-EU--Greece-Bailout/id-736a128502e64c62b207d5c501fac839</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS, Greece (AP) — With a deadline just hours away to come up with a detailed economic reform plan, Greece requested a new three-year rescue from its European partners Wednesday as signs grew its economy was sliding toward free-fall without an urgently needed bailout.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video
Buy AP Photo Reprints
ATHENS, Greece (AP)  With a deadline just hours away to come up with a detailed economic reform plan, Greece requested a new three-year rescue from its European partners Wednesday as signs grew its economy was sliding toward free-fall without an urgently needed bailout.
As its banking system teetered near the edge, the government extended bank closures into next week, while international creditors were in open disagreement over whether to award the country debt relief  with Germany at odds with the International Monetary Fund.
Without a deal, Greece faces an almost inevitable collapse of the banking system, which would be the first step for the country to fall out of the euro.
As Thursday's deadline loomed, the government sought to reassure its European creditors that it would enact tax and pension reforms quickly in exchange for loans from Europe's bailout fund, the European Stability Mechanism.
In a formal request that was filled with vague promises but short on details, the Greek government pledged to "immediately implement a set of measures as early as the beginning of next week"  but did not specify what these were.
After months of fruitless negotiations with the Greek government, the skeptical eurozone creditor states have said they want to see a detailed, cost-accounted plan of the reforms by Thursday. That is meant to give enough time to review the plan before all 28 leaders of the full European Union meet on Sunday in what has been termed as Greece's last chance to stay in the euro.
But Greece's major creditors were hardly in lock-step over what path to take in dealing with the struggling but defiant EU member nation.
IMF chief Christine Lagarde reiterated Wednesday that Greece's massive debt would need restructuring, something that Germany  Greece's largest European lender  has resisted.
Speaking in Washington, Lagarde said Greece needed to continue cost-cutting reforms, but added: "The other leg is debt restructuring, which we believe is needed ... for debt sustainability."
"It well may be that the numbers may have to be revisited, but our analysis has not changed," she said of the need for granting Greece better repayment terms.
U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew added pressure on the European lenders, arguing debt relief was needed for a deal  and describing a Greek euro-exit as a "geopolitical mistake."
"I don't think any prime minister of Greece could sell all the additional fiscal measures, plus the structural reforms that are needed without some sense of what the debt sustainability looks like," he said in Washington.
Earlier Wednesday, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said his country was seeking a deal that would bring a definitive end to his country's financial crisis. Greece has had two bailouts from its European partners and the International Monetary Fund since May 2010, totaling 240 billion euros ($260 billion).
"We need to ensure the medium-term funding of our country with a development and growth program," Tsipras told lawmakers at the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France.
Applause rose from left-wing lawmakers in the turbulent chamber when Tsipras said aid to Greece has only helped banks, not ordinary Greeks, as some held up "No" signs to back Greek voters' rejection of more austerity.
Tsipras insisted he has "no hidden agenda" to drive Greece out of the euro and that last Sunday's referendum in which Greeks roundly rejected more belt-tightening reforms does not mean a break with Europe.
The head of a conservative group in the parliament, Belgium's Guy Verhofstadt, said he was "furious" at Tsipras' failure to spell out specifics of his reform plans.
Tsipras said Greece's troubles predated his arrival in office in January and condemned the "austerity experiment" his country has endured over the past five years that he blames for spiraling unemployment and poverty.
"We demand an agreement with our neighbors, but one that gives us a sign that we are on a long-lasting basis exiting from the crisis  which will demonstrate to us that there is light at the end of the tunnel," he said.
Tsipras vowed to continue reforms, but warned of the austerity-weariness of the Greek public. "This has exhausted the patience and resilience of the Greek people," he said.
In Greece, meanwhile, people already struggling with eight days of shuttered banks and limits on money withdrawals learned the finance ministry was extending the closures until next Monday. Greeks cannot take out more than 60 euros ($67) a day from ATMs and are unable to send money abroad, including to pay bills or to stock their businesses, without special permission.
The head of France's central bank said he feared the "collapse" of the Greek economy and "chaos" if Greece doesn't strike a deal by Sunday.
In unusually strong language, Christian Noyer told Europe-1 radio he predicted "riots" in Greece if no deal is reached. He also indicated the European Central Bank would effectively pull the plug on its emergency liquidity measures for Greek banks if no deal is struck.
Highlighting the rising anger with Tsipras, European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker had a stark warning for Greece after Tuesday's eurozone summit.
"We have a Grexit scenario, prepared in detail," he said, apparently referring to the situation in which Greece would be forced out of the currency union.
___
Keaten reported from Paris. Associated Press writers Michael Corder, Raf Casert, Menelaos Hadjicostis and Derek Gatopoulos in Brussels, and Angela Charlton in Paris contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:44:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Greek banks to stay closed until Monday</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-08-EU--Greece-Bailout-The%20Latest/id-97f54b56d28b4f139f4fc62fecf9141a</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS, Greece (AP) — The latest on the Greek financial crisis (all times Athens local):</Description>
        <MainBody>ATHENS, Greece (AP)  The latest on the Greek financial crisis (all times Athens local):
___
11:05 p.m.
The Greek finance ministry says the government has extended bank closures in the country up to and including Monday, maintaining the daily withdrawal limit at 60 euros ($66).
Banks were closed and restrictions imposed on June 29, after a heavy volume of withdrawals by depositors threatened lenders with collapse.
The European Central Bank has maintained its level of emergency assistance  but has demanded higher collateral  after Greece's bailout program expired on July 1 and the country failed to cover repayments due to the International Monetary Fund.
The bank closures have piled pressure on Greece's left-wing government to reach a new agreement with bailout creditors, and abandon a pledge to end austerity measures following a six-year recession.
___
10:45 p.m.
IMF Managing Director Christine Lagarde said Greece's national debt requires restructuring for bailout programs to work.
Speaking in Washington D.C., Lagarde said Greece needs to continue cost cutting reforms.
And she added: "The other leg is debt restructuring, which we believe is needed in the particular case of Greece for it to have debt sustainability. That analysis has not changed. It well may be that numbers may have to be revisited but our analysis has not changed."
The IMF and lead eurozone lender Germany are at odds over whether Athens should be offered debt relief  a request renewed Wednesday by Greece's government.
Athens is trying to negotiate a third bailout program  worth an expected 50 billion euros ($55 billion)  as it faces the risk of losing its euro membership.
___
7:35 p.m.
The European Central Bank has decided not to increase the amount of emergency credit that Greek banks can draw on.
A banking official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because the decision was not made public, said the ECB's emergency liquidity assistance was left unchanged.
The official said the bank is waiting to see how Greece's creditors respond to its financial aid request and its reform agenda, due to be published by Thursday.
The Greek banks have needed increased credit to deal with the daily drain of deposits. The ECB's failure to increase so-called ELA in line with Greek requests is one of the reasons why capital controls have been imposed in Greece, including the 60-euro a day withdrawal limit.
-- By Elena Becatoros in Athens.
___
6:20 p.m.
U.S. Treasury Secretary Jacob Lew says Greece came within a whisker of narrowing differences with creditors before negotiations broke off and Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called a referendum on creditor proposals.
The gap, he said, was just a "couple of billion euros"  negligible when compared to the "hundreds of billions of dollars" potential damage the global economy faces if Greece leaves the euro.
Lew said a solution was still possible but that it wasn't entirely clear one will be found.
Lew insisted that the Obama administration has been engaged, helping both sides understand the options available but that the solution rested with Europe.
"They will have to solve it," Lew said in an appearance at the Brookings Institution in Washington.
At the moment, he said the risks to the U.S. economy were not immediate.
___
6:05 p.m.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls thinks Greece's new request for aid is a "positive" move as the country battles to maintain its euro future.
Valls told the lower house of Parliament that France "refuses" to consider a Greek exit from the euro.
He said Greece's earlier request for help shows "real advances" toward dialogue in the latest crisis  even though the Greek government has yet to submit details of its proposed economic reforms in exchange for the new aid money.
Valls warned of geopolitical consequences if Greece sinks into financial catastrophe, such as trouble dealing with high flows of immigrants from outside the European Union or worsening tensions with Russia.
He said France is pushing for compromises between Greece and creditors, because that's "how Europe was built."
___
4:25 p.m.
Greece's main business and tourism associations have warned of an "explosion of unemployment" if the government fails to find a deal with creditors soon and reopen banks.
In a joint letter to the government Wednesday, five associations urge Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras not to risk the country's place in the euro.
Their letter says that "Unless business activity resumes soon, with a restoration of liquidity, there will be an explosion of unemployment that will be dramatic and will wipe out all the sacrifices made by the Greek people over the past five years."
More than one-in-four Greeks remain out of work, with the crisis and bailout austerity measures costing roughly a million jobs, mostly in the private sector.
___
3:55 p.m.
France's government spokesman says his country is trying to play mediator between Germany and Greece.
Stephane Le Foll said French President Francois Hollande's goal is "to find a sort of middle ground between the position of Germany and the position of Greece."
France, he said, is listening to those countries that accept the idea of a Greek exit from the euro but that it's important for his country "to facilitate, and above all keep a broad perspective" on the fact that the idea of European unity is also at stake.
France's Socialist government has been one of Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' few allies and is using France's role as a key, founding member of the European Union to try to gain a bit more flexibility.
___
3:40 p.m.
Spanish Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy is using a musical metaphor to describe a seeming change of approach by the Greek government as it tries to convince creditors to lend it money soon.
Rajoy told a press conference in Madrid that the "tune" being played by Greek has changed "and that's a good thing."
Rajoy said he's looking forward to seeing the "lyrics" on Thursday  a reference to the time when the Greek government has been asked to provide substantive reform proposals that underlies its request earlier for a three-year financial rescue from Europe's bailout fund.
"I hope things work out," he said. "Greece has lost a lot of time in recent months."
___
2:50 p.m.
Greece has made a request for a three-year loan from Europe's bailout fund and has pledged to "immediately implement" tax and pension related measures as of Monday.
In the letter sent to the European Stability Mechanism earlier, the government said it will "set out in detail its proposals for a comprehensive and specific reform agenda" on Thursday at the latest.
Greece's aim, the letter went on, was to regain "full and affordable market financing to meet its future funding requirements as well as sustainable economic and financial situation" by the time the loan ends at the latest.
The letter also says the country is committed to honoring its financial obligations to its creditors on time.
"We trust Member States appreciate the urgency of our loan request," it said.
___
2:45 p.m.
Greece's prime minister insists he has "no hidden agenda" to drive the country out of the eurozone amid criticism over his government's handling of negotiations for a new bailout deal.
Alexis Tsipras told the European Parliament that his only goal was to strike "a fairer, more sustainable agreement" with the other 18 eurozone countries.
Tsipras said he wouldn't have said that Sunday's referendum result was a mandate for a fairer deal rather than "a break with Europe" if he had really wanted Greece to ditch the euro.
Over 60 percent of Greeks voted in the referendum against an austerity plan demanded by the country's creditors.
___
2:40 p.m.
Germany's Finance Ministry is stressing that Greece must deliver a detailed list of reforms in its application for aid from Europe's bailout fund.
Ministry spokesman Martin Jaeger said Wednesday that "this application must be comprehensive." He said it won't be enough simply to write a letter stating that Greece wants help from the European Stability Mechanism.
Jaeger says an "integral part" of the application must be a detailed account of what reform measures Greece plans in exchange for an aid program.
He is stressing that Athens can't simply return to proposals that were on the table before Greece's previous bailout expired June 30.
"We need a future-oriented, comprehensive reform program," he said.
Jaeger says he hasn't yet seen the initial request for aid that Greece submitted and can't assess it.
___
1:50 p.m.
The head of France's central bank says he fears the "collapse" of the Greek economy and "chaos" if Greece doesn't strike a deal by Sunday with European creditors.
Christian Noyer told Europe-1 radio that the European Central Bank has been supporting Greek banks for months, but that there is a limit to its support.
He said that "we are resolutely committed to maintaining Greece in the eurozone" and that's why emergency liquidity has been provided.
"But we are in an abnormal situation that can no longer last," he said.
And in unusually strong language, the French central bank chief also predicted "riots" in Greece if no deal is reached.
__
1:40 p.m.
A teleconference of the eurozone's 19 finance ministers about the Greek crisis will not be held later.
Michel Reijns, the spokesman for the eurozone's top official Jeroen Dijsselbloem, tweeted that Greece's request for support from Europe's bailout fund will be dealt with by officials from the eurogroup working group instead.
Greece submitted a request for a new support program from the European Stability Mechanism Wednesday morning. It is due to follow up with a detailed plan by the end of Thursday of how the government plans to reform its economy.
___
1:10 p.m.
Greece has submitted its request for a rescue deal from Europe's bailout fund.
Michel Reijns, the spokesman for the eurozone's top official Jeroen Dijsselbloem, says Greece submitted the request for a new support program from the European Stability Mechanism Wednesday morning.
The government's request is the first step in a process toward a new bailout for the debt-laden country.
Athens has to follow the request up with a detailed plan by the end of Thursday of how the government plans to reform its economy if it is to receive fresh bailout cash to stave off bankruptcy and a possible exit from the euro.
Greece has been effectively told it has to have a deal in place Sunday when the leaders of the 28 EU nations meet in Brussels.
___
12:55 p.m.
Donald Tusk, who chairs meetings of European leaders, has harked back to one of Greece's famous sons to urge a resolution of the country's crisis: The historian Plutarch.
"'To find fault is easy, to do better may be difficult,'" Tusk said in a speech to European lawmakers. "I hope doing better is not so difficult as Plutarch once thought. Let us prove him wrong."
Tusk says the European Union is in a "race against time to rebuild trust" as it frantically searches for a way out of months of impasse.
Tusk warned that "our inability to find agreement may lead to the bankruptcy of Greece and insolvency of its banking system."
In a tweet, he added that if a deal can't be brokered this week, "Everyone will lose."
___
12:35 p.m.
European stock markets were solid as guarded optimism over the prospects of a deal between Greece and its creditors in time to avoid a Greek exit from the euro.
At a summit of the eurozone's 19 leaders Tuesday, Greece was effectively told it must have a reform plan agreed by Sunday or face an exit from the euro. Sunday's summit will involve the leaders of all 28 European Union nations.
"The support for eurozone membership in Greece is clear and the political and economic costs of capital controls are rising," said George Saravelos, an analyst at Deutsche Bank. "But it is a close call."
That seems to be the general view in markets with the Stoxx 50 index of leading European shares and Germany's DAX both up 0.1 percent. The euro rose 0.3 percent to $1.1043.
___
12:05 p.m.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras says his country has submitted a broad proposal to get another rescue plan and will present details in the coming days.
His government faces a Thursday deadline to present the detailed plan on how to save Greece from financial ruin, before a European Union summit Sunday.
Tsipras says his country wants a deal that will mean a definitive end to Greece's protracted financial crisis, and that last Sunday's referendum result does not mean a break with Europe.
Speaking to the European Parliament in Strasbourg on Wednesday, Tsipras says Greece's troubles date to long before he took office five months ago.
European leaders have readied a "Grexit scenario" about a possible exit from the euro.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:44:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-08-AF--Nigeria-Kidnapped%20Girls/id-b68aab61115543aaa9f366e48037c088</Link>
        <Description>LAGOS, Nigeria (AP) — Nigeria's Boko Haram extremists are offering to free more than 200 young women and girls kidnapped from a boarding school in the town of Chibok in exchange for the release of militant leaders held by the government, a human rights activist has told The Associated Press.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video
Buy AP Photo Reprints
LAGOS, Nigeria (AP)  Nigeria's Boko Haram extremists are offering to free more than 200 young women and girls kidnapped from a boarding school in the town of Chibok in exchange for the release of militant leaders held by the government, a human rights activist has told The Associated Press.
The activist said Boko Haram's current offer is limited to the girls from the school in northeastern Nigeria whose mass abduction in April 2014 ignited worldwide outrage and a campaign to "Bring Back Our Girls" that stretched to the White House.
The new initiative reopens an offer made last year to the government of former President Goodluck Jonathan to release the 219 students in exchange for 16 Boko Haram detainees, the activist said. The man, who was involved in negotiations with Boko Haram last year and is close to current negotiators, spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to talk to reporters on this sensitive issue.
Fred Eno, an apolitical Nigerian who has been negotiating with Boko Haram for more than a year, told the AP that "another window of opportunity opened" in the last few days, though he could not discuss details.
He said the recent slew of Boko Haram bloodletting   some 350 people killed in the past nine days  is consistent with past ratcheting up of violence as the militants seek a stronger negotiating position.
Presidential adviser Femi Adesina said on Saturday that Nigeria's government "will not be averse" to talks with Boko Haram. "Most wars, however furious or vicious, often end around the negotiation table," he said.
Eno said the 5-week-old administration of President Muhammadu Buhari offers "a clean slate" to bring the militants back to negotiations that had become poisoned by the different security agencies and their advice to Jonathan.
Two months of talks last year led government representatives and Eno to travel in September to a northeastern town where the prisoner exchange was to take place, only to be stymied by the Department for State Service intelligence agency, the activist said.
At the last minute, the agency said it was holding only four of the militants sought by Boko Haram, the activist said.
It is not known how many Boko Haram suspects are detained by Nigeria's intelligence agency, whose chief Buhari fired last week.
The activist said the agency continues to hold suspects illegally because it does not have enough evidence for a conviction, and any court would free them. Nigerian law requires charges be brought after 48 hours.
Thousands of suspects have died in custody, and some detainees wanted by Boko Haram may be among them. Amnesty International alleges that 8,000 detainees have died in military custody  some have been shot, some have died from untreated injuries due to torture, and some have died from starvation and other harsh treatment.
In May, about 300 women, girls and children being held captive by Boko Haram were rescued by Nigeria's military, but none were from Chibok. It is believed that the militants view the Chibok girls as a last-resort bargaining chip.
In that infamous abduction, 274 mostly Christian girls preparing to write science exams were seized from the school by Islamic militants in the early hours of April 15, 2014. Dozens escaped on their own in the first few days, but 219 remain missing.
Boko Haram has not shown them since a May 2014 video in which its leader, Abubakar Shekau warned: "You won't see the girls again unless you release our brothers you have captured."
In the video, nearly 100 of the girls, who have been identified by their parents, were shown wearing Islamic hijab and reciting the Quran. One of them said they had converted to Islam.
International indignation at Nigeria's failure to rescue the girls was joined by U.S. first lady Michelle Obama. In a radio address in May 2014, she said she and President Barack Obama are "outraged and heartbroken" over the abduction.
Jonathan's government initially denied there had been any mass abduction and delays of a rescue that might have brought the girls home became a hallmark of his other failures. He steadfastly refused to meet with the Bring Back Our Girls campaigners, charging they were politicizing the issue.
On Wednesday, President Buhari welcomed those campaigners at the presidential villa in Abuja and pleaded "We only ask for your patience." He said "The delay and conflicting reaction by the former government and its agencies is very unfortunate."
Campaign leader Oby Ezekwesili said, "The rescue of our Chibok girls is the strongest statement that this government could make to showg respect for the sanctity and dignity of every Nigerian life."
There have been unconfirmed reports that some of the girls have been taken to neighboring countries, and that some have been radicalized and trained as fighters. At least three were reported to have died  one from dysentery, one from malaria and one from a snake bite.
Last year, Shekau said the girls were an "old story," and that he had married them off to his fighters.
Lawan Zanna, whose daughter is among the captives, said this week that 14 Chibok parents have died since the mass kidnapping, many from stress-related illnesses blamed on the ordeal.
Some of the Chibok girls who managed to escape have been rejected by their community and now live with family friends, tired of hearing taunts like "Boko Haram wives."
The assumption that all girls and women held by the group have been raped is a difficult stigma to overcome in Nigeria's highly religious and conservative society.
Shekau had threatened in 2013 to kidnap women and girls if Nigeria's military did not release detained Boko Haram wives and children. The government freed them in May of that year as a goodwill gesture ahead of failed peace talks.
Boko Haram has kidnapped hundreds more  girls, boys, women and young men. Some have become sex slaves, while others are used as fighters, according to former captives.
Nigerian opinion on negotiating with the extremists is mixed. Some say the group's crimes are too heinous to be forgiven: The 6-year-old Islamic uprising has killed more than 13,000 people and forced about 1.5 million from their homes.
"A lot of people take a hard-line stance that you must never negotiate with a terrorist," said Sen. Chris Anyanwu. She called it a "very complex" issue, balancing the lives of more than 200 girls against the dangers of freeing extremists.
The militants last year seized a large swath of northeast Nigeria and declared an Islamic caliphate. Nigeria and its neighbors deployed a multinational army that forced them out of towns and villages this year, but the bloodshed has risen at a fierce rate since Buhari's May 29 inauguration amid pledges to crush the insurgency.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:44:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope insists on church role in Bolivia after limits imposed</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-08-LT--Pope-South%20America/id-8ca03c4cf767413b999cc769c2ac9a99</Link>
        <Description>LA PAZ, Bolivia (AP) — Pope Francis arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday on the second leg of his South American tour and immediately insisted that the Catholic Church continue to play an important role in society amid efforts by the government of President Evo Morales to curb its influence. He later called for dialogue between Bolivia and Chile over their longtime border dispute.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video
Buy AP Photo Reprints
LA PAZ, Bolivia (AP)  Pope Francis arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday on the second leg of his South American tour and immediately insisted that the Catholic Church continue to play an important role in society amid efforts by the government of President Evo Morales to curb its influence. He later called for dialogue between Bolivia and Chile over their longtime border dispute.
Morales hugged the pope as he descended from the Boliviana de Aviacion plane and hung a pouch around his neck of woven of alpaca with indigenous trimmings. It is of the type commonly used to hold coca leaves, which are chewed by people in the Andes to alleviate altitude sickness. It wasn't known if Francis chewed any leaves, though he was served mate tea made with coca leaves, chamomile and annis on the plane from Quito, Ecuador.
La Paz stands at 4,000 meters (about 13,120 feet) above sea level, and the Vatican decided to keep the pope's stay to just four hours to limit any problems for the 78-year-old pontiff, who has only one full lung. Francis though seemed in fine form, bundled against the cold and wind by a white shawl that he donned for his popemobile ride into town past thousands of people who came to greet him, waving handkerchiefs and singing songs of welcome.
At an airport welcome ceremony with Morales by his side, Francis praised Bolivia for taking "important steps" to include the poor and marginalized in the political and economic life of the country, South America's poorest.
Morales came to power championing Bolivia's 36 indigenous groups and enshrined their rights in the constitution, and under his leadership Bolivia's economy has boomed thanks to high prices for its natural gas and minerals. But Morales has roiled the local church by taking a series of anti-clerical initiatives, including a new constitution that made the overwhelmingly Catholic nation a secular country.
In his speech, Francis noted the Catholic faith took "deep root" in Bolivia centuries ago "and has continued to shed its light upon society, contributing to the development of the nation and shaping its culture."
"The voice of the bishops, which must be prophetic, speaks to society in the name of the church, our mother, from her preferential, evangelical option for the poor," he said.
Morales, for his part, recalled how the Catholic Church in the past was on the side of the oppressors of Bolivia's people, three-quarters of whom are of indigenous origin. But Morales, an Aymara Indian known for anti-imperialist and socialist stands, said things have changed with this pope and the Bolivian people are greeting Francis as someone who is "helping in the liberation of our people."
"He who betrays a poor person, betrays Pope Francis," Morales said.
He later gave Francis some politically loaded gifts. Chief among them: a crucifix carved into a wooden hammer and sickle, the Communist symbol uniting labor and peasants.
Another politically charged gift was a copy of "The Book of the Sea," which is about the loss of Bolivia's access to the sea during the War of the Pacific with Chile in 1879-83. Bolivia has taken its bid to renegotiate access to the Pacific to the International Court of Justice, arguing that its poverty is due in part to being land-locked. Chile has argued the court has no jurisdiction since Bolivia's borders were defined by a 1904 treaty.
Francis referred to the border dispute in a speech to civil authorities later in La Paz, calling for countries of the region to improve their diplomatic relations "in order to avoid conflicts between sister peoples and advance frank and open dialogue about their problems."
"I'm thinking about the sea, here," he said. "Dialogue is indispensable. Instead of raising walls, we need to be building bridges."
Francis denounced the constant "atmosphere of inequality" in Bolivia, where despite its economic advances in recent years nearly one in four Bolivians lives on $2 a day. And while prosperity has come to some with economic growth averaging 5 percent annually, it has "opened the door to the evil of corruption," Francis said.
Bolivia has a notoriously corrupt judiciary, with some 1,000 judges and 300 prosecutors under investigation or on trial for corruption.
Francis and Morales have met on several occasions, most recently in October when the president, a former coca farmer, participated in a Vatican summit of grassroots groups of indigenous and advocates for the poor who have been championed by Francis. Their shared views on caring for society's poorest, and the need for wealthy countries to drastically change course to address climate change, have bumped up against Morales' clashes with the local clergy.
As soon as Morales took office in 2006, for example, the Bible and cross were removed from the presidential palace. A new constitution in 2009 made the overwhelmingly Catholic nation a secular state and Andean religious rituals replaced Catholic rites at official state ceremonies.
"There are some challenging issues in terms of Evo Morales taking on a quite combative role against the church, which he sees as a challenge to his authority," said Clare Dixon, Latin American regional director for CAFOD, the English Catholic aid agency. "The church is also questioning some decisions made about development in the country."
Morales had pledged to safeguard the interests of Bolivia's indigenous. But he has alienated lowlands natives by promoting a highway through a nature reserve and authorizing oil and natural gas exploration in wilderness areas. Cheered by environmentalists abroad for his demand that wealthy nations do more to combat climate change, Morales has been under fire at home from critics, including activists in the church, who say he puts extracting petroleum ahead of clean water and forests.
Francis was expected to raise environmental concerns during his Bolivian sojourn, just as he did in Ecuador. Other highlights of the trip include his visit to the notoriously violent Palmasola prison, where a battle among inmate gangs in 2013 left 30 people dead. As in many Latin American prisons, inmates largely control the inside of Palmasola, which teems with some 3,500 prisoners, more than four in five still awaiting trial.
In a deeply personal gesture soon after he arrived, Francis stopped his motorcade along the highway heading into town at the site where a Jesuit priest, the Rev. Luis Espinal, was left in 1980 after being detained and tortured by Bolivia's paramilitary squads.
"Remember one of our brothers, a victim of interests that didn't want him to fight for Bolivia's freedom," Francis said from the popemobile to a crowd gathered at the site. "Father Espinal preached the Gospel, the Gospel that bothered them, and because of this they got rid of him."
It was a brief but poignant moment, given Francis' own experience with the right-wing military dictatorship in Argentina. Then the Rev. Jorge Mario Bergoglio, he led the Jesuit order there when two fellow priests were kidnapped by the regime, which joined like-minded governments in Bolivia and Paraguay to mount Operation Condor to wipe out and "disappear" leftist opponents.
___
Associated Press writers Frank Bajak and Paola Flores contributed to this report.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:44:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AC/DC's Rudd given home detention for threatening to kill</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-07-08-AS--New%20Zealand-AC/DC%20Phil%20Rudd/id-6d83a660760b4ed1a7fdb75ddccc1357</Link>
        <Description>SYDNEY (AP) — A New Zealand judge sentenced AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd to eight months of home detention on Thursday after the musician pleaded guilty to threatening to kill a man who used to work for him, along with possession of methamphetamine and marijuana.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video
Buy AP Photo Reprints
SYDNEY (AP)  A New Zealand judge sentenced AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd to eight months of home detention on Thursday after the musician pleaded guilty to threatening to kill a man who used to work for him, along with possession of methamphetamine and marijuana.
The 61-year-old Australian-born drummer had faced up to seven years in prison on the threatening to kill charge, but his lawyer had argued for the conviction to be set aside.
During the hearing, Tauranga District Court Judge Thomas Ingram said Rudd had a limited criminal history and posed a low risk of reoffending, Radio New Zealand reported. But Ingram said Rudd had been found with a substantial amount of drugs. And the judge rejected an argument from Rudd's lawyer that the death threat boiled down to one angry phone call.
Rudd has been out on bail since pleading guilty to the charges in April, when he acknowledged in a court summary of facts that he'd offered large amounts of cash, vehicles and a house to an associate after asking him to have the victim "taken out." He also acknowledged that he'd directly said to the victim he was going to kill him.
Prosecutors had also originally charged Rudd with murder-for-hire, but later dropped it, citing lack of evidence.
According to the court summary, the dispute began in August when Rudd threw a party at his marina restaurant, Phil's Place, to celebrate the launch of his solo album, "Head Job." But Rudd grew angry that security wasn't tight enough, and felt the launch hadn't gone well. He subsequently fired several employees, including the victim, whose name has been suppressed by the court.
About four weeks later, Rudd called an associate and told him he wanted the victim "taken out," according to the court summary. When asked to clarify, Rudd said he wanted the victim "taken care of."
In another call, according to the court summary, Rudd offered the associate "$200,000, a motorbike, one of his cars or a house," which the associate took to mean as payment "for carrying out his earlier request." Two hundred thousand New Zealand dollars is equivalent to about US$133,000. The morning after calling his associate, Rudd called the victim directly, saying "I'm going to come over and kill you."
Police found marijuana and methamphetamine in several parts of Rudd's home during a search of the house, the court summary said. They also found methamphetamine in his pocket.
Rudd's lawyer, Craig Tuck, had asked for a discharge without conviction in the case. New Zealand law gives a judge the discretion not to enter a conviction even after a defendant has pleaded guilty. Judges can do this if they think the consequences of a conviction outweigh the seriousness of the crime, a move which can allow a defendant to keep a clean record.
Rudd largely ignored questions from the waiting media pack upon arriving at court, but thanked his fans for their "fantastic" support.
It's unclear whether Rudd has a future with the Australian rock band he's been part of on-and-off for almost four decades. The band is currently using Welsh drummer Chris Slade for its "Rock or Bust" album tour, but hasn't said if that's a long-term arrangement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
