<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="BBC">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:08:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece extends bank closures</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33456182#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Greece extends bank closures and a €60 daily limit on ATM withdrawals until Monday, as Athens seeks to secure a deal with creditors on its huge debt.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece debt crisis: Banks stay shut as endgame looms
9 July 2015
From the section Europe
The Greek government has extended bank closures and a 60 (43; $66) daily limit on ATM withdrawals until Monday.
The curbs were imposed on 28 June, after a deadlock in bailout talks with creditors led a rush of withdrawals.
The European Central Bank has decided not to increase support for Greek banks until the debt crisis is resolved.
Greek PM Alexis Tsipras says he will submit "credible" reform plans on Thursday - ahead of a Sunday deadline by the EU to find a solution.
An emergency summit will involve all 28 EU members - not just the 19 eurozone countries.
European Council President Donald Tusk has warned that this was now the "most critical moment in the history of the eurozone".
"The final deadline ends this week," he said after emergency talks of the eurozone leaders in Brussels on Tuesday.
Greece is desperate for a third bailout to avoid bankruptcy and possibly crashing out of the euro currency.
'Acute crisis'
"The bank holiday is extended to July 13," the finance ministry said in a statement late on Wednesday.
There are fears that Greek banks may be running out of cash
The announcement came after the European Central Bank - which has been providing emergency liquidity to keep Greek banks from collapsing - said it would leave its current level of support unchanged.
Greece's last international bailout programme expired on 30 June and it missed an International Monetary Fund (IMF) payment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:41:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore mayor sacks police chief</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33450854#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The mayor of Baltimore axes the city's police chief months after the US city was rocked by riots following the death of a black man in custody.</Description>
        <MainBody>Baltimore mayor sacks police chief months after riots
8 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Anthony Batts had led Baltimore's police force since October 2012
Baltimore's mayor has sacked the US city's police chief, saying his leadership had become a distraction from fighting a "crime surge".
Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake said she was replacing Police Commissioner Anthony Batts with his deputy, Kevin Davis, for an interim period.
The city was rocked by riots in April when a black man died after suffering injuries in police custody.
Six officers were charged over the death of the 25-year-old, Freddie Gray.
Speaking at a news conference on Wednesday, Mayor Rawlings-Blake said Mr Batts had "served this city with distinction" since becoming police chief in October 2012.
But referring to the city's high homicide rate, she said "too many continue to die".
"The focus has been too much on the leadership of the department and not enough on the crime fighting," she told reporters, adding: "We need to get the crime surge under control."
The city has seen a sharp increase in violence since Freddie Gray's death on 19 April, with 155 homicides this year, a 48% increase over the same period last year.
On Tuesday, the police department announced that an outside organisation will review its response to the civil unrest that followed Mr Gray's death.
Freddie Gray's death followed several other cases where black men died after contact with the police
Police officers complained that they were poorly equipped and badly led during April's riots
The US justice department is also conducting a civil rights review of the Baltimore force and Mr Batts has been criticised by the city's police union.
Earlier on Wednesday, the union released its report into the police handling of the rioting.
It said officers had complained "that they lacked basic riot equipment, training, and, as events unfolded, direction from leadership".
The report also said "officers repeatedly expressed concern that the passive response to the civil unrest had allowed the disorder to grow into full scale rioting".
Recent events had "placed attention on police leadership", Ms Rawlings-Blake said, but denied her decision was influenced by the union report.
Mr Davis, who is taking over immediately as interim police chief, praised his "friend" Mr Batts and said he was a "true reform commissioner".
Mayor Rawlings-Blake said Mr Davis would "bring accountability to police, hold officers who act out of line accountable for their actions".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:26:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd sentenced</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33456793#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Former AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd is sentenced in New Zealand to eight months of house detention for drug possession and making threats to kill.</Description>
        <MainBody>Phil Rudd, AC/DC drummer, sentenced to house detention
9 July 2015
From the section Asia
Rudd's lawyer has said he could lose millions in future earnings if convicted
Phil Rudd, a drummer with rock group AC/DC, has been sentenced in New Zealand to eight months in house detention for drug possession and making threats to kill.
Rudd, 61 and born in Australia, had originally denied the charges but changed his plea in April.
The Tauranga court heard he threatened to "take out" a former employee.
A subsequent police raid on his house in Tauranga found a stash of marijuana and methamphetamine.
His sentence will be served at his beachfront home in Tauranga, with Judge Thomas Ingram warning he would be jailed if he breached the conditions, New Zealand media reported.
Telephone threats
The court had heard how Rudd had fired several employees after the failure of his solo album in August last year.
AC/DC are touring New Zealand later this year, but Phil Rudd will not be taking part
Then in September, he telephoned an associate in Australia saying he wanted one of those former employees "taken care of".
In another call he offered the associate money and high-value goods, which the man believed would be in exchange for carrying out the request.
Rudd also called the victim of the threat, saying he was going to kill him, the court heard.
The drugs were found when police raided his home on 6 November.
Rudd's lawyer had said the threats were "just an angry phone call" and that a drug conviction would have serious final consequences for the drummer, meaning he could not travel to some countries to perform.
Judge Thomas Ingram dismissed this, though accepted that Rudd had reconciled with the victim and paid compensation.
Rudd is not currently a member of AC/DC, one of the world's biggest rock bands, and has not been invited to join them on their tour of New Zealand and Australia later this year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:56:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berlusconi convicted of bribery</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33452260#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Former Italian PM Silvio Berlusconi is found guilty of bribing a senator in 2006 in an attempt to bring down the then centre-left government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Silvio Berlusconi bribery trial: Ex-Italy PM convicted
8 July 2015
From the section Europe
Silvio Berlusconi lost his parliamentary immunity last year when he was expelled from the Senate over a tax fraud conviction
Former Italian PM Silvio Berlusconi has been found guilty of bribing a senator in 2006 in an attempt to bring down the then centre-left government.
A Naples court sentenced Berlusconi to three years in jail and banned him from holding public office for five years.
The four-times prime minister denied the charges.
He will not have to serve his sentence because a statute of limitations comes into effect later this year, before any appeal can be held.
The billionaire was accused of giving 3m euros (2.5m; $4m) in 2006 to Sergio De Gregorio, then a senator from the anti-corruption Italy of Values party, to switch to Berlusconi's People of Freedom party and thus undermine the government of the time.
The trial was held in Naples as it was the seat occupied by Mr De Gregorio.
Italy's former prime minister is appealing against a prison sentence for having sex with an under-age prostitute and abuse of office, and another for leaking a confidential police wiretap.
He was also found guilty of tax fraud last year - his first definitive conviction.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:32:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Robocall victim gets $230,000 payout</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-33442795#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Time Warner Cable is ordered to pay a woman almost $230,000 after a judge rules it harassed her with automated calls.</Description>
        <MainBody>Robocall victim to get big payout from Time Warner Cable
8 July 2015
From the section Technology
Unwanted, automated calls are illegal in the US
Time Warner Cable has been ordered to pay a woman $229,500 (150,000) after a judge ruled it had harassed her with automated calls.
Texas resident Araceli King received 153 computer-controlled "robocalls", which continued after she had asked the company to stop.
US district judge Alvin Hellerstein said Time Warner Cable had acted in a "particularly egregious" manner.
The company said it would review the ruling before deciding how to proceed.
Making unwanted automated calls is illegal in the US, and companies breaking the rules can face a fine of $1,500 for each call.
Mr Hellerstein said he had tripled the penalty for Time Warner because it had made 74 calls to Ms King after she had registered her complaint.
The judge said any company that "robodials the same person hundreds of times over many months without pausing to wonder why it cannot reach him" could not complain about the higher fine.
Crackdown
The US made it illegal to make unwanted automated calls in 2009.
Since then the Federal Trade Commission has announced a "crackdown" on the practice.
Time Warner Cable has around 15 million subscribers in the US
The law says marketers must have written permission from a person before robocalls can be made, although exceptions are made for surveys or if the subject matter is political or to do with a charity.
In June, online payment service PayPal updated its user policy to suggest that its US customers would have to agree to accept automated marketing calls and messages before backtracking over the issue.
The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) enforcement bureau chief Travis LeBlanc has said "customers are not required to consent to unwanted robocalls or robotexts".
UK complaints
On 2 July, the UK's Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) said it had received a record number of complaints about nuisance calls in the past year.
It received 180,188 complaints, of which 45% were about automated calls that played a recording down the telephone.
Consumer watchdog Which is running a campaign to make company executives accountable for the nuisance calls their firms make.
"Regulators, government and industry must work harder to cut off unwanted calls and texts that annoy millions of us every day," said the organisation's executive director Richard Lloyd.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:53:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China downfall spreads to Asia shares</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33456768#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Mainland Chinese shares continue to head lower on Thursday, leading the rest of Asia down as concerns over the market's steep slide spread.</Description>
        <MainBody>China downfall spreads to Asia shares
9 July 2015
From the section Business
Mainland Chinese shares continued to head lower on Thursday, leading the rest of Asia down as concerns over the market's steep slide spread.
The benchmark Shanghai Composite was down 3.6% to 3,380.31 points despite aggressive measures by regulators such as banning big investors from selling stocks to boost the flagging market.
Chinese shares have lost more than 30% of their value in the past month.
Hong Kong's Hang Seng index was down 0.5% to 23,369.23 in early trade.
The Chinese government continued to roll out more measures on Thursday by trying to ease margin loan requirements.
The China Banking Regulatory Commission (CBRC) said it would allow financial institutions to renegotiate maturity terms regarding lending, using stock as collateral, and allow banks to ease margin requirements for borrowers.
China's inflation data for June did little to boost sentiment for investors, with the pace of consumer inflation quickening to 1.4% from a year ago, beating market expectations of 1.3%.
China concerns spread
Japan's Nikkei 225 index was down 2.2% to 19,299.67 as investors bought the yen on concerns over China's stock market and worries over Greece's future in the eurozone.
Investors generally buy the yen as a safe bet in times of uncertainty and turmoil.
The dollar was at near a seven-week low hit against the safe-haven yen overnight at 120.815.
But a stronger yen is negative for Japanese exporters, as it erodes their earnings overseas.
In Australia, the S&amp;P/ASX 200 index was down 0.9% to 5,418.00 in early trade.
South Korea's benchmark Kospi index was lower by 1.4% to 1,988.73.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>S Carolina debates rebel flag removal</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33454759#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The South Carolina House rejects amendments to a bill that would remove the Confederate battle flag from the state capitol grounds.</Description>
        <MainBody>S Carolina House debates Confederate flag removal
9 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
The South Carolina House has rejected a series of amendments to a bill that would remove the Confederate battle flag from the state capitol grounds.
Republicans proposed dozens of changes to slow the passage of the bill, which overwhelmingly passed the state senate.
At a private meeting, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley urged fellow Republicans to remove the flag.
The backlash against the emblem grew when a gunman killed nine people at a Charleston church last month.
Dylann Roof, the 21-year-old charged with the killings, was pictured flying the flag.
It was originally the battle flag of the southern states in the American Civil War when they tried to break away.
The flag is seen by some as an icon of slavery and racism while others say it symbolises US heritage and history.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley supports efforts to remove the flag
Some of the amendments focused on replacing the flag with other less contentious symbols of Confederacy. Another proposed having voters decide whether the flag should come down.
However, some amendments appeared designed to make political points such as a plan to fly the US flag upside down over the capitol or a proposal to remove all monuments and memorials from the capitol building.
One Republican proposed replacing the flag with a white flag of surrender, to symbolise his party's stance.
"I don't have a picture, but it would look like this," Christopher Corley told the chamber, waving a small white flag.
Representative Mike Pitts alone submitted 54 amendments to the bill. Some of his amendments have already been withdrawn.
Since the church killings, a number of other US states have taken action to remove flags from state property.
And large nationwide retailers have cleared their shelves of items bearing the emblem.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:16:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope focuses on poor in Bolivia</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33456627#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis speaks of the need to protect the vulnerable from capitalism, as he continues his tour of Latin America's poorest countries.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis focuses on poor in Bolivia
9 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Pope Francis was greeted by children and President Evo Morales as he landed in Bolivia
Pope Francis is visiting Bolivia, the second leg of his tour of Latin America's three poorest countries.
After landing at La Paz airport, the pontiff spoke of the need to protect the most vulnerable in society from the impact of capitalism.
He was greeted by President Evo Morales, Bolivia's first indigenous leader, who gave Francis a ritual pouch with coca - a sacred leaf in the Andes.
The Pope flew in from Ecuador. He will also visit Paraguay.
'Double religion'
At the airport welcome ceremony, the pontiff praised Bolivia - a majority indigenous country - for encouraging the poor to be active citizens.
"Bolivia is making important steps towards including broad sectors in the country's economic, social and political life," he said.
Bolivia's national anthem was sung by President Evo Morales, an Aymara Indian, standing alongside Pope Francis
President Morales is a fan of Pope Francis, who he says shares many of his views on how capitalism leads to social inequalities, BBC regional analyst Candace Piette says.
But she says Mr Morales' government has for many years had an uneasy relationship with the Catholic Church.
After taking office in 2006, Mr Morales ordered the Bible and cross to be removed from the presidential palace - both symbols of colonial Spanish oppression.
A new constitution in 2009 made Bolivia a secular state, and Andean religious rituals replaced Catholic rites at official state ceremonies.
President Morales has said he is a Catholic but - like many Bolivians - he believes there is plenty of room for both Christianity and traditional belief.
"I remain convinced that we Bolivians have a double religion, double faith," he said in January.
Many of the faithful waited for hours in the bitter cold in their traditional dress for the arrival of the Pope
But Mr Morales' attitude to the church changed radically when Francis became pope. He visited him twice in Rome and invited him to come to Bolivia, our analyst says.
Before leaving for the lowland city of Santa Cruz, Pope Francis visited the site where the body of a Jesuit Bolivian priest was found.
The priest was tortured and murdered in 1980 during the military rule for defending the rights of Bolivia's mining community.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:04:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia vetoes Bosnia genocide motion</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33445772#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Russia vetoes a draft UN Security Council resolution describing the 1995 Srebrenica massacre of Muslim men and boys as "genocide".</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia vetoes UN move to call Srebrenica 'genocide'
8 July 2015
From the section Europe
Srebrenica was the worst massacre in Europe since World War Two
Russia has vetoed a United Nations Security Council resolution that would have described the Srebrenica massacre as "genocide".
Four other members of the council abstained while the remainder voted in favour.
The killing of some 8,000 Muslim men and boys in 1995 by Bosnian Serb troops was the worst massacre in Europe since World War Two.
The motion had angered Serbia, which rejects the term.
It had been drafted to mark the 20th anniversary of the atrocity, which came amid the bloody break-up of Yugoslavia into independent states.
During the Bosnian War, which saw Serbia-backed Bosnian Serb forces fighting the Muslim-led Bosnian government, thousands seeking shelter at what was supposed to be a UN refuge were slaughtered.
The resolution said that "acceptance of the tragic events at Srebrenica as genocide is a prerequisite for reconciliation".
But Russia's UN Ambassador Vitaly Churkin said adopting it "would be counter-productive, would lead to greater tension in the region".
The vote had been put back a day to allow the US and the UK - which drafted the resolution - to try to persuade Russia not to veto it.
The Serbian President, Tomislav Nikolic, called it a "great day" for his country, the AFP agency reported.
Serbia does not have a seat on the Security Council, and had asked ally Russia to block the resolution, warning it would be divisive.
The US ambassador to the UN, Samantha Power, said: "Russia's veto is heart-breaking for those families and it is a further stain on this council's record."
A UN tribunal at The Hague has already convicted numerous people of genocide in relation to the Srebrenica killings, but a formal recognition by the UN could compel individual states to pursue prosecutions.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:27:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Guinea ruler Camara charged</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33449813#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Former Guinea military ruler Moussa Dadis Camara is indicted for his role in a 2009 massacre in Conakry, his lawyer says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Guinea stadium massacre: Former ruler Camara indicted
9 July 2015
From the section Africa
Moussa Dadis Camara hopes to make a political comeback in Guinea during presidential elections due to be in October
Guinean former military ruler Moussa Dadis Camara has been indicted in over a 2009 massacre in Conakry, his lawyer has told AFP news agency.
More than 150 people were killed when security forces opened fire on thousands of anti-government protesters at the capital's main stadium.
Women there were raped and dozens of people were never seen again.
An inquiry was launched in 2010, after Capt Camara was ousted and fled to Burkina Faso, where he still lives.
More than 150 people were killed during the September 2009 protest against the military government
Capt Camara was indicted by magistrates who came from Guinea on Wednesday to question him about his alleged involvement in the September 2009 massacre, his lawyer Jean-Baptiste Jocamey Haba told AFP by telephone from Ouagadougou, the capital of Burkina Faso.
Capt Camara's Patriotic Front for Democracy and Development said the interrogation was a "purely political" reaction to his announcement that he intended to run for president in elections due in October.
Hundreds of victims have given evidence to the massacre inquiry, local and international rights organisations say.
Capt Camara seized power in 2008 when long-time leader Lansana Conte died.
Thirteen other members of the military government are facing charges in relation the massacre, in addition to eight people already indicted.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:20:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 20 die in Algeria clashes</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33455563#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>At least 22 people have died in clashes between Arabs and Berbers around the Algerian oasis city of Ghardaia, the state news agency says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ghardaia clashes: At least 22 dead in Algerian oasis city
8 July 2015
From the section Africa
Members of the Mozabite community protested in Algiers on Wednesday to call for better protection
At least 22 people have died in clashes between Arab and Berber communities around the Algerian oasis city of Ghardaia, the state news agency says.
The city has seen clashes for the last two years, with rivalry among communities for jobs, housing and land.
But the two days of clashes in Ghardaia and two nearby cities - Guerrara and Berianne - are the most violent yet.
President Abdelaziz Bouteflika convened an emergency meeting on Wednesday.
A statement by the president urged people in Ghardaia "to help to restore calm and to preserve the age-old bonds of brotherhood which have always marked the region".
Interior Minister Noureddine Bedoui arrived in Ghardaia, a Unesco world heritage site, earlier in the day.
Mozabites - members of the local Berber community - called for better protection in a protest in the capital, Algiers, 600km (373 miles) to the north.
"The situation is very serious," one Mozabite leader told AFP. "This is not just clashes any more, it's terrorism."
Algeria's official news agency, APS, said most of the deaths were from "projectiles". It is not known to which groups the dead belonged.
A cemetery belonging to Mozabites was desecrated in December 2013, leading to fighting between groups. At least a dozen people had been killed before violence flared up again this week, AP said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:24:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraq sentences IS militants to death</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33443096#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A court in Iraq has sentenced 24 suspected members of Islamic State (IS) to death for their role in the massacre of hundreds of soldiers in June 2014.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraq sentences Islamic State militants to death for Tikrit massacre
8 July 2015
From the section Middle East
Hundreds of bodies have been exhumed since government forces recaptured Tikrit in March
A court in Iraq has sentenced 24 suspected members of Islamic State (IS) to death for their role in the massacre of hundreds of soldiers in June 2014.
As many as 1,700 soldiers, most of them Shia Muslim recruits, were killed when the jihadist group overran the Camp Speicher military base near Tikrit.
IS posted graphic photos and video online documenting the atrocity.
Iraqi government forces arrested dozens of people suspected of involvement after recapturing Tikrit in March.
Forensic teams also began exhuming the remains of victims from mass graves in the area. So far more than 470 bodies have been found at four sites.
'Relieved'
The 24 Iraqi nationals sentenced to death by hanging on Wednesday by a court in Baghdad were charged with the killings and membership of a terrorist group.
All of the defendants pleaded not guilty, insisting they had not taken part in one of the worst atrocities committed in Iraq in recent times.
Islamic State filmed soldiers they captured in Tikrit, prior to their killing
They told the court that their confessions had been coerced under torture by Iraqi officers.
But within hours of the trial's start, the defendants had been convicted on the basis of what a spokesman for Iraq's Supreme Judicial Council described as strong evidence.
"We are relieved to see these criminals receiving the maximum punishment," Ali Abdul Hamza, whose brother was among the victims, told the Associated Press as he left the courtroom.
The sentences should now be sent to a higher court within a month for approval.
Another 604 suspects wanted in connection with the killings remained at large, the judiciary spokesman said.
Photos and videos published by IS at the time of what is now known as the "Speicher massacre" showed soldiers being loaded onto vehicles and then forced to lie face down on the ground at various locations before being shot dead.
Some bodies were pushed into the River Tigris, while others were buried in at least 12 mass graves that were discovered after government forces retook Tikrit.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:44:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Paris lets cyclists skip red lights</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33446899#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Cyclists in Paris are to be allowed to ride through red lights after tests showed the move would not lead to accidents.</Description>
        <MainBody>Paris to let cyclists skip red lights
8 July 2015
From the section Europe
Paris plans to triple the number of cyclists in the city by 2020
Cyclists in Paris are to be allowed to ride through red lights after tests showed the move would not lead to accidents.
Traffic lights for bicycles will be placed under the traffic lights for cars on some junctions.
The lights will indicate when bikes can either turn right or ride ahead - even when lights for cars are on red.
Paris, blighted by smog this year, is keen for more people to take to their bikes throughout the city.
The change would "help improve the flow of cycle traffic", the statement said.
The Paris mayor's office published a guide to how the lights will be implemented
Tests held in 2012 found that allowing the cyclists to move more freely cut down the chances of collisions with cars, including accidents involving the car's blind spot.
Where there are no traffic lights for cyclists, they must respect the main lights.
Despite the move, cyclists would not have priority on the roads and must cede to pedestrians and other road users where necessary.
Paris is looking to triple the amount of bicycle journeys in the city by 2020 - ensuring people use bikes for 15% of all journeys.
A city-wide network of bike paths will be created, and up to 10,000 new parking spaces for bikes will be installed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:53:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Piazza turned into huge Risk board</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/blogs-news-from-elsewhere-33444117#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Small Italian town will transform its main square into a board game.</Description>
        <MainBody>Linkedin
The town first turned its piazza into a huge version of the board game last summer
A small Italian town is transforming its main square into a giant Risk board for a two-day tournament, it's reported.
The piazza in Sant'Eufemia a Maiella, located deep within Italy's central Majella National Park, will be covered with a 650-sq-m (7,000-sq-ft) board as part of the event later this month, the local Il Centro website reports . It's billed as the biggest game of Risk in the world by the event's organisers . Artist Liberio Furlini spent 15 days painting the huge political map of the world used in the game. Super-sized playing pieces designed to fit with the gigantic board will be used by those taking part.
Risk is a strategy game where players try to occupy each territory on the board, thereby eliminating their competitors. The rules are being slightly simplified to allow more people to compete, but the tournament's winner will need to brush up on all the finer details, as they'll be offered a place at the national Risk championship.
"We have already seen 80 people sign up to take part from all over Italy," Mayor Francesco Crivelli tells Metro News 24 . And while the mayor is partial to a game himself, he might not fancy his chances at the tournament. "Usually I like to play using the green pieces, but I lose, I always lose," he tells the channel.
Risk, or Risiko in Italian, has become popular around the world since it was first released in the 1950s
Use #NewsfromElsewhere to stay up-to-date with our reports via Twitter .
Latest Posts
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:47:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NY Stock Exchange trading restarts</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33454460#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Trading on the New York Stock Exchange restarts after being suspended for almost four hours due to a technical fault.</Description>
        <MainBody>New York Stock Exchange re-opens after trading glitch
8 July 2015
From the section Business
Trading on the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) has restarted after being suspended for more than three hours due to a technical fault.
The NYSE has yet to give full details of the problem, but emphasised that it was not the result of a cyber hack.
Other exchanges, including Nasdaq, reported no problems and were trading normally.
Earlier, United Airlines and the Wall Street Journal's website reported major technical problems.
However, US Homeland Security said the issues appeared unrelated and were not the result of "nefarious" activity.
Shares were generally lower before the suspension, and continued to fall once full trading resumed.
The Dow Jones closed 1.5% lower, or 261 points, to 17,515, while the S&amp;P 500 shed 1.7%, or 34 points, at 2,046. The tech-rich Nasdaq, 1.8% lower, or 87 points, ended at 4,909.
Trading was halted just after 1130am ET, prompting a NYSE statement: "We're currently experiencing a technical issue that we're working to resolve as quickly as possible.
"We will be providing further updates as soon as we can, and are doing our utmost to produce a swift resolution, communicate thoroughly and transparently, and ensure a timely and orderly market re-open."
The NYSE tweeted later that it was an internal technical issue, not a cyber attack.
The White House said that President Barack Obama was briefed, and the Securities and Exchange Commission said it was "closely monitoring the situation".
'Not nefarious'
The problem followed technical glitches at WSJ.com, the Wall Street Journal's website, and at United Airlines.
United Airlines said that a computer error had forced it to ground its flights in the US for the second time in recent weeks. The carrier blamed a "network connectivity issue" for the latest fault.
More than 800 United flights were delayed and about 60 were cancelled, but services were now returning to normal.
WSJ.com is now operating normally.
US Homeland Security Secretary Jeh Johnson said the issues reported by United and the NYSE were apparently not related to "nefarious" activity.
"I have spoken to the CEO of United, Jeff Smisek, myself. It appears from what we know at this stage that the malfunctions at United and the stock exchange were not the result of any nefarious actor," Mr Johnson said.
He was less clear about the problems at WSJ.com, but noted that the site "is in fact up again".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:56:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US reports big jump in heroin use</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33446695#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Heroin use in the US has surged in the past decade as experts say people using opioid painkillers are increasingly turning to heroin as a cheaper high.</Description>
        <MainBody>Heroin use jumps in US as painkiller addicts switch drugs
8 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Heroin is seen as a cheaper alternative to opiod painkillers
Heroin use in the US has surged in the past decade as experts say people using opioid painkillers are increasingly turning to heroin as a cheaper high.
The number of heroin users rose by 63% between 2002 and 2013, the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) reported on Tuesday.
Use among white Americans was mostly responsible for the jump, the CDC said.
However, the report found increases among people of all income levels and most age groups.
"Heroin use is increasing rapidly across nearly all demographic groups, and with that increase, we are seeing a dramatic rise in deaths," CDC chief Tom Frieden said.
Local police departments across the country have been dealing with an uptick in heroin overdoses in recent years, and many police officers have begun carrying life-saving medication to prevent deaths.
The CDC reported that over 8,000 people died from a heroin-involved overdose in 2013, nearly twice the number of deaths seen just two years earlier.
Federal officials cited a number of factors causing the rise in heroin use.
As authorities have cracked down on prescription drug abuse in recent years, users who have become addicted to the pills have switched to heroin. The drug is often cheaper and more easily available.
The amount of heroin being brought into the US has also increased, driving down the cost of the street drug.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:22:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colombian rebels call ceasefire</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33450816#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Colombia's Farc rebels call a one-month unilateral ceasefire starting on 20 July, but the government says more needs to be done.</Description>
        <MainBody>Colombia Farc rebels call unilateral ceasefire
8 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
The ceasefire will come into force on 20 July, the Farc announced in Cuba
Colombia's Farc rebels have announced a one-month unilateral ceasefire.
The Farc has been taking part in peace talks with the Colombian government since 2012, but violence has increased in recent weeks.
The Farc's chief negotiator at the talks in Cuba, Ivan Marquez, said he hoped the ceasefire, starting on 20 July, could lead to a bilateral truce.
The government welcomed the move but gave no sign it would do likewise and said the rebels needed to do more.
"We appreciate the gesture of a unilateral ceasefire by the Farc but more is needed, especially concrete commitments to speed up the negotiations," President Juan Manuel Santos said on Twitter (in Spanish).
For his part, Mr Marquez said the truce would "create favourable conditions in order to advance with the opposing side toward a bilateral and definitive ceasefire."
Hostilities with the Colombian military have escalated recently
Four countries helping to facilitate the peace talks - Cuba, Norway, Chile and Venezuela - issued a call on Tuesday for a de-escalation in the violence.
A previous Farc ceasefire was called in December, but clashes resumed in April with the killing of 11 soldiers and subsequent bombing raids on rebel positions.
Farc suspended that unilateral ceasefire on 22 May.
Since the ceasefire ended, several dozen rebels and soldiers have been killed.
In June, the group blew up an oil pipeline, which contaminated water and left at least 16,000 people without supplies in the municipality of Catatumbo in the north.
The talks in Havana, which began in November 2012, are aimed at ending more than 50 years of conflict. More than 200,000 people have been killed since hostilities started in 1964.
Negotiations have continued despite the violence, and agreement has been reached on several points.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:46:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guatemala ex-ruler 'unfit for trial'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33438374#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A former Guatemalan general, Efrain Rios Montt, who ruled the country briefly in the eighties has been found mentally incapable of standing trial for genocide.</Description>
        <MainBody>Guatemala: Ex-ruler Rios Montt found unfit for trial
8 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Efrain Rios Montt's lawyers say he was unaware of the army's killings of indigenous people
A former Guatemalan general, Efrain Rios Montt, who ruled the country briefly in the 1980s, has been found mentally incapable of standing trial.
He had been facing charges of genocide during one of the most brutal periods in Guatemala's civil war.
Doctors said he was not able to understand any charges against him.
The medical report will affect two separate trials where he is charged with ordering the murder of hundreds of farmers and over 1,000 Mayan Indians.
General  Rios Montt was found guilty of genocide and war crimes two years ago, and sentenced to 80 years in prison.
The main charges were that he and his former intelligence chief ordered the army to carry out 15 massacres of Ixil Maya indigenous people in Quiche in northern Guatemala, in which around 1,700 Indians were killed.
However, a high court then threw out the charges on procedural grounds and ordered a retrial.
Another trial began in January but ended after the judge was rejected for having made public opinions about genocide in a student thesis.
A new trial was set for July. This may now not take place because of the medical examiner's report declaring the ex-leader mentally incompetent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:31:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Buhari pledge to Chibok activists</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33446305#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Nigeria's new president meets Bring Back Our Girls campaigners and pledges troops for an anti-Boko Haram force will be in place by the end of July.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigeria's Buhari meets Chibok girls campaigners
8 July 2015
From the section Africa
Campaigners marched through the capital on their way to meet the president
Nigeria's President Muhammadu Buhari has for the first time met those campaigning for the release of more than 200 girls abducted by Islamist Boko Haram militants last year.
His predecessor, Goodluck Jonathan, declined to meet the Bring Back Our Girls activists.
Mr Buhari promised them that troops for a regional force to fight the militants would be in place by the end of July.
The kidnap of the girls from a school in Chibok sparked global outrage.
The mass abduction sparked one of the biggest social media campaigns of 2014, with the Twitter hashtag #BringBackOurGirls being used more than five million times.
Boko Haram has stepped up attacks since Mr Buhari took office in May vowing to tackle the insurgency "head on".
Boko Haram released a video appearing to show the girls in May 2014
In the last week, more than 220 people have been killed in suspected militant attacks.
The Nigerian military has said it has arrested "the mastermind" behind two recent attacks on the northern towns of Jos and Zaria in which almost 70 people were killed.
'How the mighty have fallen'
Addressing members of the Bring Back Our Girls campaign group and the media, the president said that the government was doing all it could to tackle insecurity, but did not refer directly to the 219 Chibok girls abducted in April 2014.
Earlier, the activists had marched through the capital, Abuja, on their way meet Mr Buhari at his official residence.
A representative for the Chibok girls meets Mr Buhari on Wednesday
Relatives of some of the missing girls were also present at the meeting
One of the founders of the Bring Back Our Girls campaign group told the BBC that "there was no time left" for the government to act.
"The rescue of the Chibok girls would be the strongest statement this government could make for having respect for the sanctity and dignity of every Nigerian life," said Oby Ezekwesili.
In his speech, Mr Buhari spoke of the "paradox" of Nigeria asking its neighbours for help, despite itself providing help to so many other countries in the past.
"How the mighty have fallen," he said.
Chibok abductions: What we know a year on
The president criticised the previous government's "incompetence" in dealing with the kidnapping and the broader Boko Haram insurgency.
Nigeria, Chad, Cameroon, Niger and Benin are all expected to provide troops for the 7,500-strong regional task force to tackle Boko Haram.
The force will be led by Nigeria but have its headquarters in the Chadian capital, N'Djamena.
This year, Chad, Cameroon and Niger have been helping Nigeria recapture territory from the insurgents.
The Chibok schoolgirls have not been seen since last May when Boko Haram released a video of around 130 of them gathered together reciting the Koran .
Some of those who were kidnapped have been forced to join the militant group, the BBC was told last week .
Amnesty International estimates that at least 2,000 women and girls have been abducted by Boko Haram since the start of 2014.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:04:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nigeria church accused over collapse</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33448236#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A church run by the popular Nigerian evangelist TB Joshua should be prosecuted after one of its buildings collapsed, killing more than 100 people, a coroner rules.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigeria church run by TB Joshua 'should be prosecuted'
8 July 2015
From the section Africa
More than 100 people - mostly visitors from South Africa - died when a church guesthouse collapsed last year
A church run by the popular Nigerian evangelist TB Joshua should be prosecuted after the collapse of one of its buildings, a coroner has ruled.
A multi-storey church hostel collapsed last September in Lagos killing 116 people, many of them South Africans.
The authorities said it had more floors than its foundation could hold.
"The church was culpable because of criminal negligence resulting in the death of the victims," coroner Oyetade Komolafe said at the inquest in Lagos.
Mr Komolafe said Mr Joshua's Synagogue, Church of All Nations (SCOAN), had not obtained proper approval before putting up the structure.
Those who built the hostel should also be investigated, he said.
TB Joshua, referred to by his followers as a "prophet", had blamed last year's incident on a small plane which he said had been circling the building, a claim dismissed by the court.
Straight after the building collapsed, emergency teams complained that church officials had blocked access to the site.
The coroner also criticised the fact that the preacher had not appeared as a witness during the inquest.
"Among the individuals and organisations summoned, only Prophet TB Joshua refused to testify," the AFP news agency quotes Mr Komolafe as saying.
The BBC's Will Ross in Lagos says the preacher went to another court arguing that the coroner did not have the right to summon him.
Mr Joshua's services, at a mega-church in Lagos's Ikotun district, are known for attracting thousands of people.
Followers in Nigeria and abroad believe he has the gifts of healing and prophecy.
Our correspondent says the coroner's verdict is really a recommendation and now it will now be up to Lagos state's director of public prosecutions to decide what legal action to take.
TB Joshua
Founded Synagogue, Church of All Nations in the 1990s
Runs Christian television station Emmanuel TV
The ministry professes to heal all manner of illnesses
Controversially this includes HIV/Aids
Known as the "Prophet" by his followers
Tours Africa, the US, the UK and South America
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:40:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China-Turkey relationship strained</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-33440998#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The treatment of Chinese Uighurs spurs flag-burning in Turkey and a China warning for tourists, writes the BBC's Selin Gerit in Istanbul.</Description>
        <MainBody>China-Turkey relationship strained over Uighurs
By Selin Girit BBC News, Istanbul
9 July 2015
From the section China
Protests in Turkey have seen Chinese flags being burned
Burnt Chinese flags, attacks on Chinese restaurants, alleged attacks on tourists who were mistaken for being Chinese and protests across the country.
For the last 10 days anti-Chinese sentiment has been on the rise in Turkey.
Turkish Muslims and Uighurs from the far western region of China share ethnicity and have close cultural and religious ties.
The protests started following reports that Uighurs in China had been banned from fasting during the holy month of Ramadan.
Muslims worldwide observe Ramadan, when the faithful abstain from eating and drinking during daylight hours.
Turkish supporters of Chinese Uighurs have been spurred by reports of Ramadan controls in Xinjiang
"Our people have been saddened over the news that Uighur Turks have been banned from fasting or carrying out other religious duties in the Xinjiang region," Turkey's foreign ministry said in a statement last week.
In response, China said it fully respects the freedom of Muslim religious beliefs and the accusations that religious rites had been banned in Xinjiang this Ramadan were "completely at odds with the facts" and exaggerated by the western media.
It said: "No state organ, public organization or individual may compel citizens to believe in religion or no religion. They may not discriminate against religious citizens and non-religious citizens."
Cihan Yavuz's Chinese restaurant, Happy China, was attacked by an angry mob in Istanbul last week.
"People are scared to come here, scared of another attack," he said.
Chinese tourists do not seem deterred from visiting despite rising tension against their country and a travel warning
Cihan Yavuz's Chinese restaurant Happy China was attacked by an angry mob
"If people want to protest the Chinese government, they can hold demonstrations in front of its embassy. It's not right to use violence for the sake of protesting," he said.
There were further reports of disturbances in Istanbul on Saturday as the Grey Wolves - the youth wing of the far right nationalist party MHP - held a march.
Chinese tourist guide Miray Hamit said four or five men with knives attacked a tourist in her group.
"They asked us where we were from and when we said we were Chinese they started hitting one of us.
"A Turkish tourist guide and I intervened to stop the attack. We all got scared. One of us got injured, though nothing serious thankfully. I got hit too," she said.
Miray Hamit thought the attackers were not necessarily affiliated with the Grey Wolves rally and could have just been passing.
'We trust Turkey'
Turkish media though reported a group of Korean tourists believed to be Chinese were attacked during the Grey Wolves' protests, an allegation they deny.
The head of Grey Wolves in Istanbul, Ahmet Yigit Yildirim, alleged the scuffles that took place were actually between the police and protesters and no harm was done to any tourists. He said no complaint was made against them.
"The safety of every tourist coming to our country is our responsibility. We can't tolerate any sort of violence," he said.
The head of the Grey Wolves says tourists were not harmed in its anti-Beijing protest
Police sources were unable to speak to the BBC. However, the Korean consulate in Istanbul said they had not received any complaints or reports of any attacks against Korean citizens in the city.
In the Turkish media the leader of MHP, Devlet Bahceli, hinted at the possibility that a Korean may have been confused with a Chinese.
But Chinese tourists do not seem deterred by the rising anti-China sentiment in Turkey.
"We are aware of what's going on. But we didn't encounter any problems. We trust Turkey. Turkish people have been very friendly to us," tourist Lucky Zhang said.
This week, the Chinese government issued travel advice to its citizens travelling to Turkey and warned them against getting too close to protests or filming them.
Who are the Uighurs?
Uighurs are ethnically Turkic Muslims
They make up about 45% of the Xinjiang region's population; 40% are Han Chinese
China re-established control in 1949 after crushing short-lived state of East Turkestan
Since then, there has been large-scale immigration of Han Chinese and Uighurs fear erosion of their culture
Xinjiang is officially designated an autonomous region within China, like Tibet to its south
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:58:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Malaysia raid in PM-linked inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33439788#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Malaysian police raid the office of a state investment fund as part of an inquiry into corruption claims involving Prime Minister Najib Razak.</Description>
        <MainBody>Malaysia fund raided in Najib Razak 'corruption inquiry'
8 July 2015
From the section Asia
Police checked documents and took away computers in the raid in Kuala Lumpur
The authorities in Malaysia have raided the office of a state investment fund as part of investigations into claims of corruption involving Prime Minister Najib Razak.
Police spent hours checking documents at the 1MDB fund's Kuala Lumpur office.
Mr Najib denies allegations that nearly $700m were transferred to his personal bank accounts from the fund.
On Tuesday officials froze six accounts as part of the inquiry. The account holders were not identified.
But the country's attorney general has since clarified that none of the accounts frozen were ones allegedly held by Mr Najib.
Najib Razak is considering taking legal action over the allegations
The 1MDB fund said it was co-operating with the police investigation.
"We can confirm that a number of officials from the task force, conducting an inquiry into 1MDB, visited our offices today," it said in a statement.
"They were provided with a number of documents and materials to aid with the investigations currently taking place."
The fund, set up by Mr Najib in 2009 and still chaired by him, denies giving any money to the prime minister.
Meanwhile, in a BBC interview, Malaysia's former leader Mahathir Mohamed called on Mr Najib to show public proof that his assets are legal.
Correspondents say he is facing the biggest crisis of his political career - pressure has been mounting since the Wall Street Journal published a detailed report last week. He was already under fire over his leadership, particularly from Mr Mahathir.
Mr Najib has previously issued a statement on Facebook, saying that the various allegations made against him are "unsubstantiated" and "outrageous".
He accuses Mr Mahathir of trying to topple him and describes his former mentor's claim that 42bn ringgits ($11bn) have gone missing from the fund as "reckless".
"These are audited debts backed by 51bn ringgits [in] audited assets." Mr Najib said in his Facebook post.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:26:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Belgium rescues 200 Syria Christians</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33439875#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Some 240 people, mainly Christians, have been brought out of Syria's second city of Aleppo and taken to Belgium in a secret, two-month operation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria conflict: Belgium rescues 200 Aleppo Christians
8 July 2015
From the section Europe
Before the war, Aleppo had one of the biggest Christian communities in the Middle East
Some 240 people, mainly Christians, have been brought out of Syria's second city of Aleppo and taken to Belgium, the government in Brussels says.
All the families had fled their homes and were at risk of repeated human rights abuse, a spokesman told the BBC.
Civil society groups helped take the families to safety in Lebanon.
Aleppo has been devastated by three years of fierce fighting between Syrian government forces, rebels and jihadist militants.
Before the war, it had a Christian population of around 160,000, one of the biggest in the Middle East.
The refugees, who included Yazidis as well as Christians, were moved out along the only open road from Aleppo to the Lebanese border.
The operation took place over two months and amid great secrecy. Belgium is one of several European countries that have come under pressure to help Christians and other religious minorities in Syria threatened with persecution.
"We did it via civil society organisations which could get them out of there," a foreign ministry spokesman said.
Few other details have been revealed, but the spokesman said some of the families had connections with people already in Belgium.
They were met on the Lebanese border by representatives from the Belgian embassy in Beirut with the help of the NGOs and have now all arrived in Belgium.
The families are now expected to be granted asylum in Belgium.
Belgium has until now only offered asylum to Syrian refugees through the United Nations, national media report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 13:01:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italy raids 'mafia crime family'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33441100#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Italian police say they have seized more than €1.6 bn ($1.76 bn) in assets from five Sicilian siblings thought to have links to the mafia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy police raids 'mafia crime family' in Sicily
8 July 2015
From the section Europe
The raid is one of the largest of its kind carried out, Italian police say
Italian police say they have seized more than 1.6 bn ($1.76 bn) in assets from five Sicilian siblings suspected of links to the mafia.
The five are thought to have been helped by the criminal group to secure public construction contracts.
Police in the regional capital Palermo say it is one of the largest raids they have ever carried out.
Analysts say Sicily's Cosa Nostra and other mafia groups have expanded their activities during Italy's recession.
Among the assets seized are bank accounts, property and furniture.
The five - three brothers and two sisters - are all in their 60s and 70s.
They worked as labourers in the early 1980s but went on to become billionaires, Italian media reported.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:13:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kurdish fighters 'retake Syria town'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33450511#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Kurdish-led fighters say they have reclaimed a town from Islamic State close to the group's northern Syrian stronghold of Raqqa.</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State conflict: Kurds reclaim Ain Issa in Syria
8 July 2015
From the section Middle East
Ain Issa is back in Kurdish fighters' control, two days after it fell to IS
Kurdish-led fighters say they have reclaimed a town from Islamic State close to the group's northern Syrian stronghold of Raqqa.
Fighters from IS seized the town of Ain Issa on Monday, but a statement by the Kurdish Popular Protection Units (YPG) said they had now taken it back.
They were supported by a female brigade, the YPJ and, the AFP agency said, by US airstrikes.
The town, only 50km (30 miles) north of Raqqa, is of strategic importance.
It is at an intersection of the main roads from Raqqa to other areas IS controls in Aleppo province, to the west, and Hassakeh province, to the east.
The UK-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights also confirmed Ain Issa was back in Kurdish fighters' hands.
In recent weeks, IS has launched several deadly counter-attacks against the Kurds.
The jihadist group had until then suffered a series of defeats in areas along the Turkish border since being forced to withdraw from the town of Kobane in January.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:48:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Yemeni soldiers killed in air strike</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33443092#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of soldiers have been killed in an air strike by a Saudi-led coalition on an army base in southern Yemen, reports say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen crisis: Dozens of soldiers killed in air strike
8 July 2015
From the section Middle East
Some reports said troops loyal to the exiled president were killed when a base in the south was hit in error
Dozens of soldiers have been killed in a Saudi-led coalition air strike on an army base in southern Yemen.
One military source said the soldiers were loyal to the exiled president and that the facility was hit in error.
But another source claimed the strike was called in to stop the soldiers defecting to the Houthi rebel movement.
More than 3,000 people have been killed since the coalition began an air campaign in March to drive back the rebels and restore the government.
On Tuesday, the UN announced that at least 1,528 civilians were among the dead.
Another one million civilians have been displaced by the conflict and more than 80% of Yemen's 25 million people now need some form of humanitarian aid.
'Error'
The incident in which the soldiers died reportedly took place on Tuesday night at the headquarters of the 23rd Mechanised Brigade in al-Abr, Hadramawt province, near the border with Saudi Arabia.
Half of those killed in air strikes and fighting on the ground since March have been civilians
A military source told the Spanish news agency Efe that coalition aircraft bombed the base, used by forces loyal to President Abdrabbuh Mansour Hadi, while attempting to stop rebel forces taking control of a nearby border crossing.
The source said that at least 70 soldiers were killed and 200 others wounded.
Efe quoted a statement by army chief Gen Mohammed Ali al-Maqdisi as saying that the strikes had been carried out "in error" and caused fatalities.
However, another military source told the AFP news agency that the coalition had intervened when dozens of soldiers at the base "defected and announced their support" for the Houthis, triggering clashes with pro-government troops.
At least 30 soldiers were killed, and armoured vehicles and troop carriers were destroyed or damaged, before the situation was brought under control, he added.
Two days ago, more than 170 people - most of them civilians - were killed and dozens wounded in coalition air strikes and clashes across Yemen.
The coalition bombardment has so far failed to defeat the rebels and allied army units loyal to ousted former president Ali Abdullah Saleh, who forced President Hadi to flee the country at the end of March as they advanced on Aden.
Mr Hadi had taken refuge in the city the previous month after the Houthis consolidated their control of Sanaa and placed him under effective house arrest.
'Deteriorating by the day'
On Tuesday, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights expressed deep concern about the situation in Yemen.
There are shortages of food, water, fuel and medicine
Spokeswoman Cecile Pouilly said its team on the ground had been able to document human rights violations, and abuses and violations of international humanitarian law, by all parties to the conflict.
They included abduction, ill-treatment, restrictions on freedom of expression and peaceful assembly, and attacks against humanitarian workers, medical staff and journalists, she added.
Basic public services are also collapsing, with shortages of medicine, essential medical supplies and fuel now at what Ms Pouilly called "critical levels".
Antoine Grand, head of the International Committee of the Red Cross in Yemen, said the situation was "catastrophic in general" and  "deteriorating by the day".
The UN also said on Tuesday that it had received only 13% of the $1.6bn (1bn) needed for its aid operation in Yemen since launching an appeal last month. Saudi Arabia has pledged $274m, but none of the money has yet materialised.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:47:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Budget debate over living wage pledge</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-33456160#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>George Osborne's Budget is to be debated by MPs after his pledge for a National Living Wage pledge sparked a political row.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harman: Families will still suffer
In a surprise announcement at the end of his speech, Mr Osborne said workers aged over 25 would be entitled to a "national living wage" from next April, to soften the impact of in-work benefit cuts.
The current minimum wage, which applies to those aged over 21, is 6.50. Those entitled to the "living wage" will get 7.20 and that will rise to 9 an hour by 2020. Labour had vowed to increase the minimum wage to 8 by 2020 during the general election campaign.
The move is expected to boost the wages of six million people but may cause firms to recruit more under-25s, who will be on a lower rate, according to the Office for Budget Responsibility.
The Treasury confirmed the measure would apply to both the public and private sectors.
The Local Government Association said it welcomed the move, but warned it would add a "potential upward pressure" to council budgets and said it expected local authorities to be compensated.
Ms Kendall attacked the policy on Twitter , saying it lagged behind the amount promoted by the Living Wage Foundation .
Ms Cooper, who claimed women would be hit harder than men by the measures in the Budget, said the new rate should "certainly not" be called a living wage.
Shadow health secretary Andy Burnham - who is also bidding to become Labour leader - said he would have paid the rate to all workers, accusing the government of "age discrimination in pay".
Business groups gave a mixed reaction to the National Living Wage pledge, with the Institute of Directors saying it was "time for companies to increase pay" but the CBI saying the government was taking "a big gamble" on wage increases that industry might not be able to deliver.
The Living Wage Foundation director Rhys Moore said the proposed 9 rate was a "massive victory" for campaigners, but that it was "effectively a higher national minimum wage and not a living wage", due to the different ways the two rates are calculated.
The TUC welcomed the announcement but said Mr Osborne was "giving with one hand taking with the other" and "massive cuts in support for working people will hit families with children hardest".
Mr Osborne announced that the 26,000 benefit cap - the amount one household can claim in a year - would be cut to 23,000 in London and 20,000 in the rest of the country.
The government will also make local authority and housing association tenants in England who earn more than 30,000 - or 40,000 in London - pay up to the market rent, but rents in the social housing sector will be reduced by 1% a year for the next four years.
The chancellor unveiled "just under half" of the 37bn in cuts he says are needed to clear the deficit, with the remainder to come from cuts to government departments to be announced in the autumn.
George Osborne was delivering his seventh Budget
Work and Pensions Secretary cheers the National Living Wage announcement
There was standing room only in the House of Commons
The chancellor announced an estimated 4.5bn cut to the 30bn-a-year tax credits system, which tops up the wages of low-paid workers, significantly reducing the amount someone can earn before they start losing benefit money.
Support for children through tax credits and universal credits will also be limited to two children, affecting children born after April 2017 unless the third child is the result of twins, triplets or other multiple birth.
Among Budget reaction, UKIP MP Douglas Carswell said it might become "politically unsustainable" to keep public sector pay rises frozen at 1% for four years if the economy grew.
But he welcomed cuts to tax credits, saying "we've got to unravel the disastrous system that Gordon Brown created" where public money subsidises big firms paying low wages.
The SNP's economy spokesman and deputy leader, Stewart Hosie, said the Budget would hit the "the poorest and the most vulnerable" and do nothing to improve productivity or encourage innovation.
A Lib Dem spokesman said: "Amongst the gimmicks and giveaways, the chancellor has hidden four more years of pain, austerity, and cuts."
How will you be affected by the chancellor's summer budget? Email haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk with your story.
Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:03:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Child sexual abuse inquiry to open</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33442588#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The independent inquiry into historical child sexual abuse in England and Wales is to open nearly a year after it was first announced.</Description>
        <MainBody>Historical child sexual abuse inquiry to open
9 July 2015
From the section UK
Justice Lowell Goddard will set out the guiding principles of the inquiry
The independent inquiry into historical child sexual abuse in England and Wales will open later, nearly a year after it was first announced.
It will examine how public bodies handled their duty of care to protect children from abuse.
Justice Lowell Goddard, who chairs the inquiry, will summarise how it will be run, including timescales and the areas of public life that will be examined.
The inquiry was first announced by Home Secretary Theresa May in July 2014.
It followed claims of a high-level cover-up of child sex abuse involving public figures, including politicians.
Justice Goddard, a New Zealand High Court judge, is the third person named to chair the inquiry; her two predecessors resigned over concerns about their links with the establishment.
Baroness Butler-Sloss, the first inquiry chairwoman, resigned a week after it was set up.
This followed calls for her to quit because her late brother, Sir Michael Havers, had been attorney general in the 1980s.
Her replacement, the then Lord Mayor of London Fiona Woolf, stood down on 31 October amid concerns over her links to former Home Secretary Lord Brittan.
What are the allegations?
In July last year, Labour MP Simon Danczuk called on Leon Brittan to say what he knew about paedophile allegations passed to him when he was home secretary in the 1980s.
The files were given to Lord Brittan, who died in January, by the late Conservative MP Geoffrey Dickens, a long-standing campaigner against child abuse.
Mr Dickens's son has said the files - now missing - contained "explosive" paedophile allegations about powerful and famous figures, including politicians.
Since Mr Danczuk's comments brought the so-called "Dickens dossier" to the fore, the focus has moved to the wider issue of how historical child sex abuse allegations were dealt with by public bodies and other institutions across the country.
Previously there had been calls for an overarching investigation into historical abuse claims in the wake of revelations that TV entertainer Jimmy Savile abused hundreds of victims at hospitals, children's homes and schools.
Read more on the "Dickens dossier" and other ongoing inquiries
In February it was announced Justice Goddard had been chosen to lead the inquiry because she was "as removed as possible from the organisations and institutions that might become the focus of the inquiry", Mrs May said.
The inquiry, which was given statutory powers and a new panel, will investigate whether "public bodies and other non-state institutions have taken seriously their duty of care to protect children from sexual abuse in England and Wales".
Justice Goddard has decided abuse victims will not sit on her advisory panel, but there will be a separate Victims and Survivors Consultative Panel and the names of its members will also be made public in her opening announcement.
Some of those who have been abused are waiting to find out how and when they will be able to give their testimonies, BBC home affairs correspondent Tom Symond says.
"The inquiry has been criticised for not making clear what support they will be given," our correspondent added.
The panel comprises Prof Alexis Jay of Strathclyde University, Drusilla Sharpling of the police inspectorate, Prof Malcolm Evans of Bristol University, and child protection barrister Ivor Frank.
Justice Goddard, who has previously led an inquiry into police handling of child abuse cases in her own country, hopes to complete the job within five years.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:33:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Microsoft to cut 7,800 more jobs</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33448207#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Microsoft cuts 7,800 jobs and takes a $7.6bn writedown as it reorganises its mobile phone unit following last year's purchase of Nokia's business.</Description>
        <MainBody>Microsoft targets mobile phone unit as 7,800 more jobs go
8 July 2015
Microsoft bought Nokia's mobile phone business last year
Microsoft is shedding another 7,800 jobs as it reorganises its Nokia mobile phone unit.
The move represents a massive shift in strategy for Microsoft since it purchased Nokia's mobile phone business for 5.44bn ($7.5bn; 4.5bn) last year.
Microsoft axed 18,000 jobs from the unit last July - the deepest cuts in the company's history.
The technology giant will also write down the value of the Nokia deal by $7.6bn.
Microsoft currently has about 118,000 employees worldwide. A statement from the government in Finland, were Nokia is based, said the job losses would include some 2,300 posts in the country.
The statement said the government was "disappointed with Microsoft's decision" and called a special ministerial meeting to consider assistance for those affected. "Loss of so many jobs is very sad for the whole society and for individuals affected," it said.
Microsoft said in a statement that it would "restructure the company's phone hardware business to better focus and align resources".
Although still strong in the software market for personal computers, the company is faces strong competition in the fight to establish its mobile handset operation. This market is dominated by devices powered by Google's Android system or Apple's iOS.
A survey by research firm IDC said Microsoft's Windows was expected to capture just 3.2% of the global smartphone market this year.
'Reinvention'
In a memo to staff, the company's chief executive Satya Nadella said: "I am committed to our first-party devices including phones. However, we need to focus our phone efforts in the near term while driving reinvention.
"We are moving from a strategy to grow a standalone phone business to a strategy to grow and create a vibrant Windows ecosystem that includes our first-party device family."
Microsoft is due to start rolling out Windows 10 later this month, introducing a new operating system that can be used to power not only personal computers but a range of mobile devices.
Last month, Microsoft announced a shakeup of top management including the departure of Stephen Elop, the former Nokia chief who joined the US tech company as part of the acquisition.
Analysis: Rory Cellan-Jones, BBC technology correspondent
Soon after the former Microsoft executive Stephen Elop became chief executive of Nokia, he wrote a memo to staff warning that the ailing company and its Symbian operating system was on a burning platform.
His solution was to jump on to another platform, the Windows Phone operating system, and eventually to sell the whole business to Microsoft. The alliance of the Windows Phone software with the Nokia hardware was supposed to create a powerful third force in the smartphone market, providing consumers with an attractive alternative to Android and Apple phones.
But now this platform too is burning, and Microsoft's $7.3bn investment in Nokia along with its smartphone has gone up in flames. Stephen Elop has already left and now nearly 8,000 employees, many of them former Nokia staff, will follow him out of the business.
Microsoft says it will now change direction, creating an "ecosystem" which will see Windows phones built by other manufacturers alongside its own handsets.
The company which dominated the desktop computer era has never been a major force in mobile computing. Microsoft describes itself as "the leading platform and productivity company for the mobile-first, cloud-first world" - but that platform still needs some work.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:00:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Computer glitch grounds aeroplanes</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-33449693#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A computing fault forces United Airlines to ground its flights for two hours, its second major IT glitch in two months.</Description>
        <MainBody>United Airlines jets grounded by computer router glitch
8 July 2015
From the section Technology
Thousands of United Airlines passengers have suffered delays because of the latest fault
A computer fault has forced United Airlines to ground its flights in the US for the second time in recent weeks.
The firm blamed a "network connectivity issue" for the latest fault .
The two-hour long issue caused delays to more than 90 of its aircrafts, according to the FlightAware website.
The airline had to enforce a shorter flight ban on 2 June after incorrect data appeared in its flight planning system .
Shares in the firm fell more than 1.5% in morning's trade.
The cybersecurity blogger Brian Krebs tweeted that the issue had been caused by a computer router malfunction rather than a cyber attack or sabotage, a fact that was later confirmed by United itself .
Several Twitter users posted photos of blank United Airlines airport screens
United is not the only carrier to have suffered such an IT-related setback over the past few months.
In April, American Airlines had to ground dozens of its jets after a flight plan tablet app, used by its pilots and co-pilots, stopped working.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:40:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Osborne unveils National Living Wage</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-33437115#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>George Osborne unveils billions in welfare cuts but springs a Budget surprise with a National Living Wage of £9 an hour by 2020.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harman: Families will still suffer
Unveiling the first Conservative Budget since 1996, Mr Osborne said the UK economy today was "fundamentally stronger than it was five years ago", with living standards rising strongly.
And his Budget was "a plan for Britain for the next five years to keep moving us from a low wage, high tax, high welfare economy; to the higher wage, lower tax, lower welfare country we intend to create".
In a surprise announcement at the end of his speech, he said workers aged over 25 would be entitled to a "national living wage" from next April, to soften the impact of in-work benefit cuts.
The current minimum wage, which applies to those aged over 21, is 6.50. Those entitled to the "living wage" will get 7.20 and that will rise to 9 an hour by 2020. Labour had vowed to increase the minimum wage to 8 by 2020 during the general election campaign.
The move is expected to boost the wages of six million people but may cause firms to recruit more under-25s, who will be on a lower rate, according to the Office for Budget Responsibility.
The Treasury confirmed the measure would apply to both the public and private sectors.
Mr Osborne announced that the 26,000 benefit cap - the amount one household can claim in a year - would be cut to 23,000 in London and 20,000 in the rest of the country.
The government will also make local authority and housing association tenants in England who earn more than 30,000 - or 40,000 in London - pay up to the market rent, but rents in the social housing sector will be reduced by 1% a year for the next four years.
The chancellor unveiled "just under half" of the 37bn in cuts he says are needed to clear the deficit, with the remainder to come from cuts to government departments to be announced in the autumn.
George Osborne was delivering his seventh Budget
Work and Pensions Secretary cheers the National Living Wage announcement
There was standing room only in the House of Commons
The chancellor announced an estimated 4.5bn cut to the 30bn-a-year tax credits system, which tops up the wages of low-paid workers, significantly reducing the amount someone can earn before they start losing benefit money.
Support for children through tax credits and universal credits will also be limited to two children, affecting children born after April 2017 unless the third child is the result of twins, triplets or other multiple birth.
Tax credits are a type of welfare payment, introduced by Gordon Brown in 2003, that allow unemployed people to keep some of their benefits when they get a low-paid job and are also paid to disabled workers and those responsible for children. They are due to be phased out when Universal Credit is introduced.
In other Budget announcements, the chancellor increased the personal allowance - the amount people can earn before they start paying tax.
He also tightened up eligibility for "non dom" tax status and said the NHS would receive a further 8bn by 2020, on top of 2bn already committed.
In her Budget response, Labour's acting leader Harriet Harman said: "The chancellor is said to be liberated without the ties of coalition holding him back but what we have heard today suggests his rhetoric is liberated from reality."
"A Budget for working people? How can you make that claim when you are making working people worse off," she said.
"You are making working people worse off by cutting tax credits and scrapping grants for the poorest students."
UKIP MP Douglas Carswell said it might become "politically unsustainable" to keep public sector pay rises frozen at 1% for four years if the economy grew.
But he welcomed cuts to tax credits, saying "we've got to unravel the disastrous system that Gordon Brown created" where public money subsidises big firms paying low wages.
The SNP's economy spokesman and deputy leader, Stewart Hosie, said the Budget would hit the "the poorest and the most vulnerable" and do nothing to improve productivity or encourage innovation.
A Lib Dem spokesman said: "Amongst the gimmicks and giveaways, the chancellor has hidden four more years of pain, austerity, and cuts."
Business groups gave Mr Osborne's Living Wage announcement a mixed reaction , with the Institute of Directors saying it was "time for companies to increase pay" but the CBI saying the government was taking "a big gamble" on wage increases industry might not be able to deliver.
The Living Wage Foundation director Rhys Moore said the proposed 9 rate was a "massive victory" for campaigners, but that it was "effectively a higher national minimum wage and not a living wage", due to the different ways the two rates are calculated.
The TUC welcomed the Living Wage announcement but said Mr Osborne was "giving with one hand taking with the other" and "massive cuts in support for working people will hit families with children hardest".
How will you be affected by the chancellor's summer budget? Email haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk with your story.
Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:05:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Root century galvanises England</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/cricket/33452339</Link>
        <Description>Joe Root's century steers England to a strong position against Australia after they make a shaky start to the first Ashes Test.</Description>
        <MainBody>First blood to the Aussies
Josh Hazlewood claimed his first Ashes wicket, dismissing Adam Lyth in the second over
Once the fireworks and fanfare of a rain-delayed opening ceremony were out of the way, Australia began their quest for a first Ashes win in England since 2001 with three early wickets.
Adam Lyth's first Ashes innings lasted only 10 balls as he was squared up by Hazlewood and sharply taken off a leading edge by David Warner in the gully.
England captain Alastair Cook had looked relatively comfortable against the new ball, but fell for 20 trying to take on Nathan Lyon's off-spin, his attempted cut lodging in Brad Haddin's gloves.
England were plunged deeper into the mire in the following over when Ian Bell was trapped lbw by a full delivery from Starc, who left the field in the final session to undergo treatment for a sore ankle.
Root to the rescue
Joe Root (left) and Gary Ballance (right) added 153 for the fourth wicket
England could easily have entered damage-limitation mode, but Root took the opposite approach.
Cutting and pulling anything short, and hurtling between the wickets, he raced to fifty in 56 balls and completed his seventh Test century soon after tea with a characteristic cover drive.
In the meantime Ballance, Root's one-time housemate, rediscovered the form that had deserted him in recent Tests as he compiled his first fifty in seven innings.
His partnership with Root was worth 153 when Ballance played around a straight ball from Hazlewood and was out lbw.
But it could have been different...
Root's crucial counter-punching innings could easily have been over before it started.
After surviving a narrow lbw appeal off his first ball, he edged his next delivery towards Haddin, who dived to his right and shelled the chance.
Summarising for Test Match Special, former England captain Michael Vaughan said Haddin's drop "could be a key moment in the series".
It will be some time before we know whether Vaughan's prophecy is fulfilled but, like all leading batsmen, Root made the most of his reprieve with a sublime hundred that changed the complexion of the day.
Johnson - awesome to ordinary
Mitchell Johnson conceded 87 wicket-less runs from his 20 overs
Central to Root's strategy was an aggressive approach towards Johnson, whose 37 wickets destroyed England in the 2013-14 series.
With the exception of a spell in which he unsettled Ballance with short balls, Johnson struggled on a pitch ill-suited to his talents.
So frequently did England hit him to the boundary that by the final session the Barmy Army felt emboldened enough to mock Johnson with chants about his wayward bowling that had not been aired since his toils on the 2010-11 series down under.
With their talisman struggling, Australia were indebted to Starc, who found late swing to have Root caught at slip and Stokes clean bowled in the final session.
Jos Buttler and Moeen Ali countered with a measured assault on the new ball to take England well past 300.
And even Buttler's disappointing demise - holing out to mid-on - could not take the gloss off a highly encouraging England display.
Stats of the day
Joe Root has scored more runs than any other player in Test cricket this year
Joe Root has scored seven Test centuries before the age of 25. Among England players, only Alastair Cook managed more - nine. Former all-rounder Ian Botham made six.
Root's century took 118 balls, making it the fastest century in the first Test of an Ashes series.
Since Root's debut in December 2012, England have had 37 century partnerships in Tests; he has been involved in 16 of them.
The 153-run stand between Joe Root and Gary Ballance means England have already equalled the number of century partnerships they managed in the entire 2012-13 Ashes series in Australia.
Since hitting 143 v West Indies at North Sound in April, England number four Ian Bell has scored 56 Test runs in nine innings at an average of 6.22.
Player reaction
England's Joe Root: "I'm really pleased with the way things have gone. I rode my luck at times, especially early on.
"It's a little bit slow. Seeing the first few not carry was a bit of a worry. There's a little bit there - there are a few little indentations which could be helpful when we bowl.
"I'm happy to be in the position we are in as a team. Hopefully we can kick on in the morning. The longer we can keep them out there, the better it is for us.
"Moeen and Broady are both very capable of scoring big scores - hopefully tomorrow is one of those days where they take it to them and we score 400-plus."
Ex-England batsman Geoff Boycott on Test Match Special
"It has been a very interesting day, lots of incidents I thought England gave the initiative away. It's a brilliant pitch to negate the two fast bowlers of Australia, slow nothingness so it's easier to play the quick bowlers, perfectly prepared for England. The Australian bowlers were striving all day for wickets, they bowled a lot of hittable balls with attacking fields even when there was nothing in the pitch and I thought that played into England's hands because there was plenty of room to hit it into the gaps."
Whose innings did not impress Geoffrey? Find out in the Pint-sized Ashes
Australia's Josh Hazlewood, who took 3-70: "The game is fairly level at this stage. Hopefully we can clean them up in the morning.
"We were good in patches. We kept it tight for periods but we leaked a few runs. When Root was batting he played fantastically and we need to find a plan for him.
"The wicket is quite slow and nullifies the short stuff but we tried to keep it full and swinging. The Duke ball is good fun - if you get it in the right areas there is always something there. If they get 40 or 50 more I think that's about par for them."
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:38:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Murray sets up Federer semi-final</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/tennis/33447089</Link>
        <Description>Andy Murray beats Vasek Pospisil under the Centre Court roof to set up a Wimbledon semi-final against Roger Federer.</Description>
        <MainBody>Andy Murray beats Vasek Pospisil to reach Wimbledon semis
By Piers Newbery BBC Sport at Wimbledon
Wimbledon 2015
Venue: All England Club Dates: 29 June - 12 July
Play: Outside courts 11:30 BST; Centre Court and Court One 13:00 BST
BBC coverage: Across TV, radio and online with up to 15 live streams. Read more: TV and radio schedules.
Britain's Andy Murray reached his sixth Wimbledon semi-final in seven years with victory over Canadian Vasek Pospisil under the Centre Court roof.
The Scot, seeded third, won 6-4 7-5 6-4 in two hours and 13 minutes, and will play second seed Roger Federer in the last four on Friday.
Murray, 28, had to cope with two rain delays, the second of which saw the roof brought across in the second set.
"It was difficult, we were stopped a couple of times," said Murray.
"I felt I played some good stuff. He served extremely well for periods. I tried to change my return position at the end of the second set to see the returns better."
Looking ahead to a 24th meeting with seven-time champion Federer, Murray added: "I know Roger very well, we walked to the practice courts together this morning.
"Friday is a different story and hopefully we can have a great match."
Murray produced a clinical performance to see off Pospisil, the world number 56, in straight sets.
Andy Roddick, three-time Wimbledon finalist
"It's what we thought would happen. We didn't think Pospisil would threaten Murray's serve too much. Murray was so solid. I think the roof helped Murray, not that he needed it, though. He looked so comfortable."
The Canadian, making his first appearance in a Grand Slam quarter-final, kept Murray's return game at bay for the most part but the Briton capitalised on fleeting chances to establish control.
Murray converted the solitary break point on offer in each of the first two sets, both with fizzing cross-court backhands that caught out Pospisil at the net.
The first break came just before play was halted for 35 minutes at 3-1 because of the rain, and a second interruption of 30 minutes in the second set saw the roof brought across, despite a burst of sunshine.
Murray did well to hold serve for 4-4 on the resumption as Pospisil pressed, and the Briton took a firm grip on the contest when he broke for 6-5.
Federer strolls to semi - highlights
Two lengthy rallies played to Murray's strength, with a breathless Pospisil given a time warning at 30-30, and the 2013 champion clinched the key break with a drop shot and a backhand.
Pospisil, 25, fended off four break points with big serves and a fifth with a brilliant drop volley as Murray raised the pressure further in the third set.
The decisive moment came at 4-4 when Pospisil, who had a first serve taken away for a second time warning, was forced out of position and played a shot between his legs facing a sixth break point.
Murray stepped in and crunched a backhand winner into the corner before saving a break point and converting his second match point in a tense closing game.
"I have loved playing here over the years," added Murray.
"I have always played some of my best tennis here. I hope I can get to another final but it will be a tough one."
Top seed Novak Djokovic will take on Richard Gasquet in the other semi-final.
Djokovic, the defending champion, overcame Marin Cilic in straight sets while Gasquet saw off French Open winner Stan Wawrinka in a five-set thriller.
Pat Cash, 1987 Wimbledon champion
"Roger Federer is in a different league from Pospisil but this was a good stepping stone towards that match. I'd pick Murray as the favourite. Murray doesn't need to do anything different; he is serving well, returning well, being patient from the baseline and moving his opponents around. At this level, it is whoever plays the big moments well, grabs the opportunities. It'll be a tough match, but Murray has the edge."
The Duchess and Duke of Cambridge, and the Countess of Wessex, watched from the Royal Box
David Beckham and his son Romeo were among the spectators on Centre Court
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:57:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>McAllister set for Liverpool coach job</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/33456515</Link>
        <Description>Former Liverpool midfielder Gary McAllister is set to become first-team coach in Brendan Rodgers' new-look backroom team.</Description>
        <MainBody>McAllister has managed Coventry and Leeds and been assistant manager at Aston Villa
8 July 2015 Last updated at 22:57
print
Liverpool: Gary McAllister to become first-team coach
Former Liverpool and Scotland midfielder Gary McAllister is set to become first-team coach in Brendan Rodgers' new-look backroom team.
McAllister, 50, is understood to have held talks with Rodgers at the club's Melwood training headquarters on Wednesday.
He will join new assistant manager Sean O'Driscoll and Dutch coach Pep Ljinders.
McAllister won the League Cup, FA Cup and Uefa Cup with Liverpool in 2001.
He has managed Coventry City and Leeds United, as well as serving as assistant to Gerard Houllier, the manager who brought him to Anfield, at Aston Villa.
Rodgers' former assistants Colin Pascoe and Mike Marsh were sacked in June following an end-of-season review with the club's American owners.
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:43:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby bust removed from theme park</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33440251#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A statue of Bill Cosby is removed from a Disney theme park in the wake of sexual abuse revelations.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bill Cosby bust removed from Disney theme park
8 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Cosby's lawyers had tried to stop the release of the 2005 documents
A statue of Bill Cosby has been removed from a Disney theme park in the wake of revelations the comedian admitted in court he gave a woman drugs before sex.
The bust had been part of a Hall of Fame exhibit at Disney's Hollywood Studios theme park in Florida.
Documents unsealed this week revealed Cosby testified in 2005 he had obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to sleep with.
Mr Cosby is facing a series of sexual assault claims dating back decades.
The 77-year-old has denied the accusations and has never been criminally charged.
Calls are mounting for other public tributes to the Cosby Show star to be removed, among them a mural at a Washington DC restaurant he has been known to frequent .
However, the Smithsonian's National Museum of African Art, also in Washington, issued a statement on Tuesday saying it would continue to display artworks lent to the institution by Cosby and his wife Camille .
The museum said it was aware of the recent revelations about Cosby and that it "in no way condones this behaviour", but said the exhibition was about the artworks and not their owners.
Ben's Chili Bowl in Washington is facing calls to remove its famous Cosby mural
Some figures in the entertainment industry have also commented on the revelations in recent days, either to offer tacit support for the comedian or to publicly distance themselves from him.
Speaking on her TV show The View on Tuesday, Whoopi Goldberg reserved judgement by saying "you are still innocent until proven guilty" and that Cosby had "not been proven a rapist".
Former supermodel Janice Dickinson, who has accused Cosby of drugging and raping her in the early eighties, responded by calling Goldberg a "stupid woman" who "needs to be fired" from her talk show spot.
Dickinson also called the release of the sealed court documents a vindication.
"It shows that he and all his people knew all along that we were telling the truth," she told People Magazine , while opening up about the impact of going public.
"It's been extremely difficult for my two children and my fiance and my friends and it has been extremely hard for me. It's so painful," said the 60-year-old.
"I want an admission of guilt. This is not over until we get a fair judge and jury and he can go under oath and stand on trial under oath for what he did to me."
Singer Jill Scott - formerly a staunch Cosby advocate - tweeted on Monday that she was " completely disgusted " and that the comedian's "own testimony offers PROOF of terrible deeds."
Film producer Judd Apatow, one of Cosby's most vocal and consistent critics, said he did not feel the unsealed files, obtained by the Associated Press news agency, revealed "anything new".
"It is only new to people who didn't believe an enormous amount of women who stated clearly that [Cosby] drugged them," he said in a statement to Esquire magazine .
"We shouldn't need Bill Cosby to admit it to believe 40 people who were victimised by him," continued the director and producer of Knocked Up, The 40-Year-Old Virgin and other film comedies.
"Maybe now more people in show business and all around our country will stand up and tell the people he attacked that we support you and believe you."
The removal of Cosby's likeness from Disney's Hollywood Studios, part of the Walt Disney World resort, followed a petition on the Change.org website that said the replica was " inappropriate ".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:51:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Han Solo origin film announced</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33439026#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A spin-off film from the Star Wars franchise will tell the back story of space smuggler Han Solo, Disney announces.</Description>
        <MainBody>Star Wars: Han Solo origin film announced
8 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
The Force Awakens sees Harrison Ford reprise his role after more than 30 years
A Star Wars spin-off film will tell the back story of space smuggler Han Solo, Disney has announced.
The new movie is to be directed by Christopher Miller and Phil Lord, the men behind the hugely successful Lego movie.
The charismatic criminal turned Rebellion hero returns in Star Wars' next instalment: The Force Awakens this Christmas.
Actor Harrison Ford last played Solo in 1983's Return of the Jedi.
No details or casting have been yet been announced but the script will be written by father and son team Lawrence and Jon Kasdan.
The senior Kasdan co-wrote The Empire Strikes Back, Return of the Jedi and The Force Awakens, the latter with director JJ Abrams.
There was a huge excitement in the fan community earlier this year when an extended trailer for the new film featured a brief appearance of Solo and his Millennium Falcon co-pilot Chewbacca, appearing to be on the deck of his famous spaceship, uttering the words, "Chewie, we're home..."
The untitled Han Solo project is scheduled to be released on 25 May 2018.
It follows the first stand-alone Star Wars anthology film Rogue One, which is due next year.
Which actors are in the running to play Han?
Aaron Paul
The Breaking Bad star has sent the rumour mill into overdrive after the Star Wars official Twitter account started following him.
The 35-year-old Instagrammed a screenshot of the moment, captioning that his "dreams are coming true." Unsurprisingly he is the favourite for the role according to bookmakers.
Aaron Taylor-Johnson
The 25-year-old Brit and husband of Fifty Shades of Grey director Sam Taylor-Johnson most recently starred in the Marvel blockbuster Avengers: Age of Ultron.
Josh Hutcherson
No stranger to movie franchises, the Hunger Games actor is Buzzfeed's number one choice .
Chris Pratt
The Jurassic World actor's star has rocketed after Guardians of the Galaxy and Jurassic World.
Rumoured to be the next star of Indiana Jones, could the Harrison Ford likeness make him a popular candidate?
Armie Hammer
Best known for his portrayal as the Winklevoss twins in 2010's The Social Network and the title for in 2013's The Lone Ranger, this role could propel Hammer into a superstar stratosphere.
Chris Hemsworth
The Aussie actor is known for his action roles, currently starring as Marvel's Thor and appearing in the Avengers movie franchise. He also appeared briefly in JJ Abrams' Star Trek reboot, as Captain Kirk's father.
Jack O'Connell
Angelina Jolie's a fan of this Brit, having cast him in her most recent directorial project, Unbroken. Last year's winner of the Bafta Rising Star Award, landing the part of Han would be the proof of the pudding.
Zac Efron
Known for his vocal roles in High School Musical and Hairspray, the role of Han would mark a change of direction for the 27-year-old.
Nicholas Hoult
Big action movies have become second nature to this 25-year-old having starred in the X-Men franchise as Hank McCoy as well as in Mad Max. He's an outside shot at the role though according to bookmakers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 12:47:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>TV channel escapes censure over J-Lo</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33440125#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A Moroccan TV channel avoids sanctions after broadcasting a controversial concert starring a "scantily dressed" Jennifer Lopez.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jennifer Lopez concert: Morocco TV channel escapes censure
8 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
The singer had previously performed in Morocco without any trouble
A Moroccan TV channel has escaped sanctions after broadcasting a controversial Jennifer Lopez concert.
The country's Prime Minister Abdelilah Benkirane ordered an investigation following Lopez's "sexually suggestive" performance at a music festival which aired on public television channel 2M.
He said the show violated Morocco's laws, and called for sanctions against the channel's management.
But the media regulator said the request was outside its remit.
Mr Benkirane said the singer's performance was 'indecent and provocative'
The American pop star's show at Mawazine festival in Rabat on 29 May sparked controversy among local media in the highly conservative Muslim country.
Writing to the president of High Audiovisual Communication Authority (HACA), Mr Benkirane demanded the regulator "take legal measures against those responsible".
He said 2M's management had "failed to intervene and stop the broadcast of the disgraceful scenes" as the concert was shown without a time delay.
The performance's "sexual overtones" were "indecent and provocative to the religious and moral values of Moroccan society," he added.
But HACA ruled that the Prime Minister's application "was inadmissible in form, because it does not fall within the scope" of the regulator's mission, which was to "address issues related to the audiovisual sector as a whole and not on specific cases".
Lopez has performed in Morocco before without trouble. However, May's gig was her first televised show.
According to TMZ an educational group is also suing the singer over the performance, claiming she "disturbed public order and tarnished women's honour and respect".
Should Lopez and her promoter be prosecuted, the sentence could be up to two years in prison.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:28:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Single mother on 10 euros a week</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33444099#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A single mother in Piraeus is among those falling into arrears in Greece. She earns about 10 euros a week and depends on charity for food and basic supplies.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Single mother on 10 euros a week in Greece
8 July 2015 Last updated at 15:28 BST
A single mother in Piraeus is among those falling into arrears in Greece. She earns about 10 euros a week and depends on charity for food and basics.
Richard Bilton reports for Panorama.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:09:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Catching Brazil's illegal loggers</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33449788#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The BBC's Wyre Davies has been out with Brazil's environmental police, as evidence shows an increase in illegal logging and deforestation in the Amazon.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Amazon deforestation: Stopping the illegal loggers
9 July 2015 Last updated at 01:09 BST
The issue of illegal logging and deforestation in the Amazon is still a huge concern in Brazil, despite progress on deforestation rates in the last decade.
Agents from IBAMA, Brazil's environmental police, keep an eye on millions of square miles of rainforest - an almost impossible task with limited resources.
With mounting evidence that the rate of deforestation in the Amazon is again on the rise, the BBC's Wyre Davies joined environmental police officers as they raided illegal logging camps in the jungle.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:34:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Pakistan suicide: 'I felt I was a burden'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33456669#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>In Pakistan's remote northern region of Gilgit-Baltistan the rate of suicides among its women is the highest in the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Pakistan women suicide: 'I felt I was a burden'
9 July 2015 Last updated at 00:34 BST
Pakistan's remote northern region of Gilgit-Baltistan is where three of the world's mightiest mountain ranges meet.
The scenic valley is described as the Jewel of Pakistan, but it has a problem. The rate of suicides among women there is the highest in the country.
Shumaila Jaffery reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:14:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Tornado drama captured in Venice, Italy</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33456741#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A tornado has swept through the outskirts of the Italian city of Venice - destroying large numbers of homes and other buildings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Tornado drama captured in Venice, Italy
9 July 2015 Last updated at 01:14 BST
A tornado has swept through the outskirts of the Italian city of Venice - destroying homes and other buildings.
Media reports suggest one person was killed and dozens injured as the storm hit the town of Dolo between Venice and Padua.
The video, originally posted by youreporter.it , shows the twister in the midst of strong winds.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:06:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: 'End privilege of ship owners and church'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33444098#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Reduce the public sector, transform public banks, open up professions for young people, end the privileges of ship owners, the Orthodox Church and others, Liberal MEP Guy Verhofstadt demanded.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
'End privilege of ship owners, military and church' - Guy Verhofstadt
8 July 2015 Last updated at 13:06 BST
Some MEPs have criticised Greece's prime minister for not putting forward "concrete proposals" in negotiations with the country's creditors.
Downsize the public sector, transform the public banks, open the markets and professions for young people, end the privileges of ship owners, the military, of the Orthodox Church, the privileges of the Greek islands and political parties, Liberal MEP Guy Verhofstadt demanded.
The former Belgian prime minister asked whether Mr Tsipras wanted to be remembered "as an electoral accident who made his people poorer in his country? Or do you want to be remembered, Mr Tsipras, as a real revolutionary reformer?"
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 11:30:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Boos and cheers for Tsipras</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33439017#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was greeted with both cheers and booing as he arrived to address the European Parliament in Strasbourg.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Boos and cheers for Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras
8 July 2015 Last updated at 09:30 BST
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was greeted with both cheers and booing as he arrived to address the European Parliament in Strasbourg.
Discussions are continuing in Brussels to try to find a solution to Greece's debt crisis, after Sunday's referendum in which the Greek people rejected the terms of a bailout deal.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:05:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Bankers despair as China freezes trade</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-33455208#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>China's regulators are taking fresh steps to try to quell volatility in the country's financial markets.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
China freezes trade as bankers despair at share plunge
8 July 2015 Last updated at 23:05 BST
China's regulators are taking fresh steps to try to quell volatility in the country's financial markets.
Investors holding stakes of more than 5% are not allowed to sell shares in the next six months.
The new rule from the country's securities regulator is intended to relieve pressure on the stock market.
The BBC's China editor Carrie Gracie reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:13:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: The artist helping migrants on Lesbos</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33452083#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The BBC's Anna Holligan speaks to a sculptor who lives on the Greek island of Lesbos and meets and helps migrants coming ashore.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Migrant crisis: The artist helping migrants on Lesbos
8 July 2015 Last updated at 20:13 BST
While Greece struggles with its economic crisis, the authorities there, are also grappling with the problem of migration.
Officials on the Greek Island of Lesbos are trying to cope with a huge surge in the number of migrants arriving there every day.
The BBC's Anna Holligan has been talking to a sculptor who lives there, who meets and helps migrants coming ashore.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:14:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A tale of two sisters and flight MH17</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33442560#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A tale of two sisters and flight MH17</Description>
        <MainBody>A tale of two sisters and flight MH17
By Natalia Antelava BBC News, Amsterdam
9 July 2015
From the section Magazine
When the Malaysian airliner, flight MH17, was shot down over eastern Ukraine nearly a year ago, the BBC's Natalia Antelava was soon reporting from the scene. A chance encounter gave her a personal connection with one of the dead passengers, and - as she describes here - prompted her to find the woman's sister.
The midwife said she'd be back by dinnertime. By 3pm it was clear that the baby was not going to wait that long.  As her contractions, and pain, grew stronger, Babs Baay crawled into the only bedroom of her tiny flat in the Dutch town of Breda. She lay on the wooden floor and, for a moment thought of dialling her cousin, who had volunteered to take her to the birthing centre.  Then she decided not to.
"I don't know why," she tells me two months later, as we sit down on a white sofa in her sunlit living room. "I guess because the only person I really wanted there was one person who could not be there. I didn't want to replace her."
Instead, Babs says, she propped her back against side of her bed and fixed her eyes firmly on the wall above her. Hanging from it are dozens of photographs of that one person:  her sister Joyce.
"She always gave me comfort and kept me calm," Babs says. "Joyce was everything - my friend, my partner, my home.  We discussed everything together, whether it was work, relationships, emotions or illness."
Joyce Baay with the missing bracelet visible on her wrist
After two hours of puffing, pushing and breathing Babs focused on remembering all she ever read or watched about delivering babies. Then she sat up, leaned over and reached for the baby's head, gently twisting her shoulder and, with a final push, delivering her daughter.
When the midwife finally turned up at the promised hour she was astonished to find the first solo delivery of her long career.
"It was a split second, and instinct too kicked in so I twisted and pulled her out and there she was, looking at me with her big blue eyes: 'Hello!' And I was so proud, I thought, 'You listened so well to mummy, you are such a brave baby,'" Babs says, little Yoeki now snoozing at her chest.
Why did Babs never call for help? She doesn't know. But the experience helped her to connect with Yoeki, she says, and somehow make her sister, Joyce, part of it too.
Joyce was always supposed to be Babs's delivery partner. Soon after Babs had decided to go through the process of artificial insemination she told her sister that she'd want her by her side in the labour room.  "She travelled a lot, so I said to her keep that in mind, to free up some time," Babs remembers.
Joyce had just been selected to guide a group of Dutch tourists through Malaysia - it was a potential career change that could lead to a lot more travel, and she was excited.  She was also keen to get to Malaysia a few days before her group arrived, and so on 17 July she boarded Malaysian Airlines flight MH17 from Amsterdam to Kuala Lumpur. She planned to be back in a month.
The Boeing 777 carrying Malaysian Airlines Flight MH17 was shot down near the Russian-Ukrainian border, in the area controlled by the Moscow-backed rebels.
On 19 July I arrived at the scene, near the village of Hrabove, with a BBC television crew. The sun was just setting over spectacular fields of sunflowers. Scattered through these fields, over an area of more than 10 sq km were the bodies of the 298 passengers and crew.
Some of what we saw was overwhelmingly gruesome, some painfully poignant. At one point as I wandered through the field I stepped on a glass jar of Estee Lauder face cream. Was the owner a holidaymaker? A businesswoman, maybe? Or one of many scientists heading to a big HIV conference?  Some of the world's leading Aids researchers were on that plane. Or maybe she was the mother of one of the 80 children on the flight?
I remember a tall man sobbing by the roadside. He must have been a journalist - no family members or international rescue workers could get to the area in those early days because of the fighting.  The man was on his phone speaking English to someone back home. He was describing duty free whisky bottles we had all seen amid the debris.  He was crying because he, like the rest of us, could not understand how glass bottles of booze could survive a fall that killed so many people.
The rebels were in a state of shock and panic. Whoever shot down MH17, it was clearly unplanned. The rebels said they would guarantee safety for an international rescue mission only if Kiev agreed to a truce. Instead, they launched their own hasty recovery operation, bringing in hundreds of local coal miners to comb through the fields.
It was one of these miners, a young slim man with face smeared in coal dust, who walked up to me as we were filming on 19 July.  "Documents," he said handing me an ID and a wallet. "What do I do with them? Please pass them on," he said, walking away before I even had a chance to reply.
We handed the documents to the rebels in charge - there was no-one else to give them to. But the name on the ID stuck in my mind: Joyce.
Long after I left Ukraine, I kept wondering who Joyce was and whether the documents ever reached her family.  When Malaysian Airlines released a list of the names of the passengers on flight MH17 I looked for hers and there it was, near the top - the only Joyce on the flight. In the months that followed, I tracked down her sister, Babs, in the Netherlands. She was pregnant at the time and we tentatively agreed to meet after birth of the baby.  The plan was that after meeting her, I'd travel to eastern Ukraine to track down the miner who found Joyce's documents. These were two people - Babs and the miner - whose worlds collided when the plane crashed, whose lives changed forever. I wanted to know how.
Imagine. That door closed and that was it. This plane was their coffin
Babs Baay
"Holland's 9/11" was how one official described to me the shooting down of MH17.  There were citizens of 10 countries on that flight - Malaysians, Indonesians, Australians, British... But the biggest group were the Dutch. More The figure of 193 Dutch deaths exceeds the number of people murdered in the Netherlands in a normal year.
The Dutch government says the investigation into MH17 is its top priority, but many are unhappy with the way it has dragged on. The investigators won't report their conclusions until October. A preliminary report in September last year said the plane broke up after being penetrated by "high-velocity objects" - which appeared to lend support to the widespread suspicion that the airliner was shot down by a powerful Buk anti-aircraft missile.
Shortly before the attack, the rebels had boasted about having access to a Russian-made Buk but subsequently both they, and their allies in Moscow insisted that the plane was shot down in an air-to-air attack by a Ukrainian fighter plane.  More recently, the rebels agreed that it was indeed a Buk missile, but insisted that it was fired from the Ukrainian side.  The official investigation should clarify this - and many in the Netherlands are already calling for an international tribunal.
Babs doesn't know who killed her sister and accepts that she might never find out.  But it has changed the way she feels about the world, she tells me.  She now carefully follows news of the conflict in Ukraine, even though a year ago she knew almost nothing about it.  She can no longer bear the sight of Vladimir Putin, she says, and switches channels every time she sees his face on television. She often logs on to a special online forum for relatives of the victims.  Recently someone posted photographs taken by a passenger inside the plane before the disaster - these were stored in a telephone that was recovered from the wreckage and returned to relatives.
Find out more
MH17 - A Sister's Story, runs on Assignment on the BBC World Service on Thursday 9 July. Click here for transmission times, or to listen online.
"Imagine," Babs says as she shows me pictures of smiling passengers settling into their seats "That door closed and that was it. This plane was their coffin."
We talk for hours, mostly about Joyce: her hopes and her dreams, her diverse group of friends, a hilarious 40th birthday party that she had organised in an Amsterdam theatre a year before her death.
Babs tells me about the phone call informing her about the crash; about checking into a hotel in Amsterdam together with the other families. The fact that they were all grieving together provided no comfort, she says.
It was there, while waiting for news from Ukraine, that Babs did a pregnancy test. "It was a very difficult moment because I knew that if it was a negative test, I would go to hell.  My world would completely fall apart."  She told no-one that she was pregnant.
The families waited in the hotel for seven days until finally, after tense negotiation between the warring sides, the Dutch were able to send military planes to collect the first 80 bodies.
I remember watching the ceremony in Hrabove amid the charred fields, the debris and men in sloppy camouflage waving guns and barking orders. A world away, at Eindhoven military airport dozens of black hearses were parked in a perfect line and the nation held its breath as the planes began to land. The contrast between the chaos of war-torn Ukraine and the dignified, choreographed reception on Dutch soil was overwhelming. What I couldn't see on my screen were the relatives, their grief hidden away from the cameras.
Babs says all she could hear was the flapping of flags at half-mast. She will never know which coffin carried her sister back. The identification process took weeks. But she remembers the day a man brought Joyce's belongings back - each item wrapped in white paper, including the documents the miner gave me on the site.
I tell Babs that I plan to go to eastern Ukraine and try to find the miner. She asks me to thank him. "It's important to me that they respected her dying," she says.
But, she tells me, there was one thing missing from Joyce's belongings - a silver bracelet her sister always wore. Babs asks me to try to track it down.
These days a trip to eastern Ukraine, where war continues, is a complex undertaking.  It involves a road journey across bombed-out countryside through many checkpoints - first on the Ukrainian, then on the Russian-backed side. Both require special permissions. I have all the documents, as I've been back to Ukraine several times over the past year, but just as I prepare to go back to look for the miner - and now the bracelet - I get bad news.  The authorities in the self-declared Donetsk People's Republic have revoked my permit - and they say this is non-negotiable.
I was barbecuing, and there it was - falling down - a big thing
Alexander, Rassypnoe, Ukraine
The reason for banning me from Donetsk appears to be a television piece that I did on my last trip to Ukraine, examining the story of a 10-year-old girl allegedly killed during Ukrainian shelling of Donetsk .  I heard the report on Russian television and decided to fact-check it.  What I found was that not only was there no shelling that day, but the girl herself had never existed. Russian journalists admitted to me on camera that they had fabricated the report because they "had to do it".
My report deeply upset the authorities in Donetsk. The story of the girl is simply one of many examples of the propaganda war between Russia and Ukraine. Flight MH17 is at the heart of this war.  Ukrainian journalists have stuck to the version, supported by the West, that rebels shot down the plane with a Buk missile. Russian television in the meantime has presented several alternative theories, including one repeated to me by rebel spokesman Eduard Basurin. "Did you know that the plane was pre-loaded with dead bodies at Schiphol airport?" he asked me on my trip to Donetsk in April 2015. "It was all part of a plan to make us look bad."
Having failed to convince Donetsk authorities that this time I was coming simply to look for a miner and a bracelet, I started investigating whether there was any way of doing this remotely. I called everyone I could think of in Donetsk, including a journalist, Katya Malofeyeva. She told me she was about to travel to the three villages at the crash site and volunteered to show people pictures of the bracelet and the miner.
Katya returned from her trip with audio recordings of several local people. Their trauma is clearly audible on tape.
"I was barbecuing, and there it was - falling down. A big thing. A big piece. And from that piece of plane people were falling. They were flying as if they were birds with their arms spread out," said Alexander in the village of Rassypnoe.
A local woman looks at the crash site of flight MH17 in August 2014
Others told Katya they were tired of talking to journalists. Some cried.  "As if he war wasn't enough to deal with," one woman said. Another, called Marina, said that her only request was a memorial for the victims. "We must preserve their memory," she said.
People are still finding things, we give everything back
Marina , Rassypnoe, Ukraine
When Katya showed Marina a photo of Joyce with her bracelet, she sounded excited. Her neighbour, Galya, had found a bracelet in her garden, she said. Last year a woman's body fell into Galya's courgette patch, and for a year she avoided the garden. But this spring she finally ventured in, and while working on the land she found a bracelet.
Marina walked Katya over to her neighbour's house, where Galya examined the photo of Joyce wearing her chunky silver band and declared it to be a different bracelet."The one I found is white with a golden rim and little jewels. Maybe you can find the family so I can return it?" she said.
Sensing Katya's disappointment, both Galya and Marina reassured her that there is a good chance the bracelet will be found.  "People are still finding things, we give everything back," Marina said.
Residents of villages around the crash site are still sensitive about allegations of looting that came after the crash. I personally saw things disappear in the chaos of those first days. Each time we arrived at the site the pile of belongings by the roadside got smaller and smaller.  Those whisky bottles, for example, vanished by the third day.  By the fifth day, the "I love Amsterdam" T-shirt that had been laid out on the grass was gone too. But there were also plenty of people, like that coal miner, who took care of the personal belongings they found.
Katya showed the coal miner's photo to everybody she met, and it turned out that he wasn't local but part of a group brought in from another area.  We will keep trying to track him down, but over the last year thousands of people have been killed in fighting in eastern Ukraine, and thousands more have fled. Katya and others say they'll keep trying to find the bracelet too.
Babs will be waiting.  For the bracelet, and, with the rest of the nation, for answers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:15:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Ypres Last Post buglers' milestone</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33440968#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The buglers who have played the Last Post 30,000 times</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Last Post: Ypres buglers' memorial milestone
9 July 2015 Last updated at 00:15 BST
Each evening at the Menin Gate in Ypres, Belgium the Last Post is sounded in an act of remembrance for the soldiers who died in World War One.
This has happened almost continuously since 1928.
The buglers who play it are local firefighters, mostly volunteers.
On 9 July the Last Post will be played there for 30,000th time.
BBC News met Rik Vandekerckhove, the Chief Officer at the fire brigade, who has been playing the bugle in the ceremony since 1980.
Video Journalist: John Galliver
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:44:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Can a historic peace deal be secured with the Taliban?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33449809#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Why Taliban talks give reasons to be hopeful</Description>
        <MainBody>Can a historic peace deal be secured with the Taliban?
By M Ilyas Khan BBC News, Islamabad
8 July 2015
From the section Asia
There are complex and deeply-rooted geo-political issues that make a peace deal with the Taliban in Afghanistan especially difficult
The first round of what officials in Pakistan are calling "exploratory" talks between the Afghan Taliban and the Kabul government is the nearest the Afghan peace process has come to an attempt at a negotiated settlement in recent years.
This is the first time the Taliban have agreed to sit across the table from Afghan officials. Previously, they insisted they could only talk to the Americans who held "real power" in Afghanistan.
And this is also the first time the Taliban have agreed to participate in talks publicly acknowledged by both Islamabad and Kabul.
Previous attempts at talks either failed, or were shrouded in secrecy and often denied by the Taliban.
Who holds key to war and peace?
The US attempt to engage the Taliban in Qatar in 2012 failed when then Afghan President Hamid Karzai objected to the Taliban raising their official flag above their office, making it look like they were a government-in-exile. Pakistanis also felt they had been bypassed at the Doha talks.
The possibility of a peace deal comes while the Afghan military's struggle against the Taliban continues unabated
In recent months, the Taliban have denied numerous claims that Taliban officials of varying levels of seniority had actually met Afghan officials at meetings which took place in Dubai, China and Norway, saying if such talks did take place, they did not have the official sanction of the Taliban leadership.
But more significantly, these latest talks were held in Pakistan, which has long been seen as holding the key to war and peace in Afghanistan.
And the fact that officials from the US, China and the UN were also in attendance lends credence to the view that some sort of a peace process may finally be taking shape in Afghanistan.
But despite all these reasons for optimism, there are complex and deeply-rooted geo-political issues that make the Afghan issue especially difficult.
Can Pakistan be trusted?
Pakistan's motives are one factor.
The Pakistani army has paid a heavy price in its battle against the Taliban in the north-west of the country
Islamabad has entertained and often projected a longstanding fear that its eastern neighbour, India, wants to destabilise it.
Afghanistan, being the only country to have opposed Pakistan's membership of the UN after independence, is seen by Pakistan as a natural conduit of Indian "conspiracies" to surround Pakistan.
The fact that political decision-making in Pakistan has largely been dominated by the military has tended to create a war economy and a security state focused more on war games than statesmanship.
The Pakistani military has long been accused of using the Taliban as proxies to control Afghanistan and counter Indian influence there.
In the short run, Pakistan has a motive to support peace in Afghanistan as a means of encouraging Chinese funds to develop its faltering economy. But the military still remains dominant and military thinking may continue to dominate its regional policies.
Will Afghan leaders play ball?
The Afghan military has also suffered heavy casualties as Nato's presence in the country has been drastically reduced
Afghanistan, too, is a government with two heads - one led by a Pashtun president, and the other by a coterie of nationalist Afghans including both Pashtun and non-Pashtun leaders.
While President Ashraf Ghani has shown a willingness to play ball with Pakistan, others have remained unconvinced, and their ideas are reinforced by the Taliban's unusually large gains across Afghanistan in over 13 years of war.
Many believe the top Taliban leaders are completely dependent on Pakistan for sanctuary and protection, and could not have ordered such widespread attacks in Afghanistan without Pakistan's knowledge or consent.
This internal bickering is not going to help an Afghan military and police force already struggling in their first post-Nato fighting season against a resurgent Taliban.
The weaker the government forces, the higher the Taliban's demands, and the stiffer the resistance of the anti-Pakistan leadership in Kabul to the terms of a peace deal.
Are the Taliban scared of Islamic State?
One measure of Pakistan's seriousness to promote peace negotiations would be the extent to which it considers President Ghani to be able to hold on to his pro-Pakistan stance.
The success of Islamic State in attracting Afghan fighters and controlling territory is likely to feature strongly in any Taliban calculations to go to the negotiating table
Pakistan will be inclined to make a greater push for a negotiated settlement if it feels President Ghani's grip on the situation is loosening. It does not want to be seen as the villain, which would increase its isolation.
It will also be keen to neutralise anti-Pakistan elements in Afghanistan, at least for the time being, so as to reduce their urge to use the Pakistani Taliban (TTP) - who have sanctuaries on the Afghan side - against targets in Pakistan.
For the Taliban, too, Mr Ghani's resilience will be an important factor in deciding when it is time to get down to serious give and take.
And how successful Islamic State (IS) are in attracting Afghan fighters and controlling territory will also feature in Taliban calculations.
If the IS threat grows, the Taliban will feel increasingly compelled to hasten a settlement for security reasons and to control the spread of a rival militant group.
With so many varying scenarios, it is hard to predict how likely it is that negotiators will arrive at an agreement acceptable to all sides.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:00:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saving plants from 'mass extinction'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33450398#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The rush to freeze plants before the next 'mass extinction'</Description>
        <MainBody>Scientists rush to freeze plant DNA before 'sixth extinction'
By Jane O'Brien BBC News, Washington
9 July 2015
From the section Magazine
Could these plants be extinct soon? The Global Genome Initiative aims to freeze plant DNA for safekeeping
As the world enters into a sixth great extinction, scientists are racing against the clock to save genetic evidence from plants around the world.
An ambitious project launched Wednesday  to collect the genomes of the planet's major plant groups within the next two years and put them into deep freeze.
The project is part of the Global Genome Initiative, which aims to gather and preserve the DNA of all life on Earth in cryo-storage facilities.
The task sounds daunting, but scientists leading the initiative at the Smithsonian's National Museum of Natural History say it will only take a few months to gather samples from half the world's plant families because they're already growing in botanic gardens. Most can be found within a five-mile (8-km) radius of Washington, DC.
There are some 500 plant families and more than 13,000 genera within those groups. The task is urgent because some species are facing extinction. In fact, scientists warn that Earth has entered its sixth mass extinction - the last such event killed the dinosaurs 65 million years ago.
Where the plant DNA will be stored
"It's not just plants - it's plants, animals and micro-organisms," says John Kress, interim Under Secretary for Science at the Smithsonian Institution.
"Everything that is alive and living in a natural habitat is now being threatened by degradation of those habitats primarily because of what we're doing as humans."
He says it's difficult to measure the rate of plant extinction but some scientists have estimated that all species of life are becoming extinct 100 times faster than normal.
The Global Genome Initiative complements ongoing efforts to save the seeds of many plants that are being stored in special vaults around the world.
"Seed banks were set up primarily to preserve the seeds of economically important crops, to keep a living bank of tissue with which we can grow these plants again in the future.  The genome project is to preserve the genomic history and content of these plants so we can understand how life works," says Kress.
The genome project and seed banks have two distinct but complementary goals
"We're learning how an organism functions. When we have the whole genome we can identify the genes that control flowering, fruiting, seed production, drought tolerance and all these things that help the plant survive in its native habitat.
DNA starts to degrade within three minutes of an organism's death. Plant samples have to be immediately frozen in canisters of liquid nitrogen before being transferred to permanent storage.
The more we understand about change, the better we can cope with it
Jonathan Coddington, Director, Global Genome Initiative
A growing international network of cryo-storage facilities is taking part in the Global Genome Initiative. There are 25 so far on every continent except Antarctica. The tanks containing the world's largest natural history genome collection are operated by the Smithsonian at a centre in Maryland. It's capable of holding more than four million samples.
Jonathan Coddington, director of the Global Genome Initiative, says genomes are vital to understanding zoonotic diseases, identifying new species and advancing medicine. One in four prescription drugs already contains materials isolated from plants.
"There is a worm that can regenerate from just one cubic millimetre of tissue. Think about spinal injuries and how much pain that causes humans. This worm can grow an entire body - how does it do that? There's a jellyfish that's immortal. What is its secret? Life is filled with mysteries like this and the mysteries are fundamentally coded in their genes," he says.
"We also need to be able to track what climate change does to ecosystems in real time. To do that we have to scale it up and make it into big data. To do that, we need the genetic signatures of all the important species in those ecosystems so we can monitor them. The more we understand about change, the better we can cope with it."
It's only recently that scientists have had the technology - and the financing - to embark upon such an extraordinary task. In 2001 genome sequencing cost around $95m (61.2m). Today, sequencing can be carried out for $600,000.
Of the world's estimated 11 million species, only two million have been documented, and only 1% of the planet's known genomes have been sequenced.
The drive to collect plant genomes is being launched at three gardens in the Washington area - the US Botanic Garden, the National Arboretum and the Smithsonian Gardens. The samples will be taken mainly by volunteers - so-called "citizen scientists".
"We are giant collectors, hoarders of plants, and it's amazing the plant diversity we manage to keep within our walls," says Ari Novy, executive director, US Botanic Garden.
"Botanical institutions such as ours have spent decades and in some cases centuries collecting plants. The US Botanic Garden has almost 250 families which is half the total number of plant families on the planet. That makes this project a lot easier."
Many of the species are being sampled from the US Botanic Garden and the US National Arboretum
Some genomes can only be collected from cultivated plants because they are effectively extinct in the wild.
Brighamia insignis, nicknamed "cabbage on a stick" is a critically endangered species found in Hawaii. The plant can no longer reproduce on its own because its only pollinator was a certain type of hawk moth that is now extinct.
The US Botanic Garden is one of the few places where it is now grown and artificially pollinated. But with the combination of live plants and future technologies enabled by genome collection, it may one day thrive in the wild.
"These genomes will be preserved forever," says Coddington. "We're putting life on ice."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:14:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Twitter reacted to NYSE 'glitch'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33450848#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>How Twitter reacted to NY stock exchange 'glitch'</Description>
        <MainBody>NYSE: How Twitter reacted to New York Stock Exchange 'glitch'
8 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Trading at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) was suspended on Wednesday due to a "technical issue" - but that didn't stop Twitter users declaring it a sign the world was about to end.
News of the NYSE shutdown broke at about 11:30 ET (15:30 GMT) - just hours after US carrier United Airlines had grounded all of its flights after an unspecified computer issue.
Coincidence? Probably. But then the Wall Street Journal website also went down. Cue hysteria, panic, and bad jokes.
Fortunately there were plenty of people in New York to check on the rest of the city:
So what happened?!
Could it have been the result of the growing need to charge our mobile phones ?
Or maybe the NYSE was hacked? After all, hacking group Anonymous had tweeted this just yesterday:
But the NYSE was quick to try and stamp out those rumours:
Of course, if in doubt, always blame the IT guys:
In classic Twitter fashion, everyone started making the same joke:
Thankfully there were a few more inventive Twitter comics out there:
Before long, everyone started planning their next moves:
But then just as things were getting exciting, it was all over:
Still, spare a thought for those caught up in Glitch Wednesday:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 10:43:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fear China's stock-market earthquake</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33440565#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>China's share-price collapse as serious as Greece</Description>
        <MainBody>From the section Business
comments
For all my obsession with the probable exit of Greece from the euro and the most important social-security-cutting and tax-reforming UK budget for many years, there is an earthquake happening in China that may end up touching our lives as much.
It is the plunge over the past month of Chinese shares - whose value has dropped by around a third since the high of 12 June.
So to make an apple-and-pears comparison: the loss in the value of Chinese companies at more than $3 trillion is about 20 times what most economists expect the write-offs of Greek government debt will ultimately turn out to be.
The difference, of course, is that the $3 trillion loss is divided among around 90 million Chinese people, rather than a handful of European governments.
But not to be sniffed at is the political significance of 90 million Chinese - who number more than membership of the Chinese Communist Party - feeling a lot less wealthy.
Which is why Beijing has been throwing everything at trying to find a way to end the rout - including cutting the cost of money - and has been failing miserably.
One of the so-called solutions to this market disaster is that an astonishing 1301 companies have had trading in their shares suspended. Their prices can't fall any more because the shares can't be bought or sold.
But this means that a further $2.6 trillion of wealth, tied up in these shares, is completely frozen - which adds insult to investors' capital-loss injury.
Here's the chilling thing. What's going on in China is madly redolent of the 1929 Wall Street crash.
Here's why.
The 150% rise over a year in the Shanghai Composite Index to its mid-June peak was largely driven by investors borrowing to buy shares, or margin trading in the jargon, just as happened in the US during the Roaring Twenties.
And the subsequent self-reinforcing collapse has been driven by China's indebted investors being forced to sell shares to meet their debts.
As for the economic significance of what is going on, well these very big stock markets in Shanghai and Shenzhen are no longer serving their core purpose of supplying equity capital to businesses - which will have a significant negative impact on Chinese growth.
And the collapse completely undermines Beijing's attempt to shift economic power from State Owned Enterprises to the private sector and markets.
The public sector is once again all powerful and all important.
And if the market rout leads to a further significant deceleration in the growth of the world's second-biggest economy, we will all feel the after shocks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
