<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="BBC">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:48:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece submits economic reform plan</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33472699#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Greece submits plans for economic reforms to eurozone officials, in a last-ditch bid to secure a new bailout from creditors.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece debt crisis: Eurozone receives economic reform plan
9 July 2015
From the section Europe
Pro-euro demonstrators gathered outside Greece's parliament on Thursday evening
The Greek government has submitted proposals for economic reforms in an effort to secure a further bailout from its international creditors.
Eurozone officials received the plan late on Thursday, two hours before a midnight deadline. They will now study it ahead of EU meetings at the weekend.
Greece's lenders had demanded tax and pension reforms in return for funds.
The indebted country needs a third bailout to avoid a default and a possible exit from the euro.
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras spent Thursday seeking agreement on the reforms from his government partners.
Follow our live updates here
Alexis Tsipras (centre, at back) spent much of the day thrashing out the agreement with his cabinet
Mr Tsipras's proposals will be considered by eurozone finance ministers on Saturday, and by EU leaders at a summit in Brussels on Sunday.
The Greek government will also seek parliamentary approval for the reform package.
Greek voters decisively rejected previous austerity proposals from the country's lenders in a referendum on Sunday.
According to reports in the Greek media, the measures submitted on Thursday evening involve tax rises and spending cuts worth more than 12bn euro - more than those rejected in the referendum.
Greek banks have been closed for nearly a fortnight with limits placed on cash withdrawals.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:16:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US 'will not rush' to seal Iran deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33457805#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>America and other major powers are not in a rush to reach a nuclear agreement with Iran, US Secretary of State John Kerry says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear: US 'will not be rushed over deal' - Kerry
9 July 2015
From the section Middle East
US Secretary of State John Kerry has said that America and other major powers are not in a rush to reach a nuclear agreement with Iran.
But he warned that the so-called P5+1 (US, UN, Russia, UK, France and Germany) would not wait indefinitely.
Meanwhile, Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif tweeted: "We're working hard, but not rushed, to get the job done."
The pace at which sanctions are lifted is a major issue at talks in Vienna.
Pressure is mounting on world powers and Iran to reach a deal on its nuclear programme and avoid the issue becoming bogged down in the US Congress.
Congress has 30 days to review any agreement as long as it receives the text by midnight Washington time (04:00 GMT on Friday). Failing that the review period will be 60 days, which will delay the lifting of US sanctions.
'Critical time'
"We're here because we believe we are making real progress," Mr Kerry told reporters in the Austrian capital Vienna on Thursday.
But he cautioned that "we are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever" and that he was prepared to "call an end" to nuclear talks with Iran if  "tough decisions" are not made.
"We also recognise that we shouldn't get up and leave simply because the clock strikes midnight. And I emphasise, given that the work here is incredibly technical and that the stakes are very very high, we will not rush and we will not be rushed."
Mr Kerry said that any deal had to withstand the test of time.
"It is not a test of a matter of days or weeks or months, it's a test for decades, that's our goal here."
Iranian FM Mohammad Javad Zarif (left) said he wanted to reach a deal
Mr Kerry (left) - on crutches - could be seen in deep conversation in the garden of the Palais Coburg, the hotel where the talks are being held
Mr Zarif, who leads the Iranian negotiators, earlier said he wanted to reach a deal. And he added on his Twitter page: "Mark my words; you can't change horses in the middle of a stream."
Separately, French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said he would be staying in Vienna to continue the negotiations, saying that "things are going in the right direction".
EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini described the talks as "sometimes heated" but overall "constructive".
The White House has said that it is unlikely that the talks will go on for many more weeks. A 30 June deadline imposed by both sides has already been missed.
The P5+1 and Iran are still believed to differ in three key areas - international inspections of Iran's non-nuclear sites, sanctions, and how Iran's compliance will be verified.
Iran also wants a UN Security Council arms embargo to be scrapped - something the US has ruled out.
World powers want to be satisfied that Iran is neither trying to develop a nuclear bomb, nor has the capability to do so in under at least a year. Iran insists its nuclear programme is for purely peaceful purposes.
The two sides have already overrun self-imposed deadlines in pursuit of a final deal on Iran's nuclear programme
If Congress rejects the deal, President Barack Obama can use his power of veto, but Congress can still overturn this. An extended review could help opposition to a deal build in the Republican-controlled legislature.
Under an interim accord, Iran and the P5+1 agreed that crippling sanctions would be eased in return for curbs on Iran's nuclear programme.
Both sides at the Vienna talks said they hoped for progress on Thursday, though there has been little concrete sign of a breakthrough.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:18:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US data breach 'hit 21.5m people'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33472585#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Hackers that breached US government databases stole the personal information of at least 21.5 million people, officials reveal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hackers 'stole data of millions of US government workers'
9 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
OPM serves as the human resource department for the US government
Hackers that breached US government databases stole the personal information of at least 21.5 million people, officials said on Thursday.
Those affected include government job applicants, federal contractors, and over a million of their partners, the Office of Personnel Management said.
The figure is more than five times higher than the number of people that were feared to have been affected.
The data breach, which came to light in April, was widely blamed on China.
Authorities in Beijing have publicly denied any involvement.
The breach prompted a series of hearings in Congress and widespread criticism of the state of US cyber defences.
Last month, officials said personnel records of 4.2 million current and former federal government employees had been stolen in an incident.
'No misuse yet'
On Thursday, OPM said that while investigating that breach they discovered additional information had also been compromised, including the social security numbers of 21.5 million individuals.
The stolen data also includes health and financial information, criminal records, and the names and addresses of government employees and their relatives.
Those affected include 19.7 million people who underwent background checks and 1.8 million others, mostly the partners of job applicants.
OPM serves as the human resource department for the US government. The agency issues security clearances and compiles records of all federal government employees.
The agency said that it had "no information at this time to suggest any misuse or further dissemination of the information that was stolen from OPM's systems."
But it said that for anyone who underwent a background investigation in 2000 or afterwards "it is highly likely that the individual is impacted by this cyber breach."
Last month, US intelligence chief James Clapper said China was the "leading suspect" in the massive data breaches.
His comments came after three days of high-level talks in which China and the US agreed to a "code of conduct" on cyber security issues.
Earlier this week, US Democratic presidential hopeful Hillary Clinton said China was "trying to hack into everything that doesn't move in America".
China has dismissed claims of involvement as "irresponsible and unscientific".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:04:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK urges Britons to leave Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33469718#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>All British nationals are being urged to leave Tunisia as "a further terrorist attack is highly likely", Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia attack: UK tourists advised to leave country
9 July 2015
From the section UK
All British nationals are being urged to leave Tunisia because "a further terrorist attack is highly likely", Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond says.
Thirty Britons were among 38 tourists killed in a gunman's attack on 26 June.
The Foreign Office estimates 2,500 to 3,000 UK tourists are in Tunisia and a few hundred British residents.
There is no specific threat, but travel firms are seeking to fly Britons out over the next few days and some are repatriating their British staff.
The Foreign Office is advising against all non-essential travel to Tunisia.
The FCO said that although the Tunisian authorities had put in place more security measures since the June attack , these did not "provide adequate protection for British tourists".
It said in its updated advice that tour operators were arranging additional flights back to the UK.
Britons are urged to get in touch with their tour operators, with those travelling independently advised to return on commercial flights.
Tunisia declared a state of emergency after the 26 June attack, which happened in the popular resort of Port El Kantaoui, just north of Sousse.
Witnesses described how a gunman, identified as Tunisian student Seifeddine Rezgui, opened fire at tourists on sunloungers outside the five-star Hotel Rui Imperial Marhaba.
Plans to build a wall along Tunisia's border with Libya to counter the threat from militants were announced earlier this week.
Mr Hammond said: "While we do not have any information suggesting a specific or imminent threat, since the attack in Sousse the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably, leading us to the view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely."
He said the Tunisian investigation into the Sousse attack and the attack on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March was ongoing.
Mr Hammond said an assessment of the security measures in tourist areas found that more work was needed "to effectively protect tourists from the terrorist threat".
Thirty of the victims of the 26 June attack were British
The Association of British Travel Agents (Abta) said those due to travel to Tunisia should contact the company they had booked through.
Travelling to Tunisia now would be likely to invalidate travel insurance policies, but most policies would provide cover for those currently in the country, it added.
Victoria Bacon, from the association, said: "All Abta members... who have customers in the region have now come forward and made a commitment to get their customers out within the next 24-48 hour period."
'I don't want to leave'
A tourist walks along the beach in Sousse near flowers left for the victims
One British tourist who arrived in Tunisia the day before the Foreign Office changed its advice said she was "shocked and disappointed" that she had to leave.
Heidi Barlow, from Derbyshire, is on holiday in Hammamet with her mother. They were due to stay until 19 July but were told about the warning to leave from friends and family in the UK.
The 34-year-old said: "I don't want to leave. I appreciate that if we have to go, we have to go, but I am not worried by the advice.
"We have these threats in Britain anyway. People have saved up their money and want to get on with their holiday."
She added: "We have seen all the extra security here and we feel very secure."
Michelle Ayres, from Newmarket, Suffolk, is staying in Sousse having arrived there last Saturday for a week-long holiday.
She said there were "about 50 British people together all packed waiting to go", adding: "Someone said that there were 10 extra flights and buses being laid on, but we haven't heard anything more on that.
"We feel we are a lot safer in the hotel, as if we leave on these buses, you may as well put up a Union Jack on them.
"They are amazing here at the hotel and with all the extra security, we feel completely safe."
Abta said people who had booked a package holiday to Tunisia would be entitled to a refund or alternative holiday.
It said low numbers of British tourists were currently in Tunisia - 25,000 are usually expected at this time of year.
Simon Calder, travel editor at the Independent, told the BBC that it would have been a "very tough decision" for the Foreign Office to change its travel advice, because "it... says to the people behind the attack at Sousse, here you are, you've got a victory.
"You've effectively wiped out Tunisia's tourist industry - or at least a large part of it - for the rest of the summer.  That is going to cause economic mayhem."
Background and analysis
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:50:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mastercard fees 'harm consumers'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33457569#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>European Union officials accuse Mastercard of overcharging consumers and retailers, breaking competition rules.</Description>
        <MainBody>EU says Mastercard overcharges consumers and retailers
9 July 2015
From the section Business
European Union officials have accused Mastercard of overcharging consumers with the fees the company charges.
"We currently suspect Mastercard is artificially raising the costs of card payments," said the EU statement .
Those fees harm consumers and retailers in the EU, competition commissioner Margrethe Vestager said.
The credit card company said it was "working with the European Commission on the issue" and was preparing a formal response.
"Throughout this procedure we have kept the needs of both consumers and merchants in mind," Mastercard said.
The EU is focusing on what is known as 'interchange fees' - the fees retailers pay banks to process card payments.
Officials say they are concerned that Mastercard violates competition rules by requiring retailers to pay artificially inflated fees to process credit card transactions.
They say this practice leads to higher prices for retailers in the EU, which they then pass on to consumers.
The charges from the EU are part of a long-running investigation.
The maximum fine that the EU can impose for antitrust infringements is 10% of the company's annual sales, according to the EU.
A separate investigation into Visa's interchange fees is also being carried out by the EU.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:33:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN declares Yemen humanitarian pause</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33458843#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The United Nations says a humanitarian ceasefire will be introduced in Yemen on Friday and will last until the end of Ramadan.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen crisis: UN says humanitarian pause to start on Friday
9 July 2015
From the section Middle East
The UN says 80% of Yemen's 25m people need some form of humanitarian aid
The United Nations says a humanitarian ceasefire will be introduced in Yemen on Friday and will last until the end of the Islamic holy month of Ramadan.
More than 3,000 people have been killed since a Saudi-led coalition began an air campaign in March to drive back Houthi rebels and restore the government.
Aid agencies say a blockade on Yemen means it is facing a humanitarian disaster.
Ramadan is expected to end on 17 July.
UN spokesman Stephane Dujarric said: "It is imperative and urgent that humanitarian aid can reach all vulnerable people of Yemen unimpeded and through an unconditional humanitarian pause."
The pause will come into effect at 23:59 local time (20:59 GMT) on Friday.
The UN says little of the promised financial aid for Yemen has materialised
On Tuesday, the UN announced that at least 1,528 civilians were among the 3,000 dead.
Another one million civilians have been displaced by the conflict and more than 80% of Yemen's 25 million people now need some form of humanitarian aid.
Charities say a lack of fuel in Yemen is making it difficult to reach those in need and to provide adequate care in hospitals.
The coalition allowed a five-day humanitarian ceasefire in May , but much of the aid promised to those in need has failed to materialise.
The UN said that it had received only 13% of the $1.6bn (1bn) needed for its aid operation in Yemen since launching an appeal last month.
Saudi Arabia has pledged $274m, but none of the money has yet materialised.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:45:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia top threat, US general says</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33469369#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A general in line for the highest US military post says Russia's recent actions are "nothing short of alarming".</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia is top threat to national security, US general says
9 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Gen Dunford said it would be "reasonable" to provide lethal weapons to Ukraine's government
A general in line for the highest US military post says Russia poses the greatest threat to national security.
During his confirmation hearing to become chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, Marine Gen Joseph Dunford called Russia's recent actions "nothing short of alarming".
Relations between the US and Russia have deteriorated since Russia annexed Ukraine's Crimea region last year.
A pro-Russian insurgency in eastern Ukraine has also prompted US sanctions.
"So if you want to talk about a nation that could pose an existential threat to the United States, I'd have to point to Russia." Gen Dunford told senators on Thursday.
Some US lawmakers have pushed for the military to provide lethal weapons to Ukraine's government, a move Gen Dunford called "reasonable".
"Frankly, without that kind of support, they are not going to be able to defend themselves against Russian aggression," Gen Dunford said.
Thus far the US has only provided non-lethal equipment and training for Ukrainian forces.
More than 6,000 people have been killed in fighting in Ukraine, which began in April 2014, between government forces and pro-Russian rebels in the eastern Donetsk and Luhansk regions.
Russia denies arming the rebels or sending troops there.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:39:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Srebrenica victims' bodies returned</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33468328#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The bodies of dozens of victims of the Srebrenica massacre are taken back to the Bosnian town for burial.</Description>
        <MainBody>Srebrenica massacre: Victims' bodies return for burial
9 July 2015
From the section Europe
Relatives of some of the newly-identified victims gathered as the coffins were loaded
The bodies of dozens of victims of the Srebrenica massacre are being taken back to the Bosnian town for burial.
The killing of some 8,000 Muslim men and boys in July 1995 by Bosnian Serb troops was the worst massacre in Europe since World War Two.
A service to bury 136 newly-identified victims will take place on Saturday, 20 years to the day since the massacre began.
Another 6,241 victims have already been identified.
A truck carrying the newly-identified remains left a mortuary in Visoko, near Sarajevo, early on Thursday.
Relatives of the victims cried as coffins were put on board.
On Wednesday, Russia vetoed a UN resolution calling the killings "genocide"
Crowds also lined the streets of the capital. Sarajevo, as the truck passed
Among them was Hafiza Tihic, 60, whose father Ramiz was among the victims.
"I don't know how he was killed, but I remember the moment when he was separated from us," she told AFP.
"I entered a bus and he was put to one side. What did they do to him later? Only they would know," she said, referring to Bosnian Serb forces.
Crowds also lined the streets of Sarajevo as the coffins passed through the Bosnian capital.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:26:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drone 'kills senior IS commander'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33466254#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A top Islamic State commander has been killed in a drone strike in eastern Afghanistan earlier this week, Afghan security officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Senior IS commander in Afghanistan 'killed by a drone'
9 July 2015
From the section Asia
Shahidullah Shahid was a spokesman for the Pakistani Taliban before defecting to Islamic State
A third senior Islamic State (IS) commander was killed in a drone strike earlier this week in east Afghanistan, Afghan intelligence officials say.
Shahidullah Shahid was a former member of the Pakistani Taliban who defected to the IS group, they say. He is believed to have had several aliases.
There has been no independent confirmation of his death.
The BBC's David Loyn in Kabul says that Shahid was a former spokesman for the Pakistani Taliban.
He was the most prominent of a group of fighters who appeared in a video in January, apparently filmed in Pakistan, pledging allegiance to the self-styled Islamic State.
Intelligence officials say that he was killed in the same drone strike on Tuesday which also killed another senior IS commander and scores of militants.
Fighting in Nangarhar province has displaced thousands of people
A three-way battle is raging in Nangarhar between the security forces, the Taliban and Islamic State militants
Our correspondent says that at least two other senior IS members in addition to Shahid have also been killed in drone strikes - showing that, while the remaining international forces in Afghanistan are not engaged in combat, they are taking seriously the reports of the emergence of the militant group.
The police chief of Nangarhar province confirmed on Thursday that Shahid had been killed in Tuesday's drone strike. However there has been no word from Nato - the only force capable of launching drone attacks in the area.
Nangarhar has seen an upsurge of fighting in recent weeks, mostly between IS and the Taliban, forcing thousands of people to flee their homes.
The province borders lawless areas inside Pakistan, and is one of the areas where IS militants are most active in Afghanistan.
"[Shahid] wanted to expand IS's operation in the country and with his death, it will have an impact on their activities," Afghanistan National Directorate of Security spokesman Hasib Sediqi told Reuters.
The security forces say that they are making gains against militants in Nangarhar province, which is reported to have seen heavy fighting in recent months
He said that Shahid was killed along with Gul Zaman - another senior IS commander- and as many as 49 other IS militants in the Achin district of Nangarhar province, where they have recently gained ground after pushing back the Taliban.
Afghanistan's spy agency, the National Directorate of Security, recently released a video on Facebook showing how its special forces were fighting against the IS threat.
IS first made its presence felt in Pakistan in April, when its regional spokesman claimed their fighters had shot dead three Pakistani soldiers.
Shahidullah Shahid
A spokesman for the Pakistani Taliban (TTP), he was sacked in October 2014 after pledging allegiance to Islamic State - the third TTP spokesman to part company with the leadership in recent months
His sacking was the latest sign of divisions in an already fragmented militant movement which over the years has comprised a bewildering array of splinter groups and factions, the BBC's M Ilyas Khan reported
A TTP statement at the time of his dismissal said that Shahidullah Shahid was a nom de guerre and its former spokesman's real name was Sheikh Maqbool
A senior TTP leader also confirmed to a BBC correspondent at the time that Shahid and five other senior figures had defected because they had doubts about the leadership of Mullah Mohammad Omar
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:27:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>S Carolina rebel flag to come down</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33457169#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The South Carolina House has voted to take down the Confederate flag from capitol grounds after a long and fractious debate.</Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate flag to be removed from South Carolina capitol
9 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
comments
The flag is seen by some as an icon of slavery while others say it symbolises US heritage
The House of Representatives in South Carolina has voted to take down the Confederate flag from capitol grounds after a long and fractious debate.
After a final procedural vote, the bill was then signed by Republican Governor Nikki Haley later on Thursday.
The flag will be removed at 10:00 ET (14:00 GMT) on Friday, according to Ms Haley's office.
Meanwhile, Republican leaders in Congress have called for talks on the flying of the flag across the US.
Republicans in the US House of Representatives cancelled a vote on Thursday on a measure that would have defended the flying of the banner in cemeteries operated by the National Park Service.
The backlash against the emblem grew when a gunman killed nine black people at a Charleston church last month.
Dylann Roof, the 21-year-old charged with the killings, was pictured holding the flag.
The flag - used by the South in the American Civil War (1860-65) - is seen by some as an icon of slavery and racism while others say it symbolises US heritage and history.
'Insult to injury'
The House vote was taken early on Thursday morning after 13 hours of debate and passed 93-27.
During a heated session, dozens of amendments by Republicans aimed at slowing down passage of the bill were rejected.
Some Republicans argued the flag was part of US history that had been "hijacked" by racists.
Analysis: Nick Bryant, BBC News, South Carolina
The flag debate has been heated on both sides
The dramatic vote came after more than 13 hours of impassioned, angry and sometimes tearful debate. In pleading with her fellow lawmakers to bring down the controversial battle flag, one Republican even reminded colleagues that she was a descendant of the Confederate President Jefferson Davis.
But it is South Carolina's recent history that has transformed this debate and in particular the pictures which emerged after last month's Charleston massacre showing the alleged killer Dylann Roof brandishing a flag long seen as a symbol of slavery, segregation and black subordination.
South Carolina was where the first shots of the Civil War rang out. Given the passions still aroused by that conflict in parts of the American south, it's tempting to see this historic vote almost as a final surrender.
Representative Mike Pitts said the flag was a reminder of how poor farmers had fought the Union not to support slavery but to protect their land rights.
Chris Corley proposed replacing the emblem with a white flag of surrender, saying: "Maybe that will make everybody happy."
But fellow Republican representative Jenny Horne, a descendant of Confederate President Jefferson Davis, recalled the funeral of state Senator Clementa Pinckney, who was killed in the Charleston attack, and said there should be no stalling on the removal of the flag.
She said: "For the widow of Sen Pinckney and his two young daughters, that would be adding insult to injury and I will not be a part of it!"
Democratic Party Representative Joe Neal said: "South Carolina can remove the stain from our lives. I never thought in my lifetime I would see this."
The Confederate flag was originally the battle emblem of the southern states in the American Civil War which tried to break away.
South Carolina was the first state to leave the union in 1860. It restored the flag in the capitol grounds more than 50 years ago in protest at the civil rights movement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:38:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkey police pepper spray protesters</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33457401#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Turkish police fire pepper spray at pro-Uighur demonstrators outside the Chinese embassy in Ankara, hours after violence hit the Thai consulate.</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkish police hit pro-Uighur protesters with pepper spray
9 July 2015
Protesters in Ankara were hit with pepper spray after pushing a police barricade
Turkish police have fired pepper spray at pro-Uighur demonstrators outside the Chinese embassy in Ankara.
It comes after protesters attacked the Thai consulate in Istanbul following the deportation from Thailand of about 100 Uighurs to China.
Rights groups have criticised such deportations, saying Uighurs face persecution in China.
Turkey has seen growing anger at Chinese discrimination against Uighurs, who are ethnically Turkic Muslims.
But China has said it respects the freedom of Muslim beliefs.
On Thursday, close to 100 people were dispersed by pepper spray outside the Chinese embassy in the Turkish capital after a barricade was knocked down.
Thai officials said protesters stormed their compound in Istanbul late on Wednesday night. No injuries were reported.
The Royal Thai Embassy in Turkey advised Thais in Turkey to not to show the national symbol or flag in public, to avoid protest venues and to "refrain from mentioning or arguing with the Turkish" on the issue of Uighurs.
On Thursday, the Thai government confirmed that about 100 Uighurs had been sent back to China the day before.
Government spokesman Weerachon Sukondhapatipak said Thailand had verified that the Uighurs were Chinese nationals before returning them, but it is unclear how their nationality was confirmed.
Thailand's Prime Minister Prayuth Chan-ocha said: "If we don't do it this way, then how would we do it?
"Or do you want us to keep them for ages until they have children for three generations?"
Thursday's protests were the latest in a number of anti-China demonstrations in Turkey
Human Rights Watch's Asia deputy director Phil Robertson said the Uighurs sent to China "will likely face torture". Rights groups have criticised Cambodia and Thailand for deporting Uighurs to China, saying they face persecution, abuse and human rights violations.
Turkey has seen increased protests and isolated attacks on tourists thought to be Chinese over China's treatment of Uighurs.
The latest spike of anti-Chinese sentiment began over allegations that Uighurs in China had been banned from fasting during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. But China has denied such reports.
In previous years, students have told the BBC they have been prohibited from taking part in Ramadan fasts, and government departments have restricted civil servants .
Many of China's Uighurs are based in the far western province of Xinjiang, which has seen increased tensions and conflict between Uighurs and authorities in recent years.
Who are the Uighurs?
Uighurs are ethnically Turkic Muslims
They make up about 45% of the Xinjiang region's population; 40% are Han Chinese
China re-established control in 1949 after crushing short-lived state of East Turkestan
Since then, there has been large-scale immigration of Han Chinese and Uighurs fear erosion of their culture
Xinjiang is officially designated an autonomous region within China, like Tibet to its south
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:48:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israeli jailed over Madonna hack</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33463464#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An Israeli man is jailed for 14 months in Tel Aviv for hacking the computers of singers including Madonna.</Description>
        <MainBody>Madonna hack: Israeli man jailed
9 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Madonna said the hack was 'a deeply devastating and hurtful experience'
An Israeli man has been jailed for 14 months in Tel Aviv for hacking the computers of singers including Madonna.
Adi Lederman, 39, was arrested in January after an investigation assisted by the FBI.
Under a plea bargain, Mr Lederman confessed to computer trespassing, infringement of privacy and property rights.
Madonna was forced to rush-release six songs from her new album after they were leaked online in December.
Although the singer was one of Mr Lederman's victims, the court did not specify he was behind the leak from her Rebel Heart record.
'Deeply devastating'
"The ease with which crimes such as this can be committed by those who have skills in the field, such as the accused, require an appropriate punitive response that has a deterrent and uncompromising message," the court said.
Mr Lederman, who was also fined 15,000 (2,600) shekels,  previously made a brief appearance on A Star Is Born - Israel's version of American Idol - before being voted off the show.
The court statement on Thursday said he had medical problems that had mitigated his sentence.
Madonna was forced release six new songs months earlier than planned after demos and unfinished mixes made their way online.
At the time she said the crime was an "invasion into my life - creatively, professionally and personally [that] remains a deeply devastating and hurtful experience".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:18:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tom Selleck 'stole water for ranch'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33455746#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Actor Tom Selleck is accused of stealing water in parched California by raiding a public hydrant for his avocado ranch.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tom Selleck 'stole water for ranch'
9 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Tom Selleck is accused of taking the water over the past two years
Actor Tom Selleck has been accused of stealing water for his ranch in parched California by raiding a public hydrant.
The Calleguas Municipal Water District in Ventura County claims a tanker truck filled up more than a dozen times over the past two years.
It said the water was delivered to the Magnum PI star's nearby 60-acre ranch, where he grows avocados.
The district is seeking a court injunction preventing Selleck from taking any more water.
The legal case comes after California communities were ordered to cut water usage by 25% amid a four-year drought that has damaged the state's agriculture industry.
Cease-and-desist
In documents filed at Ventura Country Superior Court, the complaint said the Calleguas Municipal Water District spent nearly $22,000 (14,300) to hire a private investigator from 2013-15 to record the thefts.
The most recent incident was in March, when the same truck was spotted taking water in the town of Thousand Oaks and taking it to the actor's ranch in Westlake Village on four consecutive days.
The complaint added the location of the water hydrant was in a different area than the water district that serves the actor's ranch.
The district said it sent Selleck a cease-and-desist order in November 2013, warning it would take legal action if he did not stop taking the water.
In addition to the injunction, the district is also seeking to recoup its legal fees and investigative costs.
The Ventura County Sheriff's Department also investigated and was unable to establish a crime occurred, Capt John Reilly said.
Representatives for Selleck have yet to comment on the matter.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 09:42:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India rescues wandering baby rhino</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-33457592#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Indian wildlife authorities rescue a three-day-old baby rhinoceros wandering around the Kaziranga national park in Assam</Description>
        <MainBody>India baby rhino wandering in Kaziranga park rescued
9 July 2015
From the section India
Indian wildlife authorities have rescued a three-day-old baby rhinoceros wandering around the Kaziranga national park in the north-eastern state of Assam.
The 430 sq km (166 sq miles) park is home to the largest concentration of the world's remaining one-horned rhinoceros.
Pictures showed park staff members examining and then transporting the calf through the park.
It is not known where the calf's mother is, but poaching is a common problem in Kazaringa.
Local media estimate that 12 rhinoceros have been killed by poachers since January.
Kaziranga is home to the largest concentration of the world's remaining one-horned rhinoceros
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:37:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifa gives Blazer life football ban</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/33458803</Link>
        <Description>Fifa bans former executive committee member Chuck Blazer from all football-related activity for life.</Description>
        <MainBody>What about Fifa president Sepp Blatter?
In a transcript from a 2013 US hearing, the American pleaded guilty to 10 charges.
Blazer admitted he and others on the executive committee of football's world governing body agreed to accept bribes in connection with the choice of South Africa as 2010 World Cup hosts.
He said he also facilitated bribes over the 1998 event.
A document of his agreement with US prosecutors shows Blazer was secretly co-operating with them from December 2011.
The New York Daily News reported in 2014 that Blazer had bugged meetings with Fifa executives at the London 2012 Olympics with a wire device concealed in a key fob.
Fifa had suspended its investigation into Blazer because of his "ill health" but reopened it in December 2014, leading to his lifelong ban.
In its statement Fifa added: "The decision was taken on the basis of investigations carried out by the investigatory chamber of the ethics committee in response to the final report of the Concacaf integrity committee and the latest facts presented by the US Attorney's Office for the Eastern District of New York."
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:41:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore mayor sacks police chief</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33450854#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The mayor of Baltimore axes the city's police chief months after the US city was rocked by riots following the death of a black man in custody.</Description>
        <MainBody>Baltimore mayor sacks police chief months after riots
8 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Anthony Batts had led Baltimore's police force since October 2012
Baltimore's mayor has sacked the US city's police chief, saying his leadership had become a distraction from fighting a "crime surge".
Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake said she was replacing Police Commissioner Anthony Batts with his deputy, Kevin Davis, for an interim period.
The city was rocked by riots in April when a black man died after suffering injuries in police custody.
Six officers were charged over the death of the 25-year-old, Freddie Gray.
Speaking at a news conference on Wednesday, Mayor Rawlings-Blake said Mr Batts had "served this city with distinction" since becoming police chief in October 2012.
But referring to the city's high homicide rate, she said "too many continue to die".
"The focus has been too much on the leadership of the department and not enough on the crime fighting," she told reporters, adding: "We need to get the crime surge under control."
The city has seen a sharp increase in violence since Freddie Gray's death on 19 April, with 155 homicides this year, a 48% increase over the same period last year.
On Tuesday, the police department announced that an outside organisation will review its response to the civil unrest that followed Mr Gray's death.
Freddie Gray's death followed several other cases where black men died after contact with the police
Police officers complained that they were poorly equipped and badly led during April's riots
The US justice department is also conducting a civil rights review of the Baltimore force and Mr Batts has been criticised by the city's police union.
Earlier on Wednesday, the union released its report into the police handling of the rioting.
It said officers had complained "that they lacked basic riot equipment, training, and, as events unfolded, direction from leadership".
The report also said "officers repeatedly expressed concern that the passive response to the civil unrest had allowed the disorder to grow into full scale rioting".
Recent events had "placed attention on police leadership", Ms Rawlings-Blake said, but denied her decision was influenced by the union report.
Mr Davis, who is taking over immediately as interim police chief, praised his "friend" Mr Batts and said he was a "true reform commissioner".
Mayor Rawlings-Blake said Mr Davis would "bring accountability to police, hold officers who act out of line accountable for their actions".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:16:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope focuses on poor in Bolivia</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33456627#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis speaks of the need to protect the vulnerable from capitalism, as he continues his tour of Latin America's poorest countries.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis focuses on poor in Bolivia
9 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Pope Francis was greeted by children and President Evo Morales as he landed in Bolivia
Pope Francis is visiting Bolivia, on the second leg of his tour of Latin America's three poorest countries.
After landing at La Paz airport, the pontiff spoke of the need to protect the most vulnerable in society from the impact of capitalism.
He was greeted by President Evo Morales, Bolivia's first indigenous leader, who gave him a ritual pouch with coca - a sacred leaf in the Andes.
The Pope flew in from Ecuador. He will also visit Paraguay.
'Double religion'
During the airport welcome ceremony, the pontiff praised Bolivia - a majority indigenous country - for encouraging the poor to be active citizens.
"Bolivia is making important steps towards including broad sectors in the country's economic, social and political life," he said.
Bolivia's national anthem was sung by President Evo Morales, an Aymara Indian, standing alongside Pope Francis
President Morales is a fan of Pope Francis, who he says shares many of his views on how capitalism leads to social inequalities, BBC regional analyst Candace Piette says.
But she says Mr Morales' government has for many years had an uneasy relationship with the Catholic Church.
After taking office in 2006, Mr Morales ordered the Bible and cross to be removed from the presidential palace - both symbols of colonial Spanish oppression.
A new constitution in 2009 made Bolivia a secular state, and Andean religious rituals replaced Catholic rites at official state ceremonies.
President Morales has said he is a Catholic but - like many Bolivians - he believes there is plenty of room for both Christianity and traditional belief.
"I remain convinced that we Bolivians have a double religion, double faith," he said in January.
Many of the faithful waited for hours in the bitter cold in their traditional dress for the arrival of the Pope
But Mr Morales' attitude to the church changed radically when Francis became pope. He visited him twice in Rome and invited him to come to Bolivia, our analyst says.
Before leaving for the lowland city of Santa Cruz, Pope Francis visited the site where the body of a Jesuit Bolivian priest was found.
The priest was tortured and murdered in 1980 during the military rule for defending the rights of Bolivia's mining community.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:22:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colombian rebels call ceasefire</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33450816#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Colombia's Farc rebels call a one-month unilateral ceasefire starting on 20 July, but the government says more needs to be done.</Description>
        <MainBody>Colombia Farc rebels call unilateral ceasefire
8 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
The ceasefire will come into force on 20 July, the Farc announced in Cuba
Colombia's Farc rebels have announced a one-month unilateral ceasefire.
The Farc has been taking part in peace talks with the Colombian government since 2012, but violence has increased in recent weeks.
The Farc's chief negotiator at the talks in Cuba, Ivan Marquez, said he hoped the ceasefire, starting on 20 July, could lead to a bilateral truce.
The government welcomed the move but gave no sign it would do likewise and said the rebels needed to do more.
"We appreciate the gesture of a unilateral ceasefire by the Farc but more is needed, especially concrete commitments to speed up the negotiations," President Juan Manuel Santos said on Twitter (in Spanish).
For his part, Mr Marquez said the truce would "create favourable conditions in order to advance with the opposing side toward a bilateral and definitive ceasefire."
Hostilities with the Colombian military have escalated recently
Four countries helping to facilitate the peace talks - Cuba, Norway, Chile and Venezuela - issued a call on Tuesday for a de-escalation in the violence.
A previous Farc ceasefire was called in December, but clashes resumed in April with the killing of 11 soldiers and subsequent bombing raids on rebel positions.
Farc suspended that unilateral ceasefire on 22 May.
Since the ceasefire ended, several dozen rebels and soldiers have been killed.
In June, the group blew up an oil pipeline, which contaminated water and left at least 16,000 people without supplies in the municipality of Catatumbo in the north.
The talks in Havana, which began in November 2012, are aimed at ending more than 50 years of conflict. More than 200,000 people have been killed since hostilities started in 1964.
Negotiations have continued despite the violence, and agreement has been reached on several points.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:56:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uganda presidential rivals detained</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33459274#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Two leading presidential hopefuls are arrested in Uganda for organising meetings without police permission, state media report.</Description>
        <MainBody>Uganda's Amama Mbabazi and Kizza Besigye arrested
9 July 2015
From the section Africa
Amama Mbabazi was sacked as prime minister in 2014 after three years in the job
Two leading presidential hopefuls have been arrested in Uganda for organising meetings without police permission, state media report.
Amama Mbabazi was arrested in eastern Jinja town, while Kizza Besigye was detained at his home in the capital, the New Vision newspaper said.
Both are former close allies of President Yoweri Museveni.
He is widely expected to seek re-election next year, but this has not been confirmed.
Last month, Mr Mbabazi said he would challenge Mr Museveni, 70, by seeking the nomination of the ruling National Resistance Movement (NRM) party.
Mr Mbabazi was held in a police station in Kampala
Mr Museveni sacked Mr Mbabazi as prime minister last year, ending a close working relationship of more than 20 years.
Mr Mbabazi was arrested in Jinja as he headed out to canvass support in the eastern town of Mbale, reports the BBC's Patience Atuhaire from Kampala.
Renegade army General David Sejusa was at the police station in Kampala where Mr Mbabazi was being held to show solidarity with him, she adds.
His daughter has also been arrested, his spokesperson Josephine Mayanja-Nkangi says.
She also says no charges have been brought against him.
On Wednesday, police said Mr Mbabazi had not been cleared to hold meetings.
Dr Besigye, the former physician of Mr Museveni, is seeking the presidential nomination of the opposition Forum for Democratic Change (FDC) party.
Mr Museveni has ruled Uganda since 1986, and his critics say he has become increasingly repressive.
However, his supporters say he has provided stability and has improved the living standards of Ugandans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:10:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mozambique lion population 'grows'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33469042#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Lion numbers at Mozambique's largest game reserve have risen - partly because they feed on elephants killed by poachers, a conservationist says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mozambique lion numbers 'grow as elephants poached'
9 July 2015
From the section Africa
Lions are found in most countries in sub-Saharan Africa
The lion population at Mozambique's largest game reserve has risen partly because they are feeding on elephants killed by poachers, a conservationist has told the BBC.
Lions at the Niassa National Reserve also prey on baby elephants orphaned by poachers, Colleen Begg said.
Poachers kill the elephants to remove their tusks but leave the carcasses.
There is huge demand in Asia for tusks, which are used for medicinal purposes and as ornaments.
Mrs Begg, who heads the Niassa Carnivore Project, told the BBC the number of lions at the game reserve had increased over the last decade to between 800 and 1,000.
"The death of 6,000-7,000 elephants since 2011 has resulted in a large amount of meat that was previously unavailable," she said.
"In 2009, we recorded our first calf eaten by lions and this has also steadily increased as these are orphans that are easy to catch," she added.
The heavy poaching of elephants has benefited lions whose populations increase quickly if there is more food, Mrs Begg said.
On average, a lion eats up to seven kilograms (15 pounds) of meat a day while a female elephant provides them with 3,500 kg, she added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 13:17:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China shares surge in volatile trade</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33456768#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Mainland Chinese shares rebound after regulators make fresh efforts to calm the volatile market.</Description>
        <MainBody>China stock market surges in volatile session
9 July 2015
From the section Business
China's market regulator has introduced a string of new rules to try to relieve pressure on Chinese shares
Mainland Chinese shares rebounded on Thursday after regulators took further steps to try to calm the stock market.
The Shanghai Composite index reversed earlier losses to close up 5.76%, its biggest percentage gain since 2009.
A move to ban big investors from selling stocks may have helped to support the market, analysts said.
Meanwhile, the state-run news agency Xinhua said police were investigating "vicious short-selling" on the country's stock market.
Xinhua said authorities would "crack down" on operations that had broken the laws and regulations related to trading.
The benchmark Shanghai index closed up 202.14 points at 3,709.33.
Relieving pressure
China's market regulator has introduced a string of new rules in the past week to try to relieve pressure on Chinese shares. The Shanghai Composite has fallen by more than 30% since mid-June.
On Wednesday, the Shanghai Composite fell as much as 8.2%, leading some analysts to describe the session as 'Black Wednesday'.
In the latest efforts to try and stem the falling markets, Beijing has relaxed lending rules - making it easier for people to borrow money for investment - in the hope that they will buy more stocks. That follows a move late on Wednesday to ban investors holding stakes of more than 5% in companies from selling shares in the next six months.
Meanwhile, about 1,300 firms have halted trading in their stocks to prevent the value of their businesses falling further.
Analysis: John Sudworth, BBC News, Shanghai
The latest measure to be unveiled by the Chinese regulator is a ban on investors who hold more than 5% of any stock from selling it for six months.
It is an extraordinary restriction, but coupled with all the other government-backed efforts to shore up prices in the face of China's massive slump, it may have finally brought some stability.
That said, around half of all listed companies have voluntarily suspended trading, so it could be argued that the market is, in effect, as much seizing up as it is stabilising.
Analysts are divided over the extent to which the dramatic unwinding of China's massive lending-fuelled stock market boom poses a threat to the wider economy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 08:48:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India girl 'sold for sex' by parents</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-33456885#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Police in the southern Indian state of Kerala arrest the mother and stepfather of a teenage girl for allegedly forcing her into the sex trade.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kerala: India 13-year-old girl 'sold for sex' by parents
By Ashraf Padanna Trivandrum
From the section India
There have been several protests against rape in India
Police in the southern Indian state of Kerala have arrested the mother and stepfather of a teenage girl for allegedly forcing her into the sex trade for two years.
The 13-year-old has been rescued and taken to a state-run shelter home.
She has told counsellors that her parents would solicit customers and force her to have sex with the men.
Her mother has told a news channel that she would charge 3,000 rupees (30; $47) from a customer for her daughter.
Police said they had identified 25 of the 40 customers who had allegedly paid for sex with the teenager.
Ten others, including a broker, have also been arrested in connection with the case.
The 37-year-old mother has seven children - the oldest is 24 years old and the youngest is aged four.
The girl's mother is among a dozen people arrested so far
Her 55-year-old husband worked as a driver and would solicit customers showing the girl's photograph, police said.
The family lived in a rented house in the town of Kottakal in Malappuram district in the north of the state.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:04:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia vetoes Bosnia genocide motion</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33445772#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Russia vetoes a draft UN Security Council resolution describing the 1995 Srebrenica massacre of Muslim men and boys as "genocide".</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia vetoes UN move to call Srebrenica 'genocide'
8 July 2015
From the section Europe
Srebrenica was the worst massacre in Europe since World War Two
Russia has vetoed a United Nations Security Council resolution that would have described the Srebrenica massacre as "genocide".
Four other members of the council abstained while the remainder voted in favour.
The killing of some 8,000 Muslim men and boys in 1995 by Bosnian Serb troops was the worst massacre in Europe since World War Two.
The motion had angered Serbia, which rejects the term.
It had been drafted to mark the 20th anniversary of the atrocity, which came amid the bloody break-up of Yugoslavia into independent states.
During the Bosnian War, which saw Serbia-backed Bosnian Serb forces fighting the Muslim-led Bosnian government, thousands seeking shelter at what was supposed to be a UN refuge were slaughtered.
The resolution said that "acceptance of the tragic events at Srebrenica as genocide is a prerequisite for reconciliation".
But Russia's UN Ambassador Vitaly Churkin said adopting it "would be counter-productive, would lead to greater tension in the region".
The vote had been put back a day to allow the US and the UK - which drafted the resolution - to try to persuade Russia not to veto it.
The Serbian President, Tomislav Nikolic, called it a "great day" for his country, the AFP agency reported.
Serbia does not have a seat on the Security Council, and had asked ally Russia to block the resolution, warning it would be divisive.
The US ambassador to the UN, Samantha Power, said: "Russia's veto is heart-breaking for those families and it is a further stain on this council's record."
A UN tribunal at The Hague has already convicted numerous people of genocide in relation to the Srebrenica killings, but a formal recognition by the UN could compel individual states to pursue prosecutions.
Have you or your family been affected by this story? If you are willing to share your stories please get in touch and leave a phone number if you are willing to be contacted by a BBC journalist.
MMS and SMA 61124 or international +44 7624 800 100
WhatsApp +44 7525 900971
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:26:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Belgium rescues 200 Syria Christians</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33439875#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Some 240 people, mainly Christians, have been brought out of Syria's second city of Aleppo and taken to Belgium in a secret, two-month operation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria conflict: Belgium rescues 200 Aleppo Christians
8 July 2015
From the section Europe
Before the war, Aleppo had one of the biggest Christian communities in the Middle East
Some 240 people, mainly Christians, have been brought out of Syria's second city of Aleppo and taken to Belgium, the government in Brussels says.
All the families had fled their homes and were at risk of repeated human rights abuse, a spokesman told the BBC.
Civil society groups helped take the families to safety in Lebanon.
Aleppo has been devastated by three years of fierce fighting between Syrian government forces, rebels and jihadist militants.
Before the war, it had a Christian population of around 160,000, one of the biggest in the Middle East.
The refugees, who included Yazidis as well as Christians, were moved out along the only open road from Aleppo to the Lebanese border.
The operation took place over two months and amid great secrecy. Belgium is one of several European countries that have come under pressure to help Christians and other religious minorities in Syria threatened with persecution.
"We did it via civil society organisations which could get them out of there," a foreign ministry spokesman said.
Few other details have been revealed, but the spokesman said some of the families had connections with people already in Belgium.
They were met on the Lebanese border by representatives from the Belgian embassy in Beirut with the help of the NGOs and have now all arrived in Belgium.
The families are now expected to be granted asylum in Belgium.
Belgium has until now only offered asylum to Syrian refugees through the United Nations, national media report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 10:34:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Four million have fled Syria - UN</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33457886#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Four million Syrians have fled abroad to escape the war in their country, the UN says, calling it "the worst humanitarian crisis of our generation".</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria conflict: Number of refugees passes four million
9 July 2015
From the section Middle East
Turkey is home to the the largest number of Syrians refugees
More than four million Syrians - a sixth of the population - have fled abroad to escape the conflict in their country, the United Nations has said.
A surge in the number of people crossing into Turkey has increased the total by one million in just 10 months.
More than seven million others have been displaced inside Syria since the start of the uprising in March 2011.
The head of the UN's refugee agency, Antonio Guterres, called it the "worst humanitarian crisis of our generation".
The refugee crisis is the largest resulting from a single conflict in nearly a quarter of a century.
More than 230,000 people have also been killed in the past four years, activists say.
'Terrible situation'
The UN High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) said Turkey is home to the largest number of Syrians refugees - 1.8 million - and is reportedly preparing for a new influx as the conflict escalates near the border between the countries.
Another 1.2 million people have fled to Lebanon and 629,000 to Jordan.
Many have also attempted the perilous boat crossing to Europe. Syrians made up about a third of the 137,000 migrants who crossed the Mediterranean in the first half of 2015.
In all, about 270,000 Syrians have sought asylum in Europe.
Mr Guterres told the BBC that Europe would need to help more as the crisis worsened.
"We despair not knowing what to do with the more and more civilians risking their lives, moving onwards," he said.
"This is a human drama. This is a terrible situation for the region but this is becoming also something that we'll ask Europe to fully assume its responsibilities."
The UNHCR said that if Syrians continued to flee at the same pace it expected the number of refugees in neighbouring countries to reach 4.27 million by the end of 2015.
The agency has received less than a quarter of the $5.5bn (3.6bn) it says it needs this year to help Syrian refugees and the countries hosting them.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:26:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israeli PM warns Hamas on 'captives'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33457803#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Israel's prime minister says he holds Hamas responsible for the fate of two Israeli citizens believed held in Gaza.</Description>
        <MainBody>Israeli PM warns Hamas over two Israelis 'held in Gaza'
9 July 2015
From the section Middle East
Israel's defence ministry says Mr Mangisto "independently crossed the security fence into the Gaza Strip"
Israel's prime minister says he holds Hamas responsible for the fate of two Israeli citizens believed held in Gaza.
Benjamin Netanyahu said Israel was working to secure their safe return.
Israel said it believes one, an Ethiopian Israeli, was being held by Hamas. An Israeli Arab is also being held in Gaza, defence officials say.
Hamas has not commented on either case. The group held an Israeli soldier for five years before being exchanging him for hundreds of prisoners in 2011.
The Islamist militant group has controlled Gaza since winning elections in 2006. It reinforced its power there in 2007 after ousting its political rivals, Fatah.
Israeli defence officials say Avraham Mangisto, of Ethiopian origin, went into the Palestinian territory of his own accord last September and has been missing since then.
Israel says it has appealed to international and regional bodies to help clarify Mr Mangisto's situation and are demanding his immediate release.
"According to credible intelligence, Mangisto is being held against his will by Hamas," a defence ministry statement said.
"Israel will continue to pursue the release and return of  the citizen to Israel," it added.
Israeli President Reuven Rivlin said it was a "painful situation" and that he was in contact with Mr Mangisto's family.
"This is a humanitarian issue, and we expect those holding him to behave accordingly and return him in good health," he said.
Netanyahu appeal
Mr Netanyahu called on the international community to help secure the men's release.
"I expect the international community, which expresses its concern over the humanitarian situation in Gaza, to issue a clear call for these citizens to be released and to see to their return," he said.
The Associated Press quoted an unnamed official as saying it was unclear why Mr Mangisto went into Gaza but that he was believed to be mentally unstable.
Israeli media said the 28-year-old, from Ashkelon, had breached the heavily-guarded security fence between Israel and Gaza.
Local media said the Israeli Arab being held in Gaza was a Bedouin from Israel's southern Negev desert. His name has not been released.
The defence ministry said he had crossed into Gaza several times before.
The two cases were cleared for publication on Thursday after a court lifted a gagging order.
In 2006, Sgt Shalit was captured in a cross-border raid by Hamas, triggering a crisis which was only resolved years later in a controversial exchange for more than 1,000 Palestinian prisoners held by Israel.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:34:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Osborne seeks to relax planning laws</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-33472405#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Automatic planning permission would be granted on many brownfield sites in England in an attempt to boost economic productivity, under government plans.</Description>
        <MainBody>Osborne seeks to relax planning laws
9 July 2015
From the section UK Politics
House-building targets are being missed
Automatic planning permission would be granted on many brownfield sites in England in an attempt to boost economic productivity, under government plans.
Ministers would also get new powers to make disused land available and would relax rules on extensions in London.
Chancellor George Osborne said reforms were needed because Britain had been "incapable of building enough homes".
It comes after the government was warned its Budget plans would cut investment in new homes.
The proposed changes feature in a 90-page document to address Britain's productivity record, to be released on Friday.
It also features proposals on higher education, transport and trade.
'Upwards extensions'
BBC political correspondent Ross Hawkins said Treasury sources argue house-building boosts productivity as it is helpful to have workers living close to their workplaces.
Housing is just one part of a broad plan, they say.
The term brownfield refers to land that has previously been built on.
George Osborne, seen visiting a building site in 2013, says reforms are needed to planning laws so more homes are built
Under the plans, which will need to be approved by MPs, automatic planning permission would be granted on all "suitable" brownfield sites under a new "zonal" system, the Treasury said.
Another change would see ministers seek to scrap the need for planning permission in London for developers who wanted to extend buildings to the height of neighbouring properties.
There would also be new sanctions for councils that do not deal with planning applications quickly enough, and the government would be able to intervene in councils' local development plans.
This week the Office for Budget Responsibility warned that government plans for rent reductions in social rented homes would hit housing investment.
The OBR said 14,000 fewer affordable homes would be built and cut its forecast for investment in private housing by 0.7%.
It also said house prices were expected to rise compared with both consumer prices and household incomes.
A Treasury source said the OBR assessment considered only the impact of the Budget and did not reflect the new policy.
In his Mansion House speech in June 2014, Mr Osborne said 200,000 permissions for new homes would be made possible by 2020 as councils put in place orders to provide sites with outline planning permission.
Housing ladder
The Treasury said the new plan goes further - in effect stripping away the need for any planning permission in some brownfield locations.
The Conservative manifesto pledged to "ensure that 90% of suitable brownfield sites have planning permission for housing by 2020".
In a statement released before the publication of the productivity plan, Mr Osborne said: "Britain has been incapable of building enough homes.
"The reforms we made to the planning system in the last parliament have started to improve the situation: planning permissions and housing starts are at a seven-year high.
"But we need to go further and I am not prepared to stand by when people who want to get on the housing ladder can't do so."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:14:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Strikes cause train and Tube chaos</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-33456830#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Tube and train strikes cause travel misery, with the entire London Underground network shut down and many rail services cancelled.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tube and train strikes: Commuters face travel disruption
9 July 2015
From the section London
Long queues formed for buses at Liverpool Street Station as commuters tried to get home
Tube and train strikes have caused misery for travellers, with the entire London Underground network shut down and many rail services cancelled.
London Overground, bus and boat services were much busier than usual.
London Underground (LU) has contacted the conciliation service Acas to set up fresh talks with unions which are on strike over pay and night services.
A separate strike at First Great Western hit travel between London, the West and Wales.
Many of the staff in the Tube strike have now ended their 24-hour action, but Tube services will not resume until Friday morning.
LU said its trains were in all the right places to minimise delays when services restart, but could not rule out some disruption, according to BBC London transport correspondent Tom Edwards.
People waited patiently for buses at Victoria Station to go home
Read about how Londoners took to social media to share their travel highs and lows
The rush hour started earlier than normal for the second consecutive day as workers made alternative arrangements to get home.
An extra 200 buses were laid on, as well as additional river services, said Transport for London (TfL). Cycle hire was said to be particularly busy.
LU chief operating officer Steve Griffiths thanked Londoners for their patience and said: "We are, as we always have been, ready to talk at any time to sort out this dispute."
The strike began at 18:30 BST on Wednesday when members of the Rail, Maritime and Transport (RMT) union, the Transport Salaried Staffs Association (TSSA) and Unite walked out.
At 21:30, members of the train drivers' union Aslef began their own 24-hour stoppage.
TSSA said earlier that it wanted further talks.
RMT general secretary Mick Cash said: "The strike action on London Underground is rock solid across all lines.
"That means an end to the attempt to bulldoze through new working patterns."
LU offered staff a 2% average pay rise plus a 2,000 one-off payment for drivers affected by a planned weekend night-time service.
Daniel, a train driver for LU, said the 2% rise was a good deal but he objected to the "point blank" way unions were asked to accept the deal within four hours.
He said he also he felt compelled to strike because he felt the introduction of the night Tube was premature.
"The assets are not good enough. The rolling stock constantly breaks down, which leads to trains being withdrawn from service."
Tom Edwards, BBC London transport correspondent
Tonight the industrial action for some of the unions finished at 18:30, but it'll be more of the same for commuters as there will be no Tube today . There might be some disruption even tomorrow.
But what about the dispute? It's still a long way from being sorted even though there's a pay deal on the table. Unions have concerns about more weekend and night working due to the night Tube and say its not about the money . And they say they support the night Tube.
Even the process of talking about the changes hasn't yet been agreed. Poor industrial relations from the last dispute over ticket office closures haven't helped and in the background the government is considering changing strike legislation.
There were longer queues for buses at Victoria station in the morning rush hour
All of this means the mayor and LU have conceded the start of the night Tube might slip. There is some hope though - one of the more moderate unions, the TSSA, has called for talks to start as soon as tomorrow . And sooner or later this will have to be resolved.
London Mayor Boris Johnson has refused to rule out a delay to the opening of night Tube services, which are at the centre of the dispute between unions and London Underground.
Asked whether he expected the 24-hour service to launch on 12 September as planned, Mr Johnson said: "We will get it done this autumn."
Lots of workers used the extra river boats to make their journeys
The Tube strike coincides with a separate 48-hour walkout by First Great Western staff , which began at 18:30 on Wednesday.
Wimbledon spectator attendance was lower than this time last year and officials have not ruled out whether the travel disruption was a contributing factor.
Just over 37,000 spectators were at the All England Club on Wednesday, compared with a record attendance of 40,477 in 2014.
Wimbledon crowd numbers are down on 2014
Tony, a  22-year-old LU customer service advisor
We are the first face that customers see and we regularly get lots of grief.
I was assaulted recently by a customer because we were enforcing a one-way barrier system. He grabbed me and started threatening me. I am not paid to put up with that abuse but it's a reality of the job.
Luckily for me there were other staff in the vicinity. Under the new night Tube plans I could be on my own. Not a week goes by that we don't have three calls to the British Transport Police but it can take them up to half an hour to get there so you are basically dealing with it by yourself.
We are seeing homeless people sleeping in stations, with 24-hour running and fewer members of station staff you are going to get more problems like that with drunk people.
We've been told there will be more police officers around, but we have had no assurances about how visible they will be. It's no good if they are up in the control room or sitting with the driver if something is going on at the back of the train or in another part of the station.
We don't want to cause disruption, but it's the only option we have left to get management to address the issues we have.
On Monday, members of all four unions rejected the "final" pay offer from LU.
The typical salary for a Tube driver is 50,000 a year, the RMT said, but the unions maintain the new plans would be disruptive to their members' lives.
They claim some employees are concerned they will have to work more overnight shifts and may have to work on their own at some stations.
Aslef organiser Finn Brennan said the responsibility of the strikes "rests squarely with London Underground management" who "squandered the window of opportunity" to resolve it.
The disputed weekend night services are planned for sections of the Central, Jubilee, Northern, Piccadilly and Victoria lines.
Police marshalled crowds of people queuing for buses at Stratford station in morning rush hour
Hundreds of passengers tried to make their way through Clapham Junction station in the morning
Transport Secretary Patrick McLoughlin said the strike was of benefit to no-one and urged the strikers to accept the offer LU had made.
Traffic coming into the city from west London started to build early on the Westway
RMT workers gathered on a picket line outside Paddington station
Faringdon-based creatives Ary and Joe produced this walking map of London after a 48-hour partial Tube strike in April 2014
Key points of the dispute
The RMT, TSSA, Unite and Aslef unions say the dispute with London Underground (LU) is about workers' pay and conditions associated with the new Night Tube working
Union members have voted 9:1 in favour of strike action. Aslef said 81% of its members responded to the ballot
The unions have rejected a deal including a 2% average pay rise for all Tube employees plus a 2,000 one-off bonus for drivers on the five affected lines - by way of compensating them for night working
The RMT union says the rejected driver bonus would only have affected 1,000 Tube workers out of a work force of 20,000 and the union believed this was a divide-and-rule tactic
The unions say they want Tube workers to be fairly compensated for night working which has been linked to poor health
LU says its pay offer is both "fair and competitive"
LU says it is hiring 137 more train operators to work on the Night Tube, which would result in existing workers doing "a few extra nights per year within the existing working week"
LU says no-one was being asked to work more hours than at present
The offer includes a pay increase in 2016-17 of RPI or 1%, whichever is greater, plus a 500 launch bonus to all staff on the Night Tube lines plus a 2,000 transition bonus for drivers
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:44:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IMF cuts global growth forecast</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33464099#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The International Monetary Fund cuts its global economic growth forecast for this year, blaming a slowdown in the US.</Description>
        <MainBody>IMF cuts global growth forecast for 2015
9 July 2015
From the section UK
Olivier Blanchard said China's stock market bubble had "burst"
The International Monetary Fund has cut its forecast for global growth this year, as a result of a slowdown in the US economy.
The IMF now says the global economy will expand by 3.3% in 2015, compared with a previous forecast of 3.5%.
Last month, the IMF lowered is forecast for US growth to 2.5% in 2015 from an earlier estimate of 3.1%.
The US is a drag on the world economy, according to the IMF, because of "an unexpected output contraction".
The US economy contracted at an annual rate of 0.2% in the first quarter of the year after being hit by bad weather.
Eurozone
The IMF said Greece's crisis was having a only a marginal effect on the global economy and it left its eurozone growth forecast for 2015 unchanged at 1.5%.
It predicted Germany would grow by 1.6% and France by 1.2%, also unchanged from the previous forecast.
The IMF has left its forecast for growth in China unchanged at 6.8%, despite the recent stock market volatility .
"The bubble has burst," Olivier Blanchard, director of the Research Department at the IMF, said of the Chinese stock market's wild swings.
But he did not say that China's stock market volatility would drag down the global economy.
The IMF also cited Greece's debt crisis as a continuing risk to the global economy, but said the events in China and Greece "have not changed the broad outlook picture for the global economy".
In 2016, the IMF expects global growth to strengthen to 3.8%.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:03:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Swiss banks agree US settlement</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33470118#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Two more Swiss banks, Banque Pasche and Arvest Privatbank, settle with the US Justice Department over tax evasion by Americans.</Description>
        <MainBody>Swiss banks agree US tax evasion deal with Justice Department
9 July 2015
From the section Business
Two more Swiss banks have agreed deals with the US Justice Department over tax evasion by Americans.
Banque Pasche will pay $7.22bn (4.7bn) and Arvest Privatbank $1.04bn in penalties under a deal that means they will not face criminal charges.
Fifteen Swiss banks have already cut deals with the department under a voluntary programme in which they could report suspected tax evasion.
More deals are likely as about 100 banks have signed up to the programme.
The Justice Department said that Banque Pasche, which has operations in Monaco and the Bahamas, helped US taxpayers evade taxes relating to 186 accounts from August 2008 to August 2013.
Since August 2008, Arvest Privatbank has had 52 US-related accounts which the department felt were used to dodge taxes.
The Justice Department and Inland Revenue Service (IRS) said information provided by the two banks would help in future investigations.
"Today's agreements are significant both individually and in conjunction with the previous Swiss bank programme agreements," said Richard Weber, of IRS Criminal Investigation.
"Individually, each bank agreement provides additional information to the IRS to assist us in going after illegally concealed offshore accounts and the financial professionals who helped US taxpayers hide assets abroad," he said.
Neither Swiss bank was immediately available for comment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:54:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Disney wins starwars.co.uk battle</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-33451674#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Disney makes a UK-based fancy-dress retailer surrender starwars.co.uk and six other web addresses related to its sci-fi film franchise.</Description>
        <MainBody>Disney wins starwars.co.uk net domain battle
By Leo Kelion Technology desk editor
9 July 2015
From the section Technology
The starwars.co.uk web address currently directs users to the Jokers' Masquerade store
A Berkshire-based fancy-dress retailer is being made to surrender the starwars.co.uk web address after feeling the force of Disney's wrath.
The British company uses the address as a way to direct shoppers to a section of its Jokers' Masquerade store dedicated to Star Wars-themed costumes.
It has owned the domain name for more than a decade, and was asked to surrender it last year but refused.
Now, Nominet - which oversees .uk domains - has ruled it must do so.
The costume store's parent company, Abscissa, has also been told to give up a further six domain names used for the same purpose:
starwars.uk
The company has until 21 July to decide whether to appeal.
Disney plans to release the first of several new Star Wars movies later this year
"If the new Star Wars films by Disney were not being released, we wouldn't be having this discussion," Mark Lewis, Abscissa's chief executive, told the BBC.
"They wanted the starwars.uk domain, they haven't [got it], and in essence they've thrown their teddies out of the pram.
"That's how we feel. Are we disappointed? Yes. Are we surprised? Not necessarily."
Walt Disney Company bought Lucasfilm - the production company behind Star Wars - in 2012 for $4.1bn (2.6bn).
A spokesman said that had it acquired all the intellectual property surrounding the Star Wars franchise as part of the deal.
Abscissa had attempted to defend its ownership of the domains by highlighting that it had used the starwars.co.uk and star-wars.co.uk addresses since 2003 without being challenged.
It suggested that it was only because Nominet had introduced shorter "name.uk" domains in 2014 that Disney had acted.
Abscissa says that it sells legitimate and licensed Star Wars merchandise from its website
Last year, Nominet gave owners of .co.uk addresses a "first dibs" right-of-refusal to purchase related shorter domains - something Abscissa took advantage of.
After being contacted by Disney's lawyers, the retailer offered to transfer the starwars.uk domain to the US media giant if it could continue using starwars.co.uk and star-wars.co.uk to sell "legitimate Star Wars-branded merchandise".
However, Disney refused.
Nominet requires two facts to be proven for it to agree to force a handover:
The complainant has rights in respect of the name involved
The current registration is judged to be "abusive"
Following a three-month process, it ruled in Disney's favour.
"Star Wars cannot sensibly refer to anyone else other than the complainant," wrote Nominet's expert Steve Ormand.
"It is highly likely in my view that any user searching for Star Wars and arriving at the respondent's website will have suffered initial interest, confusion and falsely inferred a commercial connection with the complainant.
"I am also satisfied that the respondent has taken advantage of the 'pulling power' of the name Star Wars to attract users to its website."
Mr Ormand added that the fact Abscissa had used two of the domains for 10 years had no bearing on the case.
Disney runs the starwars.com domain as a fan site for its film franchise
This is far from the first case Nominet has had to resolve in this manner.
In 2014 alone, it ruled on 98 disputes , and none of these rulings led to an appeal.
They included forcing an official-looking website using the dvla-driving-licence.co.uk address to be transferred to the government, and ilovealdi.co.uk to be handed over to the supermarket chain.
Disney has previously used the service to seize waltdisney.co.uk and disneycruises.co.uk from other parties.
Abscissa itself has also benefited from the dispute-resolution process, by wresting control of jokers.co.uk from a fancy-dress rival in 2007.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:40:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moeen gives England the upper hand</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/cricket/33463749</Link>
        <Description>Moeen Ali scores 77 and takes two key wickets as England lead by 166 runs after the second day of the first Ashes Test.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ashes 2015: Moeen Ali gives England the upper hand in Cardiff
By Sam Sheringham BBC Sport at Cardiff
First Test, day two, Cardiff
England 430: Root 134, Moeen 77, Ballance 61, Starc 5-114
Australia 264-5: Rogers 95, Clarke 38
Australia trail by 166 runs
Scorecard
Moeen Ali scored 77 and took two important wickets as England gained the upper hand in the first Ashes Test against Australia.
The hosts added 87 runs to their overnight total in 14.1 overs to post 430 all out in a sun-kissed Cardiff and were then rewarded for a disciplined bowling display as Australia slipped to 264-5.
Moeen removed Steve Smith and Michael Clarke to justify his selection ahead of Adil Rashid as England's spinner.
Mark Wood took his first Ashes wicket - dismissing Chris Rogers for 95 - and Ben Stokes struck late in the day to snaffle Ashes debutant Adam Voges and put England on top.
The hosts' dominant display sealed a remarkable recovery from 43-3 on Wednesday morning as they set about avenging a 5-0 Ashes whitewash down under.
Australia, four places above England in the Test rankings, are seeking a first Ashes win in England since 2001.
Moeen is England's key man
The biggest quandary facing England's selectors before the first Test was whether to select Moeen or bow to the clamour to hand a debut to Yorkshire leg-spinner Rashid.
In the event, Moeen more than repaid the selectors' faith with a fine all-round performance on Thursday.
He added 51 runs to his overnight 26 in a flurry of shots in the morning sunshine before accounting for Australia's two most celebrated batsmen.
The verdict after day two
5 live's pint-sized Ashes: A summary of the day in two minutes
Seemingly unfazed by being hit for three fours in four balls by Smith, Moeen tempted the batsman with a flighted ball down the leg side and drew a leading edge, which was expertly caught by England captain Alastair Cook at short mid-on.
Then, just when Clarke was finding his range, Moeen held on to a sharp return catch at waist height to send the Australia captain on his way.
Rogers the nearly man
Chris Rogers has scored 50 in seven successive Test innings but not made 100 in any of them
Rogers, who will be 38 in August, continued his excellent Ashes record with a near-faultless 95.
Punching his trademark drives through the off-side and busily nurdling around the wicket, the left-hander shared half-century partnerships with David Warner, Smith and Clarke.
However he was out five runs short of a fourth Ashes hundred when he cut at a wideish away-swinger from Wood and was caught behind.
Rogers shook his head in disbelief and kicked the ground as he became the first player to score fifties in seven consecutive Test innings without converting any into hundreds.
Disciplined England, reckless Aussies
David Warner had scored seven centuries in 12 Tests prior to Cardiff
On a pitch continuing to offer little pace or movement off the surface, England's bowlers were rewarded for their patience and discipline.
Sticking to a good or full length on or outside off stump, they invited Australia to go after them and were rewarded with a succession of reckless shots.
Warner was out driving James Anderson on the up and Rogers to a needless cut before Voges miscued a drive straight to extra cover when the close of play was in sight.
Mixed day for Mitchells
Mitchell Johnson's figures were the worst by an Australian in England since Geoff Lawson in 1985
Once again, Mitchell Johnson bore the brunt of England's assault on a riotous second morning as he recorded figures of 0-111 - the worst of his Test career.
Mercilessly mocked by the home crowd, Johnson's mood worsened when he was finally awarded a first wicket, only to have it overturned.
Broad was given out caught at short leg off a Johnson short ball, but was sent back to the crease by the third umpire when replays showed Voges's catch had touched the ground.
While Johnson could not buy a wicket, Mitchell Starc continued to pick them up on the cheap.
Despite conceding more runs than his bowling partner, Starc picked up the last two wickets to complete the third five-wicket haul of his Test career.
The state of play
Ben Stokes's dismissal of Adam Voges gave England the edge
The sight of Nathan Lyon walking sheepishly to the crease for nightwatchman duties after Voges's late dismissal underlined the perception that England have Australia right where they want them.
A first-innings lead of 80 or more would cement their advantage and leave them well placed to set up a push for victory over the weekend.
And although the pitch is offering little pace, its increasingly unpredictable bounce will make batting last on it decidedly difficult for Australia.
Stats of the day
England passed 400 runs in an Ashes innings for the first time since January 2011 in Sydney, when they made 644.
England have only ever lost six Tests having scored more than 400 in the first innings. However five of those were against Australia, the most recent in Adelaide in 2006-07.
Australia opener Chris Rogers has passed 50 in his past seven Test innings, equalling the world record held by four others (Everton Weekes, Andy Flower, Shivnarine Chanderpaul and Kumar Sangakkara). He has failed to make 100 in each of those innings.
Player reaction - 'England ahead'
England's Moeen Ali told BBC Test Match Special: "In the first innings of an Ashes, it's important that we got 430 - and the way we put the Australia bowlers under pressure.
"We're slightly ahead. A couple of early wickets tomorrow would put them under pressure. I would rather be in our position than Australia's."
Ex-England batsman Geoffrey Boycott on Test Match Special
"Yesterday many of us thought England edged it. Today it was definitely their day. They got most things right and Australia got hardly anything right - they didn't bat with a lot of common sense. There is a lot of time left for England to win it. I'll be surprised if Australia get up to England's total."
Australia's Chris Rogers told BBC Test Match Special: "I started to get some rhythm with my feet and weight. Once you hit some out the middle the confidence comes through. I'm just disappointed I didn't make it count.
"The pitch is a bit two-paced now. You saw with the Adam Voges dismissal that kicked a little. It is going to get harder and harder, but if you set your stall out and you are happy to bat a long time there is still the opportunity.
"It has been an excellent day of Test cricket. England maybe have the slight upper hand but hopefully we can get a few more runs."
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:05:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Williams to meet Muguruza in final</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/tennis/33464691</Link>
        <Description>Serena Williams brushes aside fourth seed Maria Sharapova to set up a Wimbledon final against Spain's Garbine Muguruza.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wimbledon: Serena Williams beats Maria Sharapova in semi-final
By Piers Newbery BBC Sport at Wimbledon
Wimbledon 2015
Dates: Until Sunday 12 July Play: Centre Court 13:00 BST
BBC coverage: TV, radio and online with up to 15 live streams. Read More: TV and radio schedules.
World number one Serena Williams brushed aside fourth seed Maria Sharapova to set up a Wimbledon final against Spain's Garbine Muguruza.
The American, 33, extended her winning run against Sharapova to 17 matches over 11 years with a 6-2 6-4 victory.
Williams could win a sixth Wimbledon and 21st major title on Saturday, when she can also complete a 'Serena Slam' by holding all four Grand Slam titles.
Highlights: Muguruza beats Radwanska
Muguruza, 21, beat Agnieszka Radwanska 6-2 3-6 6-3 in the first semi-final.
The Venezuela-born 20th seed led by a set and a break only for 13th seed Radwanska to respond with six straight games and force a decider.
"I don't have words to explain it," Muguruza told BBC Sport.
"I worked all my life to achieve this moment. I think I was playing really well so I had to stay calm and keep a poker face."
Williams was thrilled to reach her 25th Grand Slam final, saying: "I'm so excited. I got a bit nervous because it was a semi-final and it's a long time since I've been this far."
Dominant Williams makes it 17 in a row
Sharapova had not beaten Williams since 2004, the year of her Wimbledon triumph over the American, and she was unable to prevent a 17th straight defeat.
The Russian knew she had to defend her vulnerable serve better but successive double faults handed over the opening game, to groans around Centre Court.
Lindsay Davenport, 1999 Wimbledon champion
"It's 17 times in a row now and I think Sharapova is a realist and says: 'This is just a bad match-up for me.' She just doesn't possess what she needs to challenge Serena. She was constantly fighting to hold her own serve and couldn't make any inroads on the return game. It all revolves around the serve for Serena and when that's on, I'm not sure anyone can challenge her. It's perfect."
Williams was not in the mood to offer her long-time rival any gifts and almost broke again in game three, Sharapova saving herself with an ace out wide.
A forehand into the corner earned the double break two games later and the set was wrapped up after 33 minutes, with Sharapova unable to profit from the American making just 52% of first serves.
Williams aces her way to victory
There were signs of the world number four at least gaining a foothold in the early stages of the second set, but Williams upped the pace in game five and Sharapova succumbed on break point with her fifth double fault.
Sharapova was struggling desperately to win points on her second serve and Williams let her off the hook with three missed returns on break points at 3-3, before the Russian saved two match points in game nine.
Williams still had her serve to come, however, and fired down four aces - taking her total to 13 - to complete the entire 79-minute contest without facing a break point.
Don't mention the 'Serena Slam'
Williams has adopted a policy during Wimbledon of not discussing the fact that she is close to holding all four major titles for the second time in her career.
The American, who last completed the feat in 2002-2003, said: "I don't what the pressure of that, and I'm not thinking of that.
"When you talk about it every time, you can't help but think about it. It's been OK just to free my brain from that."
Sharapova falls short of expectations
After another defeat by Williams, Sharapova found it difficult to take much solace from the fact that she had at least reached a 20th Grand Slam semi-final.
Sharapova leaves Centre Court still searching for a second Wimbledon title
"I think for many others, maybe if I was British, a semi-final would be incredible," she said. "I'd be on the front page of the paper, I know that.
"But I expect myself to be a champion of these events, and it's disappointing to come out as a loser because I know my level can be there, and my level can be at the point of holding these championship trophies.
"I know that that's what keeps me going forward."
Muguruza holds her nerve in decider
Muguruza completely dominated for a set and a half, winning more than half of the points on Radwanska's serve and hitting three times as many winners as she built a 6-2 3-1 lead.
It took 55 minutes for Radwanska to earn a break point but, when Muguruza found the net, it heralded a dramatic shift in momentum.
Tracy Austin, two-time US Open champion
"I was almost more impressed that Muguruza lost the lead and then recovered, that's a really good sign of maturity. At 21, I think she's such a major star to come. She's got a beautiful personality and I've loved her reactions when she's won. I think she's going to get a huge fanbase behind her. Over the next 48 hours it's so important for her to relish this situation and try to get ready for the final."
The Pole finally began to move her 6ft opponent around, testing her more vulnerable forehand and drawing her into the net with sliced backhands.
It brought Radwanska a run of six straight games as she levelled at one set all and broke at the start of the decider.
Muguruza, who beat Serena Williams at the French Open last year, stemmed the tide with a couple of winners to break back for 1-1 and a gripping contest unfolded.
Muguruza hopes to become Spain's first female champion since Conchita Martinez in 1994
The Spaniard won a brilliant point with a defensive lob and a crunching backhand winner for a 4-2 lead and survived a tense game when trying to serve out the win.
Radwanska had two break points and was pushing for a third at deuce when, seemingly urged on by those in her player box, the Pole challenged a Muguruza shot that Hawk-Eye showed to have clipped the line.
A relieved Muguruza converted her first match point with a big serve and forehand drive-volley to become Spain's first female finalist since Arantxa Sanchez-Vicario in 1996.
"I knew it was going to be tough," said Muguruza. "I was nervous in second set. She has a lot of experience and I had to fight."
Radwanska rues Hawk-Eye call
Radwanska admitted her decision to challenge at deuce in what proved to be the final game let an increasingly nervous Muguruza off the hook.
"It was a 50/50 call on that ball. I decide to challenge. Wasn't really a good decision," said the Pole.
Asked whether she had done so after shouts from her team at courtside, Radwanska added: "I think I did it because I'm the one to decide if I challenge or not. Nobody can do that for me."
Radwanska looked capable of getting back into the final set when she mistakenly challenged
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:38:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tour leader Martin out of race</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/cycling/33466631</Link>
        <Description>Race leader Tony Martin is out of the Tour de France after breaking his collarbone in a late crash on stage six.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tour de France 2015: Leader Tony Martin breaks collarbone
By Paul Fletcher BBC Sport
Race leader Tony Martin is out of the Tour de France after breaking his collarbone in a dramatic crash at the end of stage six.
Britain's Chris Froome, 12 seconds behind the German in second, will move into the overall lead.
Etixx-Quick Step's Martin crashed in the final kilometre with defending champion Vincenzo Nibali also involved.
Martin's team-mate Zdenek Stybar came through to win the 191.5km stage from Abbeville to Le Havre.
Britain's Chris Froome was involved in the dramatic crash at the end but insists he was not responsible
"Tony Martin will fly to BG Hospital in Hamburg immediately for surgery, and must withdraw from Le Tour de France," a team spokesman said.
Team doctor Helge Riepenhof added: "The collarbone is in lots of pieces, so it was a major impact. One of the pieces came through the skin, which means it's an open fracture. Therefore, even if it was Tony's wish to start tomorrow, I have to say he is not allowed to. Riders always want to race. Tony especially."
Martin is the second race leader to pull out after Swiss rider Fabian Cancellara fractured two vertebrae in his lower back on Monday.
Team Sky's Froome tweeted shortly after Thursday's stage that he had managed to get away with a "minor graze to his knee" after finding himself in the middle of the chaos, but Martin was not so fortunate.
"I was unlucky. I don't even remember how I went down. I touched the rear wheel of the rider in front of me - Bryan Coquard - but it's the Tour, luck and bad luck are always close," the German said.
Martin, who was in yellow for the second day, went down heavily within the last kilometre and, after eventually picking himself up, had to be nursed to the finish line by three of his team-mates.
Analysis from BBC Sport's Matt Slater
For 99% of today's stage I was convinced we were going to have our first "slow news day" at the Tour, apart from some nice news, perhaps, about Daniel Teklepolka-dot's pioneering efforts.
And then, boom, we lose another race-leader, dozens of riders hit the tarmac (again), Vincenzo Nibali thinks it's Chris Froome's fault and throws a water bottle in his direction and a team-mate of the stricken Tony Martin escapes up the road for a famous win.
It seems Etixx-Quick-Step like their symphonies bitter sweet.
The unlucky Martin's exit means Froome, who was blameless, inherits yellow. His Tour prospects continue to flourish but Mark Cavendish will miss Martin's engine in tomorrow's crucial sprint.
Martin - and indeed the rest of those involved, including GC contender Nairo Quintana, who also went down - were awarded the same time because the crash took place within the last three kilometres of the stage.
His Etixx-Quick Step team-mate Mark Cavendish - beaten in a sprint finish on Wednesday - crossed the line unscathed and will hope to contest what is expected to be a bunch sprint at the end of stage seven on Friday.
That would be the 26th stage win of Cavendish's career as he goes in search of his first victory since stage 13 of the 2013 Tour - but his chances will not be helped with Martin, a key member of his lead-out train, absent.
Team boss reaction to Martin's crash
The dramatic late drama led to an initial period of confusion as riders tried to scrape themselves off the road - and it came at the end of what had been a relatively sedate day's racing, with the peloton rolling into the sunshine of Le Havre later than the organisers expected.
The most notable achievement had been by MTN-Quebeka's Eritrean rider Daniel Teklehaimanot, who was part of a lengthy three-man breakaway that enabled him to collect enough points to claim the King of the Mountains jersey.
He did so by finishing first in the day's three category four climbs, collecting one point for each to overhaul Joaquim Rodriquez and in doing so become the first African to wear the polka dot jersey.
Teklehaimanot, Europcar's Perrig Qumeneur and, eventually, Cofidis rider Kenneth Van Bilsen were all swept up as the peloton picked up the pace towards the finish.
The sharp climb at the end was supposed to rule out the pure sprinters and favour the likes of Slovak Peter Sagan and German John Degenkolb but it was Czech Stybar who burst clear to win a stage on his debut Tour de France.
Sagan was left a frustrated second - the 14th time he has finished second at a Tour stage.
Tour de France 2015: Chris Froome looks likely to win - Jonathan Vaughters
Martin was in obvious pain as he was helped off the tarmac following his crash
Tony Martin (second right) is supported by his team-mates who escort him over the finishing line after crashing
Zdenek Stybar celebrates as he crosses the finish line to win the sixth stage
Daniel Teklehaimanot cannot hide his delight after becoming the first African to take the King of the Mountains jersey
Eritrea's Daniel Teklehaimanot passes over a bridge as he rides in a breakaway group
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:48:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Richter art gets choral soundtrack</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33467380#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Painter Gerhard Richter and composer Arvo Part, two of Europe's most celebrated creative figures, join forces for a special exhibition in Manchester.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gerhard Richter and Arvo Part unite art and music in Manchester
By Ian Youngs Arts reporter
9 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Arvo Part (left) and Gerhard Richter met through the Manchester International Festival
Painter Gerhard Richter and composer Arvo Part, two titans of European culture, have joined forces to bring art and music together for a special exhibition in Manchester.
Richter, widely regarded as the world's greatest living artist, has unveiled eight paintings dedicated to Part.
And Part has composed a choral work to be performed alongside the paintings.
The pair launched the partnership at the Whitworth gallery, which was named the UK's museum of the year last week .
They were introduced and encouraged to work together by Alex Poots, artistic director of the Manchester International Festival.
Richter is showing eight paintings from two new series: Birkenau, based on photographs of the Auschwitz-Birkenau concentration camp in World War Two; and Doppelgrau (Double Grey), which have different shades of grey on glass.
Richter's Birkenau paintings were completed earlier this year
Members of Estonian choir Vox Clamantis mingle with gallery visitors to perform
Earlier this year, one of the 83-year-old German's paintings sold for more than 30m - a record for a living artist. He had a major retrospective at the Tate Modern in London in 2011.
In response to Richter's art, the 79-year-old Estonian composer wrote a haunting 95-second choral piece titled Drei Hirtenkinder aus Fatima.
"It is very exciting for me and an honour that our works will converge," Part said. "As different as they may seem, they must be somehow related."
The work will be sung in the gallery by the 14-member Estonian choir Vox Clamantis until Saturday, and then by community choirs from Manchester until 19 July.
'Deeply touched'
Curator Hans-Ulrich Obrist, who helped arrange the meeting between Richter and Part, said they had "a great interest in each other's work".
He said: "We found out that they not only like each other's work a lot but they also got along really well and there are many biographical parallels.
"They were born more or less the same time, they both lived in the east [of Europe], they both experienced the Second World War and so on."
Part initially said he was not intending to write any new music at that time.
"And then all of a sudden like a miracle, not only did Gerhard dedicate his work to Arvo and create this amazing new work, but also Arvo broke the news that he had written music, which is this piece," Obrist said.
"The key idea was to bring these two aspects together."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:19:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Sherlock special image revealed</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33459750#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The BBC releases a new image from the upcoming Sherlock special, set in Victorian times.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sherlock Victorian special image revealed
9 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Creator Steven Moffat said the special will be a standalone episode
The BBC has released a new image from the upcoming Sherlock special.
The picture features stars Benedict Cumberbatch and Martin Freeman dressed in period costume for the episode, which is set in Victorian times.
Creator Steven Moffat revealed earlier this year the special would be a historical adventure that stood alone from the main series.
Series four of Sherlock is due to return to screens in 2017.
The BBC has not confirmed when the special episode will be broadcast, but it is rumoured to be around Christmas time this year.
Speaking ahead of a Sherlock panel at Comic-Con later, Moffat said the 90-minute episode would be "a different version of the show we're used to".
"It's like we checked the books and discovered we'd set it in the wrong time period by mistake and it's like we're correcting it," he said.
"We're really proud of it, we think it's a real cracker. But that'll be it until series four."
The BBC teased an image of Benedict Cumberbatch and Martin Freeman in Victorian dress in November
The writer also bemoaned Twitter after quitting the social media platform in 2012.
"I think Twitter is a useful tool for promoting a show, but I think it is the worst possible form of audience research," he said.
"That is not a typical audience member talking. It might be interesting, it might be witty, it might be clever, it might be insightful, but it's not what they're all saying."
He said one of the biggest pitfalls was "mistaking Twitter's reaction for the audience's reaction".
"People on Twitter are having fun, they're making gags... it's like overhearing a pub conversation, when you're at a pub do you tell the truth, or do you try and get attention?"
Moffat added he and co-creator Mark Gatiss had yet to begin writing Sherlock's fourth series.
The third series bowed out last year with the detective appearing to shoot villain Charles Augustus Magnussen, and teased viewers criminal mastermind Moriarty may have cheated death and be set for a return.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:48:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>James Bond musical plans cause spat</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33463456#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Plans for a James Bond musical causes a row between the producers of the show and the owners of the 007 franchise.</Description>
        <MainBody>James Bond musical plans cause spat
9 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Daniel Craig is the current James Bond
Plans for a James Bond musical have caused a spat between the producer of the show and the owners of the superspy franchise.
Merry Saltzman - the daughter of late Bond producer Harry Saltzman - told Playbill last week she had secured rights to stage a Broadway show.
But on Wednesday, Bond rights holders MGM and Danjaq denied they licensed any rights, legally preventing a show.
However, Saltzman has said her musical is a parody and did not need approval.
She added the show would go ahead as planned, opening in late 2017 or early 2018.
In a statement on the 007 website , Danjaq and MGM said they had not "licensed any rights to Merry Saltzman or her production company to create a James Bond musical".
"Danjaq and MGM jointly control all live stage rights in the Bond franchise, and therefore no James Bond stage show may be produced without their permission."
'Key word parody'
Responding to the statement, Saltzman told Playbill : "We are producing a parody, no permissive rights are required from Eon, Danjaq, MGM et al to produce our show; it will not infringe on their intellectual property.
"Eon, Danjaq, and MGM's statements are accurate as far as they go. [My company] Placeholder Productions' and my statements are also accurate. Placeholder did not claim to have purchased rights to a stage production from Eon et al (nor did we intend to imply we had).
"Placeholder did (and did claim to) purchase rights to a James Bond musical parody written by Dave Clarke with music and lyrics by Jay Henry Weisz.
"The key word here is 'parody'. Parody, the courts have repeatedly upheld, is fully protected under the fair use principle of the US Copyright Act of 1976 and, as such, does not require permission from the owners of the intellectual property being parodied."
Producers said James Bond: The Musical will have an original storyline and feature "several Bond villains, plus some new ones" as well as "our own Bond girl".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:14:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Tornado drama captured in Venice, Italy</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33456741#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A tornado has swept through the outskirts of the Italian city of Venice - destroying large numbers of homes and other buildings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Tornado drama captured in Venice, Italy
9 July 2015 Last updated at 01:14 BST
A tornado has swept through the outskirts of the Italian city of Venice - destroying homes and other buildings.
Media reports suggest one person was killed and dozens injured as the storm hit the town of Dolo between Venice and Padua.
The video, originally posted by youreporter.it , shows the twister in the midst of strong winds.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:01:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Uganda's Mbabazi and Besigye released</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33469428#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Two presidential hopefuls in Uganda have been released, hours after they were arrested.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Uganda's Amama Mbabazi and Kizza Besigye released
9 July 2015 Last updated at 22:01 BST
Two presidential hopefuls in Uganda have been released, hours after they were arrested.
Police say veteran opposition leader, Kizza Besigye, and the former prime minister, Amama Mbabazi, were detained because of fears over public order violations.
They were arrested just hours before they were due to appear at campaign rallies.
Focus On Africa's Patience Atuhaire reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:03:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Coding brothers inspired by Google</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33469427#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Brothers Osine and Anesi have developed an Android web browser, calling it Crocodile Browser Lite.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Coding brothers inspired by Google Chrome
9 July 2015 Last updated at 20:03 BST
Nigerian brothers Osine and Anesi have developed an Android web browser.
Inspired by Google Chrome, they named their browser Crocodile Browser Lite.
It has been described as a functional, fast browser for feature and low end phones.
Focus on Africa went to meet them at their home in Lagos.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:58:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: The vest that helps exam cheats</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-33464732#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Justin Rowlatt looks at the technology designed to help people cheat in exams in India.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
The vest that helps exam cheats
9 July 2015 Last updated at 17:58 BST
The Indian Supreme Court recently ordered 600,000 students to re-appear for a test after reports of large-scale cheating.
Cheating during exams is illegal in India, but it is still widespread.
In recent years those wanting a helping hand have been able to take advantage of modern technology and a whole market in devices to aid cheats has sprung up.
Justin Rowlatt reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 09:00:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Naked man steals US police car</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33457379#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A man has been arrested in New Mexico in the US after allegedly running around in the nude and stealing a police car.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Naked man steals police car in New Mexico
9 July 2015 Last updated at 07:00 BST
A man has been arrested in Curry County, New Mexico in the US after allegedly running around in the nude and stealing a police car.
A police camera filmed Jesus Tarango, 37, climbing into a deputy county sheriff's vehicle and driving it away.
He was apprehended a short time later and faces several charges.
Pictures courtesy Curry County Sheriff's office
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 11:53:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Clouds of ash from Indonesia volcano</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33457382#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Mount Sinabung on Sumatra in western Indonesia is continuing to spew clouds of ash into the air and down slopes towards people's homes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Indonesia volcano Sinabung spews clouds of ash towards homes
9 July 2015 Last updated at 09:53 BST
Mount Sinabung on Sumatra in western Indonesia is continuing to spew clouds of ash into the air and down slopes towards people's homes.
Authorities are monitoring activity from the volcano, after raising the alert to the highest possible level in early June.
More than 10,000 villagers whose homes are in the danger zone have since been evacuated.
Adnan Nawaz reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 11:12:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Greek businesses gear up for Grexit</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33457384#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Business owners in Patras, western Greece, explain what a so-called Grexit might mean for them.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Greek debt crisis: What would Grexit mean for businesses?
9 July 2015 Last updated at 09:12 BST
Greece's exit from the eurozone has become a genuine possibility, as European Union leaders prepare for a final decision at a summit on Sunday.
So what would a so-called Grexit mean for businesses operating in Greece?
The BBC spent the day in Patras in western Greece to find out.
Video journalist: Howard Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:14:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Angry plea over 'symbol of hate'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33457387#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Republican representative Jenny Horne gives an emotional plea for the removal of the Confederate flag from capitol grounds in South Carolina.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Confederate flag: Republican calls for 'symbol of hate' removal
9 July 2015 Last updated at 10:14 BST
The House of Representatives in South Carolina has voted to take down the Confederate flag from capitol grounds after an "impassioned and sometimes tearful" debate.
Republican representative Jenny Horne was among those calling for the flag's removal.
The backlash against the emblem grew when a gunman who killed nine black people at a Charleston church last month was pictured holding the flag.
Speaking during the debate, Ms Horne said: "I cannot believe that we do not have the heart in this body to do something meaningful, such as take a symbol of hate off these grounds on Friday."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 10:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>From 'Lost Boy' to education minister in South Sudan</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33448231#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>From 'Lost Boy' refugee to South Sudan minister</Description>
        <MainBody>From 'Lost Boy' to education minister in South Sudan
By James Copnall BBC Africa, South Sudan
9 July 2015
From the section Africa
Valentino Achak Deng was once a "Lost Boy", a small, frightened child who walked for months across what is now South Sudan to flee a brutal war, narrowly escaping becoming another casualty of the conflict.
He lived in refugee camps in Ethiopia and Kenya, getting the education he had missed on his terrifying journey, before he was eventually relocated to the US.
Mr Deng's life story was made into a bestselling book, What is the What, by the American author Dave Eggers.
Now, in a twist so unlikely it might have been rejected by a writer of fiction, Mr Deng has become the minister for education in Northern Bahr el-Ghazal, one of the 10 states in South Sudan which gained its independence from Sudan on 9 July 2011.
Mr Deng says even he finds it "difficult to imagine", but here he is, a boy in rags transformed into a minister in a smart suit.
"If one is positive and optimistic, good things can happen," he says.
Valentino Achak Deng:
"The lesson I can draw is that people can always learn, come through tough times and persevere and grow"
Mr Deng has big ambitions for the children under his care, and says his own example shows what is possible.
"The lesson I can draw is that people can always learn, come through tough times and persevere and grow.
"It's exciting when you see a lot of children go through - a lot of smiles and success stories."
Mr Deng was named education minister in Northern Bahr el-Ghazal late last year, after successfully setting up a school in the town of Marial Bai, funded in part by proceeds from What is the What.
During our conversation, one parent came up to profusely thank Mr Deng for the education the school is providing his kids.
Healing divisions
At the school, Mr Deng has brought in children from Pibor, a conflict-affected area at the opposite end of the country.
It is part of an ideology the former Lost Boy hopes can help overcome South Sudan's ethnic and regional divisions.
"I wanted the kids from Northern Bahr el-Ghazal to learn with the kids from all the other nine states of South Sudan, and benefit from the cross-cultural environment," he says.
"Where you know someone speaks another language but they're South Sudanese, someone lives a different lifestyle but they're South Sudanese, someone comes from a different location but he's just as important as you at Marial Bai Secondary School."
Construction on Marial Bai Secondary School began in 2008, two years after the publication of What is the What
Now, though, Mr Deng has broader challenges, as a state minister in a part of the country with very divided politics, and which is facing the economic crisis brought on by South Sudan's civil war.
Mr Deng says he lacks qualified teachers, in part because so many children are flocking to school.
School buildings are a problem too. Many lessons take place under trees in villages, which means the makeshift classrooms are impractical during the rainy season.
Children often come to school hungry "which affects their ability to learn", Mr Deng says.
And many struggle to understand English, the official language of South Sudan, particularly if they grew up in Sudan before independence, when Arabic was the official language.
'Fluctuating prices'
Northern Bahr el-Ghazal has been spared the worst of the fighting in the civil war that began 18 months ago, but the national crisis is still taking its toll.
"The prices fluctuate, the teacher cannot survive on their salary," Mr 'Deng explains.
"The kids go hungry; they do not go to school because they have to survive."
Many lessons take place under trees in villages in South Sudan
Nationally, Mr Deng is "worried that we are losing a good number of students to illiteracy, because of the violence".
"Education is transformation, but it can only do so much if people are forced to leave school."
Mr Deng thinks of himself as a man getting things done rather than as a politician, but he knows from very personal experience what sort of difference education can make.
"'When I walked across the southern Sudan barefoot, I literally knew nothing, [had] not even a map, [knew] not where I was, not how to navigate myself in the forest or how to look for signs of dangers or any of those.
"I was just a naive kid walking, looking for safety."
Mr Deng's own educational journey, interrupted by war and reinvigorated in the refugee camps of Ethiopia and Kenya, convinced him that his homeland would have been much better off if more people had gone to school.
'Look for solutions'
"We had fewer educated people in the country; we had fewer schools; we had virtually no basic infrastructure; we had no industrialised agriculture system.
"And that had a lot to do with war, which took South Sudan back a number of years.
"So with education, I would not have gone through the difficulties I went through. Somebody would have worked out something, some alternatives."
Valentino Achak Deng believes education will help South Sudan put a stop to violence
Now Mr Deng has the opportunity to help educate thousands of kids, as state education minister or through his school.
His own life was devastated by conflict, then transformed by education.
It leaves him with a strong message for his fellow South Sudanese.
Many countries in the region, like Rwanda, Uganda and Ethiopia, have recovered from terrible ordeals, and Mr Deng is convinced South Sudan can too.
"What I pray that we do as leaders of this young nation is that we say stop to the violence, stop to anything that destroys a soul, look for a solution, and we can be like anybody."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:14:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A tale of two sisters and flight MH17</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33442560#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A tale of two sisters and flight MH17</Description>
        <MainBody>A tale of two sisters and flight MH17
By Natalia Antelava BBC News, Amsterdam
9 July 2015
From the section Magazine
When the Malaysian airliner, flight MH17, was shot down over eastern Ukraine nearly a year ago, the BBC's Natalia Antelava was soon reporting from the scene. A chance encounter gave her a personal connection with one of the dead passengers, and - as she describes here - prompted her to find the woman's sister.
The midwife said she'd be back by dinner time. By 3pm it was clear that the baby was not going to wait that long.  As her contractions, and pain, grew stronger, Babs Baay crawled into the only bedroom of her tiny flat in the Dutch town of Breda. She lay on the wooden floor and, for a moment thought of dialling her cousin, who had volunteered to take her to the birthing centre.  Then she decided not to.
"I don't know why," she tells me two months later, as we sit down on a white sofa in her sunlit living room. "I guess because the only person I really wanted there was the one person who could not be there. I didn't want to replace her."
Instead, Babs says, she propped her back against the side of her bed and fixed her eyes firmly on the wall above her. Hanging from it are dozens of photographs of that one person:  her sister Joyce.
"She always gave me comfort and kept me calm," Babs says. "Joyce was everything - my friend, my partner, my home.  We discussed everything together, whether it was work, relationships, emotions or illness."
Joyce Baay with the missing bracelet visible on her wrist
After two hours of puffing, pushing and breathing Babs focused on remembering all she had ever read or watched about delivering babies. Then she sat up, leaned over and reached for the baby's head, gently twisting her shoulder and, with a final push, delivered her daughter.
When the midwife finally turned up at the promised hour she was astonished to find the first solo delivery of her long career.
"It was a split second, and instinct too kicked in so I twisted and pulled her out and there she was, looking at me with her big blue eyes: 'Hello!' And I was so proud, I thought, 'You listened so well to mummy, you are such a brave baby,'" Babs says, little Yoeki now snoozing at her chest.
Why did Babs never call for help? She doesn't know. But the experience helped her to connect with Yoeki, she says, and somehow make her sister, Joyce, part of it too.
Joyce was always supposed to be Babs's delivery partner. Soon after Babs had decided to go through the process of artificial insemination she had told her sister that she'd want her by her side in the labour room.  "She travelled a lot, so I said to her keep that in mind, to free up some time," Babs remembers.
Joyce had just been selected to guide a group of Dutch tourists through Malaysia - it was a potential career change that could lead to a lot more travel, and she was excited.  She was also keen to get to Malaysia a few days before her group arrived, and so on 17 July she boarded Malaysian Airlines flight MH17 from Amsterdam to Kuala Lumpur. She planned to be back in a month.
The Boeing 777 carrying Malaysian Airlines Flight MH17 was shot down near the Russian-Ukrainian border, in the area controlled by the Moscow-backed rebels.
On 19 July I arrived at the scene, near the village of Hrabove, with a BBC television crew. The sun was just setting over spectacular fields of sunflowers. Scattered through these fields, over an area of more than 10 sq km were the bodies of the 298 passengers and crew.
Some of what we saw was overwhelmingly gruesome, some painfully poignant. At one point as I wandered through the field I stepped on a glass jar of Estee Lauder face cream. Was the owner a holidaymaker? A businesswoman, maybe? Or one of many scientists heading to a big HIV conference?  Some of the world's leading Aids researchers were on that plane. Or maybe she was the mother of one of the 80 children on the flight?
I remember a tall man sobbing by the roadside. He must have been a journalist - no family members or international rescue workers could get to the area in those early days because of the fighting.  The man was on his phone speaking English to someone back home. He was describing duty-free whisky bottles we had all seen amid the debris.  He was crying because he, like the rest of us, could not understand how glass bottles of booze could survive a fall that killed so many people.
The rebels were in a state of shock and panic. Whoever shot down MH17, it was clearly unplanned. The rebels said they would guarantee safety for an international rescue mission only if Kiev agreed to a truce. Instead, they launched their own hasty recovery operation, bringing in hundreds of local coal miners to comb through the fields.
It was one of these miners, a young slim man with a face smeared in coal dust, who walked up to me as we were filming on 19 July.  "Documents," he said handing me an ID and a wallet. "What do I do with them? Please pass them on," he said, walking away before I even had a chance to reply.
We handed the documents to the rebels in charge - there was no-one else to give them to. But the name on the ID stuck in my mind: Joyce.
Long after I left Ukraine, I kept wondering who Joyce was and whether the documents ever reached her family.  When Malaysian Airlines released a list of the names of the passengers on flight MH17 I looked for hers and there it was, near the top - the only Joyce on the flight. In the months that followed, I tracked down her sister, Babs, in the Netherlands. She was pregnant at the time and we tentatively agreed to meet after the birth of the baby.  The plan was that after meeting her, I'd travel to eastern Ukraine to track down the miner who found Joyce's documents. These were two people - Babs and the miner - whose worlds collided when the plane crashed, whose lives changed forever. I wanted to know how.
Imagine. That door closed and that was it. This plane was their coffin
Babs Baay
"Holland's 9/11" was how one official described to me the shooting down of MH17.  There were citizens of 10 countries on that flight - Malaysians, Indonesians, Australians, British... But the biggest group were the Dutch. The figure of 193 Dutch deaths exceeds the number of people murdered in the Netherlands in a normal year.
The Dutch government says the investigation into MH17 is its top priority, but many are unhappy with the way it has dragged on. The investigators won't report their conclusions until October. A preliminary report in September last year said the plane broke up after being penetrated by "high-velocity objects" - which appeared to lend support to the widespread suspicion that the airliner was shot down by a powerful Buk anti-aircraft missile.
Shortly before the attack, the rebels had boasted about having access to a Russian-made Buk but subsequently both they and their allies in Moscow insisted that the plane was shot down in an air-to-air attack by a Ukrainian fighter plane.  More recently, the rebels agreed that it was indeed a Buk missile, but insisted that it was fired from the Ukrainian side.  The official investigation should clarify this - and many in the Netherlands are already calling for an international tribunal.
Babs doesn't know who killed her sister and accepts that she might never find out.  But it has changed the way she feels about the world, she tells me.  She now carefully follows news of the conflict in Ukraine, even though a year ago she knew almost nothing about it.  She can no longer bear the sight of Vladimir Putin, she says, and switches channels every time she sees his face on television. She often logs on to a special online forum for relatives of the victims.  Recently someone posted photographs taken by a passenger inside the plane before the disaster - these were stored in a telephone that was recovered from the wreckage and returned to relatives.
Find out more
MH17 - A Sister's Story, runs on Assignment on the BBC World Service on Thursday 9 July. Click here for transmission times, or to listen online.
"Imagine," Babs says as she shows me pictures of smiling passengers settling into their seats, "that door closed and that was it. This plane was their coffin."
We talk for hours, mostly about Joyce: her hopes and her dreams, her diverse group of friends, a hilarious 40th birthday party that she had organised in an Amsterdam theatre a year before her death.
Babs tells me about the phone call informing her about the crash; about checking into a hotel in Amsterdam together with the other families. The fact that they were all grieving together provided no comfort, she says.
It was there, while waiting for news from Ukraine, that Babs did a pregnancy test. "It was a very difficult moment because I knew that if it was a negative test, I would go to hell.  My world would completely fall apart."  She told no-one that she was pregnant.
The families waited in the hotel for seven days until finally, after tense negotiation between the warring sides, the Dutch were able to send military planes to collect the first 80 bodies.
I remember watching the ceremony in Hrabove amid the charred fields, the debris and men in sloppy camouflage waving guns and barking orders. A world away, at Eindhoven military airport, dozens of black hearses were parked in a perfect line and the nation held its breath as the planes began to land. The contrast between the chaos of war-torn Ukraine and the dignified, choreographed reception on Dutch soil was overwhelming. What I couldn't see on my screen were the relatives, their grief hidden away from the cameras.
Babs says all she could hear was the flapping of flags at half-mast. She will never know which coffin carried her sister back. The identification process took weeks. But she remembers the day a man brought Joyce's belongings back - each item wrapped in white paper, including the documents the miner gave me.
I tell Babs that I plan to go to eastern Ukraine and try to find the miner. She asks me to thank him. "It's important to me that they respected her dying," she says.
But, she tells me, there was one thing missing from Joyce's belongings - a silver bracelet her sister always wore. Babs asks me to try to track it down.
These days a trip to eastern Ukraine, where war continues, is a complex undertaking.  It involves a road journey across bombed-out countryside through many checkpoints - first on the Ukrainian, then on the Russian-backed side. Both require special permissions. I have all the documents, as I've been back to Ukraine several times over the past year, but just as I prepare to go back to look for the miner - and now the bracelet - I get bad news.  The authorities in the self-declared Donetsk People's Republic have revoked my permit - and they say this is non-negotiable.
I was barbecuing, and there it was - falling down - a big thing
Alexander, Rassypnoe, Ukraine
The reason for banning me from Donetsk appears to be a television piece that I did on my last trip to Ukraine, examining the story of a 10-year-old girl allegedly killed during Ukrainian shelling of Donetsk .  I heard the report on Russian television and decided to fact-check it.  What I found was that not only was there no shelling that day, but the girl herself had never existed. Russian journalists admitted to me on camera that they had fabricated the report because they "had to do it".
My report deeply upset the authorities in Donetsk. The story of the girl is simply one of many examples of the propaganda war between Russia and Ukraine. Flight MH17 is at the heart of this war.  Ukrainian journalists have stuck to the version, supported by the West, that rebels shot down the plane with a Buk missile. Russian television in the meantime has presented several alternative theories, including one repeated to me by rebel spokesman Eduard Basurin. "Did you know that the plane was pre-loaded with dead bodies at Schiphol airport?" he asked me on my trip to Donetsk in April 2015. "It was all part of a plan to make us look bad."
Having failed to convince the Donetsk authorities that this time I was coming simply to look for a miner and a bracelet, I started investigating whether there was any way of doing this remotely. I called everyone I could think of in Donetsk, including a journalist, Katya Malofeyeva. She told me she was about to travel to the three villages at the crash site and volunteered to show people pictures of the bracelet and the miner.
Katya returned from her trip with audio recordings of several local people. Their trauma is clearly audible on tape.
"I was barbecuing, and there it was - falling down. A big thing. A big piece. And from that piece of plane people were falling. They were flying as if they were birds with their arms spread out," said Alexander in the village of Rassypnoe.
A local woman looks at the crash site of flight MH17 in August 2014
Others told Katya they were tired of talking to journalists. Some cried.  "As if the war wasn't enough to deal with," one woman said. Another, called Marina, said that her only request was a memorial for the victims. "We must preserve their memory," she said.
People are still finding things, we give everything back
Marina , Rassypnoe, Ukraine
When Katya showed Marina a photo of Joyce with her bracelet, she sounded excited. Her neighbour, Galya, had found a bracelet in her garden, she said. Last year a woman's body fell into Galya's courgette patch, and for a year she avoided the garden. But this spring she finally ventured in, and while working on the land she found a bracelet.
Marina walked Katya over to her neighbour's house, where Galya examined the photo of Joyce wearing her chunky silver band and declared it to be a different bracelet."The one I found is white with a golden rim and little jewels. Maybe you can find the family so I can return it?" she said.
Sensing Katya's disappointment, both Galya and Marina reassured her that there is a good chance the bracelet will be found.  "People are still finding things, we give everything back," Marina said.
Residents of villages around the crash site are still sensitive about allegations of looting that came after the crash. I personally saw things disappear in the chaos of those first days. Each time we arrived at the site the pile of belongings by the roadside got smaller and smaller.  Those whisky bottles, for example, vanished by the third day.  By the fifth day, the "I love Amsterdam" T-shirt that had been laid out on the grass was gone too. But there were also plenty of people, like that coal miner, who took care of the personal belongings they found.
Katya showed the coal miner's photo to everybody she met, and it turned out that he wasn't local but part of a group brought in from another area.  We will keep trying to track him down, but over the last year thousands of people have been killed in fighting in eastern Ukraine, and thousands more have fled. Katya and others say they'll keep trying to find the bracelet too.
Babs will be waiting.  For the bracelet, and, with the rest of the nation, for answers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:09:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The rise and fall of Quaaludes</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33428487#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The prescription drug that was misused and then disappeared</Description>
        <MainBody>The rise and fall of Quaaludes
By Harry Low and Tom Heyden BBC News Magazine
9 July 2015
From the section Magazine
Quaalude was popular in the US in the 1970s. Now, the drug is back in the headlines after the revelation that comedian Bill Cosby admitted getting them to give to women he wanted to have sex with.
The admission was made in 2005, but the court papers were only released this week.
They refer back to a period when Quaalude was taken as a recreational drug - so much so that the sedative pill has been banned in the US for over 30 years.
Anyone who has seen Leonardo DiCaprio's depiction of a Quaalude binge in Martin Scorsese's The Wolf of Wall Street - in which he can barely speak, can't walk and certainly can't drive - may well wonder what why anyone would take it intentionally.
Quaalude is a tradename for methaqualone, which was first synthesised in 1951 in India. Germany and Japan were the first big markets, where the drug racked up an extensive record of addiction and abuse. In the UK it was known as Mandrax, a name still used in South Africa.
Law enforcement officers confiscating Mandrax pills in South Africa
By the time it reached the US in the 1960s, it was being used to treat insomnia and anxiety.  However, it didn't take long for the drug's potent features to be misused.
"Doctors were essentially giving them out like candy," says Justin Gass, author of a book about the drug. "It was very easy to obtain Quaaludes in the mid-late 1970s and early 1980s."
People could buy them in semi-legal "stress clinics" without needing to visit a GP. They were pseudo-medical centres that would hand out the maximum legal prescription. These tactics would often be the clinics' eventual downfall, says David Herzberg, professor of history at the University at Buffalo.
At its height during the 1970s, Quaalude could be found across the US and earned the nickname "disco biscuits".
"America in the 1950s and 1960s was having a sedative boom," Herzberg explains, "so there was this wonderful market for them." As the barbiturates popular in the 1950s became stigmatised, drug companies introduced newer sedatives such as Librium and Valium, which claimed to be significantly different.
Quaalude was part of that new wave. And although unpatented, meaning any pharmaceutical company could produce methaqualone, Quaalude was the name that stuck.
Herzberg says people found it more pleasant to take than other sedatives.
The main consumers - at least recreationally - were young people. "[They'd] decided that all the drugs their parents took were these soul-killing corporate things that would turn you into a conformist robot," Herzberg says.
Musicians sang about them. David Bowie's Time references "Quaaludes and red wine" while Frank Zappa speaks of "Quaalude moonlight"
David Bowie sang about Quaaludes
Quaalude had a novelty but also a distinct selling point. "It got the reputation of relaxing people so that they can have freer sex," Herzberg says, which made them catch on across college campuses. Bay City Rollers lead singer Les McKeown has said he was raped by another man at the height of their fame after being given Quaaludes.
It provides users with a "really powerful high", says Gass, now a professor of neurosciences at the Medical University of South Carolina. It takes just 30 minutes to start having an effect, which can last up to six hours.
But it could be dangerous, particularly when mixed with alcohol, as it often was. "People would lie down to go to sleep and just not wake up," says Gass. "That was quite common."
In the UK, methaqualone was sold under the name Mandrax and became popular too. Rolling Stones guitarist Keith Richards admitted possessing the drug in October 1973.
Earlier that year, a tribunal heard testimony that a Mandrax addict had taken between 10 and 12 tablets before driving a car into a bus, killing two and injuring four others, the Times reported. "A further trend of misuse is mixing Mandrax and alcohol, with disastrous results," said a Church of Scotland committee report on moral welfare.
They increasingly drew negative attention. "There's no doubt we've lost a considerable amount of business because of this substitution of the trade name for the generic name," Elliot Fisher, lawyer for Lemmon, who made the drug, told Associated Press in 1981. He said he was writing up to 50 letters a week to newspapers and police forces complaining about the use of the word "Quaalude" and finding many respondents were surprised it was a trademark.
Regulators eventually stepped in. By 1984, the drug was listed as Schedule I in the US and a Class B drug in the UK, which makes its production and distribution illegal altogether.
Rohypnol, a drug commonly cited in rape cases, which is part of the Valium family, has sometimes been referred to as the Quaaludes of the 1990s. It has many of the same effects, says Gass. It's quick to work, erases memory and is a muscle relaxant.
Methaqualone is no longer legitimately manufactured but it's still possible to find people claiming to sell Quaaludes on the streets, explains Gass.
"But they are generally nothing more than a combination of different barbiturates which they hope would create the same effect but it certainly does not."
More from the Magazine
An undercover operation smashed one of the most extraordinary drug rings the world has ever seen and changed British policing forever. What was Operation Julie?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 10:26:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Vietnamese veterans stories</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/in-pictures-33408096#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>North Vietnamese veterans tell their stories</Description>
        <MainBody>From the section In Pictures
The conflict in Vietnam ended 40 years ago, with chaotic scenes in Saigon, now Ho Chi Minh City, as the North Vietnamese Army closed in on the heart of power, its tanks ploughing through the gates of the South Vietnamese presidential palace on 30 April 1975.
On board one of the tanks was Pham Xuan Do, who is seen in the picture above proudly wearing his uniform from the time.
The picture was taken during a project led by Raul Roman, co-founder of UBELONG , and Lonnie Schlein, a former New York Times photojournalist who took a party of 14 people to Vietnam in May, with the aim of capturing the stories of those who fought for the North Vietnamese Army (NVA) or Viet Cong.
A North Vietnamese tank drives through the main gate of the presidential palace in 1975
Do served in the NVA as a lieutenant captain from 1965 to 1975. He said he misses some of the excitement of war, but now that time has passed feels "forgiveness".
The projects aim is to see the war from the perspective of North Vietnamese veterans, and to mark 20 years since the then US President Bill Clinton normalised diplomatic relations between the two countries, on 11 July 1995.
"It's really important work because the world needs to be reminded that the dark shadow of the Vietnam War still looms large in this country," says Mr Roman.
"This work is really special also because it's an international civic initiative by ordinary citizens, a sort of peace mission designed to bring people together."
The group conducted more than two dozen in-depth interviews with veterans, travelling to Hanoi and rural locations bombed during the war.
Many of these areas were subjected to use of the toxic chemical Agent Orange, a defoliant sprayed over jungle areas to destroy enemy cover.
Vietnam says several million people have been affected by Agent Orange, including 150,000 children with severe birth defects.
Here are a selection of the stories they uncovered.
Le Ba Bon
Le Ba Bon, 63, was from a family of rice farmers and withdrew from school in 1972 to join the North Vietnamese Army. He said: "Starting life after the war was terrifying to me. With my injuries, I could not continue my education or find a job. But I have let go of my hurt and pain. It's time to look into the future and begin cooperating." (Photograph by Joey Rosa)
Pham An Thic
Pham An Thic (left) served in an artillery unit from 1965 to 1977 and was the only son in his family who survived the war. His mother, Dau (right), now almost blind, remembers receiving the letters from the government announcing that her other four sons had been killed.
"I didn't know how they had died," she said.
"I didn't know what they were doing when they died. I just knew that they were gone. Losing a child is the greatest sadness."
Thic's wife (centre) waited for him for 12 years. "I did not know if he was dead or if he was alive," she said.
"All I could do was to take care of my children and work hard so I could feed them.
"I wasn't special. I was one of thousands of Vietnamese wives and mothers who had to survive without their husbands during the war."
She recalls the day her husband returned. She was working in the rice fields when one of their neighbours gave her the news. "I ran all the way home," she said.
"I was so happy to see him after so long." (Photograph by Raul Roman)
Tran Thi Thon
Tran Thi Thon served in the North Vietnamese army from 1965 to 1975, delivering supplies from the North to the South.
"The day I remember most vividly was the day we found a downed American pilot.," she said.
"I saw that he had lost his shoe, so I took my shoe off and strapped it on his foot.
"Then, I took my handkerchief out and wiped the blood off his face.
"I felt very sympathetic because he was just another human and he didn't want to be in this war just like I didn't.
"The pilot then told my crew to hide, as a rescue helicopter was on its way and they would shoot us.
"But the helicopter never came and the pilot was captured by our soldiers."
While making her deliveries, she saw a yellow liquid covering the jungle.
It felt cool to the touch, so she and her teammates picked leaves and rubbed the substance on their skin to refresh themselves. It was Agent Orange.
Now, the skin on her arms, legs, and stomach is covered in scars.
She underwent several operations to repair the damage.
But the worst consequence of the exposure were the birth defects of her son, who died of lung cancer at the age of 35, and her daughter, who is physically and mentally disabled. (Photograph by Lonnie Schlein)
Luong Ngoc Lam
Luong Ngoc Lam was photographed at Friendship Village, a shelter for veterans and children affected by Agent Orange. He served as a field soldier for the NVA from 1966 to 1975.
His proudest moment was participating in the taking of Saigon.
"When the war ended, I had not seen my wife in 10 years," he said. "I returned home to learn that she had held 10 funerals during that period, including one for my younger brother.
"Coming home to learn that he had been killed was devastating." (Photograph by Joey Rosa)
Luong Duc Pho
Luong Duc Pho was a driver, transporting soldiers in his jeep as well as rebuilding and clearing roads to facilitate the transportation of weapons and food.
Pho waited 15 years to recover the body of his brother killed in the war.
"The young generation doesn't know anything about the hardships of war," he said.
"They have never been through this. They don't know what being hungry means.
"It is important that they learn more to understand what we endured and why we did it." (Photograph by Raul Roman)
Tran Van Van and his wife, Pham Thi Sang
Tran Van Van and his wife, Pham Thi Sang, are pictured at their home in Binh Giang.
Van served in the North Vietnamese Army from 1965 to 1972 and was stationed on the border of Cambodia on the Ho Chi Minh trail, tasked with protecting the road from bombers.
"We were bombed so often, and so many people died on the battlefield," he said.
"The badly injured were taken to the aid station, but I buried my dead friends on the battlefield. I miss them greatly."
He was eventually discharged after being injured in a bombing.  He often relives that event in his nightmares.
While Van was fighting, his wife worked as a rice farmer in order for the family to survive.
"We were very poor and always hungry because there wasn't enough rice for me and my babies," she said.
"One of the hardest moments of my life was when I had to go into the fields after my baby was born, but I had no choice.
"I didn't want to tell Van so I wrote him letters of encouragement to stay and fight in the war. Our country was more important."
During the seven years in the army, Van only saw his family once, for a 10-day span in 1968.
During that time he and his wife conceived a child, Tran Van Tin, now 46, who was born with severe health problems which is believed to be due to Van's exposure to Agent Orange. (Photograph by John DeSanto)
Vu Thanh La
Vu Thanh Lan fought with the Viet Cong in Quang Nam and Quang Ngai for more than a decade.
"I don't allow my grandchildren to ask about the war because I don't want to poison their views of the United States and the world," he said. (Photograph by John DeSanto)
Nguyen Van Vuong
Nguyen Van Vuong  started as a soldier in the North Vietnamese Army in 1966 and ended his service in 1971 after contracting malaria.
In the battle of Quang Tri, during the Tet Offensive in 1968, his unit of 100 men was devastated. He was one of 20 who survived.
Later, he lost most of his hearing during a bombing raid.  Returning home after the war was not easy.
"My village was destroyed and government assistance couldn't support me," he said.
"My dream was to start a family, but it was not to be."  (Photograph by Lonnie Schlein)
Tran Van Thinh
Tran Van Thinh joined up aged 19 and ended his service with a high rank and multiple medals of honour.
In the battle of Quang Tri in 1968 he was hit by a bomb that blew off part of his left arm and shattered his right leg.
Married for 30 years with one son and two grandchildren, he lost two brothers in the war.
"I was very young. All I knew at that time was that I had to fight the Americans to reunify my country," he said.
"My most disturbing memory was killing two American soldiers." (Photograph by Joey Rosa)
All photographs  UBELONG .
The Vietnam War
1954 - Geneva Accords signed dividing Vietnam in two - the Communist North helps guerrillas in the South fight US-backed Southern troops
1964 - US bombs targets in North Vietnam
1965 - The first US combat troops arrive in Vietnam
1973 - The Paris Peace Accords on "Ending the War and Restoring Peace in Vietnam" are signed, officially ending direct US involvement - but fighting between North and South continues
30 April 1975 - North Vietnamese troops enter Saigon - South Vietnam is controlled by Communist forces and the country is reunited ending the war
It's estimated that more than three million people were killed in the conflict
Other pieces that might be of interest include:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:20:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why the volatility in Chinese markets?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33457211#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Why the volatility in Chinese markets?</Description>
        <MainBody>Why the volatility in Chinese markets?
9 July 2015
From the section Business
China's stock markets have lost more than 30% of their value since mid-June, a worrying statistic for investors and the government.
On Wednesday 8 July, a stock market index called the Shanghai Composite, which is regarded as a benchmark and an indicator for all share movements in China, fell as much as 8%, leading some analysts to call the trading day Black Wednesday.
Earlier this year, however, China's share market had been one of the best performing in Asia - if not the world.
More than 80% of people who invest in China's stock market are so-called "mom and pop" investors
Why did prices initially rise in China?
More and more investors piling into the market, often using borrowed money, pushed share prices up 150% between June 2014 and June 2015.
Today, about 85% of investors are not finance professionals but individuals who were spurred on by government policies that encouraged investment in the markets.
Since 2010 it's been easier to borrow money to invest - so-called margin financing. And that made it easier for less-wealthy people to get involved.
Investment, and talking about investment, has become a pastime for millions of people.
But analysts widely agree there has been a lot of naivety, with a belief the markets could only go up and up.
What's causing the fall?
Just as investors followed their friends and family into the stock market - now they're following them out. That herd mentality can exaggerate market moves very swiftly.
Small investors "are by their nature enthused by momentum", says market specialist Chris Weston from IG Markets. "If the market is rallying, they feel like they need to be involved on fear of missing out. That momentum is now headed sharply lower and so they want out."
Meanwhile long-term investors who have been in the market for more than a year are likely to still be sitting on profits and so as things are getting rocky, some are selling.
Does the fall reflect deeper problems in the Chinese economy?
Many analysts say this is a correction and that shares have been overvalued for a long time.
There does not seem to be any correlation between this crash and the health of the wider economy.
The gains in Chinese stocks last year didn't reflect economic improvement. China has, in fact, been slowing over the past 12 months.
So unlike earlier Chinese market crashes, notably in 2008 when the economy slowed, this seems to be linked directly to issues around the stock market.
Estimates suggest the current crisis affects about 15% of households directly
Will the stock market crisis spread to the wider economy?
It could. If it turns out that Chinese investors have been putting their money into risky, poorly regulated investments there could be a spill over effect, just as the US mortgage market collapse caused a major financial crisis in 2007-08.
But as a proportion of the Chinese economy, stocks are not especially big - unlike mortgages in the US.
Stock market investment is still a largely urban phenomenon in China and so estimates suggest the current crisis affects just 15% of households directly.
Brokerages have been lent on by the government to help stabilise the market
What is the government doing to prop up the markets?
China's regulators have barred investors holding stakes of more than 5% from selling their shares for the next six months.
Major Chinese brokerages have pledged to buy stocks to help stabilise the market.
Share flotations - or initial public offerings - have been suspended because they usually divert funds from existing stocks, pushing prices down.
And China's central bank has said it will inject money into a state-owned company that finances margin trading - a type of trade which involves borrowing from a broker to purchase stock - to help people buy more shares.
The volatility has spilled over into Hong Kong shares
And is that working?
It didn't seem to be. Until Wednesday whatever the government did, share prices just kept falling.
The market had a better day on Thursday, however, which could be a sign that the Chinese government's measures are starting to have an impact.
Should the government be worried?
Since 2013, the government has been cheering on the stock market and getting investors to buy up shares.
This was seen as national priority - a way to carry out economic reforms in China that were driven by market forces rather than the government.
If these inexperienced investors see the value of their stocks slashed then expect anger. Even if Chinese state broadcasters have been fairly quiet on the subject - social media certainly hasn't.
For Premier Li Keqiang and Prime Minister Xi Jinping their financial credibility is on the line.
And why has the Hong Kong market been falling too?
With the exception of a few institutional investors, foreigners can't invest directly in mainland Chinese stocks. And so large Chinese companies wanting to tap overseas investment money often have a listing on the Hong Kong market too.
So the volatility in Hong Kong markets is reflecting concern from international investors about the Chinese market.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 08:44:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Organised crime threatens Brazil's Amazon</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33449810#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Organised crime responsible for rising Brazil deforestation</Description>
        <MainBody>Wyre Davies Rio de Janeiro correspondent
9 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
comments
We are flying low in helicopter formation over the Brazilian Amazon with agents from Ibama - the state-funded institute responsible for environmental protection.
No country has done more than Brazil in recent years to tackle the previously rampant levels of deforestation but there is a good reason the agents have their guns drawn - we have seen statistics which show that rates of Amazon destruction are again on the rise.
There are big profits to be made from illegal logging and the fraudulent clearing of rainforest for valuable cash crops and these helicopter patrols are often shot at.
Trying to locate illegal logging operations in the midst of this dense jungle from the air is like looking for the proverbial needle in a haystack.
Destroyed on the spot
There are probably thousands of small illegal logging camps across the Amazon. Men armed with machetes and chainsaws, cutting down valuable Brazilian hardwoods are the foot soldiers in a highly profitable and dangerous trade.
Ibama agents are at the forefront of the campaign against illegal deforestation
Bulldozers illegally destroying the forest openly operate during the day
Greenpeace is calling for a ban on wood exports from Brazil
Locating illegal logging operations in dense jungle from the air is like looking for a needle in a haystack
On the ground, the Ibama agents show little sympathy to the loggers.
Those that are caught risk arrest, their camps are set alight and their machinery, including expensive tractors and other equipment, are destroyed on the spot.
All of this might appear harsh but, says Maria Luisa de Sousa, the Ibama official who has been co-ordinating this month-long operation in northern and eastern Mato Grosso, the fight to save the Amazon is increasingly a fight against organised crime.
"You can compare it to the struggle against drugs trafficking. The crime and the criminals keep on adapting."
As we wait for our helicopter to be refuelled before heading out on another mission she adds: "They're getting even more sophisticated, using even bigger tools to deforest, which makes it even more dangerous for us.".
Everything felled
We fly on, over virgin jungle, but also over immense fields of soya and corn, cash crops that have earned valuable export profits for Brazil in recent decades and also help to feed the growing population in the south of the country.
Some of the most recent deforestation sometimes seems blatant and egregious. Down below we spot two huge tractors - the "new beasts" of the jungle.
They are involved in one of the most destructive forms of deforestation in the Amazon.
In this case, several acres of trees have been felled in a couple of days or weeks. Dragging a huge, steel chain between them, the tractors have felled everything in their path.
New monthly figures show that deforestation rates in some parts of Brazil have almost doubled compared to last year.
Those statistics also show that increasing amounts of wood are illegally taken from protected indigenous reserves.
Threatening gangs
Three hours' drive from the town of Aripuana, I spent two days with members of the Cinta Larga tribe.
They may wear Western-style clothes and live in wooden shelters, rather than grass huts, but they mainly live in and off the forest.
Debate is raging in Brazil over the right to develop and exploit its natural resources over the need to protect biodiversity
Owners of legal timber operations like this one say that only properly managed exploitation of the Amazon - including indigenous areas - can ensure the rainforest's survival
Ibama agents have access to helicopters but are still pushed to deal with the scale of illegal deforestation
Members of the Cinta Larga tribe rely on the forest for their survival
This is a reserve being increasingly invaded by illegal loggers - unscrupulous and sometimes threatening gangs who cut down trees by day and spirit away truckloads of wood by night.
"The loggers come in here for the valuable hardwoods that have already been lost elsewhere," says Amadeus.
"That's why the pressure on our land and all the indigenous lands around here is so strong."
Read more about the concerns of Amazon residents.
In some areas, its thought that as much as 80% of the timber felled is done so illegally - from state-owned or indigenous land.
Back in Aripuana, there seems to be as many timber mills as there are coffee shops in Rome.
It is in the sawmills that illegal or "dirty" wood with false certification gets mixed up with the legitimate industry.
"There's no way to tell which timber is legal and which is illegal after the chain is contaminated," says Greenpeace researcher Marina Lacorte.
"We're asking international companies and importers to stop buying timber from Brazil because there's no guarantee that official documents can guarantee the legal origin," she adds.
Managed exploitation
Such a move would surely be harsh on those legal timber companies who have nothing to hide about their operations.
The problem facing those fighting illegal deforestation is telling which timber is legal and which is illegal
Increasing amounts of wood have been illegally taken from protected indigenous reserves
This satellite image clearly shows the level of deforestation in Mato Grosso
Environmentalists say that the government is not doing enough to protect one of the world's most beautiful areas
SM Wood &amp; Laminates only deals in certified timber and in its yard huge, decades-old logs await cutting up for export.
More than 50 people work at the plant in a region where 20 million Brazilians now live.
Manager Vanderlei Nunes is frank and honest in his view that only by placing a monetary value on the forest, allowing managed exploitation of the Amazon - including indigenous areas - can the rainforest survive.
"I think that people in the south of Brazil and in Europe and the US think the forest is untouchable, but they forget that there are people living and working here," says Mr Nunes, who like many of those who now call the Amazon home, initially came here in search of work from other parts of Brazil.
"So until we find a formula for them to live from the forest - get an income from it and give it a value - then the Amazon problem won't be resolved."
Last week in a highly publicised trip to Washington, Brazil's President Dilma Rousseff expressed her "deep concern" for the climate and in a joint press conference with US President Barack Obama, she made numerous pledges about the environment - promising among other things to stop all illegal deforestation.
But many environmentalists are sceptical about her ability to deliver on her promises.
Under tighter economic constraints her government has repeatedly cut environmental budgets, while the emphasis has often lent towards the right of Brazil to develop and exploit its resources over the need to protect biodiversity.
As long as that remains the case and if President Rousseff fails to match the rhetoric in Washington with the appropriate resources, the future of this unique wilderness remains in jeopardy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
