<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Greece offers sweeping sales tax hikes and pension cuts in new proposals to creditors - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/09/greece-offers-sweeping-sales-tax-hikes-and-pension</Link>
        <Description>Greece offers sweeping sales tax hikes and pension cuts in new proposals to creditors - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>More: NAACP, NCAA plan to end boycott of South Carolina with removal of Confederate flag - @postandcourier</title>
        <Link>http://www.postandcourier.com/article/20150709/PC16/150709386/naacp-ncaa-plan-to-end-boycott-of-south-carolina</Link>
        <Description>More: NAACP, NCAA plan to end boycott of South Carolina with removal of Confederate flag - @postandcourier</Description>
        <MainBody>Email Facebook @prentissfindlay
Jul 9 2015 4:57 pm Jul 9 6:00 pm
The NAACP and NCAA are both poised to lift their boycotts of South Carolina now that the Confederate flag will be removed from the Statehouse grounds.
Online
For complete coverage of the shooting at Emanuel AME Church, including victim profiles, videos, photo galleries and more, go to postandcourier.com/church-shooting .
The NAACP will consider an emergency resolution to lift its long-standing economic boycott at its national convention in Philadelphia on Saturday, President Cornell William Brooks said Thursday.
The announcement was made following the General Assemblys decision to remove the flag from the Statehouse grounds.
Today, South Carolina ushers the state and our country into a new era  one of unity and inclusion at a time of such profound tragedy, he said in a statement posted on the NAACP website.
The NCAA Board of Governors said in a statement Thursday that its boycott of the state ends with the removal of the Confederate flag from the Statehouse grounds.
For nearly 15 years we have specifically protested the flag by not allowing states like South Carolina to host pre-selected NCAA championships. With this impending change, and consistent with our policy, South Carolina may bid to host future NCAA championships once the flag no longer flies at the Statehouse grounds, said Kirk Schulz, NCAA Board of Governors chair and Kansas State University president.
The boycott began 15 years ago in response to the states decision to keep the Confederate flag on the Statehouse grounds after removing it from atop the Capitol dome.
The United Auto Workers and the NCAA joined the NAACP in the boycott.
The states move to remove the flag honors the lives of the nine people slain on June 17 in the shooting at Emanuel AME Church in Charleston, including the Rev. Clementa Pinckney, who was a state senator, Brooks said.
This decision will make South Carolina more welcoming and affirming of all people irrespective of their skin color, he said.
The Charleston Metro Chamber of Commerce applauded the General Assemblys courageous action in a statement.
This is an important day that will result in many opportunities for our future, the chamber said.
South Carolina is now, more than ever, a place where people will want to visit and where businesses will want to grow, the chamber said.
More importantly, it is a place where the people who reside here work through their differences to show respect and love through the most difficult of times, the chamber said.
The banner has long been a thorn in the side of state colleges, who were unable to host predetermined NCAA championship events such as the mens basketball tournament, post-season golf events and bowl games. Following suit, the ACC moved its baseball tournament from Myrtle Beach to Durham, N.C.
Although the NCAA ban didnt impact post-season events decided on merit  such as baseball, where the University of South Carolina and Clemson have regularly played on their home fields  USCs nationally-ranked womens basketball team was forced to play NCAA tournament games away from Colonial Life Arena until the format for the event was changed prior to this season.
The mens NCAA basketball tournament has been absent from the state since the first and second rounds were contested in Greenville in 2002, which was scheduled before the ban went into effect.
The Confederate flag has flown on the Statehouse grounds for 54 years since being put up as a way of marking the 100th anniversary of the Civil War and also to protest the civil rights movement.
Gov. Nikki Haley and other conservatives didnt begin a push to remove the flag until nine black churchgoers were killed during Bible study by a gunman who police say was motivated by racial hatred.
Haley signed the bill to remove the flag late Thursday afternoon after the House passed it earlier in the day. The measure says the flag must be removed within 24 hours of her signature. The final bipartisan compromise will remove the flag and place it in the nearby Confederate Relic Room and Military Museum.
The flag is scheduled to come down in a ceremony planned for 10 a.m. Friday morning.
David Caraviello contributed to this report.
Keywords
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>House Speaker John Boehner, R-Ohio, calls on President Obama to instill new leadership in Office of Personnel Management after breach 'so we can move forward in a fashion that begins to restore the confidence of the American people' - statement</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/09/house-speaker-john-boehner-r-ohio-calls-on-presi</Link>
        <Description>House Speaker John Boehner, R-Ohio, calls on President Obama to instill new leadership in Office of Personnel Management after breach 'so we can move forward in a fashion that begins to restore the confidence of the American people' - statement</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 09, 2015, 09:51 PM GMT
(
21:51
)
House Speaker John Boehner, R-Ohio, calls on President Obama to instill new leadership in Office of Personnel Management after breach 'so we can move forward in a fashion that begins to restore the confidence of the American people' - statement
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Tornado warning issued for Socorro County, NM - @KOATLiveUpdates</title>
        <Link>http://www.koat.com/weather/tornado-warning-issued-for-socorro-county/34082662</Link>
        <Description>Tornado warning issued for Socorro County, NM - @KOATLiveUpdates</Description>
        <MainBody>Tornado warning issued for Socorro County
UPDATED3:42 PM MDT Jul 09, 2015
A tornado warning has been issued for Socorro County.
It will expire at 4 p.m.
Click for statewide weather alerts
A severe thunderstorm capable of producing a tornado was located 17 miles northeast of Socorro around 3:30 p.m. It's moving northeast at 20 mph.
Be cognizant of flying debris. Damage to mobile homes, roofs, windows and vehicles will occur. Tree damage is likely.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>US Secretary of State Kerry on passing of former Saudi Arabia Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal: 'He was a man of vast experience, personal warmth, great dignity, and keen insights who served his country loyally and well. The longevity of his term in office ... is a sign of the universal respect with which he was viewed'</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/09/us-secretary-of-state-kerry-on-passing-of-former-s</Link>
        <Description>US Secretary of State Kerry on passing of former Saudi Arabia Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal: 'He was a man of vast experience, personal warmth, great dignity, and keen insights who served his country loyally and well. The longevity of his term in office ... is a sign of the universal respect with which he was viewed'</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 09, 2015, 09:47 PM GMT
(
21:47
)
US Secretary of State Kerry on passing of former Saudi Arabia Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal: 'He was a man of vast experience, personal warmth, great dignity, and keen insights who served his country loyally and well. The longevity of his term in office ... is a sign of the universal respect with which he was viewed'
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Sen. Bill Nelson, D-Fla., to have surgery to remove prostate cancer - @WFLA, @lesleyclark, @jackiefell</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/WFLA/status/619253938328506368/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Sen. Bill Nelson, D-Fla., to have surgery to remove prostate cancer - @WFLA, @lesleyclark, @jackiefell</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Authorities put up barriers at South Carolina Statehouse to keep people away from Confederate flag, which is set to be removed Friday - @SamInteractive</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/SamInteractive/status/619247384959287296/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Authorities put up barriers at South Carolina Statehouse to keep people away from Confederate flag, which is set to be removed Friday - @SamInteractive</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Authorities responding to fire on Kitsap County, Wash., beach - @KIRO7Seattle</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/KIRO7Seattle/status/619247224338317312/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Authorities responding to fire on Kitsap County, Wash., beach - @KIRO7Seattle</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Variety reports songwriter Roy C. Bennett dies at 97; wrote songs for Sinatra, Elvis, the Beatles - @Variety</title>
        <Link>http://variety.com/2015/music/people-news/roy-c-bennett-dies-at-97-wrote-songs-for-sinatra-elvis-the-beatles-1201537186/</Link>
        <Description>Variety reports songwriter Roy C. Bennett dies at 97; wrote songs for Sinatra, Elvis, the Beatles - @Variety</Description>
        <MainBody>Courtesy of Roy C. Bennett Family
July 9, 2015 | 01:24PM PT
Carmel Dagan
Roy C. Bennett , a songwriter who, with Sid Tepper , wrote songs for anextraordinarily wide range of artists including Duke Ellington, Louis Armstrong, Ray Charles, Frank Sinatra, Elvis Presley and the Beatles, died July 2 in Queens, New York. He was 97.
The duo wrote 45 songs for Elvis alone, including most of the songs in the film Blue Hawaii. In 2002, Bennett and Tepper were honored in Memphis for their part in Presleys career.
Many of the songs they penned  most notably, Red Roses for a Blue Lady  are what the industry calls evergreens. One of their songs, The Naughty Lady of Shady Lane, from 1954, was recently featured on ABCs Dancing with the Stars.
Bennett began his career writing songs at the age of 11  with Tepper, who was to become his decades-long partner. Tepper died in April at the age of 96.
In his autobiography Keith Richards of the Rolling Stones fame makes note of one of their songs (Travelin Light, recorded by both Cliff Richard and Hermans Hermits). It was among the records that influenced Richards early on and was an important part of what he and others referred to as the Awakening  the birth of rock and roll on U.K. shores.
In addition to Armstrong, Ellington, Charles, Sinatra, the Beatles and Presley, Tepper and Bennett also wrote songs for Carl Perkins, Jeff Beck, Hermans Hermits, the Dave Clark Five, Perry Como, Andy Williams, Ray Charles, Cliff Richard, Eddie Arnold, Marty Robbins, Slim Whitman, Bert Kaempfert, Wayne Newton, Robert Goulet, Dean Martin, Dinah Shore, Nancy Wilson, Connie Francis, Sarah Vaughn, Guy Lombardo, Eartha Kitt, the Ink Spots, Louis Prima, Arthur Godfrey, Tommy Dorsey and Lawrence Welk.
Among the songwriters hits were The Naughty Lady of Shady Lane, Kiss of Fire, Say Something Sweet to Your Sweetheart, Kewpie Doll, G.I. Blues, Suzy Snowflake, Puppet on a String, Stairway of Love, Nuttin for Christmas, The Woodchuck Song, Glad All Over, Dont Come Running Back to Me, New Orleans and the Elvis-Ann-Margret duet The Lady Loves Me.
Bennett was born Israel Brodsky  known as Izzy  to a poor family in Brooklyn. He was a quiet boy, but his singing ability was evident at an early age, and early on, he was torn between his two major talents, singing and writing. His vocation was songwriting, but his avocation, to which he was passionately dedicated for decades, was choral singing. In the 1970s he published a book on the art of choral singing.
He went to City College in New York but returned in his mid 40s to graduate, making that final push because he thought it was important to set an example for his children.
They won a BMI Award for 1 million plays of Kiss of Fireand a Country Music Award for Eddie Arnolds rendition of Red Roses for a Blue Lady.
His creativity did not diminish in his old age. Not that long ago, he finished a new composition  a love song entitled Cuando (or When), put to the melody of La Paloma.
Bennett is survived by his wife, Ruth Bennett; two sons, Keith and Neil Bennett; and three grandchildren.
Filed Under:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Federal judge decides trial for lawsuit against former Florida State football quarterback Jameis Winston to be held in Orlando - @WESH</title>
        <Link>http://www.wesh.com/sports/judge-to-decide-on-location-of-civil-trial-in-jameis-winston-rape-case/34054468?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=wesh</Link>
        <Description>Federal judge decides trial for lawsuit against former Florida State football quarterback Jameis Winston to be held in Orlando - @WESH</Description>
        <MainBody>Judge decides on civil trial location for Jameis Winston rape case
Plaintiff's attorney says trial will be held in Orlando
UPDATED5:10 PM EDT Jul 09, 2015
Winston files countersuit against accuser
Tampa Bay Buccaneers quarterback Jameis Winston filed a countersuit against accuser Erica Kinsman, and the No. 1 NFL Draft pick said again in the federal court filing that he did not rape the woman. Winston's attorneys, John F. Myers and Da...
Full document: Judge denies Jameis Winston's motion
The woman who claims she was raped by Winston in December 2012 is suing him.
Judge Anne Conway ruled there is no reason to move the case to Tallahassee, as Winston wanted, because both he and the plaintiff live in Central Florida.
The attorney for Winston, who filed a motion to move the case to Tallahassee, told the judge that it made more sense to have it in Tallahassee because he intends to take the jury to the bar and the apartment where the accuser says she was with Winston in December 2012.
"The witnesses and the evidence we want to rely on are all in Tallahassee. The same people and materials that were used in the (FSU) code of conduct hearing," defense attorney David Cornwell said. Jameis is doing great. Jameis is focusing on becoming the starting quarterback of the Tampa Bay Buccaneers.
According to David King, attorney for the woman, his client fears for her safety and the jury pool could be tainted in Tallahassee. He cited a survey that shows 63 percent of people living in the state capital identify themselves as Florida State fans.
In a case like this, it's important that anything outside the courtroom does not affect the ultimate decision. We want the decision to be made on the facts of the case in the courtroom, and we think there is a better chance of that occurring here in Orlando, King said.
"The bias arises from her public relations campaign to vilify Mr. Winston in the media, Cornwell said. This young man won all but one football game in college with things hanging over his head. He knows how to focus."
Top video: Confederate flag flies again in Marion County
A hearing Wednesday at the federal courthouse in downtown Orlando lasted an hour.
Winston was investigated by Tallahassee and FSU police in the case, but was never charged with a crime.
He signed a four-year contract with the Buccaneers for more than $25 million.
Tweet
Copyright 2015 by WESH.com All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
WESH 2'S GREG FOX WAS IN COURT. JAMEIS IS DOING GREAT. JAMEIS IS FOCUSED ON BECOMING THE STARTING QUARTERBACK OF THE TAMPA BAY BUCCANEERS. THAT'S WHAT THE ATTORNEY FOR FORMER FLORIDA STATE STAR JAMEIS WINSTON IS TELLING US AS THE NEW TAMPA BAY BUCS QUARTERBACK EMBARKS ON A CAREER THAT WOULD MAKE HIM ONE OF THE RICHEST NFL PLAYERS IN HISTORY. HANGING OVER HIS HEAD IS A LEGAL CLOUD THAT COULD RUIN HIS REPUTATION. THE WOMAN WHO ACCUSED HIM OF RAPE IN DECEMBER OF 2012 IS SUING WINSTON IN ORLANDO FEDERAL COURT. WINSTON'S ATTORNEY ARGUED THE CASE SHOULD BE MOVED TO TALLAHASSEE BECAUSE THAT'S WHERE THE WITNESSES AND THE EVIDENCE ARE. THE WOMAN'S ATTORNEY TOLD THE JUDGE... HER ATTORNEY ALSO SAID HE'S CONCERNED THE JURY POOL COULD BE BIASED. LIKELY BIG FANS OF THE FOOTBALL PLAYER. BUT WINSTON'S ATTORNEY SNEERED AT RECENT INTERVIEWS BY THE WOMAN SAYING IN COURT THAT BIAS ARISES FROM HER PUBLIC RELATIONS CAMPAIGN TO VILIFY MR. WINSTON IN THE MEDIA. THE WOMAN'S ATTORNEY SAYS THE BOTTOM LINE IS BOTH SIDES ARE HERE. NOT IN THIS CASE WHERE BOTH THE PLAINTIFF AND DEFENDANT RESIDE IN THE MIDDLE OF DISTRICT OF FLORIDA. AS FOR WINSTON? HE IS REPORTEDLY LETTING ATTORNEYS HANDLE A MATTER THAT HAS LINGERED FOR THREE YEARS. FOR THIS YOUNG MAN WON ALL BUT ONE GAME IN COLLEGE WITH THINGS HANGING OVER HIS HEAD. HE KNOWS HOW TO FOCUS. JAMEIS WINSTON'S ATTORNEY POINTS OUT HE HAS NEVER BEEN
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Report: Toronto drivers being told UBER will pay for any bylaw tickets they receive while new rules are written up - @newstalk1010</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/newstalk1010/status/619244578961383424</Link>
        <Description>Report: Toronto drivers being told UBER will pay for any bylaw tickets they receive while new rules are written up - @newstalk1010</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>UK's Philip Hammond: 'My thoughts are with the people of Saudi Arabia at the passing of Prince Saud al-Faisal, who served his country as foreign minister for 40 years' - @PHammondMP</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/PHammondMP/status/619242906738515968</Link>
        <Description>UK's Philip Hammond: 'My thoughts are with the people of Saudi Arabia at the passing of Prince Saud al-Faisal, who served his country as foreign minister for 40 years' - @PHammondMP</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>National Active and Retired Federal Employees president on Office of Personnel Management breach: 'For these 21.5 million people, a lifetime's worth of information was exposed; they deserve nothing less than a lifetime of protection. Three years is not enough and will not bring peace of mind to those awaiting official notification they were impacted by this incident' - statement</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/09/national-active-and-retired-federal-employees-pres</Link>
        <Description>National Active and Retired Federal Employees president on Office of Personnel Management breach: 'For these 21.5 million people, a lifetime's worth of information was exposed; they deserve nothing less than a lifetime of protection. Three years is not enough and will not bring peace of mind to those awaiting official notification they were impacted by this incident' - statement</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 09, 2015, 08:44 PM GMT
(
20:44
)
National Active and Retired Federal Employees president on Office of Personnel Management breach: 'For these 21.5 million people, a lifetime's worth of information was exposed; they deserve nothing less than a lifetime of protection. Three years is not enough and will not bring peace of mind to those awaiting official notification they were impacted by this incident' - statement
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Senior Iranian official: Lifting arms embargo is our position, Russia's position and China's position; difficult to bring 6 positions together - @rezamarashi</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/rezamarashi/status/619242213621391360</Link>
        <Description>Senior Iranian official: Lifting arms embargo is our position, Russia's position and China's position; difficult to bring 6 positions together - @rezamarashi</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>Monkey escapes from enclosure at Memphis, Tenn., zoo; visitors escorted indoors - @WMCActionNews5</title>
        <Link>http://www.wmcactionnews5.com/story/29514092/monkey-escapes-from-enclosure-in-memphis-zoo?clienttype=generic</Link>
        <Description>Monkey escapes from enclosure at Memphis, Tenn., zoo; visitors escorted indoors - @WMCActionNews5</Description>
        <MainBody>Monkey escapes from Memphis Zoo enclosure
Posted:
MEMPHIS, TN (WMC) -
A monkey escaped from its enclosure atMemphis Zoo.
Zoo officials asked visitors to leave the area and escorted them to an area indoors as a safety precaution. They do not believe there is any danger to visitors or other animals at this time.
Officials say that they know where the macaque, Zimm, is, but they are still trying to catch the small primate.
Copyright 2015 WMC Action News 5. All rights reserved.

Thursday, July 9 2015 5:46 PM EDT2015-07-09 21:46:56 GMT
Phillip Van Zandt Photography
With more people spending time outdoors and an increase in thunderstorm activity,the most deaths fromlightning strikes occur in the month of July. Meteorologist Brittney Bryant is giving you tips on how to protect you and your family from this dangerous weather phenomena. More &gt;&gt;
With more people spending time outdoors and an increase in thunderstorm activity,the most deaths fromlightning strikes occur in the month of July. Meteorologist Brittney Bryant is giving you tips on how to protect you and your family from this dangerous weather phenomena. More &gt;&gt;
breaking
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>NCAA Board of Governors chair on Confederate flag bill: 'We commend South Carolina lawmakers for taking this action'; says state may bid to host future championships once flag is taken down - @NCAA</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/NCAA/status/619241057973211136/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>NCAA Board of Governors chair on Confederate flag bill: 'We commend South Carolina lawmakers for taking this action'; says state may bid to host future championships once flag is taken down - @NCAA</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Smoke from large brush fire in southwest Miami-Dade looms over nearby houses - @nbc6</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcmiami.com/news/local/Brush-Fire-in-Southwest-Miami-Dade-312988521.html</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Smoke from large brush fire in southwest Miami-Dade looms over nearby houses - @nbc6</Description>
        <MainBody>YOU MAY ALSO BE INTERESTED IN...
Play Gallery
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley says 9 pens used to sign Confederate flag removal bill will go to families of Charleston church shooting victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/09/south-carolina-gov-nikki-haley-says-9-pens-used-t</Link>
        <Description>South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley says 9 pens used to sign Confederate flag removal bill will go to families of Charleston church shooting victims</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 09, 2015, 08:21 PM GMT
(
20:21
)
South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley says 9 pens used to sign Confederate flag removal bill will go to families of Charleston church shooting victims
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>Apple's stocks slump 2% to suffer 5th-straight loss, taking it to 5-month low - @MarketsTicker</title>
        <Link>http://www.marketwatch.com/story/apples-stocks-5th-straight-loss-takes-it-to-5-month-low-2015-07-09?mod=BreakingNewsSecondary</Link>
        <Description>Apple's stocks slump 2% to suffer 5th-straight loss, taking it to 5-month low - @MarketsTicker</Description>
        <MainBody>Back to Top
Copyright 2015 MarketWatch, Inc.  All rights reserved.
By using this site you agree to the Terms of Service , Privacy Policy , and Cookie Policy .
Intraday Data provided by SIX Financial Information and subject to terms of use .                 Historical and current end-of-day data provided by SIX Financial Information. Intraday data                 delayed per exchange requirements. S&amp;P/Dow Jones Indices (SM) from Dow Jones &amp; Company, Inc.                 All quotes are in local exchange time. Real time last sale data provided by NASDAQ. More                 information on NASDAQ traded symbols and their current financial status. Intraday                 data delayed 15 minutes for Nasdaq, and 20 minutes for other exchanges. S&amp;P/Dow Jones Indices (SM)                 from Dow Jones &amp; Company, Inc. SEHK intraday data is provided by SIX Financial Information and is                 at least 60-minutes delayed. All quotes are in local exchange time.
Apple Inc. U.S.: Nasdaq: AAPL
$120.07
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley signs bill to remove Confederate flag from Statehouse grounds; flag to come down at 10 am ET on Friday</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/09/south-carolina-gov-nikki-haley-signs-bill-to-remo</Link>
        <Description>South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley signs bill to remove Confederate flag from Statehouse grounds; flag to come down at 10 am ET on Friday</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 09, 2015, 08:19 PM GMT
(
20:19
)
South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley signs bill to remove Confederate flag from Statehouse grounds; flag to come down at 10 am ET on Friday
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
