<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="canada">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Judge warns child abuse under-reported in Britain and one in 20 may have been a victim</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Judge+warns+child+abuse+under+reported+Britain+have+been/11201665/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Justice Lowell Goddard opened a wide-ranging public inquiry into decades of abuse in Britain&amp;#8217;s schools, hospitals and other institutions</Description>
        <MainBody>

Judge warns child abuse under-reported in Britain and one in 20 may have been a victim

By The Associated Press July 9, 2015 1:51 PM



This is  an undated handout file photo issued by Britain's Home Office via PA  of Justice Lowell Goddard.
LONDON  Britain has been stunned by revelations about child sexual abuse, a judge said Thursday, warning that the true scale of the crime has been underestimated and one in 20 children may have been a victim.
Justice Lowell Goddard opened a wide-ranging public inquiry into decades of abuse in Britains schools, hospitals and other institutions, vowing that no one, no matter how apparently powerful, will be allowed to obstruct our inquiries.
A dam of official silence around child abuse in Britain began to break after the 2011 death of entertainer Jimmy Savile, when dozens came forward to say he had abused them. Subsequent revelations have implicated taxi drivers, entertainers, clergy, senior politicians and others. There have also been claims that police failed to investigate allegations of abuse for decades.
Earlier this year Goddard, a judge from New Zealand, was appointed to investigate how public agencies  including government bodies, police, hospitals, the army, churches and the BBC  handled allegations.
Goddard said abuse has been systematically under-reported by police and the true picture may be even worse than the current figures indicate. She said estimates from a childcare charity suggest one U.K. child in every 20 has been sexually abused; some academics believe the level is higher.
The inquiry plans to release its final report in 2020 but Goddard promised annual updates starting next year. Victims will be able to testify anonymously and former civil servants will not be charged if they disclose official wrongdoing.
Goddard has told police and other institutions not to destroy any records relating to child care.
The abuse claims reach so deeply into British society that finding someone to lead the inquiry was problematic. Two previous chairwomen were appointed and then rejected because of their connections to the establishment.
While the inquiry doesnt have the power to find people guilty of crimes, Goddard said it will not hesitate to name abusers, regardless of their positions in society.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Confederate flag in S. Carolina to be removed Friday</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Bill+remove+Carolina+statehouse+Confederate+flag+signed+today/11200516/story.html</Link>
        <Description>COLUMBIA, S.C. &amp;#8212;&amp;#160;South Carolina&amp;#8217;s governor has signed a bill to remove the Confederate flag from the Statehouse grounds, more than 50 years after it was raised in protest of the civil rights movement. Gov. Nikki Haley signed the bill Thursday on the second floor of the Statehouse, where through a window the secessionist battle flag [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate flag in S. Carolina to be removed Friday

By The Associated Press, Ottawa Citizen July 9, 2015 1:30 PM



COLUMBIA, S.C. South Carolinas governor has signed a bill to remove the Confederate flag from the Statehouse grounds, more than 50 years after it was raised in protest of the civil rights movement.
Gov. Nikki Haley signed the bill Thursday on the second floor of the Statehouse, where through a window the secessionist battle flag was visible outside. She was surrounded by the family members of those killed in the church shooting last month.
The law requires the flag to be removed and placed in the states Confederate Relic Room. Haley says it will come down at 10 a.m. Friday.

There were hugs, tears and high fives in the House chamber after this mornings voteto remove the flag. Members who waited decades to see this day snapped selfies and pumped their fists. But even among the celebrations, there was more than a bit of sadness.
After the Civil War, the flag was first flown over the dome of South Carolinas Capitol in 1961 to celebrate the 100th anniversary of the war. It stayed as a protest to the Civil Rights movement, only moving in 2000 from the dome to its current location.
The push that would bring down the Confederate flag for good only started after nine black churchgoers, including state Sen. Clementa Pinckney, were gunned down during Bible study at the historic Emanuel African Episcopal Church in Charleston on June 17. Police said the white gunmans motivation was racial hatred. Then three days later, photos surfaced of the suspect, Dylann Roof, holding Confederate flags.
I am 44 years old. I never thought Id see this moment. I stand with people who never thought they would see this as well, said House Minority Leader Todd Rutherford, who called the victims martyrs. Its emotional for us not just because it came down, but why it came down.
Republican Rep. Rick Quinn, whose amendment appeared it might at least delay the flags removal for several hours, was happy too after getting a promise that lawmakers would find money for a special display at the Relic Room for the Confederate flag that was about to be removed as well as the one that flew over the Statehouse dome in 2000 when a compromise was passed to move the rebel banner to its current location.
It was done in a way that was a win to everyone, said Quinn, who voted for the bill.
The back-to-back votes came around 1 a.m. Thursday after more than 13 hours of passionate and contentious debate.
As House members deliberated well into the night, there were tears of anger and shared memories of Civil War ancestors. Black Democrats, frustrated at being asked to show grace to Civil War soldiers as the debate wore on, warned the state was embarrassing itself.
Changing the Senate bill could have meant it taking weeks or even months to remove the flag, perhaps blunting momentum that has grown since the church massacre.
Republican Rep. Jenny Horne reminded her colleagues she was a descendent of Confederate President Jefferson Davis, and scolded fellow members of her party for stalling the debate with dozens of amendments.
She cried as she remembered Pinckneys funeral and his widow, who was hiding with one of their daughters in a church office as the gunman fired dozens of shots.
For the widow of Sen. Pinckney and his two young daughters, that would be adding insult to injury and I will not be a part of it! she screamed into a microphone.
She said later during a break she didnt intend to speak but got frustrated with fellow Republicans.
Opponents of removing the flag talked about grandparents who passed down family treasures and lamented that the flag had been hijacked or abducted by racists.
Rep. Mike Pitts, who remembered playing with a Confederate ancestors cavalry sword while growing up, said for him the flag is a reminder of how dirt-poor Southern farmers fought Yankees not because they hated blacks or supported slavery, but because their land was being invaded.
Those soldiers should be respected just as soldiers who fought in the Middle East or Afghanistan, he said, recalling his own military service. Pitts then turned to a lawmaker he called a dear friend, recalling how his black colleague nearly died in Vietnam.
Black lawmakers told their own stories of ancestors. Rep. Joe Neal talked about tracing his family back to four brothers, brought to America in chains to be bought by a slave owner named Neal who changed their last names and pulled them apart from their families.
The whole world is asking, is South Carolina really going to change, or will it hold to an ugly tradition of prejudice and discrimination and hide behind heritage as an excuse for it, Neal said.
Other Democrats suggested any delay would let Ku Klux Klan members planning a rally July 18 a chance to dance around the Confederate flag.
Instead, Democrats were using a line Gov. Haley often says, calling it a great day in South Carolina.
The governor issued her own statement. It is a new day in South Carolina, a day we can all be proud of, a day that truly brings us all together as we continue to heal, as one people and on, she said.
By Jeffrey Collins
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>U.S. pledged $500M to form army of 5,400 Syrian rebels to fight against ISIL — but they’ve recruited just 60 men</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/pledged+500M+form+army+Syrian+rebels+fight+against+ISIL+they/11200854/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Obama has been promising since June 2013 to train, arm and equip a 'moderate' rebel fighting force in the Syrian war. That pledge was renewed after the rise of ISIL</Description>
        <MainBody>

In this photo released on Sept. 29, 2014 by a militant website, an ISIL fighter holds his AK-47 machine gun as he relaxes on the bank of the Euphrates river in Raqqa, Syria.
The U.S. is training just 60 Syrian rebels to fight Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), well short of the 5,400 the Pentagon outlined as the core of a non-regime, pro-western army.
The figure was given by Ashton Carter, the U.S. defence secretary, as he addressed questions from the Senates armed forces committee on the Obama administrations much-criticized policy on the Middle East.
President Barack Obama has been promising since June 2013 to train, arm and equip a moderate rebel fighting force in the Syrian war. That pledge was renewed after the rise of ISIL, an al-Qaeda offshoot.
In January, the Pentagon said $500 million agreed by Congress in October would be spent training 5,400 moderate rebels who would fight ISIL. The aim was to find 3,000 in the first year, and in February the Pentagon was vetting the first of 6,000 rebel volunteers.
It took until June to whittle these down to a shortlist of 1,500, with the aim to remove anyone with a record of fighting for extremist groups. So far, just 60 have actually begun training.
The revelation that the American effort to fight ISIL on the ground in Syria amounted to just 60 men was heavily criticized by the committee.
John McCain, whom Obama beat for the presidency in 2008, said: There is no compelling reason to believe that anything we are doing will be sufficient to achieve the presidents goal of degrading and ultimately destroying ISIL.
Our means and our current level of effort are not aligned with our ends. That suggests we are not winning, and when you are not winning in war, you are losing.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Churches, community groups across Canada rally to resettle Syrian refugees</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/national/Churches+community+groups+across+Canada+rally+resettle/11195619/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The pressure is on after the federal government agreed to resettle 10,000 Syrian refugees over the next three years and said it would lean heavily on private sponsors</Description>
        <MainBody>Churches, community groups across Canada rally to resettle Syrian refugees

By Douglas Quan July 9, 2015



Two years ago Yaser Al Mtawa, above left, a Queens University PhD student, visited his nieces and their parents in Jordans Zaatari refugee camp. He has since been working  to relocate the family to Canada and, with the help of Save a Family in Syria, a multifaith group that helps refugees settle in Ontario, the family of five arrived last week.
Across Canada, churches and community groups are appealing to members to open their hearts  and wallets  to help bring refugees from war-ravaged Syria to this country.
The pressure is on after the federal government agreed to resettle 10,000 Syrian refugees over the next three years and said it would lean heavily on private sponsors to reach that goal.
While many religious and community groups are heeding the call  holding movie nights, bake sales, wine parties and concerts to raise money  they are also miffed Ottawa isnt shouldering more of the responsibility.
Usually the government takes the leap first and then our cases filter from that, said Alexandra Kotyk, treasurer of the Canadian Refugee Sponsorship Agreement Holders Association. Its a bit of a backwards system were doing now.
The conflict in Syria has driven nearly four million people to Turkey, Lebanon, Jordan, Iraq and Egypt. With these host countries dangerously overstretched, Antonio Guterres, the United Nations high commissioner for refugees, has appealed to industrialized nations to help resettle 130,000 of the refugees by the end of 2016.
Without massive international support almost two million Syrian refugees under 18 risk becoming a lost generation, he said in February.
Tens of thousands of desperate Syrian asylum-seekers have paid smugglers to get themacross the Mediterranean Sea to southern Europe, contributing to a maritime refugee crisis of historic proportions, the UN refugee agency said last week. Yet members of the European Union remain deeply divided over how to accommodate the influx.
Chris Alexander, the federal immigration minister, promised this year Canada would take 10,000 Syrian refugees over the next three years, on top of the 1,300 the government had committed to bring in (and who have since arrived). Private sponsors would support about 60 per cent of them and the government would help the rest.
Canadas private sponsorship program was created in 1979 in response to the refugee crisis in Southeast Asia. Under the program, community groups help refugees for one year after their arrival with housing, food and clothing, as well as enrolment in schools and language training.
In Victoria, residents are working with the Anglican diocese of British Columbia to raise $38,000 to resettle a Syrian couple and their three children, currently in Turkey. You are invited to an evening of wine and appetizers to raise funds to sponsor a Syrian refugee family, read a poster for an event this spring.
The Canyon Heights Church in North Vancouver and the Pentecostal Assemblies of Canada hope to raise $50,000 to bring over a family of five that fled to Cairo.
We are a family of women, me, my two daughters and two grandchildren, reads a message fromthe family on the Canyon Heights churchs website.
It is extremely difficult to integrate in Egyptian society when we are not welcomed in the first place.  we truly have run out of solutions.
In Brampton, Ont., five churches affiliated with the Anglican United Refugee Alliance are holding concerts and movie nights to raise $15,000 to help sponsor a refugee family.
One of the most ambitious efforts is in Winnipeg, where community groups are working with the United Church of Canada to raise $120,000 to resettle three families who fled to Lebanon.
I called everyone I knew, said Rev. Loraine MacKenzie Shepherd of Westworth United Church. People were galvanized by it.
When you think about the dire situation, its hard not to act, said Barbara Wynes, the churchs outreach coordinator. Its difficult to imagine the conditions and the horror of what their children are experiencing.
All asylum-seekers must undergo security checks and medical examinationsfirst.As community groups await their arrival, theres more than a little grumbling about the federal governments limited help.
Traditionally, refugee advocates say, Ottawa sets a target of how many refugees it will sponsor, then private sponsors take on cases over and above the governments figure.
The government now says earlier statements private sponsors would take on 60per cent of cases were merely notional.
Thats little comfort to the sponsors, who say the government needs to stop being so vague.
Critics also say it has not adequately addressed concerns it is discriminating against Muslim refugees by giving priority to members of religious minorities.
In December, Conservative MP Costas Menegakis, parliamentary secretary of the immigration minister, told the House of Commons, We will prioritize persecuted ethnic and religious minorities, those at demonstrated risk, and we will make no apologies for that.
Federal New Democratic Party critic Paul Dewar said the governments stance smacks of meddling and prejudice and circumvents criteria established by the UN refugee agency for prioritizing cases. Those deemed most vulnerable include women and girls at risk, survivors of violence and torture, and those facing threats to their physical safety because of gender or sexual identity.
Canada continues to focus on vulnerable refugees in need, some of whom are being persecuted based on their religious beliefs, an immigration department spokeswoman said. But nobody is excluded.
Some observers worry all the attention on Syrian refugees could come at the expense of people from other places.
We are thinking in particular of refugees in Africa, who have long been neglected, Loly Rico, president of the Canadian Council for Refugees, wrote to the government this year.
But immigration officials insist the planned intake from Syria is on top of previous commitments. In 2015, Canada will accept 260,000-285,000 new permanent residents  about 10 per cent of these will be admitted on humanitarian and compassionate grounds, a spokeswomansaid.
Canada has one of the most generous refugee policies in the world.
National Post
 Email: dquan@postmedia.com | Twitter: dougquan
Number of Syrian refugees countries have pledged to resettle since 2013 (as of June 29)
Australia: 5,600
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>FBI raids home of ‘Subway Guy’ Jared Fogle</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/raids+home+Subway+Jared+Fogle+connection+with+child/11194545/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The raid on Fogle's Indiana home comes months after the former director of the his non-profit organization was charged with possessing and producing child pornography</Description>
        <MainBody>

Subway restaurant spokesman Jared Fogle walks to a waiting car as he leaves his home Tuesday, July 7, 2015, in Zionsville, Ind. FBI agents and Indiana State Police have removed electronics from the property.
The FBI and state police have raided the Indiana home of Subway restaurants spokesperson Jared Fogle, famous for shedding more than 200 pounds of weight by eating Subway sandwiches.
The raid took place at 6:30 a.m. Tuesday at Fogles home in Zionsville, Indiana, with agents removing electronics from the property and searching the house with a police dog.
Earlier this year,the then-executive director of Fogles foundation was arrested on child pornography charges.
FBI agent Wendy Osborne said the agency was conducting an investigation intheaffluent suburb, but wouldnt say whether it involved Fogle or describe the nature of the investigation.
Subway said in a statement that it is very concerned about the raid, which it believes is related to a prior investigation of a former employee of the Jared Foundation, an organization founded by Fogle to raise awareness about childhood obesity. Subway did not immediately say whether that employee was former foundation executive director Russell Taylor.
The company had removed references to Fogle from its website by late afternoon and issued another statement, saying the two have mutually agreed to suspend their relationship due to the current investigation.
Jared continues to co-operate with authorities and he expects no actions to be forthcoming, the company said. Both Jared and Subway agree that this was the appropriate step to take.
In April of this year, Russell Taylor, the former director of the Fogles non-profit organization The Jared Foundation, was arrested and charged with possessing and producing child pornography. He attempted suicide behind bars a month later.
FBI investigators have not confirmed a link between Taylors case and Tuesdays raid on Fogles residence.
Fogle first came to prominence in 1999 after his Subway-inspired weight loss led to a series of news stories. He subsequently became an official spokesperson for the sandwich chain, often seen on TV commercials holding out his former pants waistline to highlight his weight change. In 2004 Fogle established The Jared Foundation to educate children and parents on childhood obesity and healthy living.
According to a 2013 article in the New York Daily News , Fogle still gets free Subway sandwiches by flashing a black card at any restaurant and has a net worth of $15 million .
National Post, with files from the Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Harinder Singh Cheema, one of Quebec's most wanted, arrested in San Francisco</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/local-news/Harinder+Singh+Cheema+Quebec+most+wanted+arrested/11198673/story.html</Link>
        <Description>One of Quebec's 10 most wanted people was arrested in San Francisco, seven-and-a-half years after a warrant was issued by Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harinder Singh Cheema, one of Quebec's most wanted, arrested in San Francisco

By Michelle Pucci, Montreal Gazette, Montreal Gazette July 9, 2015

Cheema
Photograph by: Courtesy                , Montreal Gazette
One of Quebecs 10 most wanted peoplewas arrested in San Francisco, seven-and-a-half years after a warrant was issued by Canada.
Harinder Singh Cheema from Montreal was wanted in thedeath of his 29-year-oldwife Gurpreet Kaur on Christmas Eve in 2007. He is accused of second-degree murder.
News of his arrest came in a noticeby Montreal police on Wednesday.
Police learned that Cheema, 36, could be in the San Francisco area on June 26 and had been working with the bureau of external affairs from the Directeur des poursuites criminelles et pnales to have him arrested by American authorities.
On Christmas day in 2007, police found Kaursbody beaten, strangled and wrapped in bedsheets on the balcony outside the coupleshome on Deguire St. in St-Laurent. They lived with their small children, who were only threeweeks and 18 months oldat the time.
In the investigation, police discovered that Cheema had been seen leaving the apartmentthe morning of Dec. 24. He dropped off his children dressed in only undershirts under their snowsuits at the home ofKaurs bestfriend.
From there, police said he fled to Toronto, where he stayed with his lover before flying to Vancouver with a ticket she bought for him. Police also said he arrived in Canada ona fake passport while carrying a Russian drivers licence.
On Jan. 10, 2008, a nationwide warrant was issued for his arrest. Interpol issued a worldwide red notice for his arrest. The investigation was even featured that year on Americas Most Wanted, the now-defunct reality crime show.The case appeared on the Fox television show after an appeal by a Montreal detective.
The victim, Kaur, had beenliving in Canadafor four years and was a permanent resident when she was killed. Cheema, an Indian citizen,does not have permanent resident status inCanada.
Kaurhad leftIndia after she was raped by police, who accused her of associating with Sikh terrorists.After Kaursbody was found, herchildren were placed in foster care by child protection services.
Cheema will be extradited to Quebec.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Morse: Don't send Western ground troops to fight ISIL</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Morse+send+ground+troops+fight+ISIL/11198112/story.html</Link>
        <Description>In his final instruction to the U.S. Armed Forces, retiring Chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Gen. Martin Dempsey has advised Americans to prepare for some very long wars against real and potential adversaries that may not be fought on conventional battlefields.</Description>
        <MainBody>Morse: Don't send Western ground troops to fight ISIL

By Eric Morse, Ottawa Citizen July 9, 2015



Members of the Canadian Forces board an Airbus CC-150 Polaris at CFB Trenton in Trenton, Ont., on Thursday, Oct. 23, 2014. The Canadian forces will help fight the ISIL and be based out of Kuwait City, Kuwait.
Photograph by: Lars Hagberg                , Ottawa Citizen
In his final instruction to the U.S. Armed Forces, retiring Chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Gen. Martin Dempsey has advised Americans to prepare for some very long wars against real and potential adversaries that may not be fought on conventional battlefields.
The message was couched as an update to the National Military Strategy and does not contain a lot that is new to seasoned Pentagon-watchers, but it is a hard-headed appraisal that the world is entering a period of prolonged violent instability for which the U.S. has to adjust its focus to seriously increased complexity and to comparatively decreased freedom of action.
As farewell testaments go, this may not have quite the same ring to it as either President Dwight D. Eisenhowers warning against the military-industrial complex, or Augustuss final advice to Tiberius not to further expand the Roman Empire, but it might have a better chance of being listened to.
Dempsey is neither emperor nor president, but he does seem to have had a conversion on the road to Damascus in the year since ISIL swarmed into Iraq, when he was musing about a major ground commitment. Thankfully, that hasnt happened.
ISIL is still there and still a threat, though not as invincible as purported; in its heartland of Northern Mesopotamia, it is making advances but also suffering setbacks. Its ability to withstand the air campaign is due at least as much to the coalitions reticence over collateral damage as to any effective countermeasures of its own, though in the past week there have been increasingly heavy airstrikes around strategic (and populated) locations in Syria.
Media reports tend to inflate ISIL achievements; about two weeks ago, it threw a small force into Kobane which the Kurds eradicated. It (deliberately) inflicted heavy civilian casualties, but if ISIL had been able to hold Kobane, they would have held it. It was a flashy diversion from a far more serious three-way battle further east around al-Hasakah.
The activities of the assorted ISIL franchises elsewhere are another conversation, but its worth noting that a Caliphate is not a hamburger franchise. Brand is something, but command-and-control is everything, and there is little evidence that Raqqa has it. What they do have is a template: religion, kinetics and stupefying brutality.Politicized terror does work (as Stalin knew very well); it can also be horribly seductive. And everybody loves a bandwagon.
One snapshot of the chaos in Mesopotamia will serve to illustrate why Dempsey is right about avoiding involvement on the ground in strength. In mid-May, Ramadi in Anbar Province was captured by a comparatively small ISIL force. It was another military embarrassment for Baghdad, but Iraqi troops fled only after substantial elements of their elite forces had taken the brunt of fighting for more than a year and were worn out.
However that may be, Baghdad is now faced with a simple but difficult proposition: They have Ramadi surrounded on three sides, but they are not able to attack at the moment. When they do attack, they cannot do it without Shia militias (Anbar is Sunni) and coalition airpower. As seen in Tikrit, those two forces do not play well together, face-saving devices to the contrary notwithstanding.
But theres a far worse problem. Ramadi was a city of about half a million. An estimated 250,000 civilians remain there, while Tikrit was nearly empty. Any attempt to retake Ramadi by siege or by assault will almost certainly result in a bloodbath that will trivialize any collateral damage that Westerners can possibly imagine inflicting.
Now, imagine it with Western ground troops involved.
Eric Morse, a former Canadian diplomat, is co-chair, security studies at the Royal Canadian Military Institute in Toronto and senior fellow at the NATO Association of Canada.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Andrew Coyne: Greece’s culture of victimhood</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Andrew+Coyne+Greece+culture+victimhood/11198817/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The notion that Greece has been brought to its present humiliation, not by its own excesses but by the stupidity and cruelty of its lenders, is by now near-universal</Description>
        <MainBody>

There are many issues at play in the Greek tragedy, but the fundamental thesis being tested is this: do states have a budget constraint? Is there a limit to how much a country can spend and borrow or  as the Syriza government and its academic apologists seem to suggest  is there not?
Had either been around when Greece was first running into debt, the line would have been: relax. Governments arent like households, we owe it to ourselves, and so on. Certainly it would have been told, as its debts mounted, that by no means should it cut spending or reduce its deficit  for that would be contractionary, and besides the risks of bankruptcy werent worth the costs of austerity.
And when at length its debts grew wholly unmanageable, well, we know what the answer is: its debts should be forgiven. The obligation, in the apologist case, is entirely on the creditors, whose reluctance to make absolute reductions in debt, rather than merely make it easier for Greece to repay it, is cast as a blind tyranny, from which Greece must be freed  if not by the usual browbeating and rhetoric (terrorism), then by blackmail: Nice little currency union you have there. Pity if anything should happen to it.
So if a state cannot only spend more than it takes in, year after year, but more than it can ever hope to fund out of its own resources  more, even, than others would willingly lend it  then there really are no limits. Should Greece exit from the euro, at least while Syriza remains in power, I suppose we will see the furthest extension of this, in which it will cover any shortfall simply by printing the money.
The Greek approach has repeatedly been contrasted in media accounts with that of Germany, its largest lender and one of Europes most prosperous states  though not, as you might imagine, to Germanys favour. Germanys insistence that Greece mend its ways, its unwillingness to make new loans, still less forgive the old, without some assurance that Greece will be any more likely to repay the former than it has the latter, is presented as a kind of bizarre fetish, an obtuse cult-worship of balanced budgets.
From which we must conclude that it is Greece, impoverished and indebted as it is, that has pursued the right economic policy and Germany, and others like it, that have it wrong.
The notion that Greece has been brought to its present humiliation, not by its own excesses but by the stupidity and cruelty of its lenders, is by now near-universal. It reflects a peculiarly simplistic view of the economy as merely the sum of its parts  consumption, investment, government spending, the trade balance  with no interplay between them: if government spending goes up, it must add to the gross domestic product; if it goes down, it must subtract. This reductionist focus on aggregates  how much is spent, not how well it is spent  would be misleading enough in itself, but the hydraulic imagery with which it is usually expressed leaves out a rather important element: for governments to inject money into the economy, they must, one way or the other, siphon it out of it.
But never mind. Greeces economy has been contracting, and Greece has been going through austerity. Ergo, it must be because of the austerity. That Greece, like Europes other debtor states, was in scarcely less trouble when it was running massive primary deficits  the fiscal stimulus that, it was widely agreed, was what was required to revive Europes economy after the financial crisis  never seems to come up.
Was there ever an ideology less furnished with actual, real-life examples of success than Keynesianism? Against the multiple examples of its failure  the U.S. in the 1960s, the United Kingdom in the 1970s, France in the 1980s, Japan in the 1990s  its proponents cite but one: the U.S. in the Second World War. Give them that: if the government is prepared to hire every unemployed person to do one thing  fight a war  and the public are willing to do without all the other things those people might have made or done, you can certainly gin up full employment, for the duration. Its just not a particularly useful model in peacetime.
The same objection applies in reverse. Germanys unwillingness to forgive Greek debts  what with its obsession with balanced budgets, and all  has lately been contrasted with Germanys own experience of debt forgiveness, in the 1950s. Well, yes. The rest of Europe was willing to forgive debts that had been incurred building a war machine that had since been entirely dismantled. They were, moreover, willing to forgive the debts of a Germany that was then in the middle of an economic miracle, the product of the currency reform and radical liberalization program overseen by its economic minister, Ludwig Erhard.
That is rather a different situation, I might suggest, than todays Greece: run by Marxists, steeped in a culture of tax evasion and wrapped in the kind of excessive regulation that forbids the selling of bread in convenience stores.
National Post
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Bill Cosby accuser pressing to get entire deposition released after excerpts about quaaludes caused stir</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Bill+Cosby+accuser+pressing+entire+deposition+released+after/11200367/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The motion comes after U.S. District Judge Eduardo Robreno unsealed excerpts from Cosby&amp;#8217;s deposition this week in response to an Associated Press request</Description>
        <MainBody>Bill Cosby accuser pressing to get entire deposition released after excerpts about quaaludes caused stir

By The Associated Press July 9, 2015


Bill Cosby speaks onstage at the Thurgood Marshall College Fund 25th Awards Gala in 2013.
PHILADELPHIA  Bill Cosbys first accuser has asked a judge to release the comedians full deposition in her sex-assault lawsuit, saying that Cosby, his lawyers and agents broke the confidentiality agreement that sealed the 2006 court settlement.
Andrea Constands lawyer argued in a sanctions motion Wednesday that the entire deposition should be made public, including questions Cosby answered under oath about his use of quaaludes and other drugs, his alleged use of hush money to silence women, his deal to have an accusers story spiked and his alleged affairs with other women.
Her lawyer said Cosby and his representatives broke the confidentiality agreement with public comments made over the years and again this week, but Constand has been powerless to respond.
The release of these documents will assist other women who have been victimized and bring awareness to the fact that sexual assault is not just committed with a gun or knife but is also committed by mentors who engage in exploitative behaviours, lawyer Dolores M. Troiani wrote in asking the judge to sanction Cosby and his lawyers.
Lawyers for Cosby, 77, did not immediately return calls for comment.
The motion comes after U.S. District Judge Eduardo Robreno unsealed excerpts from Cosbys deposition this week in response to an Associated Press request, concluding that the public had a right to see the stark contrast between Cosby the public moralist and the statements he made under oath about his lifestyle and conduct.
The excerpts show Cosby admitting that he obtained quaaludes in the 1970s so that he could give them to young women he pursued for extramarital sex. Asked if they knew what they were taking, his lawyers objected and he never answered.
Frustrated by their attempts to dodge questions, Troiani went to court then to force Cosby and his lawyers to co-operate in the pre-trial deposition. She asked that Robreno force the comedian to answer 50 questions about his lifestyle, drug use and sexual encounters with 13 other Jane Doe women who had come forward to say Cosby had molested and perhaps drugged them years earlier.
The deposition eventually proceeded. And Troiani now wants his answers to those questions made public.
Although some of the women engaged in consensual relations with Cosby, their accounts substantiated defendants alleged predilection for somnophilia, Troiani wrote in her motion Wednesday, referring to a term used to describe someone aroused by having sex with an unconscious person.
Cosby settled the case after his deposition for an unknown sum. Both sides agreed to keep the terms confidential and not comment on what did or didnt happen between them.
His lawyers have not returned messages seeking comment since the release of the deposition excerpts, which they had fought. However, ABC reported that an unidentified Cosby associate, in a statement this week, said Cosby settled the suit to save accusers the embarrassment of testifying in open court. Cosbys representatives have since said the statement didnt come from anyone in the comedians camp.
They have a right to determine what if anything can be used as evidence in their respective cases
Troiani, in her motion, pointed to that statement in support of her motion.
She also said that because the unsealed material does not include Cosbys full answers, supporters could argue that the seminal question of his admission to administering Quaaludes to sex partners was taken out of context.
She said making public the entire deposition and written settlement would let people decide if thats the case.
Cosbys statements might also be of interest to women now suing him for sexual assault and defamation, she said.
They have a right to determine what if anything can be used as evidence in their respective cases, said Troiani, who sought permission this week from the Jane Doe witnesses to have Cosbys testimony unsealed.
Cosby has never been charged with a crime and has repeatedly denied the allegations. Most of the sexual misconduct accusations that more than a dozen women have made against him happened too long ago for criminal charges.
The AP generally doesnt name people who say they have been sexually assaulted unless they agree to have their names published, as Constand has done.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>A man without qualities: Jared Fogle was, and still might be, the perfect Subway spokesman</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/without+qualities+Jared+Fogle+still+might+perfect+Subway/11198071/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Even after the raid, Fogle &amp;#8212; who was not arrested or charged with a crime &amp;#8212; stepped aside with no fuss. Making no fuss, after all, is Fogle's trademark</Description>
        <MainBody>A man without qualities: Jared Fogle was, and still might be, the perfect Subway spokesman

By Washington Post July 8, 2015


Analysis
A man without qualities. A Forrest Gump who goes wherever the day takes him. A Walter Mitty who dreams only of eating Subway sandwiches with no mayonnaise.
There is no shortage of literary and cinematic archetypes that seem a lot like Jared Fogle  until Tuesdays FBI raid at his home, Subways brand-making, drama-free, regular-guy spokesman. Even after the raid  believed to be related to the arrest of a former employee of Fogles foundation on child pornography charges  Fogle, who was not arrested or charged with a crime, stepped aside with no fuss.
Making no fuss, after all, is Fogles trademark.
Subway and Jared Fogle have mutually agreed to suspend their relationship due to the current investigation, a Subway spokesman said in a statement late Tuesday, as The Washington Posts Sarah Larimer and Abby Ohlheiser reported. Jared continues to cooperate with authorities and he expects no actions to be forthcoming. Both Jared and Subway agree that this was the appropriate step to take.
Fogles representatives stressed that Jared has quite an appetite for cooperation.
Jared has been cooperating, and continues to cooperate, with law enforcement in their investigation of unspecified charges, Fogles attorney, Ron Elberger, said in an e-mailed statement to The Post. He has not been detained, arrested or charged with any crime or offense.
Somehow, the FBIs interest in Fogle  why not just call him Jared?  only highlighted the (for now) suspended brand ambassadors fundamental appeal: He is a blank slate. If this pitchman is leading a sordid double life  if he is a Bill Cosby, a Lance Armstrong, a Jerry Sandusky  it wont just be unexpected. It will be a complete shock.
Fogle is comparatively bland, which may be his secret, Will Higgins of the Indianapolis Star wrote in 2008. His persona is friendly, not funny; kindly, not abrasive. His charm is a kind of Johnny Carson-like insipidity that may not excite but wears well over time.
Higgins saw Jareds remarkable unremarkability as key to his success.
Charmins milquetoast Mr. Whipple, remember, hung on for two decades, he wrote.
Jared hasnt hung on quite that long, but he is getting there. Introduced by Subway to the public in 2000, Jared, then a student at the University of Indiana at Bloomington, came to the fast-food chain fully formed: Once tipping the scales at 425 pounds, he lost 245 pounds in 11 months on a self-devised diet that he told virtually no one he was on until his sagging jeans made it obvious. Instead of braying his intention to lose weight to the skies, he took the nobler road of quiet struggle.
I ate a 6-inch turkey sub for lunch and a 12-inch Veggie Delite for dinner, and I had diet soda and a small bag of baked chips or pretzels with each meal, Jared wrote in a 2006 memoir called, appropriately, Jared, the Subway Guy. I never put cheese, mayo, or oil on my sandwiches, just mustard, and I never snacked between meals.
Were Jareds experiment part of a peer-reviewed scientific study, it would be suspect. Jareds results were self-reported; there was no control group; unless Jared tragically regained his weight, nearly tripling his girth, the experiment could not be repeated. Also, as has been pointed out, Jareds success wasnt necessarily related to the healthfulness of Subway meals, but to calorie restriction: He went from eating more than 10,000 calories a day, he wrote, to eating a little over 1,000 calories a day.
But sandwich sellers have no need for scientific studies.
That story played a huge role in (Subways)growth, Mary Chapman, the senior director of product innovation at Technomic, a market research firm, told the Associated Press. The New York Daily News summed up the Jared factor in 2013: After his first national commercial  he has since filmed more than 300  Subways sales shot up 20 percent. Overall, sales more than tripled to $11.5 billion in 2011, from around $3 billion in 1998.
Chapman added: Its not just Jared the man, its what it represents.
Yet Jared the man cant easily be differentiated from Subway. While other brand ambassadors can be hard to manage  Tiger Woods shilled for Hero MotoCorp, but is a former golf superstar who enjoyed the occasional extramarital affair  Jared brings no such baggage to the table. His book and the medias coverage of him before the raid tell a simple story: He was fat as a child, he got thin while eating at Subway in his early 20s, and he has been a Subway spokesman and health advocate ever since. Those who dig will learn a little more: He is Jewish, he has been (quietly) divorced, and he likes Dave Matthews. Even with the failed marriage, there is no O.J. Simpson here.
In a telling moment in his memoir, Jared, a young man still in college getting ready for his first big-time commercial, is sent to wardrobe.
I needed the wardrobe department to supply me with regular guy clothes, which looked pretty much like what I wore all the time, he wrote.
Do not mistake Jareds unrelenting vanilla style or totally unremarkable Twitter account for a lack of intelligence, business acumen or competence. He is reportedly worth $15 million; South Park episodes are written about him; he can work a crowd like Montel Williams or Oprah Winfrey.
But if Jared wants to parlay the fame he stumbled into 15 years ago into something else  an acting career, a talk show, a sponsorship deal with a higher-end brand that didnt once use a weird shoe-elasticity chemical in its bread  that move doesnt seem to be coming. Other food addicts  the late John Candy and Chris Farley, for example  were brilliant artists or performers. Jared is a brilliant . . . brand ambassador.
If Jared was going to transcend his (role as) spokesman at Subway, it would have happened by now, Robert Thompson, a professor of popular culture at Syracuse University, told the Indianapolis Star in 2008.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Judge awards nearly $230,000 to woman ‘harassed’ by 153 cable company robocalls to wrong number</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Judge+awards+nearly+woman+harassed+cable+company+robocalls/11197241/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Her lawyer said it sends a message to companies that it&amp;#8217;s necessary to pay attention to human beings, even when technology is used to make repeated calls</Description>
        <MainBody>

U.S. District Judge Alvin Hellerstein in Manhattan ordered Time Warner Cable Inc. to make the $229,500 payment to Araceli King of Irving, Texas, citing the New York-based companys particularly egregious behaviour as it violated the Telephone Consumer Protection Act of 1991.
NEW YORK  A federal judge sent a message on Tuesday when he awarded nearly US$230,000 to a Texas woman, finding that a cable company crossed the line when it harassed her with 153 robocalls even after she complained about the wrong numbers.
U.S. District Judge Alvin Hellerstein in Manhattan ordered Time Warner Cable Inc. to make the US$229,500 payment to Araceli King of Irving, Texas, citing the New York-based companys particularly egregious behaviour as it violated the Telephone Consumer Protection Act of 1991.
King sued last year, saying she had repeatedly asked the company to stop making the calls.
Susan Leepson, a Time Warner spokeswoman, said the company is reviewing its options and determining how to proceed.
Hellerstein said he tripled the US$1,500 penalty for each call because Time Warners actions were particularly egregious since it continued making the calls even after King complained in a seven-minute phone conversation in October 2013 with a company representative that the calls to her phone were apparently meant for a customer she did not know. The judge noted that 74 of the calls were made after Time Warner received a copy of Kings lawsuit in March 2014.
The companys recurring theme in its legal arguments was that it was an unwitting victim of an unpredictable federal law that was not intended to turn an innocuous call to a wrong number into large damages, the judge said.
The responsible company will reduce its exposure dramatically by taking proactive steps to mitigate damages, while its competitor, who unthinkingly robo-dials the same person hundreds of time over many months without pausing to wonder why it cannot reach him, cannot complain about much higher liability, the judge wrote.
Kings lawyer, Sergei Lemberg, said his client is delighted. He said the decision sends a message to consumers to stop taking it on the chin when robocalls dont stop and a message to companies that its necessary to pay attention to human beings, even when technology is used to make repeated calls.
Millions of U.S. consumers get robocalls. Only a few of them take it a step forward and get a lawyer, the Stamford, Connecticut, attorney said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>Glavin: In Canada, an embarrassing foreign policy debate</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/Opinion/Glavin+Canada+embarrassing+foreign+policy+debate/11198228/story.html</Link>
        <Description>With voter support for the New Democratic Party surging to heights not seen since the 1980s and the prospect of a tight three-way race in October's elections emerging as something wholly new to the alchemy of campaign strategies, the one thing that's showing no signs of any change at all is the pathetic unseriousness of this country's debates about foreign policy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Glavin: In Canada, an embarrassing foreign policy debate

By Terry Glavin, Ottawa Citizen July 8, 2015



OTTAWA - May 30, 2013 - (L-R) Liberal leader Justin Trudeau, prime minister Stephen Harper and NDP leader Tom Mulcair debate each other in the House of Commons during the week of May 27, 2013. For 0531-col-Den-Tandt ORG XMIT: POS1305301530472063
With voter support for the New Democratic Party surging to heights not seen since the 1980s and the prospect of a tight three-way race in Octobers elections emerging as something wholly new to the alchemy of campaign strategies, the one thing thats showing no signs of any change at all is the pathetic unseriousness of this countrys debates about foreign policy.
The histrionics over that lurid Conservative Party electioneering advertisement  the one that targeted Liberal leader Justin Trudeau against a backdrop of stills from a jihadist snuff video  is a particularlyembarrassing case in point. Even a profound rupture in global security and an unfolding human tragedy of colossal, historic proportions will get reduced, in Canadian federal politics, to a low contest of cartoonishlyobtuse and parochial talking points.
First, heres whats happening in the real world.
The mass atrocities that continue to be inflicted upon the people of Iraq and Syria beggar the imagination. The response of the United Nations, the United States and the NATO countries, Canada included, has been to deliberately and consistently replicatethe alibis that gave succour to the mass murderers of the 1990s in Kosovo and Bosnia  where help came too late for at least 100,000 innocents  and in Rwanda, where a genocide carried off 800,000 people and rescue never came at all.
In Iraq, about 40,000 people have been killed since December of 2011, when President Barack Obama formally declared victory and ended the American military mission in that country. Thats nearly twice the Iraqi death toll from Obamas first four years in office. The primary butchers are the human-abattoir pornographers of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), headquartered in their Syrian redoubt at Raqqa. Iraqsbarbaric Iranian-aligned Shia militias come in a very close second.
In Syria, at least 300,000 people have been killed since 2011, when the tyrant Bashar al-Assad responded to a democratic uprising by waging war on his own people and seeing to it that ISIL was free to carry out massacres in any pockets of Syrian resistance beyond his immediate grasp, and free as well to spread its mayhem into Iraq. More than three million Syrians are refugees. Another 12 million  more than half the countrys remaining population  are in dire need of humanitarian help.
Assad and his Iranian Quds Force and Hezbollah allies are the guiltiest culprits in all this, by far.Almost every day, entire neighbourhoods, towns and villages are being blasted into oblivion as Assads air force rains down crude barrel bombs,packed with gasoline, dynamite, nails, scrap iron and chlorine gas. Syriasancient city of Aleppo now looks just like London during the blitz.
What everybody knows full well is that to stop the war, first you have to stop Assads bombing. Everybody also knows that to impose and enforce a no-fly zone, with or without the consent of the Russian and Chinese veto holders on the UN Security Council,is also the right thing to do. Its the only effective anti-war remedy.But in Canada, to even admit this out loud is to stand accused of being pro-war, whichbrings us to the funhouse mirror in which the real world is reflected back upon Canadas federal politics.
While Stephen Harpers Conservatives insist that their foreign policy is distinguished by a principled refusal to simply go along to get along, going along to get along has ended up being the only thing the Conservatives can claim for Canadas contribution to the U.S.-led coalition carrying out bombing runs on ISIL targets in Syria and Iraq. Were standing with our allies. Were going along to get along.
In the real world, everybody knows that U.S. PresidentBarack Obama isnt interested in stopping thewar, because to do so would require an effort that would unavoidably complicate his nuclear rapprochement with Tehran, Assads primary sponsor. So Canada goes along to get along by providing the American-run effort in Syria and Iraq with a half-dozen F-18s and a few dozen special operations troops. At the moment, this may well be all Canada can do to stop at least some of the slaughter. So long as ISIL targets are getting hit hard from the air, at least the Kurds of Iraq and Syria are benefitting from a bit of breathing space.
But even after Kosovo, Bosnia and Rwanda, the minor contribution the Conservatives are making still goes too far for a great many Canadians, and Thomas Mulcair is savvy enough to know how to pander to Quebecs rednecks and reactionary isolationists in a way that requires only a slight repackaging to appearas though hes forwarding a presentably progressive and anti-war policy to more delicate anglophone voters.
Mulcair is too clever by half to allow his cynicism to be easily exposed, butJustin Trudeau is another thing altogether. So there was Trudeau on CBCs Power and Politics, unable to explain against whom, if not even the savage marauders of ISIL, he might ever deploy the Canadian Forces, and calling CBC veteran Terry Milewskis perfectly sensible question nonsensical. Trudeau referred to CanadasCF-15 bombing mission (the aircraft are known as CF-18s) and referred to the Canadian Forces troops in Kurdistan as JTF, by which he appears to have meant Joint Task Force 2 (JTF2), when in the real world those soldiers are in any case from the Canadian Special Operations Regiment.
Some deft editing to make Trudeau sound even sillier, some gruesome background imagery and jihadist mood music and hey presto, a Conservative Hes Just Not Ready campaign ad. Then the CBC demands that YouTube and Facebook pull the video on the basis of a transparently lame copyright argument. Then the Conservatives make themselves look ridiculous with the defence that their advertisement was more truthful than the news medias reporting of ISIL. Before you know it, the spin has bent itself into a debate about whether the Conservatives have violated their own anti-terror law by using ISIL footage for propaganda purposes.
This is not the way a serious country should address itself to deaths of hundreds of thousands of innocents, the agonies of millions of Arabs, Kurds, Yazidis, and Assyrians, the abdication of the United Nations from every solemn convention it has ever adopted on the subject of war crimes and crimes against humanity and the most promiscuous use of poison gas since the First World War.
But its the way its done in Canadian politics, and its probably going to keep getting worse until polls close October 19.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>In Greece’s new economic order, Chanel is more valuable than cash</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Greece+economic+order+Chanel+more+valuable+than+cash/11197467/story.html</Link>
        <Description>For one woman, the previously unthinkable luxury of a designer handbag is now an investment, a tangible possession that the government cannot take away</Description>
        <MainBody>

A designer handbag is a luxury one woman never would have allowed herself before the banks shut down. But now she considers it an investment, a tangible possession that the government cannot take away.
ATHENS  In Greeces new economic order, Chanel is becoming more valuable than cash.
Banks in this Mediterranean nation have been shut down for more than a week and are just days away from running out of money. Many Greeks worry that at least some of their hard-earned deposits could vanish even under the best outcome of renewed negotiations between the countrys leaders and its creditors over a bailout package.
Even those who have hoarded cash fear that the value of the euro will plummet, or that a return to the drachma could leave them stranded with the wrong currency.
And so 48-year-old Sophia Marcoulakis is considering converting her cash into something more stable: a designer handbag.
Its a luxury the mother of two never would have allowed herself before the banks shut down. But now she considers it an investment, a tangible possession that the government cannot take away.
You have a feeling that money has lost its value, said Marcoulakis, a corporate lawyer. Its just a number.
Such is the level of distrust among Greeks of their own banking system, a crisis of confidence that only further weakens financial institutions already on life support. It exemplifies the challenge that Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras faces in restoring credibility, not only with skeptical European creditors but also among a deeply divided public traumatized by years of austerity.
Residents began pulling their money out of Greek banks in January after the leftist political party Syriza won parliamentary elections and swept into office with promises to stand firm against the harsh spending cuts demanded by Greeces creditors in return for fresh aid. The showdown between Athens and the rest of Europe intensified at the end of last month, and banks enacted strict limits on withdrawals and transfers abroad to prevent any more money from leaving the country.
Electronic debit transactions are still allowed, but some stores have stopped accepting them. Credit card purchases on Amazon and iTunes are prohibited. Greeks can withdraw only 60 euros a day in cash from banks, the equivalent of about $84.
Many residents worry that its only a matter of time  perhaps just days  before Greece turns into Cyprus circa 2013. Then, the debt-laden island forced residents and businesses to give up 47.5 percent of deposits above 100,000 euros held in local banks in exchange for funding from Europe. To prevent a run on the financial system, Cypriots were allowed to access only 300 euros a day and to charge up to 5,000 euros on their credit cards each month.
The question for many Greeks these days becomes whether to spend money now or watch it vanish into thin air later.
If they want to take some of my money, let me spend it first
For Chris Dako the answer is simple: Buy now. Since the bank closures, the 25-year-old waiter is paid in cash daily. And on Tuesday, he planned to turn that money into a new pair of shoes.
What shoes? he asked with a smile. The best.
Specifically, sneakers that will set him back 185 euros. He intends to spend up to 500 euros as a hedge against his funds that are now trapped inside his bank account.
If they want to take some of my money, let me spend it first, Dako said.
Of course, many Greeks have little money  in the bank or elsewhere. Estimates for the percentage of the population living in poverty range as high as 44 percent. Greek media reported that between 40,000 and 50,000 workers were fired or suspended after the banks shut down. Many are unable to pay their bills and are using their cash for necessities such as food.
Wealthier Greeks, meanwhile, are storing their money in more traditional safe havens. Kostas Theodoropoulos, former head of investment at Eurobank Asset Management, estimated that 40 percent of withdrawals were simply transferred to foreign bank accounts. Another 10 percent or so were invested in mutual funds domiciled in Luxembourg, he said, and the remaining 50 percent of withdrawals were stuffed under the mattress.
Several Greeks said they were using that mattress money to pay off debt or other bills ahead of time to avoid a cash crunch later. And though having a secret money stash at home is common in Greece, many said the amount has increased. One family hid theirs in the freezer, next to the steaks.
Car sales in Greece, including sales of luxury vehicles, surged this spring even as the nation marched toward defaulting on its loans. Though official data attributes the rise to turnover in rental car fleets, some commentators suggested that Greeks would rather buy cars than hold money in the banks. Similar spikes in car sales were reported in the months before Cyprus and Russia instituted banking restrictions.
Before the financial freeze, customers lined up at Nikias in the wealthy Kolonaki neighborhood of Athens to sell their jewels and Rolex watches in return for cash. But over the past week, the shops owner said he has had 20 to 30 calls interested in the opposite exchange.
The owner, who declined to give his name, said the callers wanted to buy gold coins and kilo bars  the most expensive items his store carries. But he no longer accepts electronic bank transfers because he is worried about a potential loss on deposits himself.
Then we would be the ones to have the problem, he said.
So his shop is stuck in a Catch-22: He will take only cash, but none of his customers can access enough to purchase his goods.
Everyone is on hold, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Composite image of girl found in trash bag on a beach viewed a staggering 45 million times on Facebook</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Composite+image+girl+found+trash+beach+viewed+staggering/11197393/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The mystery of Baby Doe began on June 25, when a woman walking her dog on Deer Island called 911 and reported finding a trash bag containing the girl's body</Description>
        <MainBody>

Composite image of girl found in trash bag on a beach viewed a staggering 45 million times on Facebook

By The Associated Press July 8, 2015



This flyer released Thursday, July 2, 2015, by the Suffolk County Massachusetts District Attorney includes a computer-generated composite image depicting the possible likeness of a young girl, whose body was found on the shore of Deer Island in Boston Harbor on June 25, inside a bag that also contained a black and white zebra-print blanket.
In her computer-generated image, she is the picture of innocence: a 4-year-old girl with long brown hair, chubby cheeks and expressive brown eyes. The image has attracted a staggering 45 million views on Facebook as investigators try to identity the child whose remains were found on a Boston Harbor beach nearly two weeks ago.
The mystery of Baby Doe began on June 25, when a woman walking her dog on the western shore of Deer Island called 911 and reported finding a trash bag containing the girls body. The child was wearing white leggings with black polka dots. Inside the bag with her remains was a zebra-print blanket.
Police immediately appealed to the public for help in identifying the girl. Using photos of her remains, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children created a composite image of what the girl may have looked like when she was alive.
After that image and photos of the leggings and blanket were posted on the Massachusetts State Police Facebook page, investigators were astonished by the number of views and shares the posting received. As of late Tuesday, more than 45.4 million people had viewed the image.
But authorities still havent identified the girl.
It has by far shattered our previous record for Facebook views, said Jake Wark, a spokesman for Suffolk County District Attorney Daniel Conley, whose office is overseeing the investigation.
Adding to the mystery is that investigators still havent been able to figure out how she died. There were no obvious signs of trauma to her body, and an autopsy performed by the state medical examiners office did not determine the manner or cause of her death.
Conley said Tuesday that authorities are awaiting the results of toxicology tests to determine if the girl was poisoned or ingested drugs.
She weighed 30 pounds and was about 3 feet tall. Her body was reasonably intact, but had a modest amount of decomposition. Authorities wont say how long they believe she had been dead by the time her remains were discovered.
They also dont know if the girl lived in Massachusetts or came from another state. They will not say whether the trash bag containing her body washed up on shore or was left on the beach by someone.
Investigators have received dozens and dozens of tips from the public, and those leads have prompted police to check on the well-being of 20 girls in the same age range. All of those girls were found safe and sound.
Conley said the outpouring of support by people who have shared the girls image on social media is gratifying and gives him confidence that her identity eventually will be determined.
During a news conference Tuesday, Conley spoke directly to the girls parents or caretakers: Please step forward, clear your conscience and help us identify this young child.
Conley would not elaborate on whether the childs parents or caretakers are a focus of the investigation and said authorities dont know if the girls death was an accident or a crime.
Her death and the mystery surrounding her identity has touched a chord in many people. State police say their Facebook posting on the girl has received more than 10 times the views of their previous highest post. People from Maine to California, Canada and Puerto Rico have shared the posting, with many of them expressing sorrow or anger over the girls death.
How can someone just throw a child away? wrote one woman from Arizona.
This is just horrible, no one is missing this little angel! wrote another woman from Clovis, California.
Barbara Smith, 67, of Missoula, Montana, said she has shared the girls image three times and plans to share it again and again until investigators figure out who she was and how she died.
Im about to become a great-grandmother, so it just touches you, she said in a telephone interview. Its sad that there was a little girl out there of her age that was found by herself and nobody has claimed her.
State police spokesman David Procopio said investigators are grateful to the public for caring about this little innocent.
But we continue our request for leads, he said.
We need people to continue to look at her and think about her and let us know if anything in their memory clicks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>Federal government sanctioned Russian sponsor of FIFA world cup as tournament ended; timing questioned</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/News/canada/Russian+sponsor+FIFA+world+sanctioned+tournament+ended/11197310/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Questions are being raised over why the Conservative government waited until the last week of the FIFA Women&amp;#8217;s World Cup to sanction one of the soccer tournament&amp;#8217;s largest sponsors.</Description>
        <MainBody>Federal government sanctioned Russian sponsor of FIFA world cup as tournament ended; timing questioned

By Lee Berthiaume, Ottawa Citizen, Ottawa Citizen July 8, 2015



USA midfielder Carli Lloyd (R) is congratulated by teammates after scoring a goal during their 2015 FIFA Women's World Cup semi-final football match between USA and Germany at the Olympic Stadium in Montreal on June 30, 2015.
Photograph by: Franck Fife                , Ottawa Citizen
Questions are being raised over why the Conservative government waited until the last week of the FIFA Womens World Cup to sanction a Russian gas company that was one of the soccer tournaments largest sponsors.
State-controlled Gazprom was among 14 Russian organizations added to Canadas sanctions list on June 29 in retaliation for Russias annexation of Crimea and support for separatist rebels in eastern Ukraine. The list also included a Russian separatist group, a motorcycle club and a number of weapons manufacturers.
The move came as Gazproms logo was being splashed across stadiums in Edmonton, Moncton, Montreal, Ottawa, Winnipeg and Vancouver as one of the Womens World Cup tournaments five largest top-tier sponsors. The others were Coca-Cola, Adidas, Hyundai and Visa.
It also came more than nine months after the U.S. added Gazprom to its own sanctions list. The European Union, with which Canada and the U.S. have been co-ordinating sanctions against Russia, has targeted some of Gazproms subsidiaries, but not the main company itself.
Asked about the timing of the sanctions, Foreign Affairs Minister Rob Nicholsons spokeswoman Julie Di Mambro said: We make foreign policy decisions when the government believes it is the right time to act.
Di Mambro did not respond when asked whether the government would be investigating to see if the sanctions had been broken during the World Cup. She referred further questions, including whether FIFA was consulted or notified before the sanctions were imposed, to the world soccer body.
Trade lawyer John Boscariol, an expert on Canadas sanctions regime at McCarthy Tetrault, said its unlikely any rules were broken as the measures against Gazprom are about as soft as you can get. Unlike those that forbid all financial transactions, the sanctions against Gazprom ban only certain loans to and from the company.
So in some ways, I guess what youre saying is we dont want you to support Gazprom through financing, Boscariol said. But otherwise you can deal with them.
The government has been extremely secretive with how and why it adds certain individuals, companies and groups to its sanctions list. Boscariol described it as a bit of a black hole, with officials citing national security and other reasons not to divulge any information on the process.
The Conservative government has been extremely critical of Russia over Ukraine, and Boscariol said Canada has been aggressive when it comes to sanctions. But he suggested theres also some politicking involved, as the government has largely failed to highlight the different types of sanctions.
The Russian Embassy in Ottawa has described the latest sanctions as counterproductive, and called on Canada to reverse this confrontational course that leads nowhere and bring back common sense, pragmatism and diplomacy.
NDP foreign affairs critic Paul Dewar questioned why the government didnt sanction Gazprom along with the U.S. last year, and said it missed an opportunity to really put some pressure on Russia by refusing to take any action until the FIFA womens soccer tournament was almost over.
It shows chaos, confusion, a lack of comprehension about what their policy is, said Dewar, who saw Gazproms logo while attending several World Cup games in Ottawa. If their plan was to wait until FIFA was over, they didnt do that. If their plan was to have an effect, they would have announced it long before FIFA.
Dewar said he finds it hard to believe the government and FIFA didnt have some type of discussions before the tournament, and concededthe pushback the government may have felt from the soccer body.
But he noted the government also said it wouldnt let business interests interfere in Canadas response to Ukraine, before sparing several Russian officials with ties to Bombardier and the oil sands who had been sanctioned by the U.S.
It continues to be a policy that is more about hot rhetoric than an effective, clear strategy when it comes to targeted sanctions, Dewar said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>‘I was bleeding and waiting to die': How a teen survived firing squads twice during Srebrenica massacre</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/bleeding+waiting+teen+survived+firing+squads+twice+during/11197772/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Nedzad Avdic felt the blood of the previous victims sticking to his bare feet as he walked with his hands tied behind his back toward the exit of a school to be shot</Description>
        <MainBody>

In this photo taken. Saturday, June 27, 2015, Srebrenica massacre survivor Nedzad Avdic, 37, walks through the graves of those killed in the massacre and buried at the Memorial Center in the Srebrenica suburb of Potocari, 150 kilometers northeast of Sarajevo.
Nedzad Avdic felt the blood of the previous victims sticking to his bare feet as he walked with his hands tied behind his back toward the exit of a school to be shot.
The voices of hundreds of other male Muslim Bosnians from Srebrenica echoed from the classrooms as the soldiers demanded that the prisoners chant Srebrenica was and always will be Serb! as gunfire killed them one by one outside.
It was 17-year-old Avdics turn to become one of the 8,000 men and boys killed after the eastern Bosnian town of Srebrenica fell to Serb forces. As the 20th anniversary of the carnage of July 11-13, 1995, approached, Avdic decided he needed to speak out publicly.
I just wanted it to be quick, Avdic, now 37, told The Associated Press at the school in the village of Petkovci, where Serb troops brought him and other men caught as they tried to flee Srebrenica.
From the 15,000 men and boys who headed over the mountains toward government-held territory, the Serbs hunted down 6,000 and detained 2,000 others who had surrendered immediately. They were then shot at various sites around the town. The slaughter was the worst massacre in Europe since World War II.
As Avdic stepped out of the school and waited for his turn to face the firing squad, he said he saw piles of bodies lying in the heat.
Suddenly the soldiers changed their minds and loaded him and others onto a truck and took them to another site to be shot. As they were taking the men off in groups of five and lined them up in front of the firing squad, Avdic hid behind other men on the back of the truck just to live for a few seconds more, he remembers.
I just wanted it to be quick
It was his turn again. He felt the sharp stones under his feet as he jumped out and lined up.
The rattle of gunfire started up again, and he fell face down on the stones, but still felt the pain. He was shot. But not dead.
For hours, Avdic lay motionless among a pile of bodies, listening to killings deep into the night. I was bleeding and waiting to die, he said.
When another truck left and it became silent, he lifted his head. Something was moving a few rows of bodies in front of him. The other survivor spotted him too and asked him to come and untie him. Avdic couldnt walk but rolled himself over and the two men chewed on each others ropes to free their hands.
Covered by darkness, they sneaked over the bodies into a nearby forest before the next truck arrived. The other survivor, who Avdic says doesnt want to be identified, tore his shirt and bandaged Avdics wounds. In the morning, the two crawled up the hill and took another look down on the killing field. Backhoes were loading the dead bodies on trucks which then drove away.
For four days and nights the two men kept moving, looking for government-held territory. Avdic was crawling and his companion was moving ahead of him and clearing the path to make it easier. He begged the survivor to leave him to die but the man begged him back to keep going. The man brought him water in his shoe.
On a Serb graveyard the two found an open bottle of Coca-Cola near a freshly dug grave. They drank it together with the ants in it.
The two never noticed when they crossed the front line, but they eventually reached a Muslim village and emerged from the woods, bloody and exhausted.
He passed out again as a bunch of people were giving him water. But he knew: He survived.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Gazette Midday: Greece appeals for EU bailout in exchange for economic reforms</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/local-news/Gazette+Midday+Greece+appeals+bailout+exchange+economic/11197563/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Hello and welcome to montrealgazette.com and welcome to Midday. Here&amp;#8217;s the rundown on some of the stories we&amp;#8217;re following for you today. Greece made a request for aid from Europe&amp;#8217;s bailout fund Wednesday as it rushed to deliver details of its proposed economic reforms in time to secure the country&amp;#8217;s future in the euro and [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>Gazette Midday: Greece appeals for EU bailout in exchange for economic reforms

By James Mennie, Montreal Gazette, Montreal Gazette July 8, 2015



An EU and a Greek flag wave in front of the ancient temple of Parthenon atop the Acropolis hill in Athens on July 7, 2015. Eurozone leaders will hold an emergency summit in Brussels on July 7 to discuss the fallout from Greek voters' defiant "No" to further austerity measures, with the country's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras set to unveil new proposals for talks..
Photograph by: ARIS MESSINIS                , Montreal Gazette
Hello and welcome to montrealgazette.com and welcome to Midday. Heres the rundown on some of the stories were following for you today.
Greece made a request for aid from Europes bailout fund Wednesday as it rushed to deliver details of its proposed economic reforms in time to secure the countrys future in the euro and avoid a descent into financial chaos.The government has asked for a three-year loan program and insisted the rescue will be accompanied by major economic reforms. No amount was mentioned.According to the letter sent to the European Stability Mechanism, Athens said it would immediately implement a set of measures as early as the beginning of next week.Those include tax and pension reforms, details of which will be presented Thursday at the latest. Those are two of the issues that divided the Greek government and creditors over the past few months of protracted discussions.
Quebecs anti-corruption squad is conducting searches and talking to individuals at four locations in Montreal, Sherbrooke and communities around Sherbrooke on Wednesday morning.The searches, which are being carried out by 60 investigatorsat businesses and residences, are related to an ongoing investigation by the Unit permanente anticorruption, or UPAC, into the city of Montreals canceled $355.8-million water-management contract, which an audit report in 2009 confirmedirregularitiesin the tendering process.The report, by city auditor-general Jacques Bergeron,led city hall to terminate the deal with the consortium GNIeau.The target of the searches on Wednesday is the company Le GroupeS.M. Inc., a source told the Montreal Gazette.
The renovated Cabot Square will officially open Wednesday at a ceremony attended by Montreal Mayor Denis Coderre.The park has been closed since last June while it underwent  a $6.3-millionrenovation as part of downtown Ville-Marie boroughs plan to redevelop Ste-Catherine St.between Concordia University and Atwater Ave.The renovations include wider sidewalks, better lighting, new benches, and a renovated vespasienne, as well as space for cultural activities.
Anew group that says it will use the courts to defend the environment in Canada plans to fire its opening salvo at the city of Montreal and its projectto allow high-densityresidential development on a vast natural space in western Pierrefonds. Montreal lawyer Campbell Stuart said hewillfile an injunction against the city, the Montreal Metropolitan Community and a developerin Quebec Superior Court on Wednesday morning on behalf of the new organization, which is called Legacy Project (or Projetgnration in French), and a Pierrefonds resident.The object of the injunction request is to have a judge recognize the protected agricultural zoning of a nearly 20-hectare parcel of land that slices through a 180-hectare area of natural space where the administration of Mayor Denis Coderrehas declared its intention to allow the development of 5,000 to 6,000 homes. The zone is besideanother 180-hectare areaof natural space further west and close to the border between Pierrefonds and Senneville thatthe administration says it willconserve as an eco-territory.
And finally, when English poet John Milton wrote of Time, the subtle thief of youth in the 17th century, he probably wasnt thinking of a high school reunion. But if youve ever been to such an event, Miltons words may have crossed your mind as you walked around the room shaking hands with classmates who had become bald and fat before their time and those who looked like they hadnt aged a day since you last saw them.A team of researchers led by Duke University assistant professor Daniel Belsky believes that some of the secrets to the aging process may lie in understanding the phenomenon of why people grow old at such differing rates. By slowing down the aging process we could prevent not just one disease but many simultaneously, Belsky, a researcher at Dukes Center for the Study of Aging and Human Development , said.
Stay with us for more on these stories and breaking news as it happens at montrealgazette.com

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>‘The new vestige of racism': Republicans fight for Confederate flag at South Carolina House</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/vestige+racism+Republicans+fight+Confederate+flag+South/11197410/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Rep. Mike Pitts said banishing all Confederate flags at the South Carolina House would be equal to erasing history</Description>
        <MainBody>

COLUMBIA, S.C. The Confederate flag that flies at the South Carolina Capitol could soon be making its last stand.
The South Carolina House will begin debating the flags fate Wednesday. If House members back a Senate bill to take the flag down, Gov. Nikki Haley could sign it into law before the end of the week and the flag would be removed and taken to the Confederate Relic Room.
But some House Republicans are saying not so fast, and plan to offer amendments that would preserve some kind of symbol in front of the Statehouse to honour their Southern ancestors.
One of them, Rep. Mike Pitts, said to banish all flags from the site would be akin to erasing history, including that of his family members in Laurens County and the mountains of North Carolina and Virginia.
I guess my plan for tomorrow is to be a lot like my ancestors were at the Bloody Angle, Pitts said, referring to part of a Virginia battlefield where fighting raged for nearly 24 hours in 1864, leaving Confederate dead stacked four deep behind their fortifications. And fight until I have nothing left to fight with.
I guess my plan for tomorrow is to be a lot like my ancestors were at the Bloody Angle. And fight until I have nothing left to fight with.
Pitts said his favourite amendment proposes flying the flag of the 1st South Carolina Volunteers regiment, a blue banner similar to the state flag with its Palmetto tree and crescent moon but with a wreath around the tree. Similar art is etched on a wall inside the Statehouse, Pitts said.
Pitts didnt share all his amendments Tuesday, but The Associated Press was able to obtain copies of the more than two dozen proposals.
One would allow a popular vote to determine the flags future. Another would allow the rebel banner to fly only on Confederate Memorial Day in May, and a third proposal would replace the Confederate battle flag with a different banner.
Other amendments appear more like parodies than serious alternatives to the Senate bill: One would fly the United States flag upside down above the Statehouse dome, and another would remove all of the monuments at the Statehouse, regardless of whether they honour Confederates.
Any change to the Senate bill is unacceptable to the 46 Democrats in the 124-member House  a critical number because some Democrats will have to support any bill to take down the flag to reach the two-thirds threshold required by law, Minority Leader Todd Rutherford said.
Rutherford said any flag that goes up beside the monument to Confederate soldiers will be the new vestige of racism.
If the House amends the Senate bill, the Senate will have to agree with the changes or lawmakers will have to reconcile their differences in a conference committee, possibly delaying action for weeks. Several senators said the lopsided 36-3 final vote on the flag shows they do not want their bill to change.
As strong as the support was, it would be absolutely foolish to attempt to amend the Senate bill, Republican Sen. Larry Martin said.
If the two sides cant reach an agreement, or the House rejects the Senate bill, the flag debate would likely be dead for this year.
To stress the Senates unity after Tuesdays vote, senators invited the widow of their slain colleague, Clementa Pinckney, to the floor. She stood just inside the door in a black dress, only a few feet from her husbands desk, which was draped in black cloth with a single white rose on top. Every member stood as she entered and later walked up to her, offering condolences.
She wanted to show her gratitude, state Sen. Gerald Malloy said. As you can see, Clementa shined on her as well. His grace is contagious. It is contagious throughout this state.
In addition to being a state senator, Clementa Pinckney was the pastor of the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston. He and eight parishioners were fatally shot during a Bible study in the church on June 17. The suspect appeared in photos brandishing the Confederate flag as a symbol of hate.
Associated Press writer Meg Kinnard contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>Ukranian military pilot Nadia Savchenko now stands accused of murder of two Russian journalists</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Ukranian+military+pilot+Nadia+Savchenko+stands+accused+murder/11197328/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Savchenko, a lieutenant in the Ukrainian army and the country&amp;#8217;s first female combat pilot, was captured by pro-Russian separatists</Description>
        <MainBody>Ukranian military pilot Nadia Savchenko now stands accused of murder of two Russian journalists

By The Telegraph July 8, 2015



Ukrainian airforce officer Nadezhda (Nadia) Savchenko reacts inside a defendants' cage as she attends a hearing at the Basmanny district court in Moscow on March 4, 2015. Savchenko, 34, now stands accused of the murder of two Russian journalists, investigators in Moscow have said.
Russian investigators have upgraded the charges against Nadia Savchenko, the Ukrainian helicopter pilot jailed in Russia, as her lawyers said they expected her trial to begin this summer.
Savchenko, 34, now stands accused of the murder of two Russian journalists, investigators in Moscow have said.
She was previously charged with complicity in the deaths of Igor Kornelyuk and Anton Voloshin, two employees of Russias state owned VGTRK television holding who died while covering the war in Ukraine last year.
They have toughened the charges  the prosecutors have changed their concept, Ilya Novikov, one of Savchenkos defence lawyers, said on Tuesday.
Savchenko, a lieutenant in the Ukrainian army and the countrys first female combat pilot, was captured by pro-Russian separatists while fighting alongside the Aidar volunteer battalion near the city of Luhansk on June 18 last year. Russian prosecutors say she subsequently voluntarily crossed the border and attempted to seek asylum in Russia, where she was arrested and charged with acting as a spotter for a mortar attack that killed Kornelyuk and Voloshin on the same day.
The new charges were announced as investigators moved to bring the case to trial after a year of pre-trial detention. Russias chief investigator said on Monday that the investigation had been completed and had been sent to prosecutors for confirmation of the indictment before submission to a court for consideration.
Vladimir Markin, the head of Russias powerful Investigative Committee, said Savchenkos case had been made part of a broader criminal investigation into acts of genocide and use of illegal weapons and methods of warfare by the Ukrainian armed forces.
No date has yet been set for the trial, but Mark Feygin, another of Savchenkos defence team, said on he believed prosecutors were under pressure from the Kremlin.
Savchenko maintains that she had nothing to do with the deaths of the journalists, was captured a full hour before the mortar strike that killed them, and that she was transported across the border against her will by Russian intelligence officers.
The case has made Savchenko a cause celebre in Ukraine, where she was elected as an MP in absentia at parliamentary elections in November.
In March Petro Poroshenko, the president, made her a Hero of Ukraine  the countrys highest honour.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>Opinion: Religious violence is not a myth</title>
        <Link>http://montrealgazette.com/news/world/opinion-religious-violence-is-not-a-myth</Link>
        <Description>It's important to educate the public on what may become the defining issue of our age.</Description>
        <MainBody>More from Hector Avalos, Special to Montreal Gazette
Published on: June 22, 2015 | Last Updated: July 8, 2015 8:51 AM EDT
Buddhist monks attend a conference about the religious violence that has shaken the country at a monastery on the outskirts of Yangon on June 13, 2013.  Buddhist monks from across Myanmar gathered to explore ways to ease religious tensions, after some of them  were implicated in attacks on Muslims. Deadly unrest -- mostly targeting Muslims -- has laid bare deep divides in Buddhist-majority Myanmar and clouded major political reforms since military rule ended two years ago. YE AUNG THU / AFP/Getty Images
Share Adjust Comment Print
In an opinion piece published June 17 ( Its not fair to blame violence on religion ), Paul Allen, an associate professor of theological studies at Concordia University, seeks to refute what he calls the mythof religious violence.
I learned of Allens articleafter speaking at a conference held on June 16 on Religion, Violence and the Ethics of Biblical and Religious Studies at Concordia University. The event, organized by Andr Gagn, also an associate professor of theological studies at the same institution, was co-sponsored by the departments of Religion and Theological Studies.The conferencewas meant to highlight new scholarship on the issue.
I was invited to be the keynote speaker because of my book, Fighting Words: The Origins of Religious Violence (2005) and many other publications in this area of research. In my work, I repeatedly have addressed the claim that the role of religion in violence is mostly illusory.
In my view, Allenis wrong in suggestingthatnew scholarship has established the mythical nature of religious violence.
Allen cites as examples the work of William T. Cavanaugh and Karen Armstrong.
In The Myth of Religious Violence (2009) Cavanaugh argues that religion should not be blamed for violence because it is too entwined with politics, economics and other cultural components. Cavanaugh claims that the modern secularizing state is mainly responsible for artificially separating religion from other aspects of the culture.
But some ancient texts show that separating out religion as a motive for violence preceded the modern state. For example, one ancient report (hadith) of the teachings of Muhammad remarks:   a person who participates in (holy battles) in Allahs Cause and nothing causes him to do so except belief in Allah and in His Messenger  will be recompensed by Allah  (Book of Belief, 26; Shahih Al-Bukhari; Darrussalam edition).
Indeed, Islamic scholars had thought carefully about how to separate religious motives from other motives when engaging in holy war. Religious motives for violence are those that derive from belief in the will of the god or gods.
To cite another case, some, including Cavanaugh, havesuggestedthe motives behind theSt. Bartholomews Day Massacre, wherein Catholics massacred thousands of Protestants in Paris in 1572, werepolitical rather than religious. However, a closer examination of historical primary sources revealssubstantial evidence that indicatesotherwise, includingimportant Vatican correspondence, the celebration of the slaughter by Pope Gregory XIII andthe murals celebrating it in the Sala Regia of the Apostolic Palace at the Vatican.
Or heres a contemporaryexample of religious violence: Today there are thosewho thinkgay people should be killed, and some act on this belief.The only or main reason they may offer is their viewthat God thinks homosexuality is a sin. It is difficult to deny that the motive is religious belief, rather than some political or economic threat posed by gay people, in such cases.
As forKaren Armstrong, Allen says she reaches her conclusions based on exhaustivetextual and cultural analysis. While Armstrongs work is highlypopular, this description overstates her research.For example, the chapter on The Hebrew Dilemma in her Fields of Blood: Religion and the History of Violence (2014) relies mostly on secondary sources (the work of other scholars, as opposed to her own study of the original documents). She pays little or no heed toscholarship opposing her claim that biblical genocides were just a literary trope.
Religious violence is not a myth, and its important to educate the public on what may become the defining issue of our age.
Hector Avalosis a professor ofreligious studies atIowa State University.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
