<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="caribbeannewsnow">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barbados government retracts Commonwealth claim</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Barbados-government-retracts-Commonwealth-claim-26836.html</Link>
        <Description>BRIDGETOWN, Barbados -- Following a report by Caribbean News Now on Monday that, according to the Barbados Government Information Service (BGIS), Commonwealth regulations require that a candidate for the position of secretary general must be put forward by the region...</Description>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Barbados government retracts Commonwealth claim
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Antigua and Barbuda Prime Minister Gaston Browne (L) and Barbados Prime Minister Freundel Stuart
By Caribbean News Now contributor
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados -- Following a report by Caribbean News Now on Monday that, according to the Barbados Government Information Service (BGIS), Commonwealth regulations require that a candidate for the position of secretary general must be put forward by the region, the BGIS has since substantially truncated the release in question on its website.
As we reported, there is in fact no Commonwealth regulation that a candidate for the post of secretary general has to be nominated by a region, contrary to the erroneous original statement on the BGIS government website. Only individual member states may nominate candidates.
In the history of the Commonwealth, candidates for the post of secretary-general have been nominated only by their own countries. While regional support could be useful to a particular candidate, it is certainly not a Commonwealth regulation. As an example, in the current contest for the post, it is Botswana alone that has nominated its candidate, not the African region.
In fact, much of what Barbados Prime Minister Freundel Stuart had to say on the matter, as reported, is either misleading or factually incorrect.
Initially Stuart said, accurately, that the question of the candidates for the post of Commonwealth secretary-general was not discussed by Caribbean heads of government during last weeks Caribbean Community (CARICOM) summit in Barbados.
In point of fact, the matter of candidates for the Commonwealth secretary-general at the election in Malta in November was never on the agenda for the Barbados summit, and it could not have been because not all CARICOM members are Commonwealth states -- Suriname, Haiti and Montserrat are not members of the 53-nation Commonwealth.
Any discussion of the Commonwealth secretary-general's post could therefore only have taken place in the margins of the CARICOM meeting and then only with the agreement of all the heads of government.
However, notwithstanding that the issue is not a matter for CARICOM as such, Stuart reportedly went on to claim that Bureau of the Conference of Heads of Government had been mandated to deal with the matter and will make recommendations.
Antigua and Barbuda Prime Minister Gaston Browne, in a letter to Stuart on Tuesday, said it was absolutely inaccurate that there was any decision by heads to mandate the Bureau to make recommendations.
Neither I nor any member of my delegation participated in any such decision. Other heads of government have also indicated to me that they know of no such decision, Browne said.
According to Browne, these reports convey misleading information to other Commonwealth governments.
In any event, my government objects to this important matter being reviewed by the Bureau and for the Bureau to make recommendations. Therefore, I expect the Bureau to take no action whatsoever, Browne said in his letter, copied to all heads of government and to the secretary-general of CARICOM.
Our 12 Commonwealth Caribbean governments have had ample time to consider this matter, but have been unable to do so because of obfuscation by a few, Browne said, concluding that the matter is now beyond the Commonwealth Caribbean governments.
Currently nominated and vying for the position of Commonwealth secretary-general are Sir Ronald Sanders (Antigua and Barbuda), Baroness Patricia Scotland (Dominica) and Dr Bhoendradatt Tewarie (Trinidad and Tobago).
In Cuba, on December 8 last year, at a meeting of the Commonwealth Caribbean countries in the margins of a Cuba-CARICOM conference, nine of the 12 Commonwealth Caribbean countries indicated clearly that they would stand behind the Antigua and Barbuda candidate, Sir Ronald Sanders, for the post.
Stuart, who had absented himself from the meeting, reportedly insisted when he learned of the decision that formal endorsement should await a meeting where all heads of government would be present. That meeting was held in February 2015 in The Bahamas and although Antigua and Barbuda's candidate continued to enjoy overwhelming support, Trinidad and Tobago refused to withdraw its candidate Dr Bhoendradatt Tewarie and Barbados and Dominica declined to withdraw the British Baroness Patricia Scotland.
Related article:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More required vacation leave for St Lucia police commissioner</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-More-required-vacation-leave-for-St-Lucia-police-commissioner-26837.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
More required vacation leave for St Lucia police commissioner
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Saint Lucia commissioner of police, Vernon Francois
By Caribbean News Now contributor
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- Commissioner of the Royal St Lucia Police Force, Vernon Francois, who was expected to return to work on June 30, has been instructed to remain on leave for another 30 days.
Almost two years ago, on August 12, 2013, Caribbean News Now published a report that, according to local sources, Francois had been requested to take accumulated vacation leave totalling some 400 days following an incident when he was not permitted to board a flight from Hewanorra International Airport in Saint Lucia to the United States to participate in US organized and financed training programmes.
The report prompted a flurry of official denials, culminating in press release entitled False Statements from the Office of the Prime Minister.
Recent developments give reason to revisit the crystal ball of the False Statements claim, along with a report by the Caribbean Community Implementation Agency for Crime and Security (CARICOM IMPACS) that is having serious repercussions.
The US State Departments 2014 human rights report on Saint Lucia has once again highlighted concerns surrounding the police, the penal and justice system that resulted in the suspension of all financial and technical assistance by the US to the Royal Saint Lucia Police Force (RSLPF).
During Operation Restore Confidence (ORC) 2010 and 2011, 12 persons were killed during encounters with officers of the RSLPF in response to an unprecedented wave of homicides and violent crime on the island. Five of the 12 men shot dead were killed in a single operation in Vieux Fort.
In 2012, local inquests concluded that six of the shootings were justified but the US indicated that it did not have confidence in the outcomes of the hearings, while relatives of the victims have insisted they were murdered. The Saint Lucia government enlisted the services of eight investigators from the Jamaican Constabulary Force (JCF) through IMPACS to investigate the police killings.
Sanctions against Saint Lucia took a variety of forms, including travel bans, asset freezes, arms embargoes, capital restraints, foreign aid reductions, trade restrictions, and general export controls by the application by the US of the so-called Leahy Law.
Earlier reports included the US visa revocation of the former deputy commissioner of police, Moses Charles, who led the special task force during Operation Restore Confidence.
On March 8, 2015, Prime Minister Dr Kenny Anthony delivered a televised address A Distressing Issue to Confront based on the findings of the report by the JCF. He called the report extremely damning because it could compromise investigations that were still taking place, and to protect witnesses and that, The crime problem in Saintt Lucia is facilitated by corrupt politicians, government officials, business persons and the police officers, that the force worked from a black list or death list of persons deemed criminals and officers staged all shooting-death sites to legitimize their actions.
The stark reality we confront is that the United States will only lift these sanctions if in their judgment all necessary corrective steps have been taken the Secretary of State must determine and report to the United States Congress that the government of the affected country, in this case Saint Lucia, is taking effective steps to bring the responsible members of the security forces unit to justice. In effect, if the sanctions are to be removed, we must show proof that we are taking corrective steps to deal with the situation, Anthony said in his address.
The report also revealed that the weapons supposedly found on the scene of the alleged extra-judicial killings were from sources other than the victims. The investigators said the weapons were planted on the scene of the shootings.
Anthony described the report of the investigators as extremely damning and brings home the extreme gravity of this matter.
We cannot continue in a situation where we are viewed as a pariah state by our partners in the fight against crime and lawlessness, Anthony said.
Prior to Anthonys address to the nation on the IMPACS report in March, Francois proceeded on 40 days vacation leave and Errol Alexander was appointed acting commissioner of the RSLPF.
Former national security minister Guy Mayers has expressed his displeasure, calling the manner in which the police commissioner is being treated as disrespect, irresponsible and shoddy treatment by the government of Saint Lucia.
Former commissioner of police Ausbert Regis says Mayers stand is hypocritical and he is not the man to come and talk about that, since he does not have the credibility, having participated in similar or worse disrespect of a police commissioner.
Remember in 2007, I was sent on leave for over a year and a half and it was leave earned, and John Broughton was put in my place as acting police commissioner, said Regis,
Was it right that I was served with a letter of transfer by a corporal on a Saturday evening at the Dennery Fish Festival at minutes to ten in the evening? he asked.
The letter stated that I was transferred effective three days ago, in fact, I was transferred retroactively, Regis recalled.
In an invited comment, Castries Central MP, Richard Frederick, said that the current situation surrounding the RSLPF shows a lack of respect and undermines the confidence of the police force.
Frederick continued, This may just exacerbate the crime situation I believe the government needs to find a medium of communication between those rival gangs I am willing to participate, willing to use whatever experience I have gathered over the years... to quell the rivalry.
So far Anthony has kept the IMPACS report confidential in the midst of 11 homicides in 2015 and extreme violence on the streets of Saint Lucia.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Government investigating reports of St Kitts-Nevis flagged vessel carrying illegal whale meat</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Government-investigating-reports-of-St-Kitts-Nevis-flagged-vessel-carrying-illegal-whale-meat-26838.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Government investigating reports of St Kitts-Nevis flagged vessel carrying illegal whale meat
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Winter Bay
By Andre Huie
BASSETERRE, St Kitts (WINN) -- Minister of agriculture and marine resources Eugene Hamilton says the government is investigating whether a vessel bearing the St Kitts and Nevis flag was involved in any illegal fishing activity relating to whaling. An international animal rights group Avaaz has a current campaign calling on the government of St Kitts and Nevis to immediately remove its flag from the vessel Winter Bay, which is reportedly carrying millions of dollars worth of endangered whale meat.
The group is arguing that this is an illegal activity and if the government removes the St Kitts and Nevis flag, the vessel would not be able to dock and conduct its operation. Hamilton told WINN that if the investigation shows that the Winter Bay was involved in anything illegal based on international laws, the government will take a decision.
Avaaz is leading a petition calling upon St Kitts and Nevis to revoke its flag from Winter Bay, which it says is carrying 1,700 tonnes of fin whale meat from Iceland. The goal is to amass 300,000 signatures within the next few days.
St Kitts and Nevis has publicly supported Japan in its whaling efforts. International critics argue that the because the Federation is receiving financial support from Japan in the form of construction of fisheries complex in both St Kitts and Nevis that it will not pull its support or criticize Japan for its whaling activities.
Hamilton does not agree.
Republished with permission of West Indies News Network

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OECS tourism ministers to meet on Thursday in Grenada</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-OECS-tourism-ministers-to-meet-on-Thursday-in-Grenada-26839.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
OECS tourism ministers to meet on Thursday in Grenada
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
ST GEORGES, Grenada -- The Organisation of Eastern Caribbean States (OECS) Council of Tourism Ministers will meet for a second occasion in Grenada on Thursday. The ministerial meeting will be convened under the theme: OECS Economic Union: Pushing the Tourism Envelope.
Some key matters to be discussed at this meeting include:
1. Ease of travel within the OECS
2. Joint representation of the OECS at international boat shows
3. The OECS Network of Excellence for Tourism and Hospitality Training and Education Project
4. The World Bank Tourism Competitiveness Project
5. OECS Community-Based Tourism Programme
6. Opportunities for collaboration between the OECS and Martinique; and also with Cuba
7. Sustainable Destination Alliance for the Americas (SDAA) programme
In addition to representation from OECS member states, including Martinique, other delegates from the Eastern Caribbean Central Bank, the Caribbean Tourism Organisation, and the Caribbean Hotel and Tourism Association will be represented at the meeting as observers.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suriname signs historic agreements with Caribbean Development Bank</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Suriname-signs-historic-agreements-with-Caribbean-Development-Bank-26840.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Suriname signs historic agreements with Caribbean Development Bank
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Minister of Trade and Industry, Don Soejit Tosendjojo, and Edward Green Technical Cooperation Division Chief of the Caribbean Development Bank, sign the agreements
PARAMARIBO, Suriname -- The Ministry of Trade and Industry on Friday signed two historic agreements with the Caribbean Development Bank for projects to improve Surinames implementation of both the CARICOM Single Market and Economy (CSME) and the European Partnership Agreement (EPA). The two projects will assist in transforming Suriname into a more competitive economy, increasing its export earnings, and making the country more attractive for investment.
The projects, to be implemented by the ministry and the Suriname Business Forum, are being funded through two grant facilities  The CSME Standby Facility and the EPA (Economic Partnership Agreement between the European Union and CARIFORUM) Standby Facility.
With the support of the Caribbean Development Bank, CARIFORUM and the EU, we will be able to accomplish some important goals with these projects, said minister of trade and industry, Don Soejit Tosendjojo. These grants through the trade facilities will allow us to bridge the gap between world trends in trade facilitation and our current system, as well as prepare ourselves to deal with the increasing challenges of operating in competitive world markets. This project is an indication of the synergy between important development partners, namely the European Union, CARIFORUM, and the Caribbean Development Bank. It also symbolizes a new relationship between Suriname and the Caribbean Development Bank, one that will enable us to harvest many benefits in the future. I express my sincere appreciation to all institutions and individuals involved who have contributed to these projects and congratulate the business community of Suriname which will be the direct beneficiary of the important work being done here.
The ministry will implement a grant from the EPA Standby Facility, which will help determine the requirements for establishing an electronic single window (ESW). The ESW will allow importers and exporters to submit all of the documentation needed to obtain licenses to trade online. Currently, applications for trade licenses must be submitted in hard copy and manually processed.
Depending on the volume of applications received and the extent to which forms have been filled correctly and accompanied by the required certificates, it can take up to a month to obtain a license. The establishment of an Electronic Single Window will allow all applications and processing to be done electronically thereby significantly reducing processing time to as little as 48 hours.
These two projects, when fully implemented, will in a tangible way demonstrate how the regions trading regime can be used to create sustainable economic opportunities for our people, said Edward Greene, division chief, Technical Cooperation Division of the Caribbean Development Bank. The projects also represent a practical example of CDBs commitment to our partnership with Suriname, and we look forward to supporting the government and private sector in Suriname in the successful execution of these projects.
Developing the Export-Readiness of Surinames Agrifood Enterprises for the CARICOM Market is a project being implemented by the Suriname Business Forum (SBF) and funded by the CSME Standby Facility to improve relationships between Suriname-based agrifood exporters and importers and distributors in two targeted CARICOM markets  Barbados and Trinidad. Once completed, the project will improve the delivery of export development support services by the Ministry the SBF. The SBF will identify businesses in the agricultural sector to receive capacity-building support to increase their ability to export to CSME member states.
The two projects form part of the relationship between CARIFORUM (the grouping of CSME member states plus the Dominican Republic) and the European Union. The two facilities are managed by the Caribbean Development Bank.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OECS Commission releases video on Martinique's accession</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-OECS-Commission-releases-video-on-Martinique%27s-accession-26841.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
OECS Commission releases video on Martinique's accession
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- The Organisation of Eastern Caribbean States (OECS) Commission has begun rolling out a series of videos on issues embracing the lives of the people of the region.
The video, which was to be released for airplay on the Caribbean Broadcasting Union Caribvision Channel on Wednesday evening, features the likely benefits of a more unified region through the historic accession of Martinique to the OECS as an associate member in February 2015.
Director general of the OECS, Dr Didacus Jules, said the video records for history the occasion when Martinique joined the OECS: This feature on Martinique's associate membership of the Organisation of Eastern Caribbean States, is one of several initiatives by the OECS Commission to promote dialogue on issues that embrace and enhance the everyday lives of the people of the region."
On Tuesday, the OECS Commission staff gathered for a viewing of the production ahead of Wednesdays release to the regional public via Caribvision, which has a presence in 22 Caribbean markets, and can also be seen in the Diaspora -- UK, USA and Canada.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caribbean countries move closer to joint management of radio frequencies</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Caribbean-countries-move-closer-to-joint-management-of-radio-frequencies-26842.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Caribbean countries move closer to joint management of radio frequencies
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
ST GEORGES, Grenada -- Countries of the eastern Caribbean are working together to promote more efficient use of their wireless communications frequencies, for greater social good.
A new agreement has been drafted to minimise cross-border interference between countries of the Organisation of Eastern Caribbean States (OECS) and the Caribbean French territories of Guadeloupe and Martinique. The new agreement will aid in the roll-out of nationwide 4G mobile broadband telecommunications networks.
The draft agreement was developed at a recent workshop on spectrum management, hosted by the Caribbean Telecommunications Union (CTU) in Grenada last month.
The workshop formed part of a harmonised caribbean spectrum planning and management project that aims to bring the spectrum policies of various Caribbean countries into closer synchronisation.
Participating countries are working together to develop a national frequency allocation table (NFAT) for each country and a regional frequency allocation table (RFAT) for the Caribbean. Among other things, the RFAT will facilitate the adoption of common frequencies and international protocols for disaster management and emergency telecommunications.
Countries are also working to produce a regional strategic plan for spectrum management.
The workshop was intended to build capacity in spectrum management in 14 Caribbean countries, including the OECS, as well as examine approaches for minimising cross border interference in wireless communications. It attracted a wide range of stakeholders, including academia, regulators, policy makers, operators and international subject matter experts.
The spectrum harmonisation project is being implemented by the CTU, with technical cooperation support from the Inter-American Development Bank (IDB) and Compete Caribbean.
The CTU is a Caribbean intergovernmental organisation focused on developing the region's telecommunications sector.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Historical portrait of Jamaica showcased in photography exhibition in Miami</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Historical-portrait-of-Jamaica-showcased-in-photography-exhibition-in-Miami-26843.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Historical portrait of Jamaica showcased in photography exhibition in Miami
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Crossing a River, courtesy of the Caribbean Photo Archive
MIAMI, USA -- In 1891, as Jamaica's economy was in the doldrums, a group of local businessmen hired a world famous photography studio to take photographs portraying the island as a commercial and touristic paradise. The images  taken by Valentine &amp; Sons of Scotland  have been privately collected and will go on display at HistoryMiami as part of the museum's upcoming exhibition Awakening Jamaica: Photographs by Valentine &amp; Sons, 1891, on view from August 6 to November 1, 2015.
The photographs were exhibited at the 1893 Worlds Fair in Chicago in the Jamaica Pavilion, but were mostly forgotten soon after, and the negatives were destroyed in 1961. Photo archivist Patrick Montgomery of the Caribbean Photo Archive has been tracking down and acquiring original prints of the 1891 photographs over the course of the last ten years. The prints will be displayed together for the first time since the Chicago fair.
"This was an ambitious project for the time and, while it unfortunately did not directly lead to the economic development for which it was intended, this project is historically relevant as an invaluable documentary record of Jamaica at the end of the 19th century," said president/CEO of HistoryMiami, Stuart Chase.
The groundwork for the exhibition began in 2013, when Montgomery donated a portfolio to HistoryMiamis collection containing eight prints, an historical map of Jamaica and a facsimile copy of the 1893 book Worlds Fair, Jamaica at Chicago; reawakening curiosity about the photographs while creating the connection between Montgomery and the museum that led to this exhibition.
On display will be more than 50 original prints and additional items from Montgomerys private collection. HistoryMiami will offer visitors the chance to learn about the creation and impact of the images, featuring urban and unspoiled rural views of the island in the late 19th century. Visitors will also be given the opportunity to learn about the art of photography at that time and how the prints were made. Also on display will be archival items related to the studio of Valentine &amp; Sons and the 1893 Chicago Worlds Fair.
"These photographs provide not only a glimpse into Jamaica's past, but also a representation of the quality and beauty that 19th century photographers could achieve," said Montgomery. Original prints such as these, made directly from large glass negatives for the tourist market, were soon after displaced by amateur snapshots and postcards, and became obsolete relics banished to attics."
This is the second exhibition that is part of the activities of the HistoryMiami Center for Photography, the first of its kind in the greater Miami area. The Center places curatorial emphasis on documentary photography and its core mission is to collect, safeguard, and share the images that tell the stories of our community and illuminate the Miami experience.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Regional Economics: Should Greek debt be forgiven?</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Regional-Economics%3A-Should-Greek-debt-be-forgiven%3F-26844.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Regional Economics: Should Greek debt be forgiven?
Published onJuly 9, 2015
By Craig Harewood
Investment Director at OurInterest Inc.
It is no secret that four Caribbean countries are amongst the most indebted countries in the world when looking at debt as a percentage of GDP: St Kitts and Nevis, Jamaica, Grenada and Barbados. Sir Hilary Beckles (current vice-chancellor of the University of the West Indies) called for debt forgiveness for the region and urged the Caribbean heads of government to follow suit.
There is the historical argument that the Western world benefitted from the Caribbean by extracting wealth without compensation. Additionally, there are numerous precedents outlining the International Monetary Fund providing some debt forgiveness. So for what it is worth, perhaps being very bias, I believe that the Caribbean should receive some debt relief.
Following that reasoning one would probably assume that I would also be in favour of Greek debt forgiveness; my answer isnt as clear cut.
PIGS are destroying Europe - Should Greek debt be forgiven?
PIGS is an acronym used to refer to the majorly indebted countries in Europe  Portugal, Italy, Greece, and Spain (the acronym is sometimes seen as derogatory). The other countries will no doubt be seeking debt forgiveness if debt forgiveness is granted to Greece.
The question now is should Greeces creditors, including the Euro group finance ministers and the European Central Bank, grant some form of debt cancellation/ forgiveness? It is interesting that both the International Monetary Fund and the US think Greece should be given some form of debt relief.
The case for Greek debt relief/forgiveness:
 Risk of financial crisis spilling over to the rest of Europe if Greece defaults
 Keep Greece in EU (political consideration) and blunt Russias influence in Europe
 Assist Greeks (EU has a moral obligation to do such)
 In 1953 Greece was one of the countries to forgive debts owed by Germany
The case against Greek debt relief/ forgiveness:
The case for rejection can be simplified into: if Greeces debt is cancelled then that sets a precedent for debt cancellation in other European countries. The IMF doesnt have the money to accommodate debt forgiveness in a meaningful manner on this scale.
 Italys national debt is 2.69 trillion Euros (2.98 trillion USD)
 Spains national debt is 1.05 trillion Euros (1.16 trillion USD)
 Greeces national debt is 342 billion Euros (380 billion USD)
 Portugals national debt is 276 billion Euros (307 billion USD)
Compare the size of the IMFs piggy bank (668 billion USD) to the needs of the PIGS: Portugal, Italy, Greece and Spain detailed above. The European Central Bank isnt going to print money to write off debt of the PIGS and the Eurozone governments arent going to forgive the debts of the PIGS grouping as their electorates wouldnt allow it.
The current Greek situation is:
Greece has defaulted on an IMF repayment
Greek government debt repayment ($2.21 billion USD) due by July 10
Greece has an upcoming repayment to Japan ($89.6 million USD) due by July 14
Greece has another payment to the European Central Bank (ECB) ($3.87 billion USD) due by July 20
The takeaway:
A single nation like Greece is much more important in a currency union than it would have ever been on its own. Consider Argentina, an economy two times larger than Greece, defaulting and not having nearly the same impact/ consideration as tiny Greece. This should perhaps be a selfish incentive for Caribbean nations to become part of a currency union bigger than themselves.
Fortunately, the Caribbeans debts are miniscule by comparison and our claim to debt relief is historically grounded (beyond immediate economic missteps).
Craig Harewood is the investment director at OurInterest Inc., an investment company that trades on global markets and from time to time assists small businesses and boutique investors. To learn more about OurInterest's financial products and receive financial tips follow OurInterest on FaceBook ( https://www.facebook.com/OurInterestINC ). For access to our quarterly newsletters simply email info@ourinterest.org

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Disparity and neglect at the (Mirabeau) Princess Alice Hospital in Grenada</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Disparity-and-neglect-at-the-%28Mirabeau%29-Princess-Alice-Hospital-in-Grenada-26845.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Disparity and neglect at the (Mirabeau) Princess Alice Hospital in Grenada
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Terry Noel
According to American historian and philosopher Will Durant, The health of nations is more important than the wealth of nations. Unfortunately, though, in rural Grenada this is not the case, since patients should expect some difficulty and long waiting periods in receiving medical attention at the (Mirabeau) Princess Alice Hospital, while government and, in particular, the ministry of health pays little or no attention to improving and enhancing the management structure under which the hospital currently operates.
Terry Noel has a BA in History with Political Science from The University of the West Indies, Cave Hill Campus, Barbados and he is a former vice-president of the Historical Society at UWI, Cave Hill, Barbados
In fact, while special attention is given to the General Hospital in St Georges, the Princess Alice Hospital, which is responsible for providing healthcare services to the people from the rural areas, is left to operate as a big clinic or an old hospital museum. As a result, doctors and nurses work under severe stress and pressure in an already pressurized environment in order to meet the needs of the frequent patients who are seeking medical care and attention.
Moreover, the Princess Alice Hospital has outstretched its capacity to perform the duty and function it was designed to do since it is seriously understaffed and outmoded. In fact, almost every department at the PAH is outdated. Worse yet, the PAH provides its services to a wide cross section of the population since it is the only other hospital available on the mainland apart from the General Hospital in St Georges .
For example, it provides its services to at least four parishes  St Andrews, St Patricks, St Davids and to some extent St Johns, since the people from the Clozier community in St Johns usually take their patients there because it is easier and faster to travel through the Belviedere or Winsor Road in order to get medical attention; especially when it is an emergency situation.
In fact, the disparity is so severe that a single ward in the General Hospital is better equipped, structured and managed than the entire PAH. Interestingly, while a single ward at the General Hospital generally has its own registrar or registrars, three consultants/specialists, three house officers (junior doctors) and three interns (doctors in training), which basically consist of a total of approximately nine doctors to look after the patients interests, in comparison the entire PAH has no interns and consultant, which can be dangerous to any patients wellbeing since the duty of the house officer is to review the prognosis of the patient while the consultants duty is to overlook and review all the work done by all the doctors and make changes where necessary to prevent confusion or mistakes from happening.
This is vital and important because where different doctors attend to the same patient on different shifts, there can be confusion at times. Unfortunately, the entire PAH is equipped with a mere six house officers. In fact, only recently the hospital was faced with a dilemma where one of the house officers went on vacation leave, while at the same time, the two Cuban doctors (house officers) were removed and sent to work at Carriacou, leaving only three doctors at the facility to attend to patients.
One could only imagine the stress and pressure these three doctors had to endure, since they would have been heavily overworked; not to mention the psychological and physical strain on these doctors to perform their duties. Subsequently, the situation contributed to two of the three house officers (doctors) taking sick leave, leaving only a single doctor to do the bulk of the work.
As a result, doctors at the PAH have little or no choice other than to transport a vast majority of patients to the General Hospital. So in reality, the PAH has become nothing more than a transshipment point, since the PAH isnt equipped to handle some of the most basic things. Even the transporting of patients to the General Hospital itself has its challenges since only one ambulance was available to the PAH. However, after numerous complaints, another ambulance and a van were given to the PAH.
Moreover, according to some medical practitioners, there is no consensus or protocol as to how to manage a patient in Grenada. For example, there is no protocol as to how to manage a diabetic patient. Therefore, a diabetic patient at the General Hospital can be managed differently to a diabetic patient at the PAH. So imagine new doctors coming into the system having no guideline or protocol to follow, this can only lead to problems and confusion.
This in itself is a dangerous practice, since in recent times Cuban doctors were brought here to assist in the hospitals and were left unsupervised with no protocol to adhere to. Worse yet, the Cuban doctors knew very little or no English and no translator was provided to them to assist in communication. They had to rely on computers for translation.
Moreover, there is also a shortage of human resources in regards to the auxiliary staff at the PAH, while at the same time nurses are being exported to Trinidad and Tobago and others who have finished their nursing degrees and programs have left home without being hired simply because of the governments implementation of a stringent structural adjustment programme that endorses a hiring freeze among civil servants. Where the health of any country should be paramount and should be prioritized, such programs should never be included or interfere with the health system.
For instance, at the PAH, the casualty department consists of just one nurse on a normal shift. Interestingly, casualty is normally the busiest department of any hospital, so one could only imagine how stressful the job can be on a normal basis. The nurse assigned to the casualty department now has to perform different tasks at the same time.
First, this single nurse would have to triage the patient while the doctor is waiting on the nurse and the patient.
Secondly, she would have to attend to the door to the emergency room where patients are constantly checking in for treatment.
Thirdly, she has to do stale dressings since there is a prescribed day in the week for that type of dressings. That should be handled at the district level but management insists that it should remain at the PAH. Therefore, the patient in triage and the patients waiting for attention now have to wait longer for medical attention while this is done.
Fourthly, she has to carry out the doctors order, such as medications, etc. This is the nations health, which should be the top priority of the state, since we are asking tourists and investors to invest and visit our shores.
Furthermore, the PAH has no nurses hostel where nurses can reside depending on their work schedule. Since the destruction of the nurses hostel by Hurricane Ivan in 2004, it was never rebuilt or refurbished. Similarly, the doctors main residence on the facility was never rebuilt and is still in ruins after the passage of Hurricane Ivan.
Additionally, after the matron position, there isnt anyone assigned to supervise the nurses, so there is a gap between the matron and the nurses and, although there are nurses at the facility who are qualified to fit the position, such portfolio was never given to those qualified for the job, so nurses are usually unsupervised.
Furthermore, the PAH still operates with a non-functional X-ray department, so in essence, all X-raying has to be done at the General Hospital.
Also, there are no basic labs available where basic rudimentary tests can be done to diagnose patients. Therefore, patients have to wait long periods for results from the General Hospital, which can be done by a simple test; in some instances timing is key to diagnose in order to treat the patient. Besides, the hospital isnt equipped with the information technology that will allow the PAH to access test results through some form of computerized system from the General Hospital.
Moreover, the therapy department is non-functional and there is no physiotherapist employed to rehabilitate patients at the PAH. Where patient have to undergo some form of physiotherapy for recovery, they now have to travel to the General Hospital or are left on their own at home with no professional guidance when there are qualified trained physiotherapists available in the country that the government refuses to employ.
For example, depending on the type of injury one sustains, some form of physical therapy must be prescribed or administered for proper recovery and healing. Similarly, in the case of a stroke or heart attack, which the vast majority of our senior citizens suffer, such system is most needed. Likewise, there is no dietician at the PAH. Again, depending on the diagnosis, the dietician is key to prescribing the types of food necessary for healing, which is totally out of the doctors domain.
However, although some of these facilities once existed at the PAH, these have been non-functional for many years with apparently no effort by government to remedy the problem. While these facilities and professionals are available at the General Hospital, unfortunately it is not the same at the PAH. So instead of progressing we have regressed over the years. Sadly, this is all the healthcare that the government of Grenada could offer to the people of St Andrews, St Patricks and St Davids.
Unfortunately, though, it is important to note that there is a serious disconnect between country and town in Grenada. In fact, we still operate in a backward medieval state where city takes precedence over country. So in essence, there is the town and country mentality, which our sociologists fail to adequately address. They instead hasten to address other issues such as politics.
In fact, one of the main reasons for the controllers neglect of the PAH is because of its location being in the rural St Andrews area. Strangely though, the St Andrews people have not yet realized the seriousness of this disconnect between city and rural and overwhelmingly voted for a political party that further compounded the divisive problem. So in essence, they are voting against their own self-interest, since the NNPs developmental focus is heavily based on centralization rather than decentralization.
Interestingly, the member of parliament for the area, whose interest should be addressing and correcting these pertinent issues, appears to be silent on the matter. Therefore, MPs appear to be in the position just for the sake of enjoying the position and not because they are genuinely passionate and intent on making genuine change that will benefit the people they represent.
However, it is important to note, that both Mr Dominic Paul, the owner and founder of Spice Isle Imagining Center, and Mr Hildebran James, former director of the Government Information Service (GIS), very first contact for medical help after drowning was at the PAH.
According to observers on the scene, Mr James was resuscitated at the beach and was conscious on his way to the hospital. A single nurse having to do different things at once at the casualty department would not have done him any justice. Having more nurses at the casualty department might have made all the difference in saving Mr James life. Both men have contributed immensely to the development of this country.
Therefore, it is important that the parliamentary representatives in the area and government to address these pertinent issues so as to give the people of the rural communities of Grenada, Carricou and Petti Martinique the respect and benefit they deserve. Does it have to take the prime minister or some senior member of parliament to fall ill while attending a function in the area and have to be rushed to the PAH for medical attention for government to seriously address these important issues?
The question is what is it that the PAH is actually offering the rural population as a so-called hospital in terms of healthcare and why is there such a great disparity between what is available or provided for the people of St Andrews, St Patricks and St Davids.
There is so much to be done!

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Let's stop ignoring 'Baby Daddy Disorder'</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Let%27s-stop-ignoring-%27Baby-Daddy-Disorder%27-26846.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Let's stop ignoring 'Baby Daddy Disorder'
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Jameca Falconer PhD
On the heels of Fathers Day a few weeks ago, lets continue the conversation about the significance of fathers. The issue of consistency and participation regarding black fathers is a necessary dialogue not just in the United States but even in the Caribbean. A good father is critical to the optimal development and well-being of a child (Lipscomb, 2011). Being a successful father contributes to many aspects of a childs life such as healthy child development, gender identity, responsible sexuality, emotional and social commitment and financial security.
Jameca Falconer is a psychologist, civic leader, educator and consultant in St Louis, Missouri. She was awarded a Fulbright fellowship in Global health and is at UWI Cave Hill conducting her project for the next few weeks. As the author of Baby Daddy Disorder: Solutions for Change, she urges fathers to be more involved in the lives of their children.
Perhaps you remember the moving tribute last year by Kevin Durant to his mother. It came during Durants acceptance speech after being named the NBAs Most Valuable Player.
Kevin recalls his mother waking him up before dawn to work on his game, making him run, practice, and play his best game possible. You made us believe, you kept us off the streets, put clothes on our backs, food on the table. When you didnt eat, you made sure we ate. You went to sleep hungry. You sacrificed for us. Youre the real MVP. At that point, his mother Wanda Pratt is in tears and the crowd gives her a standing ovation. By stark contrast, Durants acknowledgment of his father, Wayne Pratt, is short and obligatory. He refers to the road they have traveled and the support his father has given from afar. It turns out Wayne Pratt abandoned his wife and two boys when Kevin was 1, because, as he told the Washington Post in 2012, I was immature, selfish; I was young.
Kevin Durants story is not unlike many of the stories of other black men who have grown up in the past 30 to 40 years. Many black children grow up without the consistent presence of a father in their life. In fact, Lebron James made a post on Instagram last year thanking his dad for not being in his life. His post speaks to the acknowledgement of absence and hurt that can be caused when fathers abandon their children. Despite the scars caused by uninvolved fathers, we have morphed into a society that likes to pretend that father absence is normal and not destructive.
Fathers play an important role in a child's development from birth through adulthood. In fact, numerous studies have reached the same conclusion: Children with involved fathers fare much better in many areas -- over children with distant or no relationships with their dads. According to research conducted by pediatrics professor Maureen Black, PhD, from the University of Maryland School of Medicine, children whose fathers play an active role in their lives benefit both socially and academically. She found that fathers who are involved with their children have children with fewer problems.
Moreover, her research found better language skills and fewer behavioral problems in children with an actively involved father. Interestingly, this result is true even if the father doesn't live in the same home as the child, such as in divorce situations. It appears that how involved the dad is -- not where he lives in relation to the child -- is the crucial element.
According to 2011 US Census Bureau data, more than 24 million children live apart from their biological fathers. That is one out of every three (33%) children in America. In the African-American community, nearly two in three (64%) of African American children live in father-absent homes. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) recently (2013) published new data on the role that American fathers play in parenting their children. Regarding the actual time spent with their children, the numbers suggest that one-third of non-residential fathers communicate with their children once a month and one-third communicate less than once a month.
In my opinion, this type of communication suggests inactive parenting. Likewise, this type of parenting suggests that there is a pattern of behavior exhibited by many American men, and I have labeled it Baby Daddy Disorder. It should not be able to bring a child into the world and then only interact with that child IF its convenient for you? I argue that this is the norm in American society and in black familial structures in America and in the Caribbean.
Let's cut to the chase.
Declining marriage rates and increases in out-of-wedlock births and multi-partner fertility have given rise to complicated family structures and have increased the likelihood that fathers will not reside with all of their children. American and Caribbean culture which accepts the out-of-wedlock births and multi-partner fertility is such that it is very unlikely that children will reside with both parents.
If we look specifically at reasons that help explain the larger numbers father absent homes, there a few different possibilities. The differences in single parenthood among blacks could reflect the difference in social norms between blacks and whites that could have developed through the experience of slavery. During slavery, black women had no choice but to raise their children on their own because many of the fathers were sold away from their families.
The famous author Belle Hooks, in her "Ain't I a Woman: Black Women and Feminism" (1988), reminds us that "scholars have emphasized the impact of slavery on the black male consciousness, arguing that black men, more so than black women, were the real victims of slavery."
She states that the reality that "sexist historians and sociologists have provided the American public with a perspective on slavery in which the most cruel and de-humanizing impact of slavery on the lives of black people was that black men were stripped of their masculinity, which the psychologists and historians argue resulted in the dissolution and overall disruption of any black familial structure." In other words, black men have never recovered from this pattern of forced removal from their families.
Before we attempt to make the argument that economic hardship has influenced single parenthood among African Americans, lets look at this information. Data from the 1880s indicate that the black who faced the worst conditions  illiteracy and residing in the poorest conditions  had the highest odds of residing in a two-parent household. Thus, economic hardship for blacks made families stay together. The opposite was true for whites in the 1880s; such poor conditions were associated with absent parenting.
So, why are black fathers not involved?
I am a psychologist, teacher, researcher, parent, sister, cousin, friend and so many other titles. Thus, over the years Ive pretty much heard just about every reason for why men cannot be consistently involved in the lives of their children. Men can be very colorful in their depictions of why it is simply not possible for them to financially support their children, spend time with their children or simply make a phone call to their children.
I admit that was inspired to write a book about black fathers out of pure frustration with the state of fatherhood regarding black fathers in the US and abroad. I see many examples of how the children have not been made a priority in many black families. Ive watched many times as the children flounder during adolescence as they struggle to develop an identity despite having been abandoned. Its a harsh reality but a reality that I feel has been accepted. In my opinion, it seems that many black men are content to sire children and then simply walk away from most, if not all of the financial, emotional and psychological obligation that is the foundation of parenting.
My book is called Baby Daddy Disorder: Solutions for Change and it is a reality check on what is terribly wrong in the black community regarding father involvement. Black families are the core of every issue that plagues our community. Alcoholism, obesity and poor health, economic hardship, education, crime and violence are just a few elements that need improvement within the black community. Each one of these elements could be tackled more strategically if families were intact or if parents could work together as a team to ensure success for their children.
Its been said that It takes a village to raise a child. Even if grandmother, aunts and uncles create and work in the village, fathers need to step up, man up and get up so that they can fulfill their role in the village."
Dubowitz, H., Black, M. M., Cox, C. E., Kerr, M. A., Litrownik, A. J., Radhakrishna, A., ... &amp; Runyan, D. K. (2001). Father involvement and children's functioning at age 6 years: A multisite study. Child Maltreatment, 6(4), 300-309.
Lipscomb, R. C. (2011). Strategies to Improve Fathers' Involvement with their Childrens Development and Academic Achievement Race, Gender &amp; Class, 18(3/4), 253-267.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Repudiating the rights of our Garifuna/Garinagu people</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Repudiating-the-rights-of-our-Garifuna_Garinagu-people-26847.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: Repudiating the rights of our Garifuna/Garinagu people
Published onJuly 9, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
On 27 October 1979, following a referendum under Milton Catos Labour Party government, St Vincent and the Grenadines (SVG) became an independent country, a sovereign parliamentary democracy with complete legal and political control over its affairs.
At last, massa day done!
On 13 September 2007, the Honourable Ralph E. Gonsalves Unity Labour Party government voted to adopt the United Nations Declaration on the Rights of Indigenous People (UNDRIP). While the UNDRIP is not a legally binding instrument under international law, it does hold considerable moral standing as  a significant tool towards eliminating human rights violations against the planets 370 million indigenous people and assisting them in combating discrimination and marginalisation.
At last, the inalienable rights of aboriginal people around the world would be recognized!
These two events are inexorably intertwined. By accepting the UNDRIP, SVG was acting as a sovereign nation taking independent responsibility for the welfare, aspirations, and injustices committed against its indigenous people: the Garifuna at home and the forcibly exiled Garinagu abroad.
This responsibility to both groups of our aboriginal people is clearly spelled out in Articles 27 and 28:
Article 27.
States [in this case, SVG] shall establish and implement, in conjunction with indigenous peoples concerned, a fair, independent, impartial, open and transparent process, giving due recognition to indigenous peoples laws, traditions, customs and land tenure systems, to recognize and adjudicate the rights of indigenous peoples pertaining to their lands, territories and resources, including those that were traditionally owned or otherwise occupied or used (my italics). Indigenous peoples shall have the right to participate in this process.
Article 28.
1. Indigenous peoples have the right to redress, by means that can include restitution or, when this is not possible, just, fair and equitable compensation, for the lands, territories and resources which they have traditionally owned or otherwise occupied or used, and which have been confiscated, taken, occupied, used or damaged without their free, prior or informed consent (my italics).
2. Unless otherwise freely agreed upon by the peoples concerned, compensation shall take the form of lands, territories and resources equal in quality, size and legal status or of monetary compensation or other appropriate redress.
In 1797, 5,080 Garifuna  the bulk of the countrys aboriginal population  were forcibly transferred to an inhospitable island off the coast of Honduras. Their lands, some 11,000 acres that were granted in a treaty they were forced by the British to sign in 1769 (which saw the loss of over 20,000 acres of their land to British sugar planters), was taken from them. The few Garifuna who were allowed to remain behind in SVG were given 233 acres of land upon which they were prohibited from growing cane.
People like our own prime minister, Ralph Gonsalves, want to wash their hands of any current responsibility for the ethnic cleansing of our aboriginal population  even after signing the UNDRIP -- by claiming in his slavery and genocide reparation request that since the British government was in charge when this took place over 200 years ago, we must look to them for any restitution or compensation. This stance has neither morality nor the law on its side.
After struggling so hard for independence, the prime minister is now proclaiming that we are still not massas in our own house.
The same argument could have been made for similar wrongs committed against their aboriginal peoples by the United States, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand, just to name some other British colonial possessions, before they became independent nation-states. Each of these sovereign countries has rightly taken sole responsibility long ago for the vicious historical treatment of their indigenous peoples.
After all, if land has to be returned to the aboriginal people, it can only be returned by these now sovereign nations that alone have the legal constitutional right to grant (if publically owned) or expropriate (if privately held) property to do so.
The prime ministers blunt refusal to entertain the benign and symbolic notion of honourary citizenship for the Garinagu, if only as partial restitution for the heinous acts committed against them, is a repudiation of the spirit and intent of the UNDRIP which SVG accepted in 2007.
The harsh tone of his refusal and its use of ethnic fear mongering about the loss of jobs and homes to hoards of people invading from foreign lands is also an insult to the many indigenous peoples around the world who have been subjected to the same unspeakable treatment as our Garifuna/Garinagu.
C. ben-David
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trinidad media association criticised for hypocrisy and political bias</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Trinidad-media-association-criticised-for-hypocrisy-and-political-bias-26823.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Trinidad media association criticised for hypocrisy and political bias
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Head of the Media Association of Trinidad and Tobago, Francesca Hawkins (L) and Phillip Alexander
By Caribbean News Now contributor
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- Phillip Alexander, a candidate for the Diego Martin West constituency for the new Third Force Movement, has taken issue with the Media Association of Trinidad and Tobago (MATT), accusing it of hypocrisy and political bias.
According to Alexander, MATT is calling for tougher laws against those who they say cyber bully journalists, but is mute and silent on journalists and media houses taking liberties with peoples reputations, publishing unauthenticated speculation and outright untruths.
Isnt that hypocrisy? Alexander wrote on Facebook.
TV6 ran a third hand interview between discredited Jack Warner and an unverified recording of a voice that scandalised the prime minister in the worst way, and when challenged by the very person whose voice it is alleged to be, who insists that the entire thing is a fabrication and untrue, the reporter then scandalises HIM and alleges that he was paid off. Now how is that a level playing field? he said.
According to Alexander, someone posted on social media that  Jack Warner aims, but TV6/Express pulls the trigger .
How far is that from reality? Alexander queried.
I would like to again call on Francesca Hawkins as head of the Media Association to do everything in her power to rein in errant and rogue journalists and enforce a code of ethics among the fraternity, before this goes too far, if what she and they want is an environment where journalists are respected by the wider community, he said.
Alexander noted that using the free speech enshrined in the Constitution as a whip against the people is not why that freedom exists, and while shock and scandal brings viewers and sells papers, it exerts a heavy price on the publics perception of media as a whole and on the reputations of the journalists themselves.
I would also like to remind social media users to refrain from thuggish behaviour, that they can be strong without being disrespectful or threatening, and that the use of violence or threats of violence and racist slurs solves nothing and in the end only makes things worse.
A journalist, who was turned down for a job in the state sector, is reportedly at the centre of the anti-government statements from MATT.
The journalist prompted a MATT statement recently, claiming that cyber-bullying was taking place in government-owned media.
However, according to the Voice newspaper, a couple of years ago, that journalist sought to be employed in an important public sector post but did not make the grade.
Close associates say the journalist has since been bitter toward the government.
MATT last week made an issue of criticisms levelled against certain investigative journalists by a presenter on a government-owned radio station.
But the association has not spoken out on an assertion by government minister Dr Roodal Moonilal that there is structural bias at the Trinidad Express newspaper, with eight anti-government columnists.
The body has not commented on repeated revelations of inadequate research, biased editorials and commentaries, screening of letters to the editors and the sensationalising of unfounded allegations from opposition politicians.
MATT has also not commented on the slanderous nature of several radio talk shows, some of which incite divisiveness and promote racism.
MATT is a historically troubled and largely ineffective organisation, with its entire executive resigning en bloc two years ago after flip-flopping over several days on purported press freedom issues.
Other unanswered questions relate to the role of the Trinidad Express and its staff in local politics, especially opposition interests, and the nature of Barbados-based Sir Fred Gollops interest or agenda in the politics of Trinidad and Tobago that he should allow the media group of which he is the chairman to defame and assault local politicians and media workers with untruths and fabricated stories.
Gollop is the chairman of ONE Caribbean Media Limited, the regional media organization under which Caribbean Communications Network (CCN) and the Trinidad Express fall.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chinese contractor strikes back at Bahamas megaresort developer</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Chinese-contractor-strikes-back-at-Bahamas-megaresort-developer-26824.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Chinese contractor strikes back at Bahamas megaresort developer
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
The Baha Mar property
NASSAU, Bahamas -- Baha Mars contractor, China Construction America (CCA), said in a statement that the Bahamas megaresorts decision to file for bankruptcy protection in Delaware is the direct result of its failure to secure adequate financing and its mismanagement of the design of the resort project at Cable Beach.
This mismanagement includes replacing the principal architect after construction had commenced, the late and incomplete delivery of design packages and over 1,300 construction change directives.
CCA said the vast majority of the Baha Mar debtors are organized under the laws of The Bahamas, the Baha Mar project is located in The Bahamas, and the Bahamian people are deeply invested in the future of the project.
It said Baha Mars decision to file for bankruptcy protection in the United States was, therefore, misplaced and calculated to benefit the projects developer over the interests of The Bahamas and its people.
Baha Mar Ltds recent public attempt to shift responsibility away from itself and blame CCA Bahamas and our subcontractors for the delays in the projects completion is misleading and dishonest, CCA said.
It is insulting to the many talented and hardworking employees and subcontractors that work for CCA Bahamas and harms the interests of the people and government of The Bahamas that are represented by this landmark project.
Since February 2015, CCA Bahamas and our subcontractors have performed nearly $72 million of contract work for which we have received no payment.
Our aggregate investment in and commitment to the project, including money advanced by CSCEC (China State Construction Engineering Corporation) on behalf of the developer, approximates $220 million. We have continually acted in good faith in the performance of this work reliant upon the belief that Baha Mar Ltd would fulfill its responsibilities as the owner.
CCA Bahamas is committed to holding Baha Mar Ltd accountable for its improper actions and failed commitments to the Bahamian government, the people of The Bahamas, and all of its creditors.
We look forward to working with the financial community and the Bahamian government in order to complete this important project.
Meanwhile, after the failure of the Bahamas government to pay the salaries of Baha Mar workers for yet another day, Baha Mar on Monday night sent out a statement attacking the Christie administrations actions as disgraceful.
Baha Mar also slammed the governments behaviour as unconscionable and disappointing, accusing the administration of concocting a sideshow for its own purposes.
The ministry of finance initially said Baha Mars employees would be paid by last Friday, but after workers were still not paid on Monday, the ministry claimed delays in obtaining payroll particulars from Baha Mar were behind the failure to pay and promised employees would be paid on Tuesday.
In response, Baha Mar said the governments behaviour has sown confusion and doubt about the future of the project.
Baha Mar filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy in Delaware last Monday. The following day, in the UK, it sued China State Construction Engineering Corporation for $192 million in damages.
The delay in Baha Mar citizens being paid is a government of The Bahamas issue, not a Baha Mar issue, Baha Mar said.
Baha Mar essentially provided the government over five days ago the information the government requested.
Subsequently, the government has kept coming back to Baha Mar continually for more information, even as the government announced in the newspapers [Monday] morning that it had made arrangements for prompt payment.
Each time Baha Mar has provided as quickly as possible the requested information.
Baha Mar finds it disgraceful that the salaries due Baha Mar employees have not yet been paid. Baha Mar was fully prepared to pay these salaries in a timely manner having received approval from the US court under chapter 11 to do so.
The government however saw fit, apparently for its own reasons, to participate in the obstruction of this process and has to date been unable to deliver on its promise regarding Baha Mar citizens.
We urge the government to fulfill this obligation, which it said it was assuming for this pay period.
The company refers to its employees as citizens.
The Guardian understands that the ministry of finance did not receive full employee payroll information from Baha Mar until 11:25 a.m. on Monday, leading to processing issues at the Royal Bank of Canada.
Payment information was reportedly processed at the bank on Monday, except for 40 employees who do not have bank accounts. Those employees will receive checks issued by Financial Secretary John Rolle, The Guardian understands.
Last Thursday, Attorney General Allyson Maynard-Gibson committed that the government would pay out $7.5 million this month to cover the salaries of 2,400 Baha Mar workers.
She said paying the employees without conditions attached would allow negotiations to continue.
She charged that the employees should not be used as pawns in negotiations about the future of the project.
In a statement on Monday, the government said it would be unable to pay Baha Mar employees until Tuesday.
The Ministry of Finance has announced that due to the delays in obtaining payroll particulars from Baha Mar, salary payments to Baha Mar employees will be made on Tuesday, July 7, 2015, the government said in a statement.
On Friday, the government said it had made a payment of $2 million to cover Baha Mar salaries.
But Baha Mar said on MOnday, It is unconscionable and disappointing that Baha Mar should be forced to divert time and resources away from the critical task of completing construction and opening Baha Mar successfully as a result of the government concocting a sideshow for its own purposes.
One truly has to wonder why the government is not fully supporting the one investor -- the projects developer -- which, along with the people of The Bahamas, have been victimized by the repeated failures of the general contractor to complete construction on schedule and as promised.
When attorney Roy Sweeting appeared before Justice Ian Winder last Thursday in an attempt to get US court orders approved in The Bahamas, he met opposition from the government and the Export-Import Bank of China, Baha Mars major lender.
The approvals would have given Baha Mar access to $30 million in debtor in possession funds to keep the lights on.
However, Minister of State for Legal Affairs Damian Gomez said in court that the government is prepared to pay each and every Baha Mar employee.
The company later responded that the move was unorthodox and unnecessary, as it had already secured the DIP funding to pay for salaries, among other things.
Seven and half million dollars to make this payroll does not solve all of our problems, Sweeting said in court.
Republished with permission of the Nassau Guardian

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>International agencies alleged to be infiltrating Venezuela from Guyana</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-International-agencies-alleged-to-be-infiltrating-Venezuela-from-Guyana-26825.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
International agencies alleged to be infiltrating Venezuela from Guyana
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Map showing the new Venezuelan claim (shown in green)
By Caribbean News Now contributor
CARACAS, Venezuela -- Journalist Jos Vicente Rangel claimed on Monday that international intelligence agencies are carrying out infiltration activities from Guyana into Venezuela.
Based on allegedly confidential information, he claimed that the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) of the United States; the British Military Intelligence (MI6) and Israeli intelligence (Mossad) have been collaborating with the military and intelligence training of troops of Guyana Defence Force.
US Special Forces are reinforcing these activities in the area and, from the waterways of the Yuruani River in Essequibo in the vicinity of the sector called Anacoco, they are training personnel to raid Venezuelan areas as part of a social and economic destabilization program in the region, he said on Monday in his TV program "Jos Vicente Hoy (Jose Vicente Today)."
He added that, according to intelligence sources, there is a large flow of weapons from the reclamation area in Essequibo into Venezuela.
Meanwhile, the Venezuelan government has issued a new Decree No: 1,859, replacing Decree No: 1,787 of 26 May 2015, which asserted the countrys claim to a large part of Guyanas maritime territory, to support and justify the actions of its military in defending the newly created Integrated Defence Maritime Zones and Island (Zodimain).
However, the new decree on Zodimain has no fixed boundaries and the ministries of defense and interior are empowered to implement the decree.
Article 20 emphasizes that the decree aims to set boundaries, but that has to do only with activities related to defence.
"This decree is to set no boundaries, establish boundaries, nor any demarcation process in any way. Its sole purpose and exclusive range of concerns are protection against threats, risks and other vulnerabilities, so that does not mean any ruling on issues concerning territorial or alien by nature, the article reads.
After an announcement by Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro during a speech at the special session of the National Assembly on Monday, the decree was published in Official Gazette No. 40,696 on Tuesday, July 7, 2015.
In the text, constitutional, legal and doctrinal elements for the performance of any component of the FANB (Navy, Air Force and Army) in the maritime boundaries of the country are detailed.
Also, the specific military functions in the territorial waters are specified.
The ministries of defence and interior relations and justice, according to Article 19, are entitled to execute and implement the decree.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Advocacy group believes Caribbean governments will be under pressure to accept same sex marriage</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Advocacy-group-believes-Caribbean-governments-will-be-under-pressure-to-accept-same-sex-marriage-26826.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Advocacy group believes Caribbean governments will be under pressure to accept same sex marriage
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Andre Huie
BASSETERRE, St Kitts (WINN) -- Caribbean governments will be under increased pressure to recognize and accept gay marriage in their respective jurisdictions in light of the recent US Supreme Court ruling that has made same sex marriage legal in all 50 US states. Thats the view of Philippa Davies, advocacy officer with the Jamaica Coalition for Healthy Families.
The Jamaica Coalition for Healthy Families recently led and submitted a petition and declaration to Caribbean Community (CARICOM) leaders ahead of the heads of government meeting last week.
The group said it has the support of over 1,200 churches, organizations representing civil society and the private sector. It is appealing to Caribbean leadership to stand firm against international pressures to abolish certain human principles.
Davies previously gave examples of this international pressure, which includes, among other things, a threat by an international donor group to withhold funding unless the countries were more sympathetic to same sex unions or adjust laws that prohibit homosexuality.
At last weeks CARICOM meeting, UN Secretary General Ban Ki-moon addressed the opening of the meeting and said punitive laws and stigma are contributing to the HIV and AIDS epidemic in the Caribbean. He said homophobia threatens both human rights and public health and that discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation was not acceptable.
Republished with permission of West Indies News Network

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tobago House of Assembly called on to account for missing $1 billion</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Tobago-House-of-Assembly-called-on-to-account-for-missing-%241-billion-26827.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Tobago House of Assembly called on to account for missing $1 billion
Published onJuly 8, 2015
THA Chief Secretary Orville London
By Caribbean News Now contributor
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- The Tobago House of Assembly (THA) has been called on to account for TT$1 billion (US$158 million) in its 2006 financial statements, while it is asking for one of the largest allocations ever from Central Government in the 2015/2016 budget.
The THA wants $5.7 billion (US$900 million). Last year its budget was $5.68 billion and the year before, $4.95 billion.
Tobago opposition People's National Movement (PNM) senator Shamfa Cudjoe, after the recent budget presentation, said Tobago deserved its fair share.
According to the Voice newspaper, the Office of THA Chief Secretary Orville London is asking for $229 million, more than what it wants for the islands declining tourism sector, its main revenue earner.
Yet, London has remained silent on where $1 billion went.
The THA health department is asking for the largest share of its budgetary allocation but, according to minister of Tobago development, Delmond Baker, a medical doctor, residents on the island do not seem to be getting the worth of the money allocated to the sector.
Baker said at one time, for six months, the health department was able to provide only two ambulances for all its residents and questioned the mismanagement of money at the Tobago Regional Health Authority, which gets its directives from the health department.
Some commentators have questioned the spending of $5.7 billion on an island with a population of just over 60,000, or $95,000 per person, compared to a total national budget last year of $64.4 billion for Trinidads population of around 1.3 million people, or $50,000 per person.
Has Tobago really been denied of its fair share from Central Government over the years? Or is the money being mismanaged? the Voice asked.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grenada urged to abolish death penalty and to decriminalize same-sex relations</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Grenada-urged-to-abolish-death-penalty-and-to-decriminalize-same-sex-relations-26828.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Grenada urged to abolish death penalty and to decriminalize same-sex relations
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
LONDON, England -- Amnesty International has welcomed Grenadas acceptance of recommendations to ratify a number of international human rights treaties, including the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment, and notes its request for assistance from the international community in implementing these. The organization encouraged Grenada to continue to work toward ratification while availing itself of technical and financial support from the United Nations as necessary.
Amnesty International said it is disappointed, however, that Grenada has failed to accept recommendations to ratify the Second Optional Protocol to the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, aiming at abolition of the death penalty. The organization welcomed the de facto moratorium on the death penalty and the fact that, since the end of 2013, there has been no one on death row, when the sentence of the last remaining prisoner under sentence of death was commuted.
However, Amnesty International said it deeply regrets Grenadas rejection of recommendations to introduce a moratorium on executions and to reform domestic legislation on the death penalty. The organization urged the government to reconsider these recommendations and to establish a de jure moratorium on the death penalty with a view to its abolishment.
Amnesty International added that it is seriously concerned that Grenada has rejected a large number of recommendations on the rights of LGBTI persons, including to repeal all legislation criminalizing same-sex sexual relations and to include sexual orientation and gender identity as prohibited grounds for discrimination.
Amnesty International has repeatedly voiced concern that legislation remains in place that criminalizes consensual same sex relations, in violation of Grenadas international human rights obligations, including under Article 17 of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights.
The organization called on Grenada to bring domestic legislation in line with international human rights obligations, and to end all discrimination against LGBTI persons.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Normalizing relations with Cuba should also mean normalizing immigration policy, says immigration reform group</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Normalizing-relations-with-Cuba-should-also-mean-normalizing-immigration-policy%2C-says-immigration-reform-group-26829.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Normalizing relations with Cuba should also mean normalizing immigration policy, says immigration reform group
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
WASHINGTON, USA -- Last week's announcement that the United States is re-establishing diplomatic relations with Cuba should also trigger a repeal of outdated immigration policies that afford special immigration privileges to Cuban nationals, says the country's largest immigration reform group.
For more than half a century, the US has maintained policies that treat Cuban migrants differently from citizens of every other nation on earth.
"With the reestablishment of full diplomatic relations with Cuba, our outdated Cold War immigration policies with that nation must end," declared Dan Stein, president of the Federation for American Immigration Reform (FAIR).
Specifically, the thaw in relations with Cuba must result in President Barack Obama pushing for the repeal of the 1966 Cuban Adjustment Act, the end of the wet foot/dry foot policy, elimination of the minimum annual allocation of the 20,000 immigration visas for Cubans, termination of the 2007 Cuban Family Reunification Program, and a commitment by Cuba to accept repatriation of criminal aliens who are deported from the United States.
"If we are treating Cuba like virtually every other nation on earth in terms of trade, cultural exchanges and diplomacy, then we should also treat Cuban citizens like everyone else when it comes to immigration to the United States," said Stein.
Under the Cuban Adjustment Act and the wet foot/dry foot policy, Cuban nationals who set foot on American soil, regardless of how they got here, are permitted to remain and adjust their status to permanent legal immigrants after one year. In addition, under a policy established by President Bill Clinton in 1994, Cuba is the only country in the world guaranteed a minimum number of immigration visas to the US each year. Cuba is also among a handful of rogue nations that refuses to allow repatriation of their own citizens who have been convicted of crimes in the United States.
"The special immigration policies we have had for Cubans have never made sense, nor have they achieved any beneficial effect for Cuba or the US. For decades, these policies have been driven by domestic political considerations. Now they are completely without justification.
"Moving forward, Cubans who arrive here illegally or overstay visas should be subject to removal; Cuban nationals who wish to immigrate to the US should apply under the same set of rules that apply to everyone else; and we must expect that the government of Cuba will act in good faith when it comes to accepting the return of criminal aliens. Normalization means normalization," concluded Stein.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trinidad hosts preparatory Caribbean meeting for hurricane season</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Trinidad-hosts-preparatory-Caribbean-meeting-for-hurricane-season-26830.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Trinidad hosts preparatory Caribbean meeting for hurricane season
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
PORT-OF-SPAIN, Trinidad -- Aiming to strengthen the regional response system through clear coordination of roles and responsibilities during a hurricane or other emergencies, the Pan-American Disaster Response Unit (PADRU) of the International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies (IFRC) and the English speaking Caribbean National Societies, along with the Caribbean Disaster Emergency Management (CDEMA) and the Red Cross Caribbean Disaster Risk Management Reference Centre (CADRIM), gathered from 24 to 25 of June in Port-of-Spain, Trinidad to discuss preparations for the 2015 hurricane season.
This year the main objective of the meeting was to consolidate a Regional Contingency Plan for the 2015 hurricane season and to coordinate actions amongst all the National Societies, CDEMA and the IFRC to improve collaboration and information sharing.
Some of the most important issues discussed during this meeting were:
- Disaster management and risk reduction conceptual framework.
- To work as a system with a strategic approach in order to provide relevant, effective, coordinated and quality humanitarian assistance.
- Analysis of the need to review disaster management systems and contingency plans
- Analysis of the humanitarian trends and financial constraints in America and the need to collaborate with other national societies and external actors, to create synergies
- Need to share, profile and disseminate the work of the Caribbean national societies.
The Caribbean is a highly disaster prone region, enduring a fierce annual hurricane season, tropical storms, flooding and drought, as well as earthquakes. The frequency and intensity of weather-related events in particular are projected to rise due to climate change. In this context and due to the evolving complexity of disaster response and recovery, a disaster management and risk reduction system that is comprehensive, coordinated and collaborative is increasingly important.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Carnival cruise line granted US approval for travel to Cuba</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Carnival-cruise-line-granted-US-approval-for-travel-to-Cuba-26831.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Carnival cruise line granted US approval for travel to Cuba
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Beginning in April 2016, fathom will embark on weekly seven-day voyages from Port Miami aboard the MV Adonia, a 710-passenger vessel redeployed from Carnival Corporation's P&amp;O Cruises (UK) brand
MIAMI, USA -- Carnival Corporation, the world's largest travel and leisure company, has announced that the US Department of the Treasury and the US Department of Commerce granted approval for the company to begin travel to Cuba. Carnival Corporation intends to take travelers to Cuba beginning in May 2016 via its newly launched fathom brand  a new social impact travel brand providing purpose-oriented, social impact experiences, initially in the Dominican Republic.
Carnival Corporation intends to operate fathom travel itineraries directly to Cuba for the purpose of providing cultural, artistic, faith-based and humanitarian exchanges between American and Cuban citizens. Authorized under current US-to-Cuba travel guidelines, the new Cuban itineraries on fathom will strictly comply with US Department of Treasury rules that allow licensed travel companies to transport approved travelers to Cuba to engage in activities that support the Cuban people. Carnival Corporation is in active discussions and plans to work with the appropriate authorities in Cuba so that Cuban approval is granted.
Launched June 4 as Carnival Corporation's tenth global brand, fathom is designed as a purpose-driven brand to enrich the lives of its travelers and in the case of the Dominican Republic, drive sustainable social impact on a significant scale. The brand expects to attract 37,000 annual travelers who collectively could spend a total of more than 100,000 days a year either volunteering or immersing in educational and cultural exchanges in local communities.
Beginning in April 2016, fathom will embark on weekly seven-day voyages from Port Miami aboard the MV Adonia, a 710-passenger vessel redeployed from Carnival Corporation's P&amp;O Cruises (UK) brand. fathom's first impact destination will be the northern region of the Dominican Republic, where Carnival Corporation's new port of call, Amber Cove, will serve as home base.
Following the inaugural April month of voyages to the Dominican Republic, fathom intends to offer both Dominican and Cuban itineraries on a systematic and regular basis, giving travelers the opportunity to choose from two destinations and a range of activities from social impact in the Dominican Republic and educational and cultural exchanges in both countries designed to have a positive, transformative effect on the lives of the travelers.
"We are excited about receiving US approval as the very important first step to ultimately take travelers to Cuba under the existing 12 criteria for authorized travel. We look forward to working with the Cuban authorities for their approval to help make the social, cultural and humanitarian exchanges between U.S. citizens and the people of Cuba a reality," said Arnold Donald, president and CEO of Carnival Corporation. "We know there is strong demand from travelers who want to immerse themselves in Cuban culture, so this is a historic opportunity for us to enable more people to experience Cuban society. It is also an important opportunity for our new fathom brand to expand its positive influence in the world with this potential to add full-week immersion sailings to Cuba to its already planned full-week social-impact itineraries to the Dominican Republic beginning in the spring of 2016."
Tara Russell, president of fathom and global impact lead for Carnival Corporation, added: "We're incredibly excited and humbled by this potential opportunity to help travelers experience the amazing beauty and culture of Cuba, while being able to provide educational and cultural exchange activities that will benefit both the traveler and the Cuban people. After establishing the Dominican Republic as our first partner destination, Cuba represents an important step for us to expand our ability to offer meaningful and enriching experiences to purpose-driven travelers. Our goal remains the same for both destinations  to enable travelers to immerse, learn, serve and flourish while making enduring, sustainable contributions on a scalable and systematic basis. We are looking forward to building what we intend to be a beautiful and lasting friendship with the Cuban people."
Led by Russell's strong background in social entrepreneurship, fathom seeks to develop lasting social impact partnerships that allow for meaningful personal enrichment of the traveler, while providing systematic, long-term educational, environmental and economic development benefits in its partner countries.
"We're very interested in exploring the prospects of expanding our partnership with fathom to include Cuba, building new impact programs and lending our assistance to strengthen existing initiatives that will help educational, cultural and humanitarian efforts already going on in Cuba," said David Luther, founder and executive director of IDDI, a non-profit organization with the mission to help alleviate poverty in rural and urban areas in the Caribbean. "IDDI has long-standing relationships in Cuba and more than a decade of experience working on the ground side-by-side with local officials to make a positive impact in Cuban communities. Nothing else like fathom exists to bring hundreds of like-minded travelers a week to communities of people who need ongoing support. With fathom and its travelers, the potential for making a lasting impact in people's lives is tremendous. We look forward to partnering closely with fathom to take our programs to the next level, and support growth and prosperity for the citizens of Cuba."
Travelers may reserve travel on future fathom voyages

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Navigating 'Island' Parenting: The summer learning loss phenomenon</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Navigating-%27Island%27-Parenting%3A-The-summer-learning-loss-phenomenon-26832.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Navigating 'Island' Parenting: The summer learning loss phenomenon
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Mutryce A. Williams
Navigating Island Parenting is a submission of insights, quotes, tips and parenting advice that I have gathered over the years as a source of inspiration and as tools to deal with the daily challenges of parenting. This weeks issue: The Summer Learning Loss Phenomenon. The hope is that this submission would cause you to reflect on your parenting skills and also make the journey of parenting a bit easier or brighter.
Summer is a time of year that most if not all children look forward to, as it is a time of fun, frolicking, beach going, camping, sports playing and traveling. The books are thrown into the corner, uniforms strewn across the floor, the thumbs get ready for the video games and the eyes are primed for a marathon of television watching. Many parents welcome the break from school. They think it is much deserved after nine or ten months of structured instruction. Even though summer is a break from school it should not be a break from learning.
Did you know that the long summer vacation breaks the rhythm of instruction, and leads to children forgetting academic skills that have learned over the past year? According to the National Summer Learning Association (2015), if a childs brain isnt occupied or learning it is possible for his or her skills to regress. There is even a name for this dreaded phenomenon, which is supported by over 100 years of research. It is called Summer Learning Loss or the Summer Slide.
According to research:
 Low-income children, by the end of fifth grade, are about 2.5 to 3 years behind their more affluent peers. This is primarily due to summer learning loss. (Cooper, H., Nye, B., Charlton, K., Lindsay, J., &amp; Greathouse, S. (1996). The effects of summer vacation on achievement test scores: A narrative and meta-analytic review. REVIEW OF EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH, 66(3), 227-268. EJ 596 384.)
 On average, students lose about 2.6 months of grade level equivalency in mathematical computation skills during the summer. (Cooper, 1996).
 Students experience significant learning loss when they do not participate in educational activities during the summer months. Research shows that students on average score lower on standardized tests at the end of summer than they do on the same tests at the end of the school year. Low-income students experience greater summer learning losses than their higher income peers. On average, middle-income students experience slight gains in reading performance during summer vacation. Low-income students experience about a two month loss in reading achievement (Cooper, 1996).
 The research shows that achievement for both middle-and lower-income students improves at a similar rate during the school year, however, the achievement gap in reading scores between higher and lower income students increases significantly over the summer vacation (Alexander &amp; Entwisle, 1996).
 Two-thirds of the ninth grade reading achievement gap can be explained by unequal access to summer learning opportunities during the elementary school years; nearly one-third of the gap is already present when children begin school (Alexander, K., Entwisle, D., and Olson, L. 2007).
 Early summer learning losses have later life consequences, including high school completion, and whether children attend college (Alexander, K., Entwisle, D., and Olson, L. 2007).
References:
Alexander, K.L., and D.R. Entwisle. "Schools and Children at Risk." In Family-School Links: How Do They Affect Educational Outcomes?, edited by A. Booth and J.F. Dunn, 67-89. Mahwah, NJ: Erlbaum, 1996.
Alexander, K., Entwisle, D., and Olson, L. (2007). Lasting consequences of the summer learning gap. American Sociological Review, 72, 167-180.
Cooper, H., Nye, B., Charlton, K., Lindsay, J., and Greathouse, S. The Effects of Summer Vacation on Achievement Test Scores: A Narrative and Meta-analytic Review. Review of Educational Research, 66: 227-268, 1996.
Cooper, H., Nye, B., Charlton, K., Lindsay, J., and Greathouse, S. The Effects of Summer Vacation on Achievement Test Scores: A Narrative and Meta-analytic Review.Review of Educational Research, 66: 227-268, 1996.
Combating Summer Learning Loss
Did you know that six weeks in the new school year is spent re-learning old material in order to compensate for Summer Learning loss? Did you know that it can take up to two months from the first day of school for a students brain to get back on track? Did you know that as early as grade one summer learning loss can be recognized?
Here are a few suggestions which may assist in combating Summer Learning Loss
 Allocate time for learning each day.
 Design a Summer Learning curriculum for your child.
 Purchase or download age/ grade level workbooks such as Summer Bridge Activities.
 Compile a Reading List/Challenge for your child.
 Create a Summer Spelling Challenge for your child.
 Create a Summer Mathematics Challenge for your child.
 Have your child write a daily journal, a creative story or book.
 Have your child learn a foreign language such as French or Spanish - Rosetta Stone can prove beneficial.
 Visit the library often.
 Enroll your child in an educational or skills based Summer Camp or Program.
 Assist your child in seeking volunteer opportunities.
 Monitor the recreational use of television, computer, electronic and other technological devices.
Summer Break: A Time for Enrichment and Getting Ahead
In his treatise the Art of Thinking (1928), Abb Dimnet declared, Children have to be educated, but they have also to be left to educate themselves.
I concur with Dimnet, however, I dont think that summer or three months of doing absolutely nothing is what he was making reference to, as children ought to be continuously learning, even during these carefree summer months.
According to the National Summer Learning Association, the summer months should be used by children to branch out or get ahead of their studies. It should also be used to catch up on lessons that ones child may have missed or did not perfect throughout the school year. It should be used to stretch ones mind and learn new skills. Summer should be used constructively, as a head start for the next school year.
At the end of the school year, consult with your childs teacher or teachers in order to find out those areas in which your child needs improvement. Ask the teacher for suggestions, books, or recommendations on how you can assist your child in improving his or her skills over the summer break.
Most importantly, if your child is moving onto another grade seek an audience with your childs teacher or teachers to find out what his or her expectations for the next school year will be and again ask for suggestions on how you can facilitate a smooth transition into the next school year or give your child a head start.
Summer could also be used as a platform for the rest of your childs life. If your child wants a career as a journalist; he or she may volunteer at a media organization. If he or she wants to be a veterinarian he or she may choose to volunteer at a local farm, the department of agriculture or a school of veterinary studies. If your child wants to be a teacher or pediatrician, have your child volunteer at a local daycare/nursery so that he or she may gain a greater understanding of young children. If your child wants to be a designer or seamstress have him or her volunteer with a designer or seamstress. If he or she has an interest in the culinary arts, seek out a restaurateur or hotel and ask for volunteer opportunities. These are invaluable opportunities for learning. Learning doesnt have to be structured or rigid.
Quotes on Learning
Learning never exhausts the mind. Leonardo Da Vinci
You cannot open a book without learning something. Confucius
Learning is a treasure that will follow its owner everywhere. Chinese Proverb
The best of my education has come from the public library... my tuition fee is a bus fare and once in a while, five cents a day for an overdue book. You dont need to know very much to start with, if you know the way to the public library. Lesley Conger
Recommended Reading for Young Children
The Book with No Pictures  by B.J. Novak
Did I Ever Tell You How Lucky You Are!  by Dr. Seuss
What Pet Should I Get?  by Dr. Seuss
Mutryce A. Williams, a native of St Kitts and Nevis is the mother of 6-year-old Daniel and 5-year-old Nicholas. She not only values the many facets of West Indian parenting but also thinks that there is vast room for improvement. A former educator and a child/youth advocate, Mutryce firmly believes that children should not only be seen but heard. She may be contacted at mutrycewilliams@gmail.com

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: A thick lip and broad nose confession for Pope Francis on his Latin America trip</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-A-thick-lip-and-broad-nose-confession-for-Pope-Francis-on-his-Latin-America-trip-26833.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: A thick lip and broad nose confession for Pope Francis on his Latin America trip
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Derrick Miller
New Era: Since March 2013, your election was a very important change in the Roman Catholic Church. As the first Latin American, and Jesuit, it reconfirms the need for the church to re-focus on the poor. Many did not expect a sea change in the world overnight. Some have tried and failed, and other philosophies are taken over by political ideology and not the mere fact that people comes first.
Derrick Miller holds a BS degree in economics and finance, an MBA in global management and a MS in criminal justice leadership and management. He has worked in the US public safety and criminal justice field for over 14 years. He can be contacted at crijm@outlook.com and www.ourshores.org
However, given the scandal on sexual abuse in the Catholic Church that many have called a cover up for decades, where lives have been destroyed, a breath of fresh air is now upon us. Today, many of us who have embraced the faith from our parents teaching as a child are now on the sidelines, but recently we are rethinking our departure. Even some non-believers admire the churchs new platform of openness for dialog.
Our Commitment: The essence of Christianity remains an invitation to others, especially the least fortunate among us, the poor. Even looking back at Saint Pauls letter to the Romans, there was a call for unity. I understood that sometimes, geopolitical events force the church to walk a fine line on issues that range from greed, global warming, tolerance, and disparities between the haves vs. have-nots.
Centuries ago, people feeling atrocities simply due to religious beliefs is alive today. However, the church has tremendous influence on these issues. We also cannot discount that race has always been part of the church from anti-Semitism, racial injustice, sexuality, and other ideologies that divide people, but the church remains strong.
The choice this time is to visit Ecuador, Bolivia, and Paraguay. It is not simply to recalibrate the Catholic faith alone. It still enjoys over 40 percent of its members from the region, which is about 430 million throughout Latin America and the Caribbean. Being a native of the region and the head of the Catholic faith is always an added bonus. Sixty-nine percent of adults in Latin America identified as Catholic, according to a survey published in November. Many political leaders would be on their knees praying for these numbers today in a much divided world.
The Confession: What has transpired in Dominican Republic court ruling, threatening the deportation of over 200,000 people of Haitian descent is not simply an immigration issue of illegals or criminal elements, or overcrowding. It is ethnic cleansing, and one where thick lips and broad nose from the African Diaspora is at its core. Since Haitis independence in 1804, to Haitis invasion of the Spanish rule in trying to unify and to end slavery has not created harmony.
Quietly, missing from these visits is a dialog for racial harmony. We realize that the region is suffering from poverty and criminal elements that threaten social and economic stability. The exploitation and marginalization of many blacks continue, not limited to Ecuador, Bolivia, and Paraguay. However, I must keep this confession short, as others are waiting with their own stories.
The Catholic faith taught us that all are equal, and we reconfirm that during communion when all drink from the same cup. This three-second feeling of inclusion often only lasts from the pulpit back to our seats.
Even when blacks were part of major economic development in Panama, scholars have noted that West Indian migrants were discriminated against because they were English-speaking and Protestant. It was not much different from the US Jim Crow era; where they were paid less and oppressed. These new focus on ones features is a reality that has been on the table for centuries.
The Hidden Passage: Latin America and the overall Caribbean region, where the Catholic votes are almost guaranteed, needs a mass of social stratification. The polarization and marginalization of many cannot be ignored. As Dr Henry Hates noted, between 1502 and 1866, 11.2 million Africans survived the dreadful Middle Passage and landed as slaves in the New World. Those vessels of slaves, many are still trying to find an anchor.
Not too far from Dominican coast lines, blacks in Cuba [peizas negras] -- black spices, as they were once called -- despite the abolition of slavery in1820, Cuba benefited from up until 1873 according to historians.
The normalization of US and Cuba relations from 50 years ago, many have now seen images of an inclusive society between blacks and white Cubans. Havana looks like a melting pot. However, beneath these images, blacks are still being marginalized to slum areas, as they once were confined to sugar plantations from the documented shipment of slaves. Scholars have noted that the Afro-Cubans and others throughout Latin America are often relegated to the service economy where they are part of the vast fruit and vegetables street vendors, street dancers, artists, medicine women, and other things.
What has been going on is not a new paradigm shift. Many historians have traced this back to the 16th century to other places where black [La Negrita] inclusion from Costa Rica to Venezuela remains a struggle and especially where these Latin American countries regards themselves as white.
The irony is that, when many migrate from these privileged classes they enjoy in their native land, some find themselves doing jobs not even blacks would do. This does not make them any different, but it has a systematic racial tone, and it shows that marginalization cannot be diminished with an opportunity.
We cannot change our features to blend in, and when our roles are defined, such as reported, in Peru, where pallbearers jobs are precisely for blacks not because of their well-dressed tux, and pageantry in making sure one has a wonderful funeral, but simply the colour of their skin.
The Recessional Hymn: Many of us are still looking for our grandparents who fled to other regions in the Caribbean such as Jamaica, Trinidad, Haiti, Bermuda, Antigua, Barbados and other places several decades ago not because of a revolution or political turmoil, but the colour of ones skin. Afro-Caribbean influence and contribution has been significant to the regions culture and economic growth, but sometimes overlooked and forgotten.
Racial homogeneity has created political stability, high rate of literacy, and overall economic growth in some of these Latin countries.
After these hymns have been sung, religious leaders should use this moment to continue to mobilize social-economic, and justice issues, and a conversation that many believers is far more than the size of lips or pigmentation. They should be judged by their contribution to the society in creating a peaceful and successful union for all.
Addressing poverty and the environment is always important. However, concerning the plight of many blacks, they cannot only be celebrated on a football, baseball, and other professional sports field, and the community that produced these rare stars, continues to deteriorate because of their lips, and colour.
Amen: In the end despite being marginalized, the Catholic values are intact regardless of lip size. Millions of followers remain committed on even conservative values such as marriage between a man and a woman, and anti-abortion, and abstinence before marriage. However, the equality the robe must reach beyond the Sunday scripture of breaking bread together, but only some are being fed. The next stop could use an address on the ignorance of the thick lips, and broad nose.
See you at the 7.am Mass next week, same colour, thick lips and hips.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Why UDP will defeat PUP in the upcoming by-election on Wednesday</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Why-UDP-will-defeat-PUP-in-the-upcoming-by-election-on-Wednesday-26834.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Why UDP will defeat PUP in the upcoming by-election on Wednesday
Published onJuly 8, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Wellington C. Ramos
On Wednesday, July 8, 2015, the people of Dangriga town, Sarawee and Hope Creek villages will go to the polls to vote for a new representative to replace PUP Ivan Ramos who resigned recently. The election is between UDP candidate Frank Papa Mena and PUP candidate Anthony Sabal. All indications are that when all the votes are counted, UDP candidate Frank Papa Mena will be the new representative for this constituency.
Born in Dangriga Town, the cultural capital of Belize, Wellington Ramos has BAs in Political Science and History from Hunter College, NY, and an MA in Urban Studies from Long Island University. He is an Adjunct Professor of Political Science and History
I agree with the assessment that is being made for the following reasons: (1) The way the PUP removed Ivan Ramos as their party representative; (2) The candidate PUP picked to replace him, (3) The differences between Frank Papa Mena and Anthony Sabal; (4) The resources of the UDP and the PUP; and (5) The UDP is now the government of Belize and Dangriga people will not leave themselves without having the opportunity to get some money.
I will now expand on all these factors in their chronological order: (1) The way Ivan Ramos was removed as the Dangriga representative was not only disrespectful to him as a dedicated PUP but to all of his family, friends, supporters and the people who live in Dangriga town, Sarawee and Hope Creek villages. Everything was done by his party with a group of backstabbers. The party should have come to the constituency to consult the people who elected him before making their decision.
(2) Anthony Sabal is not a sociable person and comes from a different family background compared to Ivan Ramos. The Ramos family in Dangriga have always been diehard PUPs and for the PUP to do what they did to the son of Carl Ramos Kiwi, they will pay a heavy price at the polls today. Many of the people in Dangriga town are so unhappy with them that they will decide either not to vote or to vote for UDP. In such a scenario this action will benefit the UDP candidate.
(3) There are a lot of differences between Frank Papa Mena and Anthony Sabal. Papa Mena socializes with the people, the youth love him, he is charismatic, he is from the Sabal family like Anthony but will get most of his family votes.
He has also been involved in politics for a longer period of time and knows how to get out the votes.
In this election the Creole vote will be crucial. Anthony Sabals mother is Creole and Papa Menas wife is also Creole. However, Papa Menas wife is an Usher and that family has the resources to bring out the vote for Papa Mena. They have always been diehard UDPs in Dangriga politics and they are a force to reckon with. When they come out on election day it will be like crabs running wild all over Dangriga town, Sarawee and Hope Creek. They use to live on the Valley Road and have a lot of connections in the villages of Sarawee and Hope Creek.
(4) The PUP keep on talking about Petrocaribe Money. When they were in government they had access to a lot of money and did the same thing the UDPs are doing now. No political party will lose an election that they know they can win because that would be self-defeating. The UDP should and will spend what is necessary to win this election by a landslide. The UDP lost many elections that were held in Belizes history from 1953 to 1979. They know what losing is and how it feels when PUP are in power. Dean Barrow is the first UDP leader that is showing his party how to win elections, the others were afraid of PUP.
(5) The people of Dangriga town, Sarawee and Hope Creek villages know well that if they vote for PUP, they will not get any money from the UDP Central Government. A government in Belmopan working together with their representatives in Dangriga town and the villages of Sarawee and Hope Creek, will bring revenues to the constituency. I do not think that the people in my town and the villages will make a foolish mistake and vote for PUP.
I have outlined the reasons why I think that after all the votes are counted on the day of the election, Frank Papa Mena will become the new Dangriga town, Sarawee and Hope Creek Representative. Our people in Dangriga are in need of employment to feed themselves and their children. When Frank Papa is elected, he better not stop at this election but to keep the momentum going for economic development in his constituency. If he does not then when the general election is called, it will be anybodys chance to win.
Elections are not due until 2017 but the prime minister can call elections earlier if he chooses to do so. With the PUP in the current state that they are in, I do not think he is in a rush to call any.
The Peoples United Party is in desperate need for change of leadership and if it does not act quickly, they will become one of the third parties in Belize soon. After this election on Wednesday, they will be coming up with more excuses as to why they lost. The reality is that if you treat your people with disdain and disrespect, you will suffer the wrath of the people come election day. On election day all politicians become the common man and woman again and we should vote them out of office if we are not satisfied with their performance.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Poets Corner: Sovereign immunity</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Poets-Corner%3A-Sovereign-immunity-26835.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Guatemalan gunboat given sovereign immunity
In other words crown immunity
Powerful forces are working against Belize internationally
Legal protection that prevents a sovereign state from prosecution
Belize told to back off
Guatemalans just the laugh
Signaling that Elizabeth still dah the boss
Damages is 46,000 according to preliminary evaluation
When historically its always exceed $100,000
Belizes token government refuses to take a stand
Belizes government is being paid by the Guatemalans
Just as Antonio Soberanes, former union leader
Just as PUP were during the Price era
The games are the same the only difference is the players
Four Mexican officers found with weapons
Stopped at the Boom checkpoint in a white Mazda
Their names were not released
Kept in custody for a short time and given back their piece
Then government ordered their release
According the Mexican Embassy press officer
A section of the Geneva Convention
Requires countries not at war to hand over prisoners
Foreign soldiers violating our borders
Are our commanders soldiers or a bunch of yes sir men?
Toy soldier put there to pretend
Earl Arthurs was the best of them
I can understand Mexico but not Guatemala
When the constitution seh no citizenship fi any country weh no respect wi sovereignty
Minister the naturalize Guatemalans happily
No wonder no one respects our territory
Sovereign immunity means you cant touch mi
I am protected by the international political economy
This means exemption from the police and the military
Except when they out rightly break the law
Their immunity status can be withdrawn
But our authorities no have no gall
Belizes executive powers still lies in the Queen
The PM is just of manager heading the Belize scene
Elizabeth has reserved powers, you know weh I mean?
She can revoke the constitution if her orders are not performed
The US and England are Elizabeth daughters to which colonies must be warned

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
