<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:55:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>9 lives lost but unity found after Charleston shooting, residents say</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/charleston-shooting-out-of-this-tragedy-there-will-be-triumph-1.3143813?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Dylann Roof, Charleston church shooting suspect, indicted for murder
The deaths of nine innocent peopleon June 17 inCharleston, S.C., has made the citya stronger and more united community, according to local residents who vowto honour the legacy of those gunned down during a Bible study meeting.
The nephew of one of the slain worshippers at the African Methodist Episcopal Emanuel Church, faith leadersand community activists all say their city has changed for the better in the aftermath ofthe massacre, hopefully for good.
Dylann Roof has been charged in connection with the fatal shootingsat the historic black church. He is believed to have targeted the victims because they were black.
The tragedy prompted a debate about the Confederate flag in South Carolina and across the U.S. Roof allegedly wrote racist rants online, andthere are photos of Roof posing with the U.S.Civil Warbattle flag.
Despite the ongoing debate about whether the flag is a symbol of slavery and racial oppression or of southern pride, Charleston has come together in the wake of the shootings.
"June 17th made us stronger," said Andre Duncan, whose aunt, Myra Thompson, was among the victims. "It made everybody come together."
Duncan and others from Charleston were in Washington, D.C., on Wednesday to press Congress to pass stronger gun control laws. At a newsconference organized by the Brady Campaign To Prevent Gun Violence they called for new laws governing background checks for gun-seekers.
Lives sacrificed for unity
Duncan spoke about the way Charleston united in the face of such a shocking and sad event.
"I'm sorry to say this but through that tragedy it made Charleston stronger than it ever was.That nine, they sacrificed their lives to make Charleston stronger than it was supposed to be. It was an act of God to bring everybody together," Duncan said.
Pastor Thomas Dixon, a community organizer, said the city was "galvanized" and walls between races and religions that may have existed beforeare coming down.
"There is very little division within the community, along racial lines, ethnic lines, denominational lines," he said. "We all have a unified pain that is being shared there."
"Out of this tragedy there will be triumph. I can see it happening."
- Pastor Thomas Dixon
The pain is still raw. Dixon said he, and many others, can't talk about what happened that night without tears flowing into their eyes. That sadness is felt far beyond South Carolina, he said.
"You didn't have to be there to feel this connection.
"Charleston, it's the wonderful place that it's always been but there is also a greater sense of unity. Where there were ethnic barriers and things of that sort and even denominational barriers, those things have broken down a bit now as we move closer toward unity," Dixon said in an interview. "Out of this tragedy there will be triumph. I can see it happening."
How long the unity will last is a question mark, he said, but that's why he and others were in Washington, pressing Congress to make lasting changes to gun laws.
The Charleston residents are promising not to rest until that happens, and they are also intent on maintaining the new bridges that have formed between faiths and skin colours in their city.Different groups of people are interacting in a way they never used to, Dixon said, and that dialogue must keep up.
Muslims fundraise for burned black churches
"We can't go back to business as usual. We will not go back to business as usual," he pledged.
In the days after June 17, seven predominantly black churches suffered fires in multiple states. Some were arson, others may be due to lightning strikes and others are still under investigation. In the arson cases it hasn't been determined that the vandalism was racially motivated, butthe incidents nonetheless haveprompted outpourings of support for the affected communities.
A fundraising effort was launched on July 2 by several Muslim organizations that so far has raised more than $32,000 US.
Faatimah Knight, one of the organizers who works at theMuslim Anti-Racism Collaborative, said that as a black woman, she was saddened by the arsons. She also felt compelled by her religion to help.
A woman casts a shadow on a memorial message board outside the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston, South Carolina. (Brian Snyder/Reuters)
"I definitely feel like faith called me, called us, to protect those who are vulnerable, who are in a position where they are frequently attacked or dismissed," she said in a phone interview from her Brooklyn office.
"I really believe that Christians are our brothers and sisters in faith and in humanity."
Rev. Charles Boyer, a representative of the national African Methodist Episcopalcommunity who was at the newsconference in Washington, said the Emanuel church in Charleston has also benefited from the support of other faiths.
"Immediately we got an outpouring of support from every religious denomination you can think of," he said. Many AME churches across the country already had good relationships with Jewish and Muslim communities and so it comes as no surprise they are supporting each other, he said.
Like Pastor Dixon, Boyer said he's seen not only different faiths uniting in Charleston, but different ethnicitiestoo.
"There was a pure, genuine, heartfelt hurt and empathy from everyone, and it just strengthened our resolve and our belief that America can be that absolute, beloved community that we've all been pushing for," he said.
Louise Brown, an 80-year-old activist who knew all of the "Emanuel Nine" victims, said she's never seen a community come together the way Charleston has. She had one word to describe it: "Marvelous."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek PM Alexis Tsipras's path to power </title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/greek-pm-alexis-tsipras-s-path-to-power-1.3141263?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greek PM Alexis Tsipras's path to power
Greece's youngest prime minister in over a century, Tsipras has been politically active since age 14
CBC News Posted: Jul 08, 2015 5:00 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 4:48 PM ET
Within days, Greece's banks could be out of cash unless those same political charms which endeared Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras to Greek voters convince his skeptical creditors to part with more financial aid.  (Geert Vanden Wijngaert/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Greek financial crisis: How the country moves forward after the No vote
In 1990, a then 16-year-oldAlexis Tsipraswas being interviewed as one of a number of young Greek activists who had led a revoltagainst their schools, part of aprotest around proposed educationreforms.
"We would like it to be our right to decide if, at some point, we want to skip class," Tsiprassaid, according to theSpanish newspaper ElMundo.
No surprise then that, nearly 25years later, Greek's current prime ministeris still thumbing his nose at authority, this timeagainsttheEuropean powerbrokers who hold the economic fate of his country in their hands.
How Greece moves forward after the No vote
It was this message of defiance, of saying enough to the austerity measures imposed on Greece, that helpedsweephim and his self-proclaimed radicalleft-wing coalitioninto office in January, which led ultimately to thesubstantial "No" victory in the weekend's referendum
It was a victory to be surethough muted by the hugefinancial crunch his country faces.
Within days, Greek banks could be out of cash, unless those same politicalcharms that endeared Tsipras to Greek votersconvincehisskeptical creditors to part with more financial aid.
"I'm a compromiser because I want to have realistic goals," Tsipras told the Financial Times in January ."At the same time, I'm very decisive if I know it's necessary to have a fight."
Youngest PM in some time
At age40, Tsipras isthe country's youngestprime minister in over a century and a half. And while he hasbeen a political animal since his teens, joining the youth wing of the Communist Partyat age 14, he had a different career path planned, to become an engineer andwork in theconstruction business like his father.
Tsipras was born in Athens to a middle class family, and afather , "whowas solidly a man of the centre, voting regularly for the social democraticPanhellenicSocialist Movement (Pasok)," according to the Times.
When he left high school, he also dropped out of the Communist youth, but remained active in student politics at the NationalPolytechnic University of Athens,according toEl Mundo.
"He was always decisive and a pragmatist, a doer",Andreas Karitzis, a member of Syriza's Central Committee and a fellow student with Tsipras at the Polytechnic,told El Mundo. "He had an uncanny ability to identify achievable goals and do whatever necessary to achieve them."
At the time, Tsipraswanted tostudy civil engineering andfollow in thefootsteps of his father who ran a small construction company in Athens, the Times said.
After graduating he didworkas a civil engineer in the construction industry, but soon joined the youth chapter of the small leftist partySynaspismos, which eventually morphed intoSyriza (also known as the Coalition of the Radical Left).
He rose up the ranks of Synaspismos, soimpressing party officials that in 2006he was asked to represent the party and the new Syriza coalition as a mayoral candidate for Athens.
Although there was some concerns expressed within the partyabout his relativeyouth, he specificallytargetedthat demographic in the election, boostingthe parties fortunes and receiving 11 per cent of the vote, finishing in third place.
"That was the boom,"Dimitris Tzanakopoulos, a Syriza legal adviser, told theTimes. "His whole life changed."
A national figure
At that point,Tsipras was a national figure in Greece and two years laterwould become leader of Syriza, even as hispolitics are said to have moderated since his Communist youth days.
Luke March, an expert on radical left and post-Soviet politics at the University of Edinburgh, told Business Insider that Tsipras's "role has been as a leader who is able to present himself as principled but pragmatic, a conciliator and statesmanlike."
It was an image that heldwhenGreeks went to the polls earlier this year and were unswayed bythen primeministerAntonisSamaras's best efforts to portray his opponentasa radicalcommunis t.
Tsipras'election ushered in a number of firsts  thefirst time the country would beruled by a party other thanthe right-leaning New Democracy orleft-of-centre PASOK; thefirst time an incoming prime minister would not take a religious oath (Tsipras is an avowed athiest). And it was the first time Greece elected an unmarried prime minister.
Tsipras has been with his high-school sweetheartPeristera 'Betty'Batzianafor two decades. The couple has two sons, (one of whom, Orpheus Ernesto, is named after the Cuban guerilla fighterErnesto"Che"Guevera) and for years had beenliving in a rented apartment in Athens.
He may have also been the first prime minister, at least in recent times, to not wear a necktie during the oath of office.
For Tsipras, it is a casual style that voters are familiar with. And one he plans to continue, he has joked, until the country gets some debt relief,meaning hisneck could be bare for the foreseeable future.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:16:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Switzerland tests drones for mail delivery</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/switzerland-tests-drones-for-mail-delivery-1.3143689?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Switzerland tests drones for mail delivery
Matternet drones can carry one kilogram over more than 10 kilometres on a single charge
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 08, 2015 8:16 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 8:16 PM ET
Swiss postal service tests delivery by drones 1:34
Related Stories
Google's delivery drones newest front in war with Amazon
Swiss Post, Swiss WorldCargo and Matternet, a drone manufacturer, announced todaythey had started testing the use of drones to make deliveries.
According to the manufacturer's website, the flying device is specially designed for transporting small deliveries. Its extremely light structure allows it to carry loads of one kilogram over more than 10 kilometres on a single charge. It flies autonomously by following safe and clear air routes established by a cloud software designed by Matternet.
This new way of delivery could also help in emergencies and allow items to reach isolated areas and transport highly urgent priority items, according to the Swiss postal service.
The three companies said they were investigating specific uses of drone technology and examining the cost-effectiveness of these business ideas, but did not expect widespread use before five years as a number of requirements still need to be clarified, such as the legal framework conditions.
Amazon.com and other companies, including Google Inc , are also working to develop sophisticated drone operations capable of delivering packages to consumers.
Google's delivery drones newest front in war with Amazon
Drone advocates have pressed the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to accommodate advanced technology in commercial drone regulations expected by the end of 2016. The current proposed rules would limit flights to daylight hours at low altitudes and within an operator's visual line of site.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:36:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>London subway strike expected to cause commuter chaos</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/london-underground-closed-as-strike-begins-commuter-chaos-expected-1.3106893?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>London Underground closed as strike begins, commuter chaos expected
CBC News Posted: Jul 08, 2015 5:36 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 6:19 PM ET
Commuters at Earls Court Underground station attempt to complete their journey on Wednesday evening. A strike by staff and drivers on London's subway is expected to cause commuting troubles Thursday. (Peter Nicholls/Reuters )
Related Stories
Transport for London
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
London commuters can expect a bit of chaos Thursday morning as service on the Underground has stopped due to a strike.
Transport for London said subway services will be reduced"across all lines from early evening on Wednesday 8 July and there will be no Tube service at all on Thursday 9 July."
The subway operatorsaid that there would be extra bus and river service but cautioned people toexpect roads and operating transit lines to be busier than usual.
Due to #Tubestrike , all public transport &amp; roads will be busier tomorrow especially during peak hours http://t.co/9bQz35k9Xa
 @TfLTravelAlerts
Drivers and station staff walked out ina dispute over pay and schedules when a 24-hour subway service starts on some lines later this year.
Union officials have accused management of failing to negotiate seriously, something London Underground managing director Mike Brown denies.
"Talks with the trade union leaderships have gone on for over five months with little constructive engagement on their part," he said in a statement posted online.
London Mayor Boris Johnson aired his views on Twitter, saying the strike is "politically motivated  union bosses need to explain why they refuse to put new offer to members  disgraceful call it off!
According to Transport for London, the Underground sees up to four million passenger trips per day and has, at peak times, "more than 535 trains whizzing around the capital."
The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 09:37:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China stock crisis: Asian markets plunge despite Beijing's measures to halt financial meltdown</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/china-stock-crisis-asian-markets-plunge-despite-beijing-s-measures-to-halt-financial-meltdown-1.3142547?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese yuan among top 10 most traded currencies
Hong Kong's main stock index plummeted as much as 8.5 per cent on Wednesday as a sell-off in mainland Chinese shares accelerated despite the government's new measures to support the market.
The China rout also battered investor sentiment elsewhere in Asia, with other major markets finishing sharply lower. Shanghai's Composite index closed down six per cent.
The drop in Hong Kong's Hang Seng and the Shanghai Composite came despite China's government on Wednesday telling state-owned companies to buy shares, raising the amount of equities insurance companies can hold and promising more credit to finance trading.
Hundreds of companies have announced a halt to trading in their shares after emergency measures announced last weekend failed to stop a slide that has caused China's main market index to decline by more than 30 per cent since early June.
The decline threatens to fuel political tensions and set back Communist Party plans to use financial markets to make China's state-dominated economy more productive. The party wants to encourage more public stock ownership but some small investors who have seen their holdings plunge in value say they will buy no more.
Toronto becomes first renminbi trading hub in North America
Passers-by walk in front of a panel displaying the closing Hang Seng Index and China Enterprise Index in Hong Kong on Wednesday. Losses on the mainland weighed heavily on Hong Kong shares, with the Hang Seng Index down 3.3 per cent and shares of Chinese companies listed in the city falling 4.2 per cent. (Tyrone Siu/Reuters)
On Wednesday, the Cabinet agency that oversees China's biggest state-owned companies said it had told them not to sell shares and to buy more "in order to safeguard market stability."
The China Insurance Regulatory Commission said the amount of their assets Chinese insurers are allowed to invest in stocks will be increased to 40 per cent from 30 per cent. The agency said the amount of a single blue-chip company's shares that an insurance company can buy will be increased to 10 per cent from 5 per cent.
The central bank said it will provide "ample liquidity to support stock market stability" through a government-owned company that lends to brokerages to finance share purchases, a practice known as margin lending. The People's Bank of China gave no indication how much money it might inject into the system.
The central bank statement was read on state TV's national midday news.
More than 1,000 companies suspend trading
Chinese authorities have tried to reassure investors that the price decline is normal following a boom that saw the Shanghai Composite Index soar by more than 150 per cent since late 2014. On Monday, the flagship Communist Party newspaper, People's Daily, said the economy can main steady growth and provide "solid fundamentals" for "healthy development of capital markets."
Such reassurance has done little to halt the declines. On Wednesday, the Shanghai index tumbled 4 per cent and Hong Kong's market benchmark dived 4.2 per cent.
The emergency measures announced so far are aimed at shoring up the prices of shares in major state-owned companies, while those of smaller and private companies have received little support.
The weekend announcements included a pledge by state-owned brokerages to buy blue-chip stocks, or shares in major state companies.
That helped to boost prices this week of major companies such as PetroChina Ltd., Asia's biggest oil and gas producer. But shares in smaller companies have fallen.
That has prompted hundreds of companies to ask the mainland's two exchanges to suspend trading in their shares after prices of some fell by more than 50 per cent. Dozens with shares traded in Hong Kong also have requested suspensions.
Some 787 companies had suspended trading on the exchanges in Shanghai and the southern city of Shenzhen as of the end of trading on Tuesday, the newspaper China Business News reported. It said more asked to be suspended later Tuesday, raising the total to more than 1,000.
That would be almost 36 per cent of the total of 2,802 companies traded in Shanghai and Shenzhen.
In Hong Kong, shares in which trading was suspended included Sinopec, the country's No. 2 state-owned oil company.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:11:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>3 teens rescued after canoe swept into waterfall on U.S.-Canada border</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/teens-rescued-after-canoe-swept-into-waterfall-on-u-s-canada-border-1.3143714?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Teens rescued after canoe swept into waterfall on U.S.-Canada border
Boy, 15, trapped in water for hours suffered extreme hypothermia, leg injury
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 08, 2015 5:11 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 5:11 PM ET
In this photo from 2011, U.S. Forest Service employees lead a tour by canoe of the Boundary Waters Canoe Area on Lake Three near Ely, Minn. Three teenagers from a Rochester church group had to be rescued after their canoe was swept into the nearby Upper Basswood Falls. (David Joles/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Quebec canoeist recalls harrowing near-drowning and heroism of missing friend
Three teenagers from a Rochester, Minn.,church group had to be rescued after their canoe was swept into a waterfall on the U.S.-Canada border between Minnesota and Ontario, authorities say.
Those rescued included a 15-year-old boy who spent several hours trapped in the water Tuesday, said the Lake County Sheriff's Office. Suffering from extreme hypothermia and a leg injury, he was nearly unconscious during the last half-hour of the rescue. Sheriff Casey Johnson said in a statement that the other two were OK.
Thesheriff's office received a call around 1 p.m. local time about the accident on the Upper Basswood Falls in the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness, and it took over four hours for rescuers to reach and free the boy.
The teens lost control of their canoe in the rapids at the top of the falls, the sheriff's office said. The 15-year-old got trapped by the damaged canoe, which was pinned against the rocks by the force of the rushing water.
Upper Basswood Falls have been the scene of at least one fatal accident. Dick Barber, 78, of Minnetonka, Minn.,died in 2013 when his canoe went over the falls.
The boy is recovering at an Ely hospital.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:30:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore police commissioner fired 2 months after Freddie Gray riots</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/baltimore-police-commissioner-anthony-batts-fired-2-months-after-freddie-gray-riots-1.3143717?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Baltimore Police Commissioner Anthony Batts fired, 2 months after Freddie Gray riots
Headed department when 25-year-old black man died from injury sustained in police custody
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 08, 2015 4:30 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 4:39 PM ET
Baltimore Police Department Commissioner Anthony Batts has been fired a little over two moths after riots erupted in the city over the treatment of Freddie Gray, a 25-year-old black man who died from injuries sustained in police custody.  (Patrick Semansky/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Body cameras: Can they reduce confrontations with police?
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake has fired Police Commissioner Anthony Batts.
Rawlings-Blake announced the firing in a news release Wednesday afternoon. She said Deputy Police Commissioner Kevin Davis will become interim commissioner.
Rawlings did not give a reason, but the move comes amid a spike in the city's homicide rate.
Freddie Gray should have received medical attention
Baltimore was rocked with civil unrest in April after black resident Freddie Gray died one week after suffering a critical spinal injury in police custody. Six police officers have been criminally charged in Gray's death.
Since the rioting stopped, the city has seen a sharp increase in violence, with 155 homicides this year, a 48 per cent increase over the same period last year.
Six officers were charged in connection with Gray's death, with the most serious charge being second-degree depraved heart murder, which carries a maximum sentence of 30 years.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:22:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Body of Cessna passenger found as search for pilot continues after collision with F-16</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/cessna-150-f-16-collision-body-of-passenger-found-as-search-for-pilot-continues-1.3143521?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Cessna 150, F-16 collision: Body of passenger found as search for pilot continues
Michael Johnson was passenger in plane piloted by 30-year-old son, Joseph, that collided with F-16
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 08, 2015 3:22 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 4:41 PM ET
VIDEO: Jet pilot rescued after mid-air plane crash 1:13
Related Stories
2 people presumed killed in F-16, Cessna collision over South Carolina
A man and his adult son were on board a small plane that was destroyed when it collided with an F-16 fighter jet over a rural, sparsely populated area in South Carolina, a coroner said Wednesday.
Authorities found the body of 68-year-old Michael Johnson, the passenger, in the Cooper River, Berkeley County Coroner Bill Salisbury said. They are still searching the same area for the body of his son, 30-year-old Joseph Johnson, who was piloting the Cessna 150.
Connie Stallworth said Michael Johnson was her brother. His death came just days after the death of another brother, Jim Johnson, and his wife, Beverly, Stallworth said. The couple's 16-year-old grandson has been charged with second-degree murder in their slayings. Their bodies were found early Saturday morning.
"It's unbelievable. There just aren't words to express it,"Stallworth said. "I'm dumbfounded that it happened twice in a few days."
No homes damaged
Debris from the collision, which happened near Moncks Corner, was scattered over a broad area about 30 kilometres northwest of Charleston, but there were no reports of any residents hurt or homes damaged, Berkeley County spokesman Michael Mule said Tuesday.
Investigators were still searching for the body of the 30-year-old pilot of the Cessna 150 plane that collided with an F-16 jet Tuesday. The body of the passenger of the Cessna was recovered Wednesday. (WCSC-TV)
NTSB investigator Dennis Diaz told reporters Wednesday that his first goal is to document the two crash sites, which are about 16kmapart. He also said the F-16 pilot, who ejected safely, will be interviewed. However, that may not happen for several days.
Investigators will look at flight data recorders and interview witnesses, though that is expected to take months, Diaz said. He would not comment on the direction, speed or altitude at which either aircraft was traveling.
The jet's pilot, Maj. Aaron Johnson from the 55th Fighter Squadron, was taken to Joint Base Charleston's medical clinic for observation, officials from Shaw Air Force Base in Sumter said in a news release.
The jet crashed into woods around the privately owned Lewisfield Plantation, an estate dating to 1750.
"We heard the plane crash," said Leo Ramsey, who has worked at the plantation for about 30 years. "And then we took off from where I was at, I guess I was about a half-mile from it, when we saw a cloud of smoke."
Ramsey and two other workers found burning metal, splintered trees and a flaming crater where the jet had crash-landed, he said.
F-16 practising instrument approaches
Col. Stephen Jost, commander of the 20th Fighter Squadron at Shaw Air Force Base, said Maj. Johnson was flying solo, practising instrument approaches to a military base and was communicating with Charleston air traffic controllers.
Jost said he thought it was overcast at the time of the collision, but he was not aware of any weather-related problems.
It wasn't clear if a flight plan had been filed, but Berkeley County officials say the civilian pilot had indicated he was traveling to Myrtle Beach.
F-16s from Shaw Air Force Base, about 56 km east of Columbia, routinely fly training missions over eastern South Carolina and the Atlantic.
The Cessna 150 is a two-seat plane that typically weighs about 680 kg when fully fuelled. By comparison, an F-16 is about 15 metres long and weighs nearly nine tonnes, not counting fuel or weapons. Jost said the F-16 was not carrying any live munitions at the time of the collision.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:53:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fight against child marriage to get $10M in Canadian funding</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/fight-against-child-marriage-to-get-10m-in-canadian-funding-1.3143629?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Fight against child marriage to get $10M in Canadian funding
Names of organizations splitting $196M for maternal and child health programs also announced
ByLaura Payton, CBC News Posted: Jul 08, 2015 4:53 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 5:14 PM ET
Krishna, 14, pictured with her four-month-old baby Alok in 2013, married her husband Gopal when she was 11 and he was 13. International efforts to end child, early and forced marriage are getting $10 million from Canada, Foreign Affairs Minister Rob Nicholson said Wednesday. (Danish Siddiqui/Reuters)
Related Stories
Canada's maternal health billions: From Bono to birth control, what's working?
Worldwide efforts to end child, early and forced marriage are getting $10million from Canada, Foreign Affairs Minister Rob Nicholson said Wednesday, as the government also named 11 non-governmental organizationsthat will share $180 million in maternal, newborn and child health funding.
In a news release, Nicholson saidCanada will put$2.3 million towarda project to promote secondary schooling and skills development training for girls and women in Commonwealth countries. The goal is to "promote secondary schooling for girls and women and provide them with skills development training to improve their livelihoods, the release said.
Read more from Laura Payton's 2015 Travers Fellowship series
Nicholson alsoannounced the government will devote$8million over two years to supportlocal community groups and governments, as well as NGOs andcivil society groups, in efforts to combat child, early and forced marriage. Canadian embassies and high commissions will administer the money.
The announcement came on the same day as Conservative MPs announced some of the NGOs that would get funding to improve maternal, newborn and child health around the world.
Eleven Ontario-basedNGOswill share $180 million from 2015 to 2020 for projects that address such issues as nutrition, sanitation and hygiene, and health worker training.
Four British Columbia-based NGOswill share another $16.1 million.
The new funding comes from the government's $3.5-billion pledge tofollow up on its 2010-2015 foreign aid focus on maternal, newborn and child health, known as the Muskoka Initiative. The government has set aside $420 million for NGO-run programs.
The NGOs getting funding announced today are:
Action Against Hunger.
Amref Health Africa in Canada.
Christian Children's Fund of Canada.
CUSOInternational with theCanadian Association of Midwives.
effect:hope  The Leprosy Mission Canada.
Geospatial/SALASANConsulting Inc.
GRID &amp; NEA: Ghana Rural Integrated Development.
Jane Goodall Institute of Canada.
Plan International Canada.
The Presbyterian Church in Canada.
The Primate's World Relief and Development Fund.
TulaFoundation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:32:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Sky hasn't fallen' one year since Washington state legalized marijuana</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/legalizing-marijuana-was-for-the-best-says-washington-state-county-sheriff-1.3143507?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Legalizing marijuana was for the best, says Washington state county sheriff
Sheriff says its time for police and politicians to listen to the people of British Columbia
ByThe Early Edition, CBC News Posted: Jul 08, 2015 12:32 PM PT Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 12:32 PM PT
After recreational marijuana was legalized in Washington state, the first store to open to customers sold out of pot in one day.  (Elaine Thompson/Associated Press)
Sheriff reacts to one year since marijuana legalization in Washington state 5:21
Related Stories
Seattle's first legal recreational marijuana store opened one year ago today. Over that time, there have been more than a quarter-billion dollars in cannabis sales andmore than $70million generatedin taxes for local and state governments.
The legalization of recreational pot meant a significant change for the state's police approach towards the drug.
King County Sheriff John Urquhart spoke with The Early Edition's Rick Cluff about the impacts of that decision.
You are the sheriff for Washington's biggest county, including the cities of Seattle and Tacoma. What were the biggest challenges you and your officers faced in adapting to marijuana as a newly legalized substance?
Really there was nothing to adapt to. My biggest challenge was letting my officers know that it's a different ball game now, don't worry about it.
From a crime standpoint, there was nothing to enforce anymore and the sky didn't fall. It was business as usual and no big deal.
Sheriff John Urquhart says the war on drugs was an abject failure. (King County)
One of the biggest concerns about legalization here in Vancouverand in Canadais that it might lead to increasing youth access to marijuana. How closely were your forces watching for that?
That just hasn't happened. All the studies that have been done show marijuana use in Washington State is down. With the tax revenue coming in, we'll be able to devote some of that money to education.The legalization has not increased the use of marijuana by youth.
What were your expectations as this law changed?
I was the only police chief in Washington state to actually support the legalization of marijuana.
I was a drug enforcement officer and arrested lots of people for every single drug imaginable and took them to jail.What I learned during that time was that the war on drugs hasn't worked. More than that it's been an abject failure.
The citizens of the state of Washington decided they wanted to legalize marijuana. The citizens have spoken and it's time for us, the police, to listen.
Recreational marijuana is still illegal at the federal level in the United States. Did you come into any conflict with federal law enforcement officials?
No open conflict. The federal government through the department of justice has said "we don't really like this, but we see the handwriting on the wall and as long as you do certain things, we will keep hands off."
Those things are making sure marijuana isn't sold to young people under 21, that we shut down shops that aren't licensed, and that we enforce DUI statutes.
What advice would you have for law officials and politicians in Canada who may be considered about what the legalization of recreational marijuana might mean?
Listen to the people of British Columbiausually they're smarter than the politicians and the cops. Make your views known, but don't give the attitude of "we're the cops, you're not, so don't tell us how to do our job."
That's a situation that's occurred with police officers forever, and that's got to change. Just listen and it'll all be fine. 
This interview was edited and condensed. To hear the full interview, click the audio labelled: Sheriffreacts to one year since marijuana legalization in Washington state.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:00:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tom Selleck accused of stealing water for ranch in drought-stricken California</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/tom-selleck-accused-of-stealing-water-for-ranch-1.3143317?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tom Selleck accused of stealing water for ranch
Actor's property is located in drought-stricken California
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 08, 2015 2:00 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 6:54 PM ET
Tom Selleck accused of stealing water for ranch 3:26
Related Stories
California drought means shrinkage and shortage of citrus fruits
A water district is suing actor Tom Selleck, accusing the actor of stealing truckloads of water from a public hydrant and taking it to his ranch in drought-stricken Southern California.
The Calleguas Municipal Water District inVentura Countyclaims a tanker truck filled up at a hydrant on more than a dozen occasions and hauled the water to a 60-acre spread in Westlake Village owned by the Magnum, P.I. and Blue Bloods star.
The Los Angeles Times said Selleck grows avocados at the ranch.
Court documents dated June 30 say the Calleguas Municipal Water District spent nearly $22,000 US to hire a private investigator to document the alleged thefts, which date back two years.
Drought-stricken California imposes new water cuts on farmers
Representatives for Selleck did not return phone messages and emails seeking comment Wednesday. The lawsuit also names the actor's wife, Jillie Selleck.
The lawsuit comes after California communities were ordered to cut water use by 25 per cent compared with 2013 levels amid a four-year dry spell.The area in Ventura County where Selleck has his land is under mandatory cutbacks as high as 36 percent.
The district claims it sent Selleck cease-and-desist letters aimed at halting the unlawful water deliveries, but the truck was spotted as recently as March filling up at the hydrant on four days and delivering water to the ranch.
The suit does not specify how much water was taken.
In addition to legal fees and investigative costs, the water district is seeking an injunction barring Selleck and his contractors or employees from taking water from the district.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Emotion rules as Europe's anger with Greece boils over: Don Murray</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/europe-losing-patience-with-greek-fiscal-crisis-1.3141945?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Europe losing patience with Greek fiscal crisis
When it comes to Greece, punishment, say the polls, is what most Germans want
ByDon Murray, CBC News Posted: Jul 08, 2015 5:00 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 4:50 PM ET
Meet your banker. Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras (L) talks with European Central Bank President Mario Draghi during at the start of the EU leaders emergency summit on Tuesday. (REUTERS)
Playing politics with the Greek crisis 10:12
About The Author
Don Murray
Eye on Europe
A well-travelled former CBC reporter and documentary maker, Don Murray is a freelance writer and translator based in London and Paris.
Related Stories
Greek bailout referendum: World leaders react to No vote
July. The politicians of Europe scramble in panic, stirred to action by a stunning event in the continent's underbelly.
Not this July, but a hot month 101 years ago. Austria's Grand Duke, Franz Ferdinand, the heir to the throne of the Austro-Hungarian empire, was assassinated in the streets of Sarajevo, in Bosnia.
Just weeks later, the continent was at war.
By that measure, the massive 'No' to austerity in the Greek referendum Sunday, and its increasingly possible consequence, the so-called Grexit or ejection of Greece from the eurozone, seems less apocalyptic.
But the twisted tale of Europe's currency and Greece's sorry role in it has had, arguably, the same effect on the continent's leaders and nations as the shots in Sarajevo, stirring anger and filling the air with calls for punishment.
In rejecting austerity, Greek voters force Germany's hand
Consider that Germany's biggest tabloid newspaper, Bild, splashed a doctored photo of Chancellor Angela Merkel wearing a Prussian spiked helmet and blared: "We need an Iron Chancellor!"
The Iron Chancellor, of course, was Otto von Bismarck, who united Germany and fought surgical wars that punished Denmark, Austria and France in short order.
Set against that, punishing Greece should be relatively straightforward. And punishment, say the polls, is what most Germans want.
No special treatment
What's more, it is not only the Germans who feel this way.
The leaders of several countries of Eastern Europe most smaller and poorer than Greece, and still living with the consequences of two generations of Soviet rule have been scathing in their reaction to the referendum and to the fact that Greece showed up at Tuesday's emergency EU summit without even a written proposal.
Read their words: "The Slovaks will not lose one euro because of the Greeks," said Robert Fico, the Slovak prime minister.
"The Greeks said No to [European] help, and so they've also said No to the eurozone," added Ewa Kopacz, the Polish prime minister.
There were similar harsh condemnations from Lithuanian and Estonian leaders.
Those European countries that have faced similar austerity regimes in recent years such as Spain and Portugal have been conspicuous by their silence in the wake of the Greek vote.
They have been forced to swallow some bitter medicine, and are far from convinced that Greece should get special hospital privileges.
'A leap in the dark'
These are the men and women that Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was facing at the hurriedly convened European summit Tuesday.
Only the French leader, Franois Hollande, seemed intent on finding a way to help Greece stay afloat and in the euro.
But, as the French and the rest of Europe have noticed, Hollande is considerably weaker than many of his French forebears, particularly when faced with the likes of an Angela Merkel.
Germany's Iron Chancellor? Angela Merkel was all smiles going into the emergency summit. But the pre-summit warnings and body language told a different story. (REUTERS)
But will she be an iron chancellor? There are other possibilities.
Take the example of Theobald von Bethmann-Hollweg. Like Merkel, he was politely dismissed as a lightweight when he first took office in 1909.
"I shall soon get the hang of foreign policy," Bethamnn said somewhat pathetically, according to his scornful predecessor. He never really did, and his hour of destiny was July 1914.
Like Merkel, he was pulled by forces inside and outside his country over which he had minimal control.
Frustration, miscalculation, stupidity all played a role in capitals across the continent, but in the end Bethmann and his slightly mad Kaiser, Wilhelm II, had a choice: to push for peace or war.
Bethmann called it "a leap in the dark" and pushed for war.
Politics and emotion
At the time, Germany was, like today, the dominant continental power. It also had a blueprint to contain the effects of this drastic decision. Everything would go according to plan. Until it didn't.
Little has gone to plan with Greece and the euro either.
Greek's newly-appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos takes over from the mercurial Yanis Varoufakis. But he still needs a plan. (REUTERS)
This latest European summit began with Tsipras and other European leaders arguing over whether Greece had actually presented anything like a new plan for general consideration, and ended with what appeared to be an ultimatum that Sunday would be the stay or go deadline.
The Greek prime minister, with his harsh rhetoric and surprise referendum, hasinfuriated many of his so-called eurozone partners over these last weeks.
That fury was so great that the powerful German finance minister, Wolfgang Schable, was heard to say that Greece should never have been allowed into the euro in the first place.
Fury isn't a good basis for making important economic decisions, but the future of Greece in the euro no longer seems to have much to do with numbers and economics.
Like a century ago, politics and emotion seem to be driving Europe's leaders, this time towards something that they all once piously declared was unthinkable pushing a country out of the common currency.
That result would be, as the unfortunate Bethmann put it, a leap in the dark. But, once again, a majority of Europe's leaders seem prepared to make that move.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:09:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>United Airlines restoring operations after computer problems grounded all U.S. flights</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/united-airlines-ground-stop-lifted-after-computer-issues-1.3142729?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>United Airlines ground stop lifted after computer issues
Airline says 'network connectivity issue' briefly grounded all U.S. flights this morning
CBC News Posted: Jul 08, 2015 9:09 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 11:32 AM ET
'Automation issues' briefly grounded all United Airlines flights in the U.S. on Wednesday. (Jeff Haynes/Reuters)
Related Stories
United Airlines ending direct flights between Saskatchewan and Denver
United Airlines said it was restoring flight operations after grounding all U.S. flights for nearly two hours today because of "network connectivity" problems.
The Federal Aviation Administration confirmed that the "automation issues" that had caused the ground stop have been resolved.
United tweeted a statement saying it is recovering from the computer glitch and will give waivers to passengers who have to rebook their flights.
We're recovering from a network connectivity issue &amp; restoring flight ops. Well have a waiver on http://t.co/ufFoKFTNNe to change flights.
 @united
At several major U.S. airports Wednesday,United boards showing departuresand arrivalswent blank during the ground stop, and ticket agents reportedly had to resort topen and paper to check in passengers and baggage. Frustrated passengers shared photos on Twitter oflong lines and crowded airports.
 @9NEWS
The outage lasted less than two hours.
Massive system fail: #FAA confirms #UA computers down nationwide. Ticket agents checking us in with pen &amp; paper. #cnn pic.twitter.com/8YAIAEclYG
 @KyungLahCNN
Chicago radio station WGN reported theground stop did not affectUnited's regionalcarrier, United Express.
Pearson International Airport in Toronto was advising passengers to check their flight status because of potential knock-on effects of the network issue.
An industry analyst said the grounding will frustrate Air Canadapassengers travelling on shared flights with Unitedbut have little lasting impact on United or its Canadian partner.
"The next time you book a flight, you probably will remember it, but you're going to most likely look for the cheapest fare or the best connection. That's going to be a minor consideration," said David Tyerman of Canaccord Genuity.
Tyerman said there should be no impact on WestJetunless passengers are able to switch from United to the Calgary carrier.
United is a Chicago-based carrier that is the thirdlargest U.S. airline in terms of market share, controlling about 15 per cent of the domestic market.
The airlinebriefly grounded U.S. flights on June 2, also because of "automation issues,"in a move that lasted for less than an hour.
#UnitedAirlines moves &gt; 40,000 people through Chicago airport each day. Not this day though. Pandemonium ensuring. pic.twitter.com/tRQlIFPgS7
 @nightcam
It suffered a series of computer problems in 2012 after switching to a passenger information computer system previously used by merger partner Continental Airlines.
In each case, hundreds of flights were delayed. A number of high-paying business travellers defected to other airlines and revenue dropped.
Travelers waiting in long lines outside #LAX after #UnitedAirlines grounds flights. http://t.co/cE6jFdKg7W pic.twitter.com/MGOTorhLMH
"We don't know everything behind this morning's issues yet, but today's incident underscores the sense that something is very wrong at United," said Gary Leff, co-founder of frequent-flier website MilePoint.
Shares of United Continental Holdings Inc. slid twoper cent to $53.08 USin early-morning trading.
With files from The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 13:28:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Illegal Mexican immigrant's release before murder charge defended by San Francisco sheriff</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/illegal-mexican-immigrant-s-release-before-murder-charge-defended-by-san-francisco-sheriff-1.3142560?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Illegal Mexican immigrant's release before murder charge defended by San Francisco sheriff
Accused Francisco Sanchez released into public despite 5 previous deportation orders
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 08, 2015 6:28 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 08, 2015 8:35 AM ET
Francisco Sanchez, right, is led into the courtroom by San Francisco public defender Jeff Adachi, left, and assistant district attorney Diana Garciaor, centre, for his arraignment on Tuesday. The illegal Mexican immigrant has pleaded not guilty to murder. (Michael Macor/San Francisco Chronicle via AP)
Related Stories
Obama and his immigration overhaul targeted by Republicans
San Francisco Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi has defended his office's decision to release a Mexican man who was in the U.S. illegally and is now suspected in the killing of a woman at a sightseeing pier.
Mirkarimi said that the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency should earlier have issued an arrest warrant for Francisco Sanchez.
"ICE knew that he had been deported five times," Mirkarimi said. "You would have thought he met a threshold that he required a court order or a warrant. They did not do that."
Prosecutors on Monday charged Sanchez with murder in the death of Kathryn Steinle, who was shot and killed last Wednesday as she and her father took a walk on the popular Pier 14.
Steinle's killing has brought criticism down on this liberal city because Sanchez had been deported repeatedly and was out on the streets after San Francisco officials disregarded a request from immigration authorities to keep him locked up.
San Francisco is one of dozens of cities and counties across the country that do not fully co-operate with federal immigration authorities. The city goes so far as to promote itself as a "sanctuary" for people in the country illegally.
In a jailhouse interview with a TV station, Sanchez, a 45-year-old repeat drug offender, appeared to confirm that he came to the city because of its status as a sanctuary.
A well-wisher drops off flowers at the site where 32-year-old Kathryn Steinle was killed in San Francisco. (Justin/Sullivan/Getty Images)
The case has prompted a flurry of criticism from ICE officials, politicians and commenters on social media, all of whom portrayed the slaying as a preventable tragedy.
"Most of the blame should fall squarely on the shoulders of the San Francisco sheriff, because his department had custody of him and made the choice to let him go without notifying ICE," said Jessica Vaughan, director of policy studies at the Washington-based Center for Immigration Studies, which wants tougher immigration enforcement.
Rep. Bob Goodlatte, the Virginia Republican who chairs the House judiciary committee, blamed sanctuary practices and the Obama administration, saying: "The tragic murder of Kate Steinle once again underscores the need to end these reckless policies."
Mayor Ed Lee issued a statement saying city policy was never intended to protect "repeat, serious and violent felons." He asked for federal and local agencies to review what happened.
California Attorney General Kamala Harris, a former San Francisco district attorney who is running for U.S. Senate, cautioned that when it comes to immigration, "our policy should not be informed by our collective outrage about one man's conduct."
Victim had recently moved to city
Many other San Francisco politicians stayed quiet as mourners held a vigil at Pier 14 on the downtown waterfront, where the 32-year-old Steinle was gunned down, seemingly at random. She had recently moved to San Francisco.
While many cities have scaled back cooperation with ICE, few have gone as far as San Francisco.
For more than two decades, San Francisco has been considered a sanctuary for people in the U.S. illegally.
The city's sanctuary law prohibits city employees from helping federal authorities with immigration investigations or arrests unless required by law or warrant. That said, the ordinance does not prohibit local law enforcement from informing ICE that they've arrested someone in the country illegally for a felony offence or who has prior felony convictions.
From jail, Sanchez told a KGO-TV reporter in a mix of Spanish and English that he found the gun wrapped in a T-shirt while sitting on a bench at the pier.
"So I picked it up and ... it started to fire on its own," Sanchez said, adding that he heard three shots go off.
Asked if he came to San Francisco because of its sanctuary status, he said yes.
"I only want to say that if the court wants to find me guilty, I wouldn't get mad," Sanchez said during the interview, in which he appeared confused and spoke incoherently at times.
Reaction to the case
Several high-profile Americans have reacted strongly to the case, including:
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton:"Here's a case where we've deported, we've deported, we've deported, he ends back up in our country, and I think the city made a mistake. The city made a mistake not to deport someone that the federal government strongly felt should be deported. So I have absolutely no support for a city that ignores the strong evidence that should be acted on."
Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump:"This senseless and totally preventable act of violence committed by an illegal immigrant is yet another example of why we must secure our border immediately. This is an absolutely disgraceful situation and I am the only one that can fix it. Nobody else has the guts to even talk about it."
TV commentator Bill O`Reilly:"In 1996 President Bill Clinton signed the Illegal Immigration Reform and Responsibility Act, which stipulated that local and state authorities were to co-operate with the feds in apprehending illegal aliens, especially criminals  In 2010, the Obama administration openly said it would not punish cities that refuse to obey the 1996 law. So here's the deal. The mayor and city supervisors of San Francisco are directly responsible for the death of Kate Steinle and the Obama administration is complicit."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 13:09:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece PM asks for 3rd bailout in race against the clock</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greece-crisis-pm-alexis-tsipras-asks-for-3rd-bailout-1.3142570?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>How Greece moves forward after the No vote
As Thursday's deadline loomed, the government sought to reassure its European creditors that it would enact tax and pension reforms quickly in exchange for loans from Europe's bailout fund, the European Stability Mechanism.
In a formal request that was filled with vague promises but short on details, the Greek government pledged to "immediately implement a set of measures as early as the beginning of next week"  but did not specify what these were.
After months of fruitless negotiations with the Greek government, the skeptical eurozone creditor states have said they want to see a detailed, cost-accounted plan of the reforms by Thursday. That is meant to give enough time to review the plan before all 28 leaders of the full European Union meet on Sunday in what has been termed as Greece's last chance to stay in the euro.
But Greece's major creditors were hardly in lock-step over what path to take in dealing with the struggling but defiant EU member nation.
IMF chief Christine Lagarde reiterated Wednesday that Greece's massive debt would need restructuring, something that Germany  Greece's largest European lender  has resisted.
Speaking in Washington, Lagarde said Greece needed to continue cost-cutting reforms, but added: "The other leg is debt restructuring, which we believe is needed ... for debt sustainability."
"It well may be that the numbers may have to be revisited, but our analysis has not changed," she said of the need for granting Greece better repayment terms.
Members of the Europe of Freedom and Democracy Group show placards at their desks during Tsipras's speech Wednesday. (Patrick Seeger/EPA)
U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew added pressure on the European lenders, arguing debt relief was needed for a deal  and describing a Greek euro-exit as a "geopolitical mistake."
"I don't think any prime minister of Greece could sell all the additional fiscal measures, plus the structural reforms that are needed without some sense of what the debt sustainability looks like," he said in Washington.
Earlier Wednesday, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said his country was seeking a deal that would bring a definitive end to his country's financial crisis. Greece has had two bailouts from its European partners and the International Monetary Fund since May 2010, totalling 240 billion euros ($338 billion Cdn).
"We need to ensure the medium-term funding of our country with a development and growth program," Tsipras told lawmakers at the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France.
Applause rose from left-wing lawmakers in the turbulent chamber when Tsipras said aid to Greece has only helped banks, not ordinary Greeks, as some held up Nosigns to back Greek voters' rejection of more austerity.
People line up Wednesday in Athens at the main gate of the national bank of Greece as they wait to withdraw a maximum weekly amount of 120 euros ($134 US). (Petr David Josek/The Associated Press)
Tsipras insisted he has "no hidden agenda" to drive Greece out of the euro and that last Sunday's referendum in which Greeks roundly rejected more belt-tightening reforms does not mean a break with Europe.
The head of a conservative group in the parliament, Belgium's Guy Verhofstadt, said he was "furious" at Tsipras' failure to spell out specifics of his reform plans.
Tsipras said Greece's troubles predated his arrival in office in January and condemned the "austerity experiment" his country has endured over the past five years that he blames for spiraling unemployment and poverty.
"We demand an agreement with our neighbours, but one that gives us a sign that we are on a long-lasting basis exiting from the crisis  which will demonstrate to us that there is light at the end of the tunnel," he said.
In Greece, meanwhile, people already struggling with eight days of shuttered banks and limits on money withdrawals learned the finance ministry was extending the closures until next Monday. Greeks cannot take out more than 60 euros (roughly $84 Cdn) a day from ATMs and are unable to send money abroad, including to pay bills or to stock their businesses, without special permission.
The head of France's central bank said he feared the "collapse" of the Greek economy and "chaos" if Greece doesn't strike a deal by Sunday.
In unusually strong language, Christian Noyer told Europe-1 radio he predicted "riots" in Greece if no deal is reached. He also indicated the European Central Bank would effectively pull the plug on its emergency liquidity measures for Greek banks if no deal is struck.
Highlighting the rising anger with Tsipras, European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker had a stark warning for Greece after Tuesday's eurozone summit.
"We have a Grexit scenario, prepared in detail," he said, apparently referring to the situation in which Greece would be forced out of the currency union.
Follow the CBC News live blog for breaking news on the future of Greece:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
