<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 11:50:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek government's proposal submitted to eurogroup ahead of deadline</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greece-crisis-eurogroup-receives-new-proposals-1.3144321?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>How Greece moves forward after the No vote
While creditors arewaiting to see whether Greece will offer the full range of economic measures they have asked for, Donald Tusk, who chairs the EU summits, indicated earlier in the day that European officials would make an effort to address Greece's key request for debt relief.
"The realistic proposal from Greece will have to be matched by an equally realistic proposal on debt sustainability from the creditors. Only then will we have a win-win situation," Tusk said.
Greece has long argued its debt is too high to be paid back and that the country requires some form of debt relief. The International Monetary Fund agrees with the premise, but key European states like Germany have resisted the idea.
On Thursday, German Finance Minister WolfgangSchaeublesaid the possibility of some kind of debt relief would be discussed over coming days, though he cautioned it may not provide much help.
Tsipras has stretched his EU partners' patience to the limit with months of missteps and contradictory moves and now, having just days to save his country from ruin, is finding his list of allies is short. (Thanassis Stavrakis/Associated Press)
"The room formanoeuvre through debtreprofilingor restructuring is very small," he said.
Making Greece's debt more sustainable would likely involve lowering the interest rates and extending the repayment dates on its bailout loans. Germany and many other European countries rule out an outright debt cut, arguing it would be illegal under European treaties.
The comments on Thursday boosted market confidence that a compromise will be found. TheStoxx50 index of top European shares was up 2.4 per cent in late afternoon trading.
Prime Minister AlexisTsiprasmet with finance ministry officials and was holding a cabinet meeting earlier in the day to finalize his country's plan, a day after his government requested a new three-year aid program from Europe's bailout fund and promised to immediately enact reforms, including to taxes and pensions, in return.
The last-minute negotiations come as Greece's financial system teeters on the brink of collapse. It has imposed restrictions on banking transactions since June 29, limiting cash withdrawals to 60euros($83 Canadian) per day to stanch a bank run. Banks and the stock market have been shut for just as long.
'Everyone's living off a drip'
The closures, which have been extended through Monday, have led to daily lines at ATM machines and have hammered businesses. Payments abroad have been banned without special permission.
"Can you see anybody in the shop? Nobody's coming in, because everyone's living off a drip," saidMagdaPetridi, a fortune teller who runs a shop selling good luck charms, aromatic oils and trinkets. "Until a month ago business was going pretty well."
Pensioners without bank cards have been particularly hard hit as they have struggled to access their accounts. Some branches have been opened so the elderly and unemployed without bank cards can withdraw a maximum weekly sum of 120euroseach. Hundreds lined up outside banks Thursday morning, many facing hours-long waits in the heat.
A pensioner reacts as she tries to enter a National Bank branch to receive part of her pension at the city of Iraklio in the island of Crete, Greece. (Stefanos Rapanis/Reuters)
Meanwhile, manyATMshad a shortage of 20euronotes, effectively reducing the daily withdrawal limit to 50euros about $70 Canadian.
IfTsiprasdoes not get a deal, Greece faces an almost inevitable collapse of the banking system, which would be the first step for the country to fall out of theeuro.
"I believe he will have to get an agreement. We will pay dearly for it, but at least we'll get an agreement," said mechanicPantelisNiarchos, walking down the street in central Athens.
After months of fruitless negotiations withTsipras' government, elected in January on promises to repeal bailout austerity, the skepticaleurozonecreditor states have said they want to see a detailed, cost-accounted plan of the reforms.
Greece's financial institutions have been kept afloat so far by emergency liquidity assistance from the European Central Bank. But the ECB has not increased the amount in days, leaving the lenders in a stranglehold despite capital controls.
German ECB governing council member JensWeidmannargued Greek banks should not get more emergency credit from the central bank unless a bailout deal is struck.
He said it was up toeurozonegovernments and Greek leaders themselves to rescue Greece.
The central bank"has no mandate to safeguard the solvency of banks and governments," he said in a speech.
The ECB capped emergency credit to Greek banks amid doubt whether the country will win further rescue loans from other countries. The banks closed and limited ATM withdrawals because they had no other way to replace deposits.
Weidmannsaid he welcomed the fact that central bank credit "is no longer being used to finance capital flight caused by the Greek government."
Follow the CBC News live blog for breaking news on the future of Greece:
With files from Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:00:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hackers steal 21 million U.S. social security numbers</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/hackers-steal-21-million-u-s-social-security-numbers-1.3145510?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Hackers steal 21 million U.S. social security numbers
Criminal, financial, health and employment information also taken
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 09, 2015 5:00 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 5:00 PM ET
The U.S. Office of Personnel Management said hackers got hold of the user names and passwords that prospective employees used to fill out their background investigation forms, as well as the contents of interviews conducted as part of those investigations. (Kacper Pempel/Reuters)
Related Stories
U.S. Army takes down website after hack claimed by Syrian Electronic Army
Hackers stole Social Security numbers from more than 21 million people and snatched other sensitive information in a recent breach of U.S. government computer systems, the Obama administration said Thursday.
The U.S. Office of Personnel Management said Thursday that more than 19 million who applied for background investigations had their information compromised, as well as nearly 2 million of their family members  like spouses or cohabitants  who never applied for a background check.
2nd data breach exposed personal details of U.S. military and intelligence staff
OPM Director Katherine Archuleta said that, in addition to Social Security numbers, hackers took information about people's criminal, financial, health, employment and residency histories, as well as information about their families and acquaintances. She said hackers got hold of the user names and passwords that prospective employees used to fill out their background investigation forms, as well as the contents of interviews conducted as part of those investigations.
Archuleta said there was no evidence that payroll records were stolen. The administration also said there were no indications that the hackers have used the data they stole.
More calls for resignations due to hacks
House Oversight and Government Reform Committee Chairman Jason Chaffetz, a Utah Republican, repeated his call Thursday for Archuleta and her chief information officer to resign immediately.
"Their negligence has now put the personal and sensitive information of 21.5 million Americans into the hands of our adversaries," Chaffetz said in a statement. "Such incompetence is inexcusable."
Archuleta said she would not be resigning in the wake of the breaches. "I am committed to the work that I am doing," she said in a conference call with reporters Thursday.
Investigators previously told The Associated Press that the U.S. government was increasingly confident that China's government, and not criminal hackers, was responsible for the extraordinary theft of personal information. China has publicly denied involvement in the break-in.
The administration acknowledged earlier this month that hackers stole the personnel files and background investigations of current and former civilian, intelligence and military employees, contractors and even job applicants. Initially, the U.S. said the stolen data included Social Security numbers, birth dates, job actions and other private information for 4.2 million workers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 08:27:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina governor signs bill for removal of Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/confederate-flag-removal-bill-signed-by-south-carolina-governor-1.3144309?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate flag removal bill signed by South Carolina governor
Flag was raised on statehouse grounds 50 years ago in protest of civil rights movement
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 09, 2015 1:27 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 4:49 PM ET
The Confederate flag has flown on the state capitol grounds in South Carolina since the height of the civil rights movement. It is scheduled to come down Friday. (Mladen Antonov/Getty Images)
Related Stories
Beyonce and Jay Z not buying rights to Confederate flag, despite reports
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley has signed a bill to take down the Confederate flag from the state's capitol grounds. The flag is scheduled to come down at 10 a.m. local time Friday.
"Today I am very proud to say that it is a great day in South Carolina," Haley said to a jubilant crowdjust before signing.
Haley said the flag will be brought down with dignity.
The signing comes after theSouth Carolina House approved thebill to take down the Confederate flag from the capitol grounds, which was a stunning reversal in a state that was the first to leave the Union in 1860 and raised the flag again at its Statehouse more than 50 years ago to protest the civil rights movement.
The move early Thursday came after more than 13 hours of passionate and contentious debate, and just weeks after the fatal shootings of nine black church members, including a state senator, at a Bible study in Charleston.
"South Carolina can remove the stain from our lives," said 64-year-old Rep. Joe Neal, a black Democrat first elected in 1992. "I never thought in my lifetime I would see this."
ANALYSIS| Confederate flag belongs only in a museum
The House approved the Senate bill by a two-thirds margin.
Haley herself reversed her position on the flag, saying the pain, grief and grace of the families of the victims in the shooting at Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church caused her to realize that while some conservative whites saw the Confederate flag as a symbol of pride in their Southern ancestors, most of the blacks who make up a third of the state's population see it as a dark reminder of a racist past.
The man charged in the shooting, Dylann Roof, brought that view home, telling survivors of the attack that he killed blacks because they were raping white women and taking over the country, according to witnesses. Roof also reportedly took photographs of himself holding the Confederate flag.
Frustration with Republicans
A group of Republicans had mounted opposition to immediately removing the flag, but at each turn, they were beaten back by a slightly larger, bipartisan group of legislators who believed there must be no delay.
As House members deliberated well into the night, there were tears of anger and shared memories of Civil War ancestors. Black Democrats, frustrated at being asked to show grace to Civil War soldiers as the debate wore on, warned the state was embarrassing itself.
The closest vote in the GOP-controlled body came on an amendment to place the state flag beside the monument to Confederate soldiers at the front of the Statehouse. But it failed 60-60.
Changing the Senate bill could have meant it would take weeks or even months to remove the flag, perhaps blunting momentum that has grown since the church massacre.
Republican Rep. Jenny Horne reminded her colleagues she was a descendent of Confederate President Jefferson Davis, and scolded fellow members of her party for stalling the debate with dozens of amendments.
She cried as she remembered the funeral of her slain colleague state Sen. Clementa Pinckney, the pastor of Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church, who was gunned down as his wife and daughter locked themselves in an office.
"For the widow of Sen. Pinckney and his two young daughters, that would be adding insult to injury and I will not be a part of it!" she screamed into a microphone.
She said later during a break she didn't intend to speak but got frustrated with fellow Republicans.
'New vestige of racism'
House Minority Leader Todd Rutherford said Democrats were united behind the Senate bill, which would send the flag to the state's Confederate Relic Room  near the resting place for the final rebel flag that flew over the Statehouse dome until it was taken down in 2000.
Democrats didn't want any new flag going up because it "will be the new vestige of racism," Rutherford said.
Other Democrats suggested any delay would let Ku Klux Klan members planning a rally July 18 a chance to dance around the Confederate flag.
"You don't have to listen to me. But there are a whole lot of people outside this chamber watching," Rep. Gilda Cobb-Hunter said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:01:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canadian diplomat's teenager set to appeal denial of bail in Florida</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/marc-wabafiyebazu-son-of-diplomat-roxanne-dube-set-to-appeal-denial-of-bail-in-florida-1.3145374?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Marc Wabafiyebazu, son of diplomat Roxanne Dube, set to appeal denial of bail in Florida
15-year-old charged in Florida double killing that left brother dead
ByColin Perkel, The Canadian Press Posted: Jul 09, 2015 4:01 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 4:24 PM ET
Marc Wabafiyebazu, 15, son of a Canadian diplomat, plans to appeal his denial of bail after being charged in the March 30 drug-related South Florida shootout that killed his older brother and another youth. (Al Diaz/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Diplomat mom hopes to take Canadian teen home as she awaits Miami bail decision
A Canadian diplomat's teenage son charged in a double killing inFlorida that left his older brother dead is now expected to be triedin November at the earliest.
In the interim, Marc Wabafiyebazu, 15, of Ottawa, is getting setto appeal a Miami judge's ruling that denied him bail pending hismurder trial.
Wabafiyebazu, the son of Canada's consul general to Miami,Roxanne Dube, is locked up in a 1,300-bed adult detention centre,where most contact visits are barred and where he is the youngestinmate.
'Hanging in there'
"He's hanging in there as best as can be expected under theseunfortunate circumstances," said lawyer Curt Obront, who saw himthis week.
Now that the judge's formally signed no-bail order has beenreceived, Obront said he would be "appealing imminently."
Wabafiyebazu was arrested March 30 outside an apartment in whichhis 18-year-old brother Jean Wabafiyebazu and another man, JoshuaWright, 17, were shot dead. Two other men, including an alleged drugdealer, were injured.
Police allege the younger sibling confessed that he and hisbrother had gone to rip off the dealer, but the armed robbery hadgone sour.
The defence has argued that the testimony of a rookie officer,who reported the purported confession, was "absurd" and waspossibly the result of his desire to get in on a big case.
Tentative trial date set
A spokesman for the Miami-Dade state attorney's office said thisweek that a tentative trial date has been set for Nov. 2.Prosecution and lawyers were also expected to update the court ontheir progress at a status hearing in September.
Roxanne Dube, mother of Marc Wabafiyebazu, 15, sits in a Miami juvenile court earlier this year. (Walter Michot/ Associated Press)
Wabafiyebazu haspreviously pleaded not guilty.
While the prosecution does not allege Wabafiyebazu shot or eventhreatened anyone, Florida law allows for the felony murder chargeif he was part of the armed robbery that resulted in the killings.
Surveillance video shows that he remained outside until he heard thedeadly gun shots and ran inside to see what happened.
Still, a grand jury indicted him as an adult, meaning he couldface life behind bars if convicted.
At the bail hearing in May, Circuit Judge Teresa Pooler, who isan elected official, said granting him interim release was too riskygiven the possibility he could flee the United States and that shecouldn't rely on Dube to keep proper tabs on him.
Wabafiyebazu also faces an armed robbery charge on which thefelony murder charge is based.
Two other men charged in the killings, alleged drug dealerAnthony Rodriguez, 19, and Johann Ruiz-Perez, 21, have also pleadednot guilty to felony murder charges in the case. They are due for astatus hearing later this month.
Dube, who sees him twice a week through glass and is allowed acontact visit once a month, refused to comment publicly.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 19:19:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Royal Family photos released from Princess Charlotte's christening</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/photos/royal-family-photos-released-from-princess-charlotte-s-christening-1.3138990?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Royal Family photos released from Princess Charlotte's christening
Semi-private family affair celebrates newest member of the House of Windsor
Stay Connected with CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:00:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Climate change is killing off bumblebees: study</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/climate-change-is-killing-off-bumblebees-study-1.3145014?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Sea life relocating fast in response to climate change
Crushed in 'climate vise'
Bumblebees' lack of aptitude to cope withclimate change could put them at risk of extinction if humans don't take action, the researchers suggest. Some species, such as North America's rusty-patched bumblebee, have already gone nearly extinct.
"We already know that extreme heat in southern Europe, for example, has wiped out local populations of some bumblebee species," said Kerr, a biology professor and research chair in macroecology at the University of Ottawa. "In this paper, we show that this mechanism may be operating across two continents to crush bumblebee species in a kind of climate vise."
The paper shows that the bees' decline in the south and their inability to move north 'may be operating across two continents to crush bumblebee species in a kind of climate vise,' says lead author Jeremy Kerr of the University of Ottawa. (Antoine Morin)
Kerr and his co-authors are particularly concerned that bumblebees are being squeezed into smaller and smaller geographic areas while their populations are also taking a hit from threats such as habitat loss and pesticides  factors that may kill off individual bees and hives, but don't seem to affect the overall geographic range of the whole population.
"We are essentially hitting them with everything we have in our global change arsenal."
Bee researchers raise more warning flags about neonicotinoid pesticides
Better pollinators than otherbees
The loss of bumblebees is a problem because we rely heavily on bees to pollinate our crops, said Alana Pindar, a postdoctoral researcher at the University of Guelphin Ontario. Sheco-authored the paper and took part in the newsconference, which also included co-authors from the University of Calgary and York University in Toronto.
Researchers suggest that humans may be able to help save bumblebees by physically moving them further north. (Jeremy T. Kerr)
Wild bees are actually better pollinators than honeybees , and bumblebees are better pollinators than other wild bees because they're active for most of the year, from spring until fall, and can therefore pollinate a huge range of plants. Many other bee species that typically only pollinate a few species of plants for a few weeks of the year.
Bees don't deal well with warmer temperatures, Pindar said, because they evolved in cooler places, away from the tropics.
The researchers aren't sure why the bees aren't moving north, but they believeit's because they're unable to establish new populations fast enough. One bumblebee species that has the rare ability to expand northward is Europe's buff-tailed bumblebee, which builds unusually large colonies, says Kerr.
'Assisted migration'
So what can be done to save the bees? One possibility that the researchers suggest is for humans to physically move some bees north.
David Goulson, professor of biology at the University of Sussex, who was not involved in the research, said he is not convinced that would work.
This buff-tailed bumblebee in Nottingham, England, is visiting catmint flowers. Wild bees are known to be better pollinators than honeybees, and bumblebees are better pollinators than other wild bees. (Jeremy T. Kerr)
"Bumblebees are pretty mobile creatures," he said in a statement. "I think it is likely that they could move northwards on their own if suitable habitat were available to move in to."
Nathalie Pettorelli, a research fellow with the Zoological Society of London, and who was not involved in the research, said in order to save the bees, scientists will need to figure out why they can't move north.
"Without this knowledge, efficient mitigation strategies are difficult to identify," she said in a statement.
For now, the researchers behind the study suggest focusing on conservation in areas hit by climate change, but making sure bees have the habitats they need to survive. This could involve:
Preserving natural areas in higher-altitude or cooler "microclimates."
Planting gardens with bee-friendly plants such as raspberries.
Ensuring there are places left for wildflowers and bee nesting areas at the edge of farmers' fields.
"Above all," Kerr said, "we must reduce greenhouse gas pollution and come to grips convincingly with the climate change threat."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:41:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN announces humanitarian pause in Yemen conflict</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/un-announces-humanitarian-pause-in-yemen-conflict-1.3145311?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>UN announces weeklong humanitarian pause in Yemen conflict
Highest-level humanitarian emergency has left millions desperate for food, water, medicine
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 09, 2015 3:41 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 6:03 PM ET
A youth looks at houses destroyed by a Saudi-led airstrike in Sanaa, Yemen, Friday, July 3, 2015. The U.N. hopes the temporary halt in the fighting will lead to a lasting ceasefire. (Hani Mohammed/Associated Press)
Related Stories
U.S sends warships towards Yemen amid concerns about Iranian weapons
The United Nations on Thursday announced an "unconditional humanitarian pause" in Yemen's conflict starting at midnight local time Friday, with the goal of stopping the violence so that desperately needed supplies can be delivered to more than 21 million people in the Arab world's poorest country.
Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon was assured that both Yemen's exiled President Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi and Shiite Houthi rebels support halting fighting through the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, which ends July 17, UNspokesman Stphane Dujarric said. Ban's spokesman said Hadi informed the Saudi-led coalition carrying out airstrikes against the rebels that he backs a humanitarian pause in order "to ensure their support and collaboration."
Hadi had written to Ban with a series of conditions before a humanitarian pause, including a Houthi withdrawal first from the governorates of Aden, Taiz, Marib and Shabwa and the release of the minister of defence. UN diplomats and officials said pressure was put on Hadi to drop the conditions. Dujarric said he had communicated to Ban his acceptance of the pause.
"We have the expressions necessary from all parties to announce the start of this pause on Friday, July 10," Dujarric said.
But at the same time, UNofficials hope that those assurances will result in solid commitments and an actual cease-fire.
"Ultimately what we want is to be absolutely certain that the fighting stops," UNdeputy spokesman Farhan Haq told The Associated Press.
Highest-level humanitarian emergency
More than 3,000 people have been killed since March, when the Saudi-led and U.S.-backed coalition began launching airstrikes against the rebels who have seized control of the capital and other cities since September.
The coalition has imposed a near-complete air and sea blockade in Yemen, though there have been controlled openings in the air blockade recently. The airstrikes continued Thursday in the southern cities of Aden and Lahj.
The United Nations declared its highest-level humanitarian emergency in Yemen on July 1, the week after the UNenvoy for Yemen, Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed, said the country is "one step" from famine.
Dujarric said humanitarian agencies must be given unhindered access to all parts of the country.
According to the UNhumanitarian office, over 21 million Yemenis are in need of aid, representing 80 per cent of the population, and millions are close to famine.
Dujarric said if humanitarian agencies get access, they plan to stockpile supplies throughout the country.
Ahmed, the UNenvoy, has been trying, so far unsuccessfully, to get the parties in Yemen to end the conflict.
Dujarric said Ahmed is continuing to engage with all parties "to take confidence-building steps towards a durable cease-fire" leading to a withdrawal of forces, release of political prisoners and a resumption of a political process for a democratic transition.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:41:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis ducks into Burger King to don his vestments before mass in Bolivia</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/pope-francis-ducks-into-burger-king-for-quick-costume-change-1.3145380?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis ducks into Burger King for quick costume change
Pope uses fast food joint to change into his vestments before conducting mass in Santa Cruz
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 09, 2015 4:41 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 4:54 PM ET
Pope Francis waves from his popemobile as he arrives to celebrate mass at Christ the Redeemer square in Santa Cruz, Bolivia. Moments earlier, he had ducked into a local branch of Burger King to change into his vestments. (Eduardo Verdugo/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Can Pope Francis's 'street cred' shift the climate change debate?
Burger King has long been providing quick meals, but on Thursday one of the fast food chain's outlets in Boliviawas used for aquick costumechangeby none other than Pope Francis.
With hundreds of thousands of Catholic faithful waiting, Pope Francis needed a place to don his vestments to celebrate mass at Christ the Redeemer square in Santa Cruz. He had just spent more than 30 minutes in his popemobile, waving to the thousands of people who linedthe streets as he arrivedin the square for the service.
Enter the restaurant known for Whoppers and fries.
The famously unpretentious Pope used the El Cristobranch of thefast food joint, which was closed for the morning for the papal visit, before walking to the nearby altar and beginning the mass.
Alfredo Troche, manager of the Burger King, said the papal entourage had approached the restaurant and "asked for help because this was an appropriate place and we had closed."
Minutes later, during his homily, Francis blasted consumerism. He said that by materialistic logic, everything becomes an object that can be consumed and negotiated.
The company wasted no time in letting the world knowof the papal visit. Even before mass had ended, the restaurant put a post on Facebookand on the Burger King Bolivia Twitter feedthanking the Pope "for choosing the BK restaurant as your sacristy."
Bienvenido Papa Francisco, gracias por elegir el restaurante BK EL Cristo como tu Sacrista. Burger King Bolivia... http://t.co/pNBojEcG5z
 @BurgerKing_Bol
It also included an advertisement-like image showing the Pope beneath a Burger King logo and the words: "There are visits that don't just bring joy to your spiritbut also feed it."
Burger King Bolivia posted a tweet thanking the Pope for using the El Cristo branch of Burger King as his sacristy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:42:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British government tells tourists to leave Tunisia over risk of attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/tourists-in-tunisia-should-leave-due-to-attack-threat-u-k-says-1.3145277?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tourists in Tunisia should leave due to attack threat, U.K. says
Decision is a major blow to North African country's tourist industry
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 09, 2015 3:42 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 3:42 PM ET
A trumpet was played near a plaque honouring the victims killed in an attack on a beach in the popular tourist resort of al-Sousse, Tunisia. The U.K. is now urging all British travellers without an 'essential need to remain' to leave the North African country. (Mohamed Messaram/EPA)
Related Stories
Canada Travel Advisory: Tunisia
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
The British government is advising against all but essential travel to Tunisia, sayingthey believe a"further terrorist attack is highly likely."
The Foreign Office said it is advising against all but essential travel to the North African country. It said that British tourists in Tunisia should contact their travel agents, who will arrange flights to bring them home. Independent travellers were advised to return on scheduled commercial flights.
Thirty-eight tourists, 30 of them British, were killed on June 26 when a gunman stormed the Tunisian beach resort of Sousse. In March, 22 people died in an attack at the National Bardo Museum outside Tunis.
The Foreign Office said it did not have specific information about an imminent attack.
"On balance, we do not believe the mitigation measures in place provide adequate protection for British tourists in Tunisia at the present time and we have therefore changed our travel advice accordingly," it said in a statement.
Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said officials "have not taken this decision lightly but our first priority will always be the safety of our citizens."
Travel company Thomas Cook said it would be bringing customers back on its 10 scheduled flights this weekend, and use other airlines if needed. Spokesman Ian Benjafield said the company would get people home "whatever way we can."
Tour firms Thomas Cook, Thomson and First Choice all cancelled trips to Tunisia through Oct. 31.
The U.K. decision is a major blow to Tunisia's tourist industry. Hundreds of thousands of British tourists visit Tunisia each year. Many Britons left after the Sousse attack, but some 3,000 are still in Tunisia.
The Canadian government has regional travel advisories in place urging people to avoid visiting several areas.
Germany's Foreign Ministry said it was observing the situation very closely and adjusting travel advice regularly.
As of now, however, there was no immediate change to its travel advice last updated five days ago. Two Germans were killed in the Sousse attack.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:31:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly tornado near Venice captured on cellphone</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/tornado-near-venice-kills-1-with-3-others-in-grave-condition-1.3144917?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tornado near Venice kills 1, with 3 others in grave condition
Deceased was reportedly driving a vehicle which was thrown in the air
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 09, 2015 12:31 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 12:47 PM ET
CAUGHT ON TAPE: Tornado hits region near Venice, Italy 2:19
A tornado swept through an area near Venice on Wednesday evening, killing at least one and injuring some 30 people, three of whom were said to be in a grave condition.
Locals in the municipalities of Mira and Dolo in the Veneto region captured the moment the tornado hit the area with their mobile phones, filming flames and debris flying in the air above rooftops.
According to local media reports the victim was an elderly person who has not yet been identified. The victim was driving a vehicle which was raised in the air by the tornado and then slammed to the ground, local media reported.
Three people were said to be seriously injured by the tornado while other 27 had lighter injuries.
Several homes and other buildings were badly damaged by the tornado, with many locals forced to spend the night with family and friends in nearby areas.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:43:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. drone strike kills top ISIS commander in Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/shahidullah-shahid-isis-commander-in-afghanistan-killed-by-u-s-drone-strike-1.3144596?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Shahidullah Shahid, ISIS commander in Afghanistan, killed by U.S. drone strike
5 other militants also killed, Afghan intelligence says
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 09, 2015 9:43 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 11:03 AM ET
In this Saturday, Oct. 5, 2013 photo, Shahidullah Shahid, right, arrives with his bodyguard for an interview at an undisclosed location in Pakistani tribal area of Waziristan along Afghanistan border. (Ishtiaq Mahsud/Associated Press)
The Afghan intelligence agency on Thursday said a third top Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) commander in Afghanistan was killed in a U.S. drone strike in the country's east this week.
Shahidullah Shahid, a former member of the Pakistani Taliban who defected to ISIS and was operating in Afghanistan, was killed along with five militants on Tuesday, an official said.
"He wanted to expand [ISIS's] operation in the country and with his death, it will have an impact on their activities," Hasib Sediqi, spokesman for the Afghanistan National Directorate of Security (NDS), told Reuters.
Shahid was killed in the same strike that killed ISIS's No. 2 in Afghanistan Gul Zaman, along with 49 militants in the eastern Achin district of Nangarhar province where Islamic State militants have recently gained ground after pushing out the Taliban. One other commander was also killed.
Bordering lawless areas inside Pakistan, Nangarhar is one of the provinces where ISIS militants are most active.
Islamic State loyalists, mostly former Taliban disillusioned by the movement's unsuccessful bid to return to power in Kabul, are often accompanied by dozens of foreigners, hoisting black flags in several districts in the province.
A small but increasing number of mostly ex-Taliban militants are pledging allegiance to ISIS in Afghanistan, making them a target of deadly strikes there by the U.S. unmanned aircraft.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:17:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Londoners face travel chaos as strike shuts down subways</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/london-underground-strike-causes-travel-chaos-for-commuters-1.3144332?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>London Underground strike causes travel chaos for commuters
PM Cameron's office calls strike 'unacceptable and unjustified'
CBC News Posted: Jul 09, 2015 5:17 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 1:02 PM ET
RAW: Londoners feel impact of subway strike 1:29
Related Stories
London design firm wants to turn abandoned Tube lines into cycle paths
Millions of Londoners faced misery as they tried to get to work on Thursday as a 24-hour strike by staff and drivers brought the British capital's underground rail network to a complete halt.
London Underground bosses said no trains would run all day on the "Tube", as the world's oldest underground passenger railway is known, because of the stoppage which follows a dispute over plans for new night services.
Commuters who usually use the underground network were forced to walk, cycle, battle to find taxis, or cram onto crowded buses while many simply stayed at home.
London design firm wants to turn abandoned Tube lines into cycle paths
Transport bosses said they had put on extra river boat services and 200 more buses to cope, and marshals were positioned at rail stations to help manage extra demand as long queues snaked down nearby streets.
"There are plenty of industries which have to work nights and London is a 24/7 city," said Mark Crosby, waiting for a bus at Epping station in northeast London. "Everyone has a right to their own view, but I don't think they should have gone on strike."
Members of four rail unions representing staff from managers to drivers have joined the walkout, unhappy with the pay and terms offered by London Underground (LU) to implement a 24-hour service at weekends on some lines which is due to begin in September.
'Stop the misery'
"They should stop playing games and start talking to us in good faith to get a sensible solution to this dispute," said Manuel Cortes, leader of the TSSA union. "It is time to end the blame game and agree a solution which keeps London moving."
London Underground has said it has hired an extra 137 night drivers, offered a fair pay deal and said most staff would be unaffected by the changes while no one would have to work more hours.
"A night time Tube service is something Londoners and businesses have been requesting for many years," said Steve Griffiths, London Underground's Chief Operating Officer, accusing the unions of failing to engage in negotiations.
London Mayor Boris Johnson said the action was political and accused the unions of having no interest in doing a deal. He told BBC radio that union leaders should "cut the cackle, stop the misery for Londoners and allow the Tube workforce to get on with their job".
A spokeswoman for Prime Minister David Cameron said on Wednesday the strike was "unacceptable and unjustified."
The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:15:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Joni Mitchell's friend remains in charge of singer's medical care, judge decides</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/joni-mitchell-s-friend-remains-in-charge-of-singer-s-medical-care-judge-decides-1.3144539?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Joni Mitchell's friend remains in charge of singer's medical care, judge decides
Both Sides Now singer, 71, recovering at home after suffering an aneurysm in March
ByAnthony McCartney, The Associated Press Posted: Jul 09, 2015 9:15 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 9:15 AM ET
Canadian music icon Joni Mitchell stands in front of her artwork the Mendel Art Gallery in Saskatoon in 2000. A judge ruled Wednesday that Mitchell's good friend could continue to make medical decisions on behalf of the folk legend.  (Glen Berger/Canadian Press)
Related Stories
The 10 Joni Mitchell songs everyone should know
A judge on Wednesday praised Joni Mitchell's longtime friend for helping the singer-songwriter recover from an aneurysm and ruled that she should continue to make medical decisions for the musician.
Superior Court Judge David Cunningham III said Leslie Morris should remain Mitchell's conservator, with the authority to oversee medical care for the eight-time Grammy winner.
Joni Mitchell, legendary Canadian singer, suffered 'minor medical emergency,' says friend
Morris has been acting in that capacity since May, when Mitchell was recovering in a hospital from an aneurysm in late March that rendered her unable to speak for some time. The singer has since returned to her Los Angeles home and regained her speech.
Mitchell, 71, is expected to make a full recovery, a court-appointed attorney wrote in a filing Tuesday.
Cunningham was impressed with Mitchell's progress and said the conservatorship may not be needed for much longer. Morris does not have any control over Mitchell's finances, and the singer also retains her ability to vote, the judge ruled.
Morris and her attorney, Alan Watenmaker, declined to comment after Wednesday's hearing.
In addition to winning multiple Grammy Awards, Mitchell was inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in 1997.
Era-defining music
She started her career in her native Canada before moving to Southern California, where she became part of the flourishing folk scene in the late 1960s. Her second album, Clouds,was a breakthrough with such songs as Both Sides Nowand Chelsea Morning,winning Mitchell the Grammy for best folk performance.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:42:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Signal lost from Canadian barge adrift in Arctic Ocean</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/north/signal-lost-from-ntcl-barge-adrift-in-arctic-ocean-since-last-year-1.3144429?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Signal lost from NTCL barge adrift in Arctic Ocean since last year
Barge was off Russia's coast in March
CBC News Posted: Jul 09, 2015 6:42 AM CT Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 6:42 AM CT
This photo of the NTCL barge adrift northwest of Alaska's Prudhoe Bay was taken on Oct. 31, 2014. (ERA Aviation)
Related Stories
Drifting NTCL barge will likely spend winter in Beaufort Sea ice
The U.S. Coast Guard says it's no longer tracking a Canadian barge that went adrift in the Beaufort Sea last year, after aGPS beacon dropped on board last fall stopped transmitting.
In March, a tracking device aboard the barge had shown it had travelled about 800 km and was about 42 kilometres away from Russia. The signal from from the tracking device was lost in May. (Submitted by Marine Exchange of Alaska)
The Northern Transportation Company Limitedbarge broke away from its towboat in October 2014 as it was returning to Tuktoyaktuk, N.W.T., after delivering supplies to a remote site along the Canadian coastline. It is unloaded, although it was carrying 3,500 litres of light diesel in its fuel tanks.
As it drifted west in the fall, along Alaska's coast,iteventually became trapped in ice. The U.S. Coast Guard dropped the GPS beacon on the barge to help track it.
In March, thelocator beacon indicated the barge was off Russia'sSiberian coast, but the U.S. Coast Guard said the signal was getting weak.Thebeacon stopped transmitting in May.
NTCLhad saidit intendedto retrievethe barge this month.
The company has not returned calls from CBC Newsfor comment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:11:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Coffins pass through Sarajevo streets as Srebrenica massacre anniversary nears</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/bosnia-muslims-mourn-newly-identified-vicims-of-srebrenica-massacre-1.3144374?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Bosnia Muslims mourn newly identified vicims of Srebrenica massacre
About 8,000 were killed on July 11, 1995
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 09, 2015 7:11 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 09, 2015 7:19 AM ET
Bosnian Muslim women reacts as they touch a truck carrying 136 coffins of newly identified victims of the 1995 Srebrenica massacre in the town of Visoko, near Sarajevo, on Thursday.   (Dimitar Dilkoff/AFP/Getty Images)
Related Stories
Radovan Karadzic denies Bosnian war crimes role
Thousands lined Sarajevo's main street on Thursday as a huge truck bearing 136 coffins passed on its way to Srebrenica, where newly identified victims of Europe's worst massacre since World War II will be buried on the 20th anniversary of the crime.
As the truck covered with a huge Bosnian flag and with hundreds of flowers tucked into the canvas rolled down the street covered with white rose petals, the sobbing of mothers, sisters and wives of the victims broke the silence.
It stopped in front of Bosnia's presidency where the weeping crowd tucked more flowers into the canvas or simply approached it to touch it or caress the canvas that was hiding the remains of the victims found in mass graves and identified through DNA analysis.
On July 11, 1995, Serb troops overran the eastern Bosnian Muslim enclave of Srebrenica and executed some 8,000 Muslim men and boys. International courts labeled the crime an act of genocide.
The remains of Srebrenica victims are still being found in mass graves. So far some 7,000 victims have been excavated from 93 graves or collected from 314 on-surface locations and identified through DNA technology.
Edin Nuhic, who lost numerous male relatives in the massacre, has not yet found the remains of all of them. "All we can do is to think about them, to remember them and to hope that one day this country will find a way to move on," he said.
Serb commander handed over to authorities
Among the 136 victims to be laid to rest on Saturday are 18 minors. The oldest victim, Jusuf Smajlovic, was 75 when he was executed and he will be laid to rest together with his 29-year-old grandson, Hebib.
The truck also carried the coffins of father Ismet Mehmedovic and his three sons Fikret, 20, Rifet, 18, and Salih, 16.
Dozens of people walked next to the truck that was slowly passing through the capital, with more and more people tucking flowers in the canvas, the wheels and anywhere else they could reach.
In Srebrenica, organizers expect some 50,000 people to attend the funeral along with international delegations.
The United States, which led the military intervention and brokered Bosnia's peace agreement that ended the country's war after it claimed 100,000 victims, will be represented by a delegation led by former President Bill Clinton.
Meanwhile, a former Serb paramilitary commander during the 1990s Balkan wars arrived in Croatia Thursday to face war crimes charges following his extradition from Australia.
Dragan Vasiljkovic, also known as Captain Dragan and Daniel Snedden, landed in Zagreb after he was formally handed over to Croatian authorities at the airport in Sydney a day earlier.
Vasiljkovic is accused of killings and torture of civilians while he was a rebel Serb commander during the 1991-95 Croatian war. He has denied the charges that carry a maximum 20-year prison sentence in Croatia.
Serbia-born Vasiljkovic came to Australia at the age of 15 but returned to the Balkans to train Croatian Serb rebels in 1991, when Serbs took up arms against Croatia's secession from Yugoslavia.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
