<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbsnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:33:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After terror attacks, Tunisia building barrier on Libya border</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/after-terror-attacks-tunisia-building-barrier-on-libya-border-to-keep-terrorists-out/</Link>
        <Description>Move to keep out extremists comes after gunman opens fire on European sunbathers, killing dozens of tourists</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
TUNIS, Tunisia -- Tunisia's army and contractors are building a barrier along part of the country's border with Libya to keep out extremists in the wake of attacks claimed by the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria.
Prime Minister Habib Essid said the goal is to render the border "impassable" by jihadi fighters and vehicles, and construction should be finished this year.
Essid told Tunisian TV the barrier will cover 105 miles - about one-third of the border - and will include fencing, a sand wall, trenches and surveillance posts.
Tunisia's government declared a state of emergency days after a gunman killed 38 tourists , mostly Britons, on June 26 in the coastal resort of Sousse. In March, two attackers fired on tourists and others at Tunis' National Bardo Museum, killing 22 people.
Authorities say the three gunmen, who were shot dead by security forces, received weapons training in Libya.
A young woman  lays flowers at the scene of a shooting  in Sousse, Tunisia, Saturday, June 27, 2015, the morning after a lone gunman killed at least 38 people at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel.
Darko Vojinovic/AP
A prosecutor's office official, Belhassen Oueslati, said three suspected accomplices in the Sousse attack are also in police custody.
Other recent government security measures include firing some security officials, sending more than 1,300 security forces to patrol hotels, beaches and other tourist sites and closing 80 mosques whose leaders were said to incite terrorism.
Rights groups say the state of emergency mustn't trample freedoms in Tunisia's fledgling democracy. Essid insisted in parliament Wednesday the moves instead aimed "to preserve the democratic achievements" in the country.
"Today's Tunisia is not yesterday's Tunisia," he said. "The state must act in line with the law."
Tunisia overthrew its dictator in 2011, setting off the Arab Spring revolutions. While successive governments have fostered democracy in Tunisia, Libya has fallen into near-chaos - now divided between rival governments with hundreds of militias roaming the country.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 01:32:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry: "We will not rush" Iran nuclear deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/sec-kerry-we-will-not-rush-iran-nuclear-deal/</Link>
        <Description>But the secretary of state also said the U.S. would not "sit at the negotiating table forever"</Description>
        <MainBody>Secretary of State John Kerry is making a final push to deliver President Obama's biggest foreign policy goal: a nuclear deal with Iran. However,...
If negotiations drag on past Thursday, it could mean extra time for Congress to appraise and approve the deal. According to the Iran Nuclear Agreement Review Act passed in May, if the president sends a deal for Congress to evaluate after July 9, the deliberative body can take as long as 60 days -- as opposed to the previously required 30 -- to review it. Though legislators can't stop the U.S. from implementing the entirety of the deal, they can block the administration from lifting certain sanctions imposed by Congress in the first place.
According to CBS News correspondent Margaret Brennan, Kerry is poised to remain in Vienna until Friday , but that his team is still hoping to get a deal signed for Congress to review by Thursday.
Sec. Kerry: Iran nuclear talks could go either way
"This is not open ended," Kerry told reporters Thursday. "President Obama made it very clear to me last night. You can't wait forever for a decision to be made. We know that. If the tough decisions don't get made, we are absolutely prepared to call an end to this process."
Iran's Foreign Minister, Javad Zarif, also took to Twitter early Thursday to say that the negotiations were "not rushed."
We're working hard, but not rushed, to get the job done. Mark my words; you can't change horses in the middle of a stream. #IranTalksVienna
 Javad Zarif (@JZarif) July 9, 2015
Some members of Congress are signaling that a slow approach to the negotiations will make for a better overall deal.
Sen. Bob Corker, R-Tennessee, said Thursday that he was "glad they are taking their time."
"I would much rather they take time on the remaining issues and make sure they do the very best they can to get them as good as they can," the Senate Foreign Relations Committee chair told CBS News. "I'd rather they delay than end up in making what's been a very downward trend the last couple of months even more downwardly trending.  So I'm glad they are taking their time."
The committee's ranking Democrat also added his support for Kerry and his team.
"We want him to take as much time as he needs, within reason," Sen. Ben Cardin, D-Maryland, said Thursday. "As he pointed out there is not an unlimited amount of patience here.  As long as there is a reasonable path forward, we want him to take the time to get the right agreement.  And if it can't be done , we have to know soon."
The existing freeze on Iran's nuclear program is scheduled to expire Friday, July 10. Iranian diplomats say they  could conceivably agree to roll that over for the duration of the ongoing talks.
There has been a breakthrough on guaranteeing weapons inspectors access to suspect nuclear sites including those on military installations, one of the outstanding issues where the parties had major disagreements. However, there are still issues disputes about how quickly Iran will be able to ramp up enrichment after a decade-long freeze and how much development of advanced centrifuges it can continue during the agreement.  The Iranian negotiators also want the U.N. sanctions lifted including an embargo on missiles and conventional weapons.
"All that we are focused on is the quality of the agreement and that is what will continue to define our work," Kerry said.
CBS News' John Nolen contributed to this report.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:10:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Joint Chiefs nominee: Russia is top threat to U.S. security</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/joint-chiefs-nominee-russia-is-top-threat-to-u-s-security/</Link>
        <Description>Marine Gen. Joseph Dunford tells Congress Russia's recent behavior is "nothing short of alarming"</Description>
        <MainBody>Defense Secretary Ash Carter told a Senate committee Tuesday that the U.S. is only training 60 Syrians to combat ISIS. CBS News National Security...
McCain has voiced sharp criticism that the U.S. has only 60 trainees in a program to prepare and arm thousands of moderate Syrian rebels in the fight against IS militants . Dunford said the progress in training is "much less than what we estimated" and attributed the low number to a rigorous vetting process. He said that without talking with commanders on the ground, he could not provide further insight into the problems.
There are no U.S. troops in Syria, but about 3,300 U.S. forces are training and advising local security forces in Iraq. The Iraqi military, which was equipped and trained by the United States, has struggled to recover from its collapse a year ago when IS militants captured the country's second-largest city, Mosul, and swept over much of northern and western Iraq.
Since then, IS has seized control of Ramadi, the capital of Anbar province in western Iraq, and other key terrain in the region. The loss of Ramadi, Dunford said, was a tactical setback that shows how agile and adaptive IS has become. But he said the U.S. military and the Iraqis have learned from that loss.
Dunford repeatedly says he will take time to assess the programs and promised that one of his first trips, if confirmed, would be to Iraq and the region.
Asked if the number of U.S. troops in Iraq is adequate, Dunford said is it enough but that "as conditions change on the ground, it may become necessary to adjust how we implement the military campaign."
On Afghanistan, Dunford, who until last year had been serving as the top U.S. commander in the country, also said that he is willing to recommend changes in the size and pace of the troop withdrawal there if security conditions worsen.
Defense spending bills moving through Congress call for padding a war-fighting account, which is not subject to congressional spending caps, known as sequestration.
"Quite frankly, if we go into sequestration we will be unable to support the current strategy that we have to protect our nation," he said, adding that the combat readiness of U.S. forces "will suffer what I would describe, and without exaggeration, as catastrophic consequences."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:12:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Disruptive London Tube strike</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/pictures/london-tube-strike-disrupts-commute-for-millions/</Link>
        <Description>Millions of London commuters faced a day of chaotic travel as London Underground workers went on strike, shutting down the British capital's well-known subway system</Description>
        <MainBody>Next
London Tube strike
A 24-hour strike hit London's well-known subway system, the London Underground, called the Tube, leaving millions of commuters with a chaotic morning trip on Thursday, July 9, 2015.
The strike, which is over pay and work schedules due to take effect when some of the Tube's lines begin 24-hour service later in the year, started Wednesday evening, July 8.
The new "Night Tube" service is scheduled to start operation in September. Current service begins around 5:30 a.m. and the system shuts down between midnight and 1 a.m.
Here, pedestrians walk across Waterloo Bridge backdropped by the Houses of Parliament during the morning rush hour in London, July 9, 2015.
Credit: Matt Dunham/AP
London Tube strike
The Underground, which first began in 1863 - 152 years ago - as The Metropolitan Railway, now delivers 4 million journeys a day.
Commuters were forced to find alternate means of transport such as bus, taxi, or bicycle or were left to make their journey on foot.
In this photo, early morning commuters form queues to board buses at Victoria station during the Tube strike in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Niklas Halle'n/AFP/Getty Images
London Tube strike
During a 24-hour London Underground strike, workers from an outside agency give people travel advice by the closed entrance doors of Waterloo Underground station in London, on July 9, 2015.
The strike was the London Underground's first strike shutdown since 2002.
Credit: Matt Dunham/AP
London Tube strike
Commuters cross the river Thames using the Millennium footbridge during the Tube strike in London, on July 9, 2015.
There are 270 stations in the Tube system and 250 miles of track.
Credit: Ben Stansall/AFP/Getty Images
Commuters queue for buses during the 24-hour Tube strike in London, on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Frank Augstein/AP
Commuters make their way towards Waterloo Bridge in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Dan Kitwood/Getty Images
London Tube strike
Commuters wait on board a bus at Waterloo Station in London during the 24-hour Tube strike, July 9, 2015.
Credit: Dan Kitwood/Getty Images
London Tube strike
During a 24-hour London Underground strike, pedestrians walk across Waterloo Bridge, backdropped by St. Paul's Cathedral, during the morning rush hour in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Matt Dunham/AP
Commuters depart Waterloo Station in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Dan Kitwood/Getty Images
Commuters emerge from Victoria Station, London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Paul Hackett/Reuters
London Tube strike
Early morning commuters squeeze onto a bus in the City during a Tube strike in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Ben Stansall/AFP/Getty Images
Commuters wait for buses at Victoria Station, London during the 24-hour strike, July 9, 2015.
Credit: Paul Hackett/Reuters
London Tube strike
Commuters form a long queue as they wait for buses at Victoria Station, London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Paul Hackett/Reuters
London Tube strike
A commuter rides a bike through the traffic in the City during a Tube strike in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Ben Stansall/AFP/Getty Images
London Tube strike
Union protesters stand at the locked gates of Brixton Underground station during the Tube strike in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Niklas Halle'n/AFP/Getty Images
Commuters wait for buses at Victoria Station in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Paul Hackett/REUTERS
London Tube strike
Early morning commuters walk past a closed Underground gate at Victoria station during the Tube strike in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Niklas Halle'n/AFP/Getty Images
London Tube strike
During a 24-hour London Underground strike, travelers line up for buses in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Matt Dunham/AP
London Tube strike
The Tube entrance gate is closed at St. James Park Station as Tube drivers strike in London, July 9, 2015.
Credit: Frank Augstein/AP
London Tube strike
Commuters queue up for buses during the morning rush hour during the Tube strike in London, July 9, 2015.
Credit: Matt Dunham/AP
London Tube strike
During a 24-hour London Underground strike, commuters line up to rent bicycles in London on July 9, 2015.
Credit: Matt Dunham/AP
London Tube strike
A commuter talks to a member of staff at Victoria Station in London during the 24-hour Underground strike, July 9, 2015.
Credit: Paul Hackett/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:19:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Toronto police officer scolds drivers mid-interview</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/toronto-police-officer-scolds-drivers-mid-interview/</Link>
        <Description>The officer quickly told the two men involved to grow up and get back in their cars</Description>
        <MainBody>Toronto police officer scolds drivers mid-interview
July 9, 2015, 7:30 AM
|The officer was being interviewed when a road rage incident erupted on the road below. The officer quickly told the two men involved to grow up and get back in their cars. Vinita Nair reports on how the men reacted.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:18:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA bans top American soccer official for life</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/fifa-bans-us-official-chuck-blazer-life-over-fraud-racketeering-tax-evasion/</Link>
        <Description>Chuck Blazer pleaded guilty to charges of racketeering, money laundering conspiracies and tax evasion in soccer scandal that rocked the globe</Description>
        <MainBody>David Larkin, Co-Director of the ChangeFIFA Campaign, discusses FIFA President Sepp Blatter announcing he is stepping down.
He admitted receiving payments in a $10 million bribe scheme to support South Africa's successful 2010 World Cup hosting bid. The plot linked Blazer and two other then-FIFA executive committee members in getting cash which South African officials asked FIFA to transfer through the governing body's accounts in 2008.
Blazer also admitted involvement in World Cup ticket sale scams and abusing his position as CONCACAF general secretary to take millions of dollars in kickbacks from commercial deals he negotiated for the Gold Cup tournament.
He was a cooperating witness with United States federal agencies since 2011 after his tax affairs were investigated.
Blazer served on FIFA's policy-making executive committee for 16 years until 2013.
He had risen to power at CONCACAF, the regional football body governing North and Central America and the Caribbean, alongside its disgraced former president Jack Warner .
FIFA opened an ethics investigation against Blazer after the corrupt financial management of CONCACAF was exposed in 2012.
"Mr. Blazer committed many and various acts of misconduct continuously and repeatedly during his time as an official in different high-ranking and influential positions at FIFA and CONCACAF," the ethics panel said Thursday.
The FIFA proceedings were suspended in 2013 due to Blazer's ill-health and while the U.S. federal case developed.
Blazer, now 70, told a Brooklyn court in November 2013 that he had been treated for rectal cancer.
He forfeited more than $1.9 million at the time of his plea and has agreed to pay more when he is sentenced.
Blazer's life story could be made into a Hollywood film, reportedly to be produced by Ben Affleck. The rights to an upcoming book of his football administration career were bought last month.
Charming and ebullient, Blazer was a central figure in FIFA's lurid recent history and the breakdown of his relationship with Warner was a key turning point.
During the dual World Cup bidding races in 2010, Blazer posted pictures on his travel blog of meeting in Moscow with Vladimir Putin before Russia won 2018 hosting rights.
Blazer supported the United States bid which eventually lost the 2022 contest to Qatar. He famously questioned Qatar's credentials before he and his FIFA executive committee colleagues voted, saying of the searingly hot temperatures there that "I don't see how you can air-condition an entire country."
Five months later, Qatari candidate Mohamed bin Hammam seemed poised to threaten Sepp Blatter's hold on the FIFA presidency when he visited Warner's native Trinidad to meet Caribbean voters.
Blazer had primed some delegates to gather evidence of suspicious behavior, then turned whistleblower by handing FIFA a dossier which alleged a bribery plot.
Warner was forced out of football by his right-hand man's work and Bin Hammam never returned to football before resigning ahead of a second life ban by FIFA.
The fallout of the election bribery scandal saw Blazer's personal finances investigated and CONCACAF self-report to the Internal Revenue Service over a failure to file accounts for several years.
Blazer resigned from CONCACAF before he could be fired, and in April 2013 a three-man investigation panel delivered a damning report of financial mismanagement in the Warner-Blazer era.
At FIFA, Blazer let his final term as an executive committee member expire in May 2013 before exiting and awaiting his judgment on federal crimes.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:45:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tube strike brings London to a stand-still</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/london-tube-strike-underground-employees-protest-24-hour-train-plan/</Link>
        <Description>Angry commuters stuck in lines and buses for hours while Underground employees take industrial action over 24-hour plans</Description>
        <MainBody>Millions of London commuters faced a day of chaotic travel as London Underground workers went on strike, shutting down the British capital's well...
Millions of commuters jammed buses, rented bicycles or simply walked for miles as a 24-hour strike shut down the British capital's well-known subway system and threw public transport into chaos.
Train drivers on the London Underground solidly supported the strike in a dispute over pay and schedules that take effect when 24-hour service is introduced on some lines later this year. That unanimity has made this strike more severe than previous ones in which management was able to keep a few Tube lines operating.
Business groups say the strike will cost London tens of millions of dollars in lost productivity.
"I have to file a statement for today -- I don't know how I am going to do it. I am utterly fed up," said distraught attorney Susan Miller, 48. "I just don't think (strikers) have seen the big picture here."
London's subway system, with 4 million journeys a day, normally shuts down between midnight and 1 a.m., with the overnight shift reserved for track maintenance. While it has operated all night on New Year's Eve, the move to have some lines running 24 hours on weekends marks a huge shift for a 152-year-old system.
London Underground's managing director Mike Brown apologized for the disruption but insisted it was a "remarkably fair" pay offer.
"This strike is unnecessary," he said.
Transport officials say the offer included a 2 percent salary increase, a 500 pound ($770) night Tube launch bonus and an additional 2,000 pound ($3,080) bonus for night Tube train drivers.
Unions say management is trying to bulldoze new work patterns that will cause stress and wreck the work/life balance of people in critical safety jobs.
"We've wasted three months in negotiations that failed to address staff concerns," said the RMT union's general secretary Mick Cash.
The one thing everyone agreed on is that the city's commuters took it on the chin.
Lida Fallah-ardakani, 53, tried to attend a medical appointment she had scheduled five months ago. The journey normally takes an hour, but three hours into her trip Thursday she was still trying to get to St. Mary's Hospital.
"I came out of the house at 6 in the morning. But I am still in the bus to the hospital and I am not sure if I can be seen," she said.
Some commuters supported the strikers.
"You have to take action sometimes when you are up against the ... forces of capitalism," said Tricha Passes, a 58-year-old university lecturer.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:31:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tragic milestone: 4 million have fled Syria war</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/syria-war-has-created-4-million-refugees-un-says/</Link>
        <Description>"This is the biggest refugee population from a single conflict in a generation," UN agency says as war rages with no end in sight</Description>
        <MainBody>Hundreds of thousands of Kurdish refugees flee Syria for Turkey as ISIS threatens them
Turkey has seen much of the recent flow. In June alone, according to  UNHCR, more than 24,000 people arrived from northern Syria amid fighting  between the Islamic State group and Kurdish militants . The more than  1.8 million Syrians in Turkey have made it the biggest host of refugees  in the world, an expensive undertaking that the country is bearing  mostly out of its own treasury.
The dire situation in the region is pushing a wave of refugees to seek escape in Western Europe, taking increasingly risky paths as European countries resist the flow.
"We cannot afford to let them and the communities hosting them slide further into desperation," Guterres said.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:54:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2 Israeli citizens captive in Gaza Strip</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/israel-citizen-held-hamas-militants-gaza-strip-crossing-palestinian-territory/</Link>
        <Description>Government officials say issue was kept quiet in order to facilitate release of prisoner being detained "against his will" by Hamas militants</Description>
        <MainBody>Hamas says last summer's war in Gaza has sent many new young recruits their way. The teenaged members believe they'll be ready to fight should wa...
Israel's military lifted a gag order Thursday to reveal details of the matter. It is unclear why it decided to publicize the issue ten months after the incident. Senior Israeli government officials, speaking on condition of anonymity because they were unauthorized to speak publicly about the issue, said Israel had hoped keeping the affair quiet could lead to his release. They would not comment on the lifting of the gag order.
COGAT said the second Israeli citizen being held in Gaza is an Arab citizen of Israel. Israeli officials provided no further details.
The detention of Israelis in Gaza is particularly sensitive because of the prolonged saga of Gilad Schalit , an Israeli soldier captured by Hamas-allied militants in 2006 and held for more than five years before he was swapped for more than 1,000 Palestinian prisoners.
Israeli media said Israel had turned to international channels to appeal for Mangisto's release on humanitarian grounds because he was a civilian, not a soldier.
Israeli Channel 2 TV said Mengisto arrived at an Israeli beach on the Gaza border the evening of Sept. 7, left behind his bag and crossed into Gaza through a breach in the border fence apparently left from movement of Israeli tanks during the Israel-Gaza war. Mengisto is from the city of Ashkelon, Israeli media reported.
The 50-day war last summer between the Islamic militant Hamas group and Israel left 2,200 Palestinians and 73 people in Israel dead.
Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu had been in touch with Mengisto's parents and that Lior Lotan, a retired Israeli army colonel, was handling negotiations to return Mengisto to Israel, Channel 2 TV reported.
The family had been instructed not to speak publicly about the matter, media reports said, but that news of Mengisto being held in Gaza had spread through Israel's Ethiopian immigrant community.
Israeli Channel 10 broadcast an interview with a man it identified as Mengisto's father, holding up a statement critical of Israeli authorities.
"They didn't do anything," Haili Mangisto said. "Where is my son?"
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:43:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stocks rebound but for many Chinese, all is lost</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/china-stock-market-rebounds-small-time-shanghai-index-investors-hit-hard/</Link>
        <Description>While gov't action may avert broad crisis, for millions of small-time investors lured into the market, "catastrophe" has struck</Description>
        <MainBody>In a matter of just weeks, China, the world's second-largest economy, has seen a whopping $3 trillion wiped off the value of its stocks. CBS News...
China's government has banned major shareholders and executives from selling shares, and a $19 billion "market stabilization fund" was set up to buy stocks.
"I would call this a major stock market catastrophe," Zhang Guoqiang told CBS News. "We have never seen anything like this."
Zhang, a retired electrician, was among the many small-time investors trying to buy and sell stocks at the trading hall, which resembles a dingy gambling parlor.
More than 80 percent of the 90 million-plus Chinese playing the market are average citizens. Many in the trading hall on Thursday covered their faces with newspapers and shawls when the CBS News camera was switched on. They didn't want to talk, and the reasons were quite clear: they've lost a tremendous amount of their money.
Some told Doane off-camera that they'd lost anywhere from 30 to 70 percent of their savings. One man told us quite simply that his heart was broken.
Many were urged by the government to get into the stock market.
"That is real money," Peng Lixin, a retired manager of a recycling company, lamented. "Those are real fortunes being lost in there... within one month the situation came to this."
"A lot of people have been talking about a bubble in the Chinese stock markets for a while and saying it was inevitably going to burst," Gillian Tett of the "Financial Times," told CBS News. "But not many people expected the kind of crash we've seen in the last couple of weeks."
Peng told Doane he felt the government had done all it could do, but it remained to be seen whether those measures would work.
"The government can try to order investors to stop trading," explained Tett, "but it can't order people to start believing in the future or get confidence back in the markets again."
If the drastic measures taken fail to shore up stock prices, said Tett, it could shake some Chinese citizens' confidence in the all-powerful Communist Party.
"A number of investors and ordinary Chinese (are) waking up and realizing that sometimes the Chinese government isn't all powerful," she said. "They've thrown everything at this. They're pulling out emergency measures everywhere, and if these don't work to stabilize the market, the question people are going to start asking is, 'does the Chinese government actually have control over the rest of the economy?'"
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:10:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Where are all the women in tech? In London</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/london-tech-scene-home-far-more-women-than-silicon-valley-why/</Link>
        <Description>U.K. start-up scene has a lot more ladies than Silicon Valley; so why is America's digital landscape so "pale, male and stale"?</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
LONDON -- Joanna Montgomery wants you to hear your lover's heart beating as you drift off to sleep, even if your lover is thousands of miles away.
As a project during her college days, studying computer science, Montgomery designed a product to pipe that sweet sound directly to your ears -- through a small speaker in your pillow -- via a transponder worn by your significant other.
But as she told CBS News at her workspace in London, "it went viral on the internet. So then people started emailing me saying, 'can I buy it, I love it.'"
She's had about 44,000 people, most of them in the U.S., reach out to her asking about availability.
So she made her idea a reality, and called it " PillowTalk ." It should hit store shelves and retail websites later this year.
But as a young entrepreneur with no business experience, Montgomery needed help, and that's how she ended up sharing a vast, open office space in central London with dozens of other fledgling tech start-ups.
The Wayra Accelerator is an incubator for tech start-ups. Dozens of entrepreneurs get a little space and a lot of help building their businesses from Wayra's corporate backer, Spanish telecom giant Telefonica.
In exchange, Telefonica gets a cut of the companies' profits. But according to Wayra U.K. Director Gary Stewart, just having direct access to the people dreaming up the must-have gadgets of tomorrow is also a huge benefit to a company like Telefonica.
While Montgomery has a lot in common with the other aspirational minds at Wayra, she's in a minority among London's entrepreneurs; she's a woman.
WAYRA/CBS
A survey of start-ups conducted by Wayra and a number of partners found that only about 30.3 percent of the people driving London's tech scene are female.
But perhaps more startling is the comparison between that figure from the "StartUpDNA" survey and the correlating figures from similar studies carried out in the U.S., most of which show women behind only 10 percent -- or fewer -- of the start-ups in Silicon Valley.
A lot of that comes down to which individuals venture capitalists are willing to put their money behind, and the research clearly shows that it goes overwhelmingly to men rather than women.
TELEFONICA/CBS
Montgomery says she's not experienced much bias in her transition from student to entrepreneur in the U.K., but there have been isolated incidents, particularly during visits to conferences and other events in Silicon Valley.
"I had a conversation with a guy and afterward he said 'you know, you're actually quite smart.' and I said huh? And he said, 'you're, well, you're probably used to people thinking you're stupid.'"
Stewart, the Wayra director, said surveys carried out by Telefonica and partners show "women are five times more represented in the U.K. relative to the U.S."
Trying to figure out what's behind the huge difference in women in the U.S. and U.K. start-up "environments," as they're called by techies, is tricky, but Stewart, an American with degrees from two Ivy League universities, has a theory.
Wayra U.K. Director Gary Stewart (second from the left) speaks with tech start-up employees at the Wayra Accelerator in London.
CBS
"There's a queen, and the queen is a very powerful figure. They've had women as prime ministers... So I think that they're (Britons) not really that, you know, unused to women being in powerful positions."
Stewart says women -- and racial minorities -- need a confidence boost in what he calls the "hyper-masculine and macho" U.S. tech scene if they can hope to secure those vital venture capital dollars.
"When you're judging start-ups, what you're looking for is someone with almost a messianic complex, who says, kind of like Mark Zuckerburg in 'The Social Network': 'I don't really care what everyone thinks, I really believe I can create a billion dollar business,'" Stewart said.
And crucially, they need to be lured in early.
Tech commentator Shivvy Jervis, creator of the Digital Futures video series , believes "there's a role of parents and educators here; to talk to their 16-year-old daughters and their 16-year-old students to say hey, 'why not consider swapping home science for IT or coding?'"
Both Jervis and Stewart agree another big factor is the relative lack of role models across the technology industry.
"My female peers and I don't get called on as much as we'd like to be the pundits, to be the commentators on the panel shows, on the news shows when a massive tech story breaks," she told CBS News, adding with a smile that when such expertise is required on the airwaves, "we know the person that's going to be called on there is going to be pale, male, and stale."
According to Stewart, there are advantages to increasing the diversity of any tech start-up environment.
"If you have a lot of really smart people, a lot of really ambitious and passionate people trying to solve problems, but they can all add different points of view, kind of like the whole marketplace of ideas concept, at the end I think that we will get a much better output," he said.
Joanna Montgomery did leave college with a degree in computer science, and she believed in her idea enough to reject two job offers to pursue it, in spite of the advice of her peers.
"My friends were like, 'this is stupid, you're going to regret that. You have no idea what you're doing,'" she recalled.
Then her "stupid" idea won her about $36,000 in a tech competition in London, "and they all shut up a bit."
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:56:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Starving Indian kids denied free eggs over religion</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/india-official-denies-starving-schoolchildren-eggs-over-vegetarian-stance/</Link>
        <Description>Nutritionists blast state minister for decision over food program that could have helped millions of malnourished schoolchildren</Description>
        <MainBody>Angry protesters are demanding answers in eastern India after at least 22 schoolchildren died from apparent food poisoning after eating a school ...
Still, the modest menus are clearly not enough to make up for the  calories and nutrition that poverty has denied. All 35 or so children  gathered on the dirt floor of their preschool in Madkheda, a village in  the state of Madhya Pradesh, show the telltale signs of malnutrition -  coarse hair lightened to a sandy brown for lack of nutrients, limbs  stick thin, and bellies swollen from chronic hunger.
More than half the children in Madhya Pradesh state, with a population of nearly 77 million, are underweight and malnourished.
So last month, it was suggested that eggs - a key source of protein - be added to the lunch program. But that idea was rejected by Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan, the state's top elected official, a member of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party and a strict vegetarian. He suggested that milk and bananas be given to children instead.
"As long I am the chief minister of Madhya Pradesh, eggs will not be introduced," Chouhan declared in the state capital, Bhopal. "The human body is meant to consume vegetarian food, which has everything the human body requires."
The decision has outraged nutritionists and social activists who say politicians are using food to push a religious and political agenda at the expense of children's health. They accuse governments of pandering to a nationwide agenda led by the ruling Bharatiya Janata Party to draw poor and tribal communities, with their mostly animist beliefs, toward the majority religion by forcing them to become vegetarian.
India has the highest number of vegetarians in the world owing to Hinduism's predominance, although not all Hindus are vegetarians and there are millions who eat meat. Most of Madhya Pradesh's undernourished children come from ethnic, non-vegetarian tribes, some of whom are animists, who have lived for centuries in central Indian jungles, or belong to the lowest castes.
The move suggests that Modi's party hopes to spread and deepen Hinduism's influence in India by appeasing vegetarians.
"There is a deep political motive behind the decision to stop eggs. The government is forcing these people to become vegetarians and draw them closer to Hinduism," said Naresh Biswas, a food rights activist working to revive traditional farming methods and improve nutrition in Madhya Pradesh.
Similar allegations were made amid the Modi government's push to make yoga compulsory in schools nationwide, with many Muslims objecting to what they see as attempts at a "Hinduization" of the country.
Chouhan found support for his decision from his party colleague, India's Minister for Women and Child Development, Menaka Gandhi, who said the benefits of eggs were exaggerated. Besides, "eggs are expensive and there are cheaper sources of protein that could be used to feed children" in government lunch programs, Gandhi told reporters in New Delhi.
India has the world's highest number of chronically undernourished people in the world, with nearly 195 million scarcely able to afford even one meal a day, according to the Food and Agriculture Organization. That number has barely changed despite a decade of rapid economic growth that has created legions of millionaires and a burgeoning middle class.
Only 10 out of India's 29 states include eggs in children's meal programs. While none of the BJP-ruled states include eggs in children's lunch scheme, activists say even states run by other parties, such as in the Congress Party-led Karnataka state, have not included eggs to appease Hindu sentiments.
Earlier this year, the government of the neighboring state of Maharashtra, also ruled by the BJP, banned cattle slaughter and beef sales in a move that has deprived millions of lower caste and non-Hindus of a cheap source of protein. Beef in India is mostly buffalo meat and is cheaper than chicken, goat or lamb.
Development economist Jean Dreze said excluding eggs from the school supplement program was a "missed opportunity," given that they not only boost nutrition but also improve school attendance, according to studies carried out in several states.
"Indian children are among the most undernourished in the world," said Dreze of the Delhi School of Economics. "The situation is worse when it comes to rural and tribal people, who are even more deprived. They are starved of protein, vitamins, iron and other essential nutrients."
Poor nutrition leaves the children vulnerable to disease, susceptible to infections and diseases such as tuberculosis and cholera. Deprived of adequate nutrition in their formative early years, these children remain mentally and physically stunted for life.
Nutritionists say eggs are one of the cheapest ways of delivering nutrition-dense meals, with their vitamins and minerals easily absorbed by young children.
In other states, such as Bihar, one of India's poorest, the government has successfully introduced eggs in the state-run meal programs for young children and seen a rise in attendance.
Welfare workers note that eggs are easy to distribute with very little risk of being contaminated by chemicals or pollution - a huge problem in India, where there is almost no refrigeration, few storage facilities and poor transportation links.
The sleepy village of Madkheda, on a stony dirt road lined with acacia forests a couple of hours away from the city of Gwalior, had not received wheat supplies for two full weeks, leading one former teacher to buy flour on credit to keep the children's meals going.
"Unlike milk, which can be diluted, or lentils, or wheat flour, which can be adulterated, an egg is a neat package," said Sachin Jain, a food rights activist.
The vegetarian agenda promoted by high-caste politicians has even baffled and embarrassed some Hindus.
"Why would we mind if eggs are served to other peoples' children?" Sapna Baghel asked while feeding bits of bread soaked in lentils to her 2-year-old daughter at a state-run nursery in Gwalior. "We don't eat eggs, but we shouldn't stop others from eating what they like."
Her neighbor, Uma Pal, nodded in agreement. "If they could afford it, these children would eat eggs every day," she said. "Disallowing eggs from the children's lunch is a shame. This is all politics."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 09:44:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Coca tea may help Pope Francis cope with high altitude in Bolivia</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/coca-tea-may-help-pope-francis-cope-with-high-altitude-in-bolivia/</Link>
        <Description>Flight attendant serves Pope Francis tea made from coca leaves, chamomile and anise before arrival in world's highest capital city</Description>
        <MainBody>By Anna MatrangaCBS NewsJuly 8, 2015, 10:46 PM
Coca tea may help Pope Francis cope with high altitude in Bolivia
Pope Francis arrives at the international airport in La Paz, Bolivia, July 8, 2015.
ALESSANDRO BIANCHI/REUTERS
More +
LA PAZ, Bolivia -- According to a flight attendant who served Pope Francis on a flight Wednesday between Quito, Ecuador , and La Paz, Bolivia, the Pope drank a tea made of a combination of coca leaves, chamomile and anise.
Tea made from coca leaves is a common remedy for altitude sickness in the Andes.  The airport in La Paz, at more than 13,000 feet above sea level, is the highest in the world.
"He asked me for 'trimate,' which is really common also in Argentina," the flight attendant on the Boliviana de Aviacion flight said.
Pope Francis meets the faithful on a nine-day journey to Latin America preaching reconciliation and renewal
Before landing in La Paz, journalists traveling on the papal flight were also offered "trimate" as well as tea made solely from coca leaves, which has a mild flavor similar to green tea.
Coca leaves are the main ingredient in cocaine, but chewing on coca leaves or drinking tea made from them is legal and widespread in this part of the world.
The Vatican had said that the 78-year-old Pope would spend no more than four hours in La Paz to minimize negative effects from the altitude. Francis lost part of a lung as a teenager due to an infection.
Bolivian president Evo Morales hugged the Pope when he got off the plane.  Morales, a former coca farmer, then gave the Pope traditional pouch commonly used to hold coca leaves.
During the welcome ceremony at the airport, the Pope appeared robust, delivering an energetic speech urging Bolivians, who are the poorest South Americans, to continue to build an inclusive society that does not leave out the poor and disadvantaged. He also said the Catholic church needed to continue to play an important role in the life of the country, which is overwhelmingly Catholic.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 07:53:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Financial catastrophe brewing in China</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/financial-catastrophe-brewing-in-china/</Link>
        <Description>China's state-sponsored stock market is quickly unraveling after years of explosive growth</Description>
        <MainBody>Financial catastrophe brewing in China
July 8, 2015, 8:26 PM
|China's state-sponsored stock market is quickly unraveling after years of explosive growth. A collapse could have devastating consequences. For more on the stock plunge in China, CBSN's Jeff Glor talks to Yahoo! finance senior columnist Michael Santoli.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 06:27:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. lags in plan to train Syrian fighters</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/u-s-lags-in-plan-to-train-syrian-fighters/</Link>
        <Description>As a way to fight ISIS, the U.S. had initiated a $500 million program to train 15,000 Syrian opposition fighters</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. lags in plan to train Syrian fighters
July 8, 2015, 6:42 PM
|As a way to fight ISIS, the U.S. had initiated a $500 million program to train 15,000 Syrian opposition fighters. But as CBS News correspondent David Martin reports, the program is off to an embarrassingly slow start.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:58:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Effort to train Syrians to fight ISIS off to slow start</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/effort-to-train-syrians-to-fight-isis-off-to-very-slow-start/</Link>
        <Description>$500 million program to train 15,000 Syrian troops to fight ISIS has attracted only 60 recruits, according to Defense Secretary Ash Carter</Description>
        <MainBody>ByDavid MartinCBS NewsJuly 8, 2015, 7:19 PM
Effort to train Syrians to fight ISIS off to slow start
Shares
More +
WASHINGTON -- At a hearing before the Senate Armed Services Committee, Defense Secretary Ash Carter disclosed that a $500 million program to train 15,000 Syrian opposition fighters has gotten off to an embarrassingly slow start -- with just 60 recruits in training .
"I say the number 60 and I can look out at your faces and you have the same reaction I do, which is that's an awfully small number," Carter admitted.
Defense Secretary Ash Carter told a Senate committee Tuesday that the U.S. is only training 60 Syrians to combat ISIS. CBS News National Security...
Carter said 7,000 Syrians have volunteered , but they first must go through a screening process designed to weed out extremists and those who want to use American training and equipment not against ISIS , but against the Syrian regime of Bashar Al Assad -- a fight the U.S. wants no part of.
Some who make it through the screening quit the training and go home.  Said one U.S. official, "We are failing miserably."
In Iraq, the U.S. has trained some 10,000 Iraqi soldiers, but that too is going slower than planned, due to a shortage of recruits.
More alarming is that Iraqi troops in the field have, as in the recent battle for Ramadi, not been willing to stand and fight even when they outnumber the enemy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 06:01:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What China is doing to curb its market crisis</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/what-china-is-doing-to-curb-its-market-crisis/</Link>
        <Description>In a matter of just weeks, China, the world's second-largest economy, has seen a whopping $3 trillion wiped off the value of its stocks</Description>
        <MainBody>What China is doing to curb its market crisis
July 8, 2015, 6:36 PM
|In a matter of just weeks, China, the world's second-largest economy, has seen a whopping $3 trillion wiped off the value of its stocks. CBS News correspondent Seth Doane looks at how China's government is trying to handle the financial turmoil.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:49:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S., U.A.E. launch anti-ISIS messaging center in Dubai</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/us-uae-launch-anti-isis-messaging-center-dubai/</Link>
        <Description>The propaganda arm of the growing terrorist group has been slick and successful, so the White House and its partners take direct aim at it</Description>
        <MainBody>Law enforcement officials are looking into new ISIS threats directed at Twitter. ISIS uses social media to reach potential recruits and dissemina...
Journalists were not allowed to attend the project's unveiling or visit the center, which has been testing its operations and developing its branding over the past three months.
More work still needs to be done. The center does not yet have an active website of its own, and a planned Facebook presence and a dedicated YouTube channel are expected to take several more weeks to develop. Officials say they hope the center will eventually launch "proactive online messaging campaigns" to target ISIS propaganda.
About 15 to 20 full-time staff, mostly Emiratis, will work at the center for now, said Rashad Hussain, the U.S. special envoy and coordinator for strategic counterterrorism communications.
He did not have precise details on the price tag, saying it was in the tens of millions of dollars, but said the "Emiratis are taking the lead on the cost."
Separately, the United States has been expanding an existing U.S. State Department division, which Hussain heads and which was set up in 2011. It is known as the Center for Strategic Counterterrorism Communications (CSCC.)
Alberto Fernandez, who used to head the CSCC, told CBS News correspondent Margaret Brennan last month that until now, the U.S. has been far too weak fighting against ISIS' messaging .
"There is a fantasy which exists in Washington, which is this," Fernandez said. "Somehow if you put magic social media or public diplomacy pixie dust on a problem, it will go away."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:51:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will Pope Francis chew coca leaves in Bolivia?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/will-pope-francis-chew-coca-leaves-in-bolivia/</Link>
        <Description>As Pope Francis continues his South American tour many people are wondering if he will participate in drinking coca tea, a common practice in Andean nations to help control altitude sickness</Description>
        <MainBody>Will Pope Francis chew coca leaves in Bolivia?
July 8, 2015, 3:30 PM
|As Pope Francis continues his South American tour many people are wondering if he will participate in drinking coca tea, a common practice in Andean nations to help control altitude sickness. CBSN's Meg Oliver explains the significance of the coca leaf.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:03:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>London leads the way for women in tech</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/london-leads-the-way-for-women-in-tech/</Link>
        <Description>Female entrepreneurs are flocking to the Silicon Roundabout to realize their start-ups in a male-dominated industry</Description>
        <MainBody>London leads the way for women in tech
July 8, 2015, 3:00 PM
|Female entrepreneurs are flocking to the Silicon Roundabout to realize their start-ups in a male-dominated industry. Tucker Reals reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
