<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbsnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 07:53:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Financial catastrophe brewing in China</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/financial-catastrophe-brewing-in-china/</Link>
        <Description>China's state-sponsored stock market is quickly unraveling after years of explosive growth</Description>
        <MainBody>Financial catastrophe brewing in China
July 8, 2015, 8:26 PM
|China's state-sponsored stock market is quickly unraveling after years of explosive growth. A collapse could have devastating consequences. For more on the stock plunge in China, CBSN's Jeff Glor talks to Yahoo! finance senior columnist Michael Santoli.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 06:27:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. lags in plan to train Syrian fighters</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/u-s-lags-in-plan-to-train-syrian-fighters/</Link>
        <Description>As a way to fight ISIS, the U.S. had initiated a $500 million program to train 15,000 Syrian opposition fighters</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. lags in plan to train Syrian fighters
July 8, 2015, 6:42 PM
|As a way to fight ISIS, the U.S. had initiated a $500 million program to train 15,000 Syrian opposition fighters. But as CBS News correspondent David Martin reports, the program is off to an embarrassingly slow start.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:58:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Effort to train Syrians to fight ISIS off to slow start</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/effort-to-train-syrians-to-fight-isis-off-to-very-slow-start/</Link>
        <Description>$500 million program to train 15,000 Syrian troops to fight ISIS has attracted only 60 recruits, according to Defense Secretary Ash Carter</Description>
        <MainBody>ByDavid MartinCBS NewsJuly 8, 2015, 7:19 PM
Effort to train Syrians to fight ISIS off to slow start
Shares
More +
WASHINGTON -- At a hearing before the Senate Armed Services Committee, Defense Secretary Ash Carter disclosed that a $500 million program to train 15,000 Syrian opposition fighters has gotten off to an embarrassingly slow start -- with just 60 recruits in training .
"I say the number 60 and I can look out at your faces and you have the same reaction I do, which is that's an awfully small number," Carter admitted.
Defense Secretary Ash Carter told a Senate committee Tuesday that the U.S. is only training 60 Syrians to combat ISIS. CBS News National Security...
Carter said 7,000 Syrians have volunteered , but they first must go through a screening process designed to weed out extremists and those who want to use American training and equipment not against ISIS , but against the Syrian regime of Bashar Al Assad -- a fight the U.S. wants no part of.
Some who make it through the screening quit the training and go home.  Said one U.S. official, "We are failing miserably."
In Iraq, the U.S. has trained some 10,000 Iraqi soldiers, but that too is going slower than planned, due to a shortage of recruits.
More alarming is that Iraqi troops in the field have, as in the recent battle for Ramadi, not been willing to stand and fight even when they outnumber the enemy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 06:01:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What China is doing to curb its market crisis</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/what-china-is-doing-to-curb-its-market-crisis/</Link>
        <Description>In a matter of just weeks, China, the world's second-largest economy, has seen a whopping $3 trillion wiped off the value of its stocks</Description>
        <MainBody>What China is doing to curb its market crisis
July 8, 2015, 6:36 PM
|In a matter of just weeks, China, the world's second-largest economy, has seen a whopping $3 trillion wiped off the value of its stocks. CBS News correspondent Seth Doane looks at how China's government is trying to handle the financial turmoil.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:49:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S., U.A.E. launch anti-ISIS messaging center in Dubai</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/us-uae-launch-anti-isis-messaging-center-dubai/</Link>
        <Description>The propaganda arm of the growing terrorist group has been slick and successful, so the White House and its partners take direct aim at it</Description>
        <MainBody>Law enforcement officials are looking into new ISIS threats directed at Twitter. ISIS uses social media to reach potential recruits and dissemina...
Journalists were not allowed to attend the project's unveiling or visit the center, which has been testing its operations and developing its branding over the past three months.
More work still needs to be done. The center does not yet have an active website of its own, and a planned Facebook presence and a dedicated YouTube channel are expected to take several more weeks to develop. Officials say they hope the center will eventually launch "proactive online messaging campaigns" to target ISIS propaganda.
About 15 to 20 full-time staff, mostly Emiratis, will work at the center for now, said Rashad Hussain, the U.S. special envoy and coordinator for strategic counterterrorism communications.
He did not have precise details on the price tag, saying it was in the tens of millions of dollars, but said the "Emiratis are taking the lead on the cost."
Separately, the United States has been expanding an existing U.S. State Department division, which Hussain heads and which was set up in 2011. It is known as the Center for Strategic Counterterrorism Communications (CSCC.)
Alberto Fernandez, who used to head the CSCC, told CBS News correspondent Margaret Brennan last month that until now, the U.S. has been far too weak fighting against ISIS' messaging .
"There is a fantasy which exists in Washington, which is this," Fernandez said. "Somehow if you put magic social media or public diplomacy pixie dust on a problem, it will go away."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:51:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will Pope Francis chew coca leaves in Bolivia?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/will-pope-francis-chew-coca-leaves-in-bolivia/</Link>
        <Description>As Pope Francis continues his South American tour many people are wondering if he will participate in drinking coca tea, a common practice in Andean nations to help control altitude sickness</Description>
        <MainBody>Will Pope Francis chew coca leaves in Bolivia?
July 8, 2015, 3:30 PM
|As Pope Francis continues his South American tour many people are wondering if he will participate in drinking coca tea, a common practice in Andean nations to help control altitude sickness. CBSN's Meg Oliver explains the significance of the coca leaf.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:14:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lions return to Rwanda, 15 years after eradication there</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/lions-return-to-rwanda-15-years-after-eradication-there/</Link>
        <Description>The 1994 genocide also decimated Rwanda's wildlife population; story of lions one of few bright spots in southern Africa's fight against poaching and encroachment</Description>
        <MainBody>APJuly 8, 2015, 3:35 PM
Lions return to Rwanda, 15 years after eradication there
Simon Naylor, Phinda reserve manager, left, with unidentified official, watches a cage carrying a sedated lion loaded unto a truck in Phinda Private Game Reserve, South Africa, Monday, June 29, 2015.
AP Photo/Themba Hadebe
More +
PHINDA PRIVATE GAME RESERVE, South Africa - The sedated, blindfolded lions lay in the dirt, unwitting passengers about to embark on a 30-hour, 2,500-mile journey by truck and plane from South Africa to Rwanda, whose lion population was wiped out following the country's 1994 genocide .
Then conservationists hoisted the limp bodies into crates, grasping big paws, thick tails and even the imposing heads of animals that earlier pounced on an antelope carcass used as bait to bring them closer to a veterinarian with a tranquilizer gun.
The operation this week to move seven South African lions to Rwanda in east-central Africa is an upbeat tale in an otherwise challenging picture for wildlife on the continent, where poaching has surged and human encroachment is shrinking habitats. Lions are designated as vulnerable on an international "red list" of species facing threats. By some estimates, there are fewer than 20,000 lions in the wild, a drop of about 40 percent in the past two decades.
"There's just no room for them and they're being pressurized and pressurized," said Dr. Mike Toft, a wildlife veterinarian who darted five female lions Monday at the Phinda Private Game Reserve in South Africa's KwaZulu-Natal province. An Associated Press writer and photographer watched as crane operators loaded the lion crates onto a truck that arrived with two male lions from nearby Tembe Elephant Park. The vehicle then drove to Johannesburg for a charter flight to Rwanda.
Two National Geographic photographers spent nearly a year documenting the lions of the Serengeti
The lions' new home is Akagera National Park, where cattle herders poisoned Rwanda's last lions about 15 years ago after the park was left unmanaged in the genocide's wake. Returning refugees took over much of the park, reducing its size by more than half to 433 square miles in 1997, according to African Parks, a Johannesburg-based group that manages Akagera and other national wildlife parks in Africa.
The non-profit group organized the lion transfer to Rwanda, which hopes to boost a wildlife tourism industry that focuses on mountain gorillas . African Parks tried in vain to secure lions from Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania that are genetically closer to Rwanda's old lions.
Rwandans should celebrate the return of lions, wrote a columnist in The New Times, a Rwandan newspaper.
"We didn't treasure what we had (lions) until they were gone," Sunny Ntayombya wrote. "Then we scrambled around, cap in hand, begging different African countries to spare a cat or two."
At Phinda, the five lionesses bound for Rwanda were unexpectedly joined in their holding pen by three other lions that burrowed their way inside. Toft had to dart all eight before workers could enter to fasten satellite tracking collars on the five lions earmarked for travel to Rwanda.
The sedated lions looked vulnerable, jarring with the popular notion of lions as animal royalty. They were blindfolded with cloth and park staff and others moved quietly and spoke softly to reduce the chance of any lion awakening. Some photographed the lions' faces, a close-up opportunity to appreciate a carnivore that has symbolized bravery and inspired "Born Free," ''The Lion King" and other successful books and films.
This month, the International Union for Conservation of Nature noted successful lion conservation in southern Africa, but said lions in West Africa are critically endangered and that rapid population declines have also been recorded in East Africa. A national park in India also has lions.
A trade in lion bones and other body parts for traditional medicine in Africa as well as Asia is considered a growing threat. And lions can easily come into conflict with rural communities that depend on livestock.
A lion that escaped from South Africa's Karoo National Park three weeks ago was captured Monday, authorities said. A veterinarian darted the lion from a helicopter, which lifted the animal in a sling off a mountainside.
The Rwanda-bound lions arrived Tuesday at Akagera, where they are being kept in quarantine for at least two weeks before their release into the wilderness.
The two males each weigh about 550 pounds and are known to have fathered at least 12 cubs. Andrew Parker, joint operations manager for African Parks, said he expected Akagera's lion population to grow "quite quickly."
Toft, the veterinarian, said Rwanda's new lions have a "diverse" genetic makeup and that inbreeding should not be a concern for a while. South Africa, he said, could supply more lions to the continent because of robust numbers on its small, fenced reserves.
"Our lions thrive," he said. "We could easily repopulate many reserves."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:02:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope preaches to faithful in Latin America</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/pictures/pope-preaches-to-faithful-in-latin-america/</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis meets the faithful on a nine-day journey to Latin America preaching reconciliation and renewal</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope preaches to faithful in Latin America
facebook
Next
Ecuador
Pope Francis traveled to Latin America on a three nation tour, bringing him to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay. This is the second trip since his election for the Argentine born Pope; he journeyed to Brazil in 2013, soon after being elected to lead the Catholic Church.
Speaking to students and educators at a Catholic University in Ecuador's capital on July 7, 2015, Pope Francis delivered a strong speech in defense of the environment, warning that caring for the Earth is now no longer a recommendation, but an urgent requirement.
Pope Francis arrives to celebrate mass at the Bicentenario Park in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Pope Francis arrives at the El Quinche Santuary near Quito, Ecuador, July 8, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters, REUTERS
Ecuador
The Faithful attend a mass celebrated by Pope Francis at the Bicentenario Park in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Ecuadorians enthusiastically welcomed Pope Francis as large crowds lined the streets to see him in the Popemobile or outside venues. On July 6, 2015 an estimated 800,000 braved intense heat and humidity to attend the papal mass in the coastal city of Guayaquil.
Credit: Gary Granja/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis arrives to celebrate mass at the Bicentenario Park in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015. Francis, 78, said humans had damaged the planet by "our irresponsible use and abuse of the goods with which God has endowed it. We have come to see ourselves as her lords and masters, entitled to plunder it at will."
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Ecuador
A young boy ponders a wooden cross before an open-air mass officiated by Pope Francis at the Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on July 7, 2015.
Credit: Rodrigo Buendia/AFP/Getty Images
Ecuador
Pope Francis (center) prays during a mass at the Bicentenario Park in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Credit: Jose Miguel Gomez/Reuters
Ecuador
Priests take photographs as Pope Francis arrives to celebrate mass at the Bicentenario Park in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Credit: Gary Granja.Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis (center) celebrates an open-air mass at the Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on July 7, 2015.
Credit: Vincenzo Pinto/AFP/Getty Images
Ecuador
Faithful gather for an open-air mass officiated by Pope Francis at the Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on July 7, 2015.
Credit: Rodrigo Buendia/AFP/Getty Images
Ecuador
A member of the chorus takes a picture as Pope Francis celebrates a mass at the Bicentenario Park in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Ecuador
Holding an image of the Pope, an Ecuadoran awaits the arrival of Pope Francis at San Francisco Church for a meeting with political, economic and civic leaders in Quito, Ecuador on July 7, 2015.
Credit: Luis Robayo/AFP/Getty Images
Ecuador
Pope Francis hugs a young girl at the San Francisco Church in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Pope Francis arrives at the San Francisco Church in Quito, Ecuador on July 7, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Pope Francis speaks at the San Francisco Church in Quito, Ecuador on July 7, 2015.
Credit: Guillermo Granja/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis (center) enters San Francisco Church in Quito, on July 7, 2015 for a meeting with political, economic and civil leaders.
Credit: Vincenzo Pinto/AFP/Getty Images
Ecuador
Pope Francis (left) and Ecuador's President Rafael Correa acknowledge the crowd gathered below, from the government palace balcony in Quito, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: L'Osservatore Romano/Pool via AP
Ecuador
Nuns arrive at Independence square to attend the meeting of Pope Francis and Ecuador's President Rafael Correa in Quito, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Ana Buitron/AP
Ecuador
Pope Francis (left) holds his pastoral staff as he celebrates a Mass at the Samanes park in Guayaquil, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: L'Osservatore Romano/Pool via AP
Ecuador
Pope Francis leads a mass at the Los Samanes park in Guayaquil, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis (right) arrives to lead a mass at the Los Samanes park in Guayaquil, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis (center) walks, holding a bouquet of flowers, inside the Metropolitan Cathedral of Quito in Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Gary Granja/Reuters
Ecuador
Catholic faithful take pictures and record Pope Francis with their mobile phones during his visit to the Metropolitan Cathedral of Quito in Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Martin Bernetti/AFP/Getty Images
Ecuador
A woman sells images and figures of Pope Francis in Quito, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Luis Robayo/AFP/Getty Images
Ecuador
Faithfuls hold a banner that reads "Welcome Pope Francis" as Pope Francis arrives to lead a mass at the Los Samanes park in Guayaquil, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis waves to faithful from a popemobile while driving through Guayaquil, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: John Guaman/Reuters
Ecuador
Residents wait on the street for Pope Francis to arrive at the Los Samanes park in Guayaquil, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Alessandro Bianchi/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis waves to a crowd of supporters upon his arrival at Parque Samanes, where he will celebrate mass in Guayaquil, Ecuador on July 6, 2015.
Credit: Jose Miguel Gomez/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis waves to the faithful while riding on the popemobile in El Quinche, Ecuador, July 8, 2015.
Credit: Guillermo Granja/Reuters
Ecuador
A woman holds a poster with a photo of Pope Francis and Our Lady of Quinche while waiting with other faithfuls for the pope's arrival outside the National Shrine of Our Lady of the Presentation of El Quinche in El Quinche, Ecuador, July 8, 2015.
Credit: Jose Miguel Gomez/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis greets a crowd of supporters from a Popemobile in Quito, Ecuador, July 5, 2015.
Credit: Kevin Granja/Reuters
Ecuador
Supporters call out as Pope Francis drives past in a popemobile in Quito, Ecuador, July 5, 2015.
Credit: Gary Granja/Reuters
Ecuador
Pope Francis, wearing a neck sash in Ecuador's national colors, waves after he landed in Quito, Ecuador on July 5, 2015.
Credit: Jose Miguel Gomez/Reuters
Ecuador
Catholic faithful wait for Pope Francis to drive past in Quito, Ecuador on July 5, 2015.
Credit: Guillermo Granja/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:47:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WikiLeaks levels new charges on NSA's Germany spying</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/wikileaks-new-charges-nsa-germany-spying/</Link>
        <Description>Two years after first revelation of NSA efforts in Germany, spy agency accused of targeting numerous aides to Angela Merkel, as well as the chancellery</Description>
        <MainBody>APJuly 8, 2015, 2:08 PM
WikiLeaks levels new charges on NSA's Germany spying
German Chancellor Angela Merkel in the Siemens electronics manufacturing plant in Amberg, Germany, Monday, Feb. 23, 2015. (AP Photo/Michael Probst)
Michael Probst, AP
More +
BERLIN - WikiLeaks has published a new list of German phone numbers that it claims shows the U.S. National Security Agency targeted for surveillance a string of connections at the chancellery and close aides to Chancellor Angela Merkel.
Wednesday's publication came a week after WikiLeaks released a list of numbers it said showed the NSA targeted officials at various ministries. That rekindled concerns over U.S. surveillance in Germany after reports two years ago that Merkel's cellphone was targeted .
Merkel's chief of staff last week asked the U.S. ambassador for a meeting and told him that German law must be adhered to.
There was no immediate comment from the German government on the latest publication. It's unclear when exactly the partially redacted list of 56 numbers dates from.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:30:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>#CBSNBusiness: July 8, 2015</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/cbsnbusiness-july-8-2015/</Link>
        <Description>The Greek debt crisis, Microsoft planning new lay offs, will Facebook buy twitter and more lead CBSN business headlines</Description>
        <MainBody>#CBSNBusiness: July 8, 2015
July 8, 2015, 1:39 PM
|The Greek debt crisis, Microsoft planning new lay offs, will Facebook buy twitter and more lead CBSN business headlines. CBS News' Jill Wagner has the details.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:27:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A key to ISIS' success: Troops who want to die</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/key-to-isis-success-shock-troops-who-want-to-die/</Link>
        <Description>Fanatical and disciplined, ISIS' shock troop units often set off battles by literally fighting until they die, sometimes with suicide bombings</Description>
        <MainBody>Since the declaration of Islamic Caliphate in June of 2014, ISIS expanded to become one of the most feared terror groups in the world. CBS News t...
The group's tactics carried it to a sweep of northern and western Iraq a year ago, capturing Mosul , Iraq's second-biggest city. Shortly thereafter, ISIS leader Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi declared a "caliphate" spanning its territory in Iraq and Syria.
In May, it captured Ramadi , capital of Iraq's vast western Anbar province. In Syria, it seized the central city of Palmyra.
The elite shock troops were crucial in capturing Ramadi. First came a wave of more than a dozen suicide bombings that hammered the military's positions, then the fighters moved in during a sandstorm. Iraqi troops crumbled and fled as a larger ISIS force marched in.
Since U.S.-led airstrikes in Iraq and Syria have hampered the group's movements, ISIS has lost ground.  Iraqi troops and Shiite militiamen retook some cities, like Saddam's hometown of Tikrit . In Syria, Kurdish fighters backed by heavy U.S. airstrikes recaptured the border town of Kobani after weeks of devastating battles. More recently, ISIS lost Tal Abyad , another Syrian border town.
Despite that loss, ISIS shock troops attacked Kobani again last month. Around 70 fighters battled a much larger Kurdish force for two days. They were all slain, but not before killing more than 230 civilians, including roughly 100 children, and more than 30 Kurdish fighters. Around the same time, they also attacked Tal Abyad, where they battled for days until they were killed, and the northeast Syrian city of Hassakeh, where they continue to hold out.
"They weren't planning to leave alive," Kurdish commander Ghalia Nehme said of the ISIS fighters in Kobani. "It seems they were longing for heaven."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:21:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italy seizes $1.76 billion from builders linked to Mafia</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/italy-seizes-1-76-billion-sicilian-builders-cosa-nostra-mafia/</Link>
        <Description>Police say Sicilian construction company's deals with Cosa Nostra came "at the expense of honest businessmen"</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS/APJuly 8, 2015, 11:21 AM
Italy seizes $1.76 billion from builders linked to Mafia
Italian Prosecutor Maria Teresa Principato (C) gives a press conference in Palermo, Dec. 13, 2013, following the arrest of 30 people linked to Matteo Messina Denaro, the head of Cosa Nostra, including his sister and several cousins.
Getty
Police in the United States and Italy targeted organized crime operations of drug trafficking across the Atlantic. CBS News' Allen Pizzey reports...
Carabinieri police Col. Riccardo Sciuto said Wednesday the builders had made deals with the Cosa Nostra, enabling them to win public contracts "at the expense of honest businessmen."
Investigators say the infiltration of construction contracts, thanks to mobsters working inside local governments or the connivance of corrupt politicians, provides a lucrative income to the Mafia.
According to Reuters, Adelmo Lusi, the vice chief of [anti-mafia police] DIA operations, called the seizure "one of the biggest the DIA has carried out in its 20-year history."
Aided by turncoats, prosecutors have put many of the Corleone clan's top bosses, including longtime fugitives, in prison.  Mainland-based crime syndicates have eclipsed the weakened Sicilian Mafia in influence in international drug trafficking, but corruption and extortion still enrich the Sicilian Mafia.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:37:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Activist: Boko Haram offering swap for captive girls</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/nigeria-isis-affiliated-islamic-extremists-boko-haram-chibok-girls-prisoners/</Link>
        <Description>Human rights group says ISIS-linked group in Nigeria willing to free 200 teen girls in exchange for prisoners</Description>
        <MainBody>The leader of the militant Islamist group Boko Haram, responsible for kidnapping almost 300 girls in Nigeria, appeared in a new video mocking the...
Presidential adviser Femi Adesina said on Saturday that Nigeria's government "will not be averse" to talks with Boko Haram. "Most wars, however furious or vicious, often end around the negotiation table," he said.
Eno said the 5-week-old administration of President Muhammadu Buhari offers "a clean slate" to bring the militants back to negotiations that had become poisoned by the different security agencies and their advice to Jonathan.
Two months of talks last year led government representatives and Eno to travel in September to a northeastern town where the prisoner exchange was to take place, only to be stymied by the Department for State Service intelligence agency, the activist said.
At the last minute, the agency said it was holding only four of the militants sought by Boko Haram, the activist said.
It is not known how many Boko Haram suspects are detained by Nigeria's intelligence agency, whose chief Buhari fired last week.
The activist said the agency continues to hold suspects illegally because it does not have enough evidence for a conviction, and any court would free them. Nigerian law requires charges be brought after 48 hours.
Thousands of suspects have died in custody, and some detainees wanted by Boko Haram may be among them. Amnesty International alleges that 8,000 detainees have died in military custody - some have been shot, some have died from untreated injuries due to torture, and some have died from starvation and other harsh treatment.
In May, about 300 women, girls and children being held captive by Boko Haram were rescued by Nigeria's military, but none were from Chibok. It is believed that the militants view the Chibok girls as a last-resort bargaining chip.
In that infamous abduction, 274 mostly Christian girls preparing to write science exams were seized from the school by Islamic militants in the early hours of April 15, 2014. Dozens escaped on their own in the first few days, but 219 remain missing.
Boko Haram has not shown them since a May 2014 video in which its leader, Abubakar Shekau warned: "You won't see the girls again unless you release our brothers you have captured."
In the video, nearly 100 of the girls, who have been identified by their parents, were shown wearing Islamic hijab and reciting the Quran. One of them said they had converted to Islam.
International indignation at Nigeria's failure to rescue the girls was joined by U.S. first lady Michelle Obama. In a radio address in May 2014, she said she and President Barack Obama are "outraged and heartbroken" over the abduction.
Jonathan's government initially denied there had been any mass abduction and delays of a rescue that might have brought the girls home became a hallmark of his other failures. He steadfastly refused to meet with the Bring Back Our Girls campaigners, charging they were politicizing the issue.
On Wednesday, President Buhari welcomed those campaigners at the presidential villa in Abuja and pleaded "We only ask for your patience." He said "The delay and conflicting reaction by the former government and its agencies is very unfortunate."
Campaign leader Oby Ezekwesili said, "The rescue of our Chibok girls is the strongest statement that this government could make to showg respect for the sanctity and dignity of every Nigerian life."
There have been unconfirmed reports that some of the girls have been taken to neighboring countries, and that some have been radicalized and trained as fighters. At least three were reported to have died - one from dysentery, one from malaria and one from a snake bite.
Last year, Shekau said the girls were an "old story," and that he had married them off to his fighters.
Lawan Zanna, whose daughter is among the captives, said this week that 14 Chibok parents have died since the mass kidnapping, many from stress-related illnesses blamed on the ordeal.
Some of the Chibok girls who managed to escape have been rejected by their community and now live with family friends, tired of hearing taunts like "Boko Haram wives."
The assumption that all girls and women held by the group have been raped is a difficult stigma to overcome in Nigeria's highly religious and conservative society.
Shekau had threatened in 2013 to kidnap women and girls if Nigeria's military did not release detained Boko Haram wives and children. The government freed them in May of that year as a goodwill gesture ahead of failed peace talks.
Boko Haram has kidnapped hundreds more - girls, boys, women and young men. Some have become sex slaves, while others are used as fighters, according to former captives.
Nigerian opinion on negotiating with the extremists is mixed. Some say the group's crimes are too heinous to be forgiven: The 6-year-old Islamic uprising has killed more than 13,000 people and forced about 1.5 million from their homes.
"A lot of people take a hard-line stance that you must never negotiate with a terrorist," said Sen. Chris Anyanwu. She called it a "very complex" issue, balancing the lives of more than 200 girls against the dangers of freeing extremists.
The militants last year seized a large swath of northeast Nigeria and declared an Islamic caliphate. Nigeria and its neighbors deployed a multinational army that forced them out of towns and villages this year, but the bloodshed has risen at a fierce rate since Buhari's May 29 inauguration amid pledges to crush the insurgency.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:51:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian police issue selfie safety guidelines</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/russian-police-issue-selfie-safety-guidelines/</Link>
        <Description>The instructions warn against standing on railroad tracks, climbing onto roofs or posing with a gun or a tiger</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS/AP July 8, 2015, 10:23 AM
Russian police issue selfie safety guidelines
Women pose for a selfie in front of the historical Place of Execution in central Moscow, on April 30, 2015.
KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV/AFP/Getty Images
More +
Alarmed by the number of Russians who have been killed while taking photos of themselves with smartphones, Russian police have started a new campaign called "Safe Selfies."
The instructions issued Tuesday warn against standing on railroad tracks, climbing onto roofs or posing with a gun or a tiger.
These are some of the ways that police say at least 10 Russians have been killed and 100 injured while taking selfies this year.
The most recent death occurred last week when a woman fell from a bridge in Moscow.
Police spokeswoman Yelena Alexeyeva said "along with the advantages of the modern world there are also new threats. We want to remind citizens that the pursuit of 'likes' in social media can put them on the road to death."
A police safety flyer in Russia shows the wrong way to take a selfie.
THE MINISTRY OF INTERNAL AFFAIRS OF THE RUSSIAN FEDERATION
The police will hand out its selfie-safety memo to students and at public events, according to the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs.
The U.S. is not immune to the dangers of selfies.
Earlier this month, the New York City Police Department responded to a Kentucky tourist who climbed the Brooklyn Bridge to take pictures of himself. And Disney theme parks banned selfie sticks citing safety concerns after a cellular self-portrait artist prompted a roller coaster to be shut down mid-ride.
Earlier this year, New York state imposed a new law effectively putting the kibosh on selfies with tigers by prohibiting direct contact with those and other big cats. Similar laws exist in a few other states, including Kansas, where a 17-year-old girl was killed by a tiger in 2005 while taking a photo with it.
CBS/AP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:05:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Death sentence for 24 ISIS fighters over Iraq massacre</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/iraq-court-sentences-death-isis-militants-camp-speicher-massacre-tikrit/</Link>
        <Description>Men were convicted of raiding army base near Tikrit during extremist group's 2014 sweep across Iraq and executing dozens of troops</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S.-led airstrikes targeted ISIS vehicles, heavy weapons and fighting positions around Tikrit. In Iraq, the U.S. is fighting on the same side as...
Ahead of the trial, the spokesman for Iraq's Supreme Judicial Council, Abdul-Sattar Bayrkdar, promised that "the trial will be transparent and fair."
He added that some 604 other militants, believed to have taken part in the killing, were still at large.
Following the retaking of Tikrit city three months ago, dozens of people linked to the massacre were arrested by Iraqi security forces. Iraqi forensic teams immediately started exhuming bodies from mass graves believed to contain some of the hundreds of soldiers killed by Islamic State militants.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:52:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cautious move toward peace deal with Taliban</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/afghanistan-taliban-peace-talks-important-step-pakistan/</Link>
        <Description>U.S. lauds "important step" after 1st official talks between Afghan gov't and militants toppled by American military</Description>
        <MainBody>General John Campbell fields questions from his troops, and from Lara Logan, about the United States' new mission in Afghanistan
Afghan Deputy Foreign Minister Hekmat Karzai, cousin of former Afghan President Hamid Karzai, led the four member Afghan government delegation which spoke face-to-face with three Taliban representatives in the Pakistani capital of Islamabad. Their goal is to lay the groundwork for formal peace negotiations, according to a senior Afghan official.
The talks, brokered by the Pakistani government, came after months of intense efforts by Afghan President Ashraf Ghani, who believes the Afghan-Pakistani relationship struggled through an "undeclared state of war" during Karzai's tenure. Representatives of the United States and China also attended the meeting, as observers.
"As part of the commitment to facilitate an Afghan-led and Afghan-owned peace and reconciliation process, a meeting was hosted by Pakistan between the Afghan Government and Tehreek-e-Taliban Afghanistan representatives," a statement from the Pakistani Foreign Ministry confirmed.
President Ghani, speaking to journalists, members of civil society and analysts at the presidential palace on Tuesday, said his government would "always talk from a position of strength, and will also make sure that women are fully represented in dialogues."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:09:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China builds wine country in its own desert</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/china-builds-wine-country-in-its-own-desert/</Link>
        <Description>Ningxia, about 500 miles west of Beijing, is home to more than 50 wineries</Description>
        <MainBody>China builds wine country in its own desert
July 8, 2015, 8:55 AM
|When you think of wine, France, Italy and California likely come to mind first, but China is getting to work on grapes in a big way. Ningxia, about 500 miles west of Beijing, is home to more than 50 wineries. Seth Doane reports on Chinas unlikely path to the vineyards.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:19:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What attracts daredevils to run with the bulls?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/what-attracts-daredevils-to-run-with-the-bulls/</Link>
        <Description>Two Americans are recovering after being gored by bulls Tuesday at the Pamplona festival in Spain</Description>
        <MainBody>What attracts daredevils to run with the bulls?
July 8, 2015, 7:43 AM
|Two Americans are recovering after being gored by bulls Tuesday at the Pamplona festival in Spain. Charlie D'Agata reports on why runners take the risks.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:09:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>German man's mission to empower deaf North Koreans</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/german-mans-mission-to-empower-deaf-north-koreans/</Link>
        <Description>Non-profit to fund first kindergarten for deaf in isolated nation, where disabilities often leave people house-bound due to misperceptions</Description>
        <MainBody>High school students in North Korea are taught a mistranslated version of "The Diary of Anne Frank." As Mike Wallace reports, Anne's plea for pea...
"From our point of view, every deaf child has access," he said. "Since this country strongly advertises the right of children to be in nurseries and kindergartens, it is probably not so much a matter of choosing, but a matter of information and spreading the word so that the families get to know the new option and dare to bring their deaf child, overcoming the traditional hiding in the family."
To be deaf in North Korea is to endure a level of isolation that is hard to imagine.
For most of his childhood, Ri Jong Hyok was a shut in.
While his father went out to do construction work, he stayed at home in Pyongyang helping his mother make tofu. He didn't go to school . He had no friends and, with no one to teach him sign language, essentially no way to communicate with them even if he did.
"I had never seen sign language before I came here," Ri told the AP through a sign language interpreter during a visit to the country's largest school for the deaf, in Songchon, outside of Pyongyang, last year.
Ri is lucky to have found the school.
He wants to be a barber, and the school has a classroom where the students practice cutting each other's hair, with barber's chairs and pictures of various hairstyles on the walls. With few other trades open to the deaf, the most common jobs are barber or tailor for men, and hairstylist or seamstress for women.
Of the eight schools for older deaf children in North Korea, none are located in Pyongyang, though statistically the deaf population in a city the same size in a developing country would likely be in the tens of thousands.
There are roughly 300,000 deaf people in all of North Korea, according to official estimates.
But while about 10-20 percent of deaf children in developing countries are able to study in deaf schools, according to the World Federation of the Deaf, that rate is just 2 percent in North Korea, said an aid worker who spoke on condition of anonymity because of worries that ongoing projects might be hurt.
North Korean officials dispute that estimate.
Ro Kyong Su, director of the Korean Economic and Cultural Center for the Deaf and Blind, said mainstream public schools or other special-needs facilities currently accommodate most deaf or hearing-impaired students. By his calculations, there are about 6,000 school-age deaf children who need to be in schools that are specifically for the deaf. He said about half already are, and the number is rising.
"The other half will soon be able to go to school. We aren't looking at a five-year or 10-year plan. It will be much sooner than that," he said.
Officials involved in projects for the deaf acknowledge an outdated grasp of the size of the deaf community.
A major problem continues to be getting access to and diagnosing pre-school children, many of whom are shut in at home with families who have little awareness of hearing disabilities or the resources that might be available to them.
The government's figures are also based on an old, somewhat ambiguous survey. Underreporting of disabilities is common, both because of a sense of shame and a fear among parents that, if reported, their children might be sent off to distant institutions, pigeonholed and channeled into an educational or career path with few opportunities. Nevertheless, a new survey is underway, which Ro believes will provide a more reliable picture.
Grund, possibly more than anyone else, has helped influence the change in attitudes toward the deaf here.
As a teenager, he watched a TV report in his native Germany suggesting there were "practically no" deaf people in North Korea. A fourth-generation deaf child in his own family, an incredulous Grund decided to go see for himself. Grund, now 30, has since devoted himself to improving life for deaf North Koreans. He works with the bureaucracy and with the deaf to train them to plan and lead their own projects.
Though funding is always a struggle, he has received support from Catholic and Protestant groups and private donors, mainly in Germany. The biggest individual contribution came from Michael Spavor, of Paektu Cultural Exchange and the organizer of former NBA star Dennis Rodman's visit last year , who donated $20,000 to the deaf kindergarten project.
Grund's mantra for empowering the deaf, "nothing about us without us," often rankles with even the most sympathetic North Korean officials. In the country's top-down system, hearing bureaucrats who often don't understand the deaf experience are used to making decisions on their behalf.
Grund says he will continue to cooperate with deaf North Koreans - he currently works closely with about 20, up from just two in 2013 - to help them join mainstream society.
One priority is more schools for occupational training and educational opportunities for the deaf. Another is teaching more deaf children - and interpreters - how to sign. He also wants sign language interpretation made available at workplaces and meetings. But most of all, he wants to see signing on national television broadcasts, if just to raise awareness in the hearing community that the deaf exist and need not be hidden away.
"That has been my oldest dream, from the time I first came here," he said.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:33:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China tries to stem plunging stock prices</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/china-tries-to-stem-plunging-stock-prices/</Link>
        <Description>the plunge is a domestic issue, not linked to the Greek debt crisis, but it has the potential to destabilize the world's second-largest economy</Description>
        <MainBody>China tries to stem plunging stock prices
July 8, 2015, 7:14 AM
|Turmoil in Chinese stock markets is causing pain for investors in the U.S. The plunge is a domestic issue, not linked to the Greek debt crisis, but it has the potential to destabilize the world's second-largest economy. Seth Doane reports from Beijing.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
