<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:50:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina governor signs bill to remove Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/south-carolina-legislature-passes-bill-to-remove-confederate-flag</Link>
        <Description>South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley signed legislation on Thursday to permanently remove the Confederate battle flag from the state capitol grounds, following an emotional debate spurred by the massacre of nine black churchgoers last month.</Description>
        <MainBody>'Hazzard' pulled amid Confederate flag debate
COLUMBIA, S.C. - South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley signed legislation on Thursday to permanently remove the Confederate battle flag from the state capitol grounds, following an emotional debate spurred by the massacre of nine black churchgoers last month.
Haley signed the bill into law in the State House Rotunda before an audience of legislators and dignitaries shortly after 4 p.m. EDT (2000 GMT), and her office said the flag would be taken down at 10 a.m. (1400 GMT) on Friday.
The flag will go to the "relic room" of a military museum in Columbia, the state capital.
The rebel banner, carried by Confederate troops in the 1861-1865 Civil War, is seen as a symbol of racism and slavery by many, while others proudly hail it as an emblem of Southern heritage. It has flown at the state capitol for 54 years.
South Carolina was planning to keep the flag relocation "as low-key as the national media will let us," said Haley spokeswoman Chaney Adams.
In Washington, Republican leaders in the U.S. House of Representatives abruptly canceled a vote on a measure to allow the flag to be flown in cemeteries operated by the National Park Service, after an outcry by opponents.
White House spokesman Josh Earnest described the bipartisan flag vote in South Carolina as a sign of "progress."
He added, "Republicans in Congress, however, seem to have values and priorities that lie elsewhere," reference to the park service bill.
The flag, carried by Confederate troops in the 1861-1865 Civil War, is seen as a symbol of racism and slavery by many, while others proudly hail it as an emblem of Southern heritage. It has flown at the state capitol for 54 years.
A small crowd gathered on Thursday on the State House lawn waving "Take Down the Flag" signs as drivers honked their horns.
Others snapped photographs on the last full day the banner will fly from its pole at a memorial to Confederate war dead.
"I love this," said Hammie Johnson. "It's about time people came to the realization of what that flag represents to us as African-Americans, and that's slavery."
He and his wife, Esther, watched the South Carolina House of Representatives debate the bill on television until the wee hours of the morning.
"We watched all of it, every last bit," he said.
Jim Felder, 76, one of the first blacks to be elected to state House, said he never thought he would live to see the flag come down.
"I'm so proud today. ... I thought maybe my grandchildren would get it down," he said.
He and others credited Haley with lobbying Republican representatives on Wednesday to pass the bill. "She was just trying to hold them together, like herding cats," he said, adding that he had new respect for the governor.
The House overwhelmingly approved the legislation after 1 a.m. EDT (0500 GMT) on Thursday. The Senate passed it earlier in the week, also by a huge margin.
In a statement, Haley said, "It is a new day in South Carolina, a day we can all be proud of, a day that truly brings us all together as we continue to heal, as one people and one state."
The NAACP welcomed the move, calling the flag "one of the longest standing symbols of hatred and exclusion."
NAACP President Cornell William Brooks in a statement applauded Haley "for her leadership and moral courage by changing her position and supporting the flag removal" after the June 17 slayings at a landmark Charleston church with a predominantly black congregation. A white man, Dylann Roof, is accused in the murders.
The 124-member House approved the bill 94-20 after 13 hours of sometimes rancorous debate and stiff opposition from some conservative white Republicans.
Opponents in the Republican-dominated chamber launched 60 amendments seeking to soften the impact of the flag's removal, such as hoisting a different Civil War-era battle flag.
As patience wore thin, a string of Democrats, both black and white, and some white Republicans, begged the House not to drag its feet any longer, warning that amending the bill could hold up passage for weeks.
"Are we going to tarry in the foolishness of 150 years ago?" said Cezar McNight, a Democrat Representative who is black.
Republican Representative Jenny Anderson Horne, who is white, turned her frustration on fellow party members. She invoked the memory of the nine victims, including their pastor, Reverend Clementa Pinckney, a widely admired state senator.
"If you cannot be moved by the suffering of the people of Charleston, you don't have a heart," she said, breaking down in tears.
As amendment after amendment failed, flag defenders grew exasperated, accusing opponents of lacking respect for their Southern heritage.
Representative Chris Corley, a white Republican, proposed substituting a white flag for the banner, accusing his party of surrendering to media pressure.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:52:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>5 injured in 3rd running of the bulls at Pamplona's San Fermin festival</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/5-injured-in-3rd-running-of-the-bulls-at-pamplonas-san-fermin-festival</Link>
        <Description>Five Spaniards were injured Thursday as thousands of people raced alongside fighting bulls in the third bull run of Pamplona's San Fermin festival.</Description>
        <MainBody>Two Americans gored in opening bull run in Spain
PAMPLONA, Spain -- Five Spaniards were injured Thursday as thousands of people raced alongside fighting bulls in the third bull run of Pamplona's San Fermin festival.
Navarra Hospital chief Dr. Javier Sesma said the five were treated for bruises but none was in serious condition.
No one was gored in the 8 a.m. run, which lasted two minutes, 27 seconds.
An Australian was gored Wednesday and two Americans and a Briton were gored in the first run Tuesday.
The nationally televised run sees people racing with six bulls, each weighing some 500 kilograms (1,100 pounds), along a narrow 930-yard (850-meter) course from a holding pen to the city bull ring.
On Thursday, one bull charged into a group of some 20 participants, tossing and butting many, but did not gore anyone. In another incident, a bull hurled a runner to the ground after hooking a horn in the man's T-shirt from behind.
The bulls are killed by professional matadors in bullfights each afternoon during the festival.
The nine-day fiesta, which features 24-hour street partying, was made famous in Ernest Hemingway's 1926 novel "The Sun Also Rises" and attracts thousands of foreign tourists.
Bull runs are a traditional part of summer festivals across Spain. Dozens are injured each year, mostly in falls.
Two men died recently after being gored by bulls in Spanish festivals -- one last Saturday in the eastern town of Grao de Castellon and another June 24 in the southwestern town of Coria.
In all, 15 people have died from gorings in Pamplona since record-keeping began in 1924 for the San Fermin festival.
Giles reported from Madrid.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:18:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three sisters hiking in Wyoming found two days after reported missing</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/us-officials-search-for-sisters-who-didnt-return-from-wyoming-camping-trip</Link>
        <Description>A helicopter crew rescued three sisters from a wilderness area in Wyoming on Thursday, two days after they had been reported missing when they failed to return from a backcountry hike, authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Three sisters hiking in Wyoming found two days after reported missing 0
Reuters
Thursday, July 9, 2015       2:18:19 EDT PM
This undated family photo released by the Teton County Sheriffs Office shows Megan Margaret Andrews-Sharer, centre, of Milwaukee; with sisters, Erin Andrews-Sharer, right, of Columbus, Ohio, and Kelsi Andrews-Sharer, of Columbus, Ohio. A search is being conducted in a northwest Wyoming wilderness area for the three sisters who failed to return Tuesday, July 7, 2015, from an extended backcountry trip. (Teton County Sheriffs Office via AP)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
A helicopter crew rescued three sisters from a wilderness area in Wyoming on Thursday, two days after they had been reported missing when they failed to return from a backcountry hike, authorities said.
The three were spotted by the helicopter on a divide between two creeks in the Gros Ventre Wilderness and the rescuers landed and confirmed they were the missing sisters, Lori Iverson, a spokeswoman for the multi-agency team conducting the search, said in an e-mail.
"They're tired, cold, hungry, but otherwise healthy and happy to be on their way out," said Iverson, who is with the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.
The hikers, 25-year-old Megan Andrews-Sharer and her two sisters, 22-year-old Erin and 16-year-old Kelsi, were reported missing on Tuesday after they went on a backpacking trip in the area, according to officials with the team conducting the search.
A helicopter crew found them 7 miles west of where Megan Andrews-Sharer's car was discovered on Wednesday at the Swift Creek Trailhead in the Bridger-Teton National Forest south of Jackson, Iverson said.
Some 60 people on Thursday joined in the search, which was conducted with the use of dogs, horses and two helicopters, authorities said.
The sisters were experienced hikers who likely made a wrong turn during their excursion in the wilderness, Teton County Sheriff Jim Whalen said in a news release before they were rescued. They were equipped with a tent, sleeping bags and a water purifier, according to the news release.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:58:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bull chases burglary suspect through cow pasture</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/bull-chases-burglary-suspect-through-cow-pasture</Link>
        <Description>A bull decided to horn in on the action as authorities chased a suspect in northern Alabama.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bull chases burglary suspect through cow pasture 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, July 9, 2015       1:58:16 EDT PM
(Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
ARAB, Ala. -- A bull decided to horn in on the action as authorities chased a suspect in northern Alabama.
Sheriff's officials in Marshall County say the burglary suspect was taken into custody after being chased by a bull through a cow pasture.
Marshall County Sheriff Scott Walls tells WHNT-TV 26-year-old Brad Lynn Hemby was being sought in connection with a burglary Wednesday morning in Arab.
Walls says Hemby tried fleeing deputies by running through a cow pasture and a bull roaming the land joined the chase. Walls says Hemby eventually fell onto a barbed wire fence and surrendered.
Walls says stolen property was recovered from Hemby's truck and the man is charged with burglary, theft and attempting to elude. It's unclear if he has an attorney.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:43:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Life for Bourbon St. dancer's  murder, dismemberment</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/life-for-bourbon-st-dancers--murder-dismemberment</Link>
        <Description>A man convicted of murdering a Bourbon Street dancer and dismembering her body in 2012 will spend the rest of his life in prison, a state court judge said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Life for Bourbon St. dancer's  murder, dismemberment 0
Kathy Finn, REUTERS
Thursday, July 9, 2015       1:43:59 EDT PM
Terry Speaks. (Kenner Police Department/HO)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
NEW ORLEANS - A Louisiana man convicted of murdering a Bourbon Street dancer and dismembering her body in 2012 will spend the rest of his life in prison, a state court judge said on Thursday.
Judge Stephen Grefer imposed the mandatory life sentence on Terry Speaks, 42, after denying Speaks' motion for a new trial, the judge's law clerk, Suzanne Ciaccio, said.
Speaks filed the new trial request on Monday, arguing the judge had not asked him about his mental health before allowing him to represent himself at trial.
Speaks, who claims he once tried to kill himself and was diagnosed with a borderline personality disorder, clumsily handled his own defence through one day of jury selection and opening statements before asking that his court-appointed public defender step back in.
The four-day trial featured grisly evidence, including photos of slain dancer Jaren Lockhart's body parts.
Prosecutors said Speaks and his then-girlfriend, Margaret Sanchez, went to Temptations Gentlemen's Club in New Orleans' French Quarter on June 6, 2012, and offered Lockhart, 22, hundreds of dollars to go with them to a private party.
Speaks and Sanchez took Lockhart to their home in nearby Kenner, La., stabbed her to death and cut up her body, prosecutors said, and then drove to Mississippi and threw her remains off a bridge near the Gulf Coast. Body parts began washing up on coastal beaches the next day.
In 2014, a grand jury charged Speaks and Sanchez with second-degree murder, obstruction of justice and conspiracy to obstruct justice. In addition to the life sentence for the murder count, the judge imposed sentences of 40 years and 20 years, respectively, on Speaks for the obstruction charges.
Grefer scheduled the trial of Sanchez, 31, for Dec. 7, Ciaccio said.
Speaks already is serving an eight-year prison sentence for failing to register in Jefferson Parish as a sex offender following a 2003 conviction in North Carolina for having sex with a minor.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:14:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bodies of men killed in South Carolina fighter jet crash found</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/bodies-of-men-killed-in-south-carolina-fighter-jet-crash-found</Link>
        <Description>The bodies of a 30-year-old pilot and his father, killed when their private plane crashed with an Air Force fighter jet, have been found, South Carolina officials said Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bodies of men killed in South Carolina fighter jet crash found 0
Reuters
Thursday, July 9, 2015       1:14:43 EDT PM
Emergency personnel from Berkeley County stand outside a campground surrounded by police tape near Moncks Corner, S.C., Tuesday, July 7, 2015, after an F-16 fighter jet smashed into a small plane over South Carolina. (Brad Nettles/The Post and Courier via AP)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
The bodies of a 30-year-old pilot and his father, killed when their private plane crashed with an Air Force fighter jet, have been found, South Carolina officials said Thursday.
Joseph Johnson and his father, Michael Johnson, 68, died on Tuesday when an F-16 fighter jet on a training mission to Charleston, S.C., collided with their Cessna 150.
Their bodies were recovered on Wednesday in the Cooper River near the crash site, Berkeley County Coroner Bill Salisbury told Reuters.
Preliminary results from the autopsies were expected to be available on Thursday afternoon, with final results and toxicology reports to follow within six weeks, he said.
The pilot of the fighter jet, Maj. Aaron Johnson, ejected from his plane and survived the crash. He was flying out of Shaw Air Force Base in Sumter on a routine training flight.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:16:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>KKK wants to 'adopt' a highway; Appeals court to hear suit</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/kkk-wants-to-adopt-a-highway-appeals-court-to-hear-suit</Link>
        <Description>A Georgia appeals court will hear arguments on Thursday in a Ku Klux Klan chapter's lawsuit against the state for refusing the white supremacist group's application to "adopt" a stretch of highway.</Description>
        <MainBody>KKK gets OK for pro-Confederate flag rally
ATLANTA - A Georgia appeals court will hear arguments on Thursday in a Ku Klux Klan chapter's lawsuit against the state for refusing the white supremacist group's application to "adopt" a stretch of highway.
The KKK chapter, backed by the American Civil Liberties Union, sued Georgia in 2012 after it refused to let it join the state's adopt-a-highway program, which involves volunteers picking up trash and planting trees along designated sections of road. Logos of participating groups appear on signs along the highways.
Georgia officials cited public safety concerns when they denied the application, telling the Klan chapter that erecting a sign with its name could lead to social unrest and distract drivers.
The court takes up the case at a time of soul-searching across the U.S. South about race relations. Lawmakers in neighbouring South Carolina are debating whether to remove the Confederate battle flag from the statehouse grounds, a longstanding demand of those who see it as a racist symbol.
The issue was resurrected after the massacre of nine African Americans at a Charleston church. The white man charged with the murders posed with the flag on a website featuring a racist diatribe.
Georgia's reasons for denying the application by International Keystone Knights of the Ku Klux Klan Inc were "frivolous" and designed to "shift their duty to uphold free speech to a court," the lawsuit said.
"We decided to take this case because it is such a clear violation of the speech rights of the group," said Debbie Seagraves, who was executive director of the Georgia ACLU when the suit was filed. "We can't let that slide."
In court documents, Georgia argues that letting the Klan participate would amount to the state's endorsement of the Klan's beliefs, since road signs are a "quintessential method used by governments to communicate with the public."
A county judge last year refused a motion to dismiss the lawsuit and the state appealed to the Georgia Court of Appeals, which will hold oral arguments Thursday.
In 1997, Missouri rejected a similar request from a Klan chapter on the grounds that the group's membership rules discriminated against non-whites.
A federal appeals court ruled that requiring such a group to alter its membership requirements to qualify for the adopt-a-highway program would "censor its message and inhibit its constitutionally protected conduct."
The case is the State of Georgia et al. v. International Keystone Knights of the Ku Klux Klan Inc. et al.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:52:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jeb Bush says Americans should have chance to work longer hours</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/jeb-bush-says-americans-should-have-chance-to-work-longer-hours</Link>
        <Description>Republican presidential candidate Jeb Bush said Americans should have the chance to work longer hours, a remark that drew criticism from Democrats but which he said was intended to highlight that an improved U.S. economy could create more full-time jobs.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jeb Bush outlines immigration position in N.H.
HUDSON, New Hampshire - Republican presidential candidate Jeb Bush said Americans should have the chance to work longer hours, a remark that drew criticism from Democrats but which he said was intended to highlight that an improved U.S. economy could create more full-time jobs.
Bush told a forum hosted by the Union-Leader newspaper of Manchester that his aspiration for the country if he is elected in November 2016 would be to generate annual 4% economic growth "as far as the eye can see, which means we have to be a lot more productive."
"Workforce participation has to rise from its all-time modern lows," Bush said. This means, he said, "that people need to work longer hours and through their productivity gain more income for their families."
The Democratic National Committee quickly pounced on the comment as being out of touch with the concerns of ordinary Americans. Democrats were successful in making that charge against 2012 Republican nominee Mitt Romney, and would like to do the same with Bush.
"It is easily one of the most out-of-touch comments we've heard so far this cycle. Jeb Bush would not fight for the middle class as president," DNC spokeswoman Holly Shulman said in a statement.
Bush was asked about the comment by reporters after a town hall event in Hudson. He said the U.S. economy needs to grow far faster than currently to allow people to move from part-time work to full-time so they can better provide for their families.
"You can take it out of context all you want, but high sustained growth means people work 40 hours rather than 30 hours and that by our success they have disposable income for their families to decide how they want to spend it rather than standing in line and being dependent upon government," he said.
Bush frequently cites the need to improve what he calls a weak Obama economy. In June, the U.S. economy generated 223,000 jobs and the jobless rate dropped to 5.3%, but the reduction had much to do with people leaving the workforce. The labour participation rate dropped to 62.6%, the lowest since 1977, and average hourly earnings did not rise.
"If anyone is celebrating this anemic recovery, then they are totally out of touch," Bush said. "The simple fact is people are really struggling. So giving people a chance to work longer hours has got to be part of the answer. If not, you are going to see people lose hope. And that's where we are today."
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:51:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baby dies after being left inside SUV</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/baby-dies-after-being-left-inside-suv</Link>
        <Description>Police in South Florida say an 11-month-old baby died after being left inside a sport utility vehicle parked outside their apartment near Fort Lauderdale.</Description>
        <MainBody>Baby dies after being left inside SUV 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, July 9, 2015       10:51:43 EDT AM
(Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
LAUDERHILL, Fla. -- Police in South Florida say an 11-month-old baby died after being left inside a sport utility vehicle parked outside their apartment near Fort Lauderdale.
Lauderhill police spokesman Gregory Solowsky says the baby's parents and four other children were unloading groceries on Wednesday afternoon and forgot to get the baby out of the vehicle. He says about an hour later, they realized the baby wasn't in the house. They returned to the Ford Explorer and found the baby inside.
They called 911 and began CPR. But the child was unresponsive.
Solowsky says paramedics continued to administer CPR on the way to the hospital, but the child was declared dead Wednesday evening.
He says the parents are being co-operative with the investigation and that the entire family is extremely distraught.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:40:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Car crash victims waited 3 days for help?</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/car-crash-victims-waited-3-days-for-help</Link>
        <Description>Police in Scotland have launched an investigation after a couple was found in a crashed car three days after reports of a crash near a busy highway.</Description>
        <MainBody>Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
LONDON -- Police in Scotland have launched an investigation after a couple was found in a crashed car three days after reports of a crash near a busy highway.
Authorities say that a dead man and seriously injured woman were found off the roadway in the car on Wednesday near the city of Stirling. An investigation is underway into the failure to follow up reports of a crash on Sunday morning.
Assistant Chief Constable Kate Thomson says in a statement that "for reasons currently being investigated, that report was not followed up at the time."
The injured woman is in critical condition in a hospital in Glasgow.
The accident is believed connected to an ongoing missing persons investigation involving 28-year-old John Yuill and 25-year-old Lamara Bell, who were last seen on Sunday.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:21:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cops killed man for threatening to throw rock: Officer</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/09/cops-killed-man-for-threatening-to-throw-rock-officer</Link>
        <Description>A Washington state man was holding a large rock and drew back his arm as if he was going to throw it when police officers opened fire and killed him, one of the officers said in a recording released Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Officer who shot farm worker had aided him in fire
SPOKANE, Wash. -- A Washington state man was holding a large rock and drew back his arm as if he was going to throw it when police officers opened fire and killed him, one of the officers said in a recording released Wednesday.
Pasco police officer Adam Wright said he decided to shoot because he feared officers or members of the public would be injured or killed by the rock wielded by 35-year-old Antonio Zambrano-Montes, a Mexican national.
"I had a clear shot and I decided to take it," Wright said in a May 8 interview with authorities investigating the shooting.
The recording and documents in the case were released by Franklin County authorities in response to public records requests by The Associated Press and other media. Other documents and recordings were released last week.
The killing of Zambrano-Montes on Feb. 10 was captured on video and sparked weeks of protests in the central Washington city of 68,000 residents.
Franklin County Prosecutor Shawn Sant is deciding whether the three officers who shot Zambrano-Montes should face criminal charges.
The three officers fired a total of 17 shots at Zambrano-Montes, striking him seven times.
Wright told investigators that he watched Zambrano-Montes throw one large rock at officers that missed and then transfer another rock from his left to his right hand.
"He's reloading into his throwing hand," Wright recalled thinking. "I was not willing to let him continue threatening us."
Wright said he fired twice and believed both bullets struck Zambrano-Montes. But the former orchard worker continued walking, with three officers in pursuit.
Zambrano-Montes stopped again, turned toward the officers and cocked his arm in a throwing motion, Wright told investigators.
"It was clear to me he was going to throw the rock," Wright said.
Wright shot again multiple times, and the other two officers also fired, and Zambrano-Montes dropped to the ground. A rock lying next to his body weighed 2.8 pounds, investigators found.
In the documents released last week, police and eyewitnesses described Zambrano-Montes repeatedly yelling at officers to shoot him. Toxicology reports also showed he had a large amount of methamphetamine in his system.
Authorities contend Zambrano-Montes had been throwing rocks at passing motorists and police, and a stun gun failed to subdue him before he was shot. Cellphone video showed three officers chasing the man before shooting him as he turned around.
One officer, Ryan Flanagan, has resigned in a move his lawyer has said was unrelated to the shooting. The other two, Wright and Adrian Alaniz, remain on paid leave.
Flanagan and Alaniz also said in previously released documents that they felt they had little choice but to shoot.
Attorney George Trejo Jr., who represents Zambrano-Montes' estranged wife and daughter, has said the prosecutor should charge the officers immediately with either first- or second-degree murder.
In another audio file, the shooting victim's aunt Angelita Zambrano told investigators her nephew had broken both his hands after falling from a ladder in a farm field.
He was depressed and in a lot of pain because of the injury, she said. Still, he told her two days before he was shot that he planned to start work again the following week.
"Why did they kill him like that when they had other options?" she asked investigators. "He wasn't going to kill them with rocks."
The Tri-City Herald reported Wednesday that police interviews with several relatives of Zambrano-Montes portrayed him as a troubled soul.
Those interviews detailed his bouts with depression and drug abuse, several suicide attempts and violent run-ins with Pasco police in recent years, the newspaper reported.
He had been drinking heavily and using methamphetamine more often since his wife left for California with their two daughters several years ago, the newspaper said, citing the family.
His mental state had deteriorated so severely that his family wanted to take the orchard worker back to his parents' remote village in Michoacan state, Mexico, to get his life back on track, the newspaper reported.
No one answered the telephone Wednesday when the AP called the law office of Benjamin Crump, who represents the parents of Zambrano-Montes.
Associated Press reporter Julie Watson in San Diego contributed to this report.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:11:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>London's transit system grinds to halt as subway workers strike</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/londons-transit-system-grinds-to-halt-as-subway-workers-strike</Link>
        <Description>Many London commuters left work early Wednesday to beat the start of a strike that's expected to shut down the city's subway system.</Description>
        <MainBody>London's transit system grinds to halt as subway workers strike 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       3:11:10 EDT PM
Commuters at Earls Court underground station, awaiting the arrival of a train, attempt to complete their journey on Wednesday evening, in London, Britain, July 8, 2015. A strike by staff and drivers on London's underground train network later on Wednesday, which is set to chaos travel misery for millions of commuters, is "unacceptable and unjustified", a spokesman for Prime Minister David Cameron said.  REUTERS/Peter Nicholls
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
LONDON -- Many London commuters left work early Wednesday to beat the start of a strike that's expected to shut down the city's subway system.
Drivers and station staff were walking out for 24 hours from 6:30 p.m. in a dispute over pay and schedules when a 24-hour subway service starts on some lines later this year.
Subway operator Transport for London says so many drivers are expected to participate that it will be impossible to run any trains during the walkout. In past strikes, management managed to keep a few lines running.
The Underground handles 4 million journeys a day, and the strike by members of four unions will likely paralyze the capital's transport system, despite extra bus and river services.
Union officials accused management of failing to negotiate seriously, but London Mayor Boris Johnson branded the strike "totally unnecessary, cynically timed and politically motivated."
Prime Minister David Cameron's spokeswoman, Helen Bower, described the strike as "unacceptable and unjustified."
"It's going to hit families, workers and businesses across the capital," she said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:22:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italian police seize US$1.77B of assets in mafia bust</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/italian-police-seize-us177b-of-assets-in-mafia-bust</Link>
        <Description>Italian police seized assets worth more than 1.6 billion euros (US$1.77 billion) on Wednesday from five Sicilian siblings suspected of links to the island's Cosa Nostra mafia, in one of the biggest ever such operations.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italian police seize US$1.77B of assets in mafia bust 0
Wladimiro Pantaleone, Reuters
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       1:22:29 EDT PM
The Palermo division of Italy's dedicated anti-mafia police (DIA) have seized dozens of bank accounts, motor vehicles and 800 buildings one of the biggest the busts in the 20-year history of the DIA. REUTERS/Alessandro Bianchi
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
PALERMO, Italy - Italian police seized assets worth more than 1.6 billion euros (US$1.77 billion) on Wednesday from five Sicilian siblings suspected of links to the island's Cosa Nostra mafia, in one of the biggest ever such operations.
The three Virga brothers and two sisters - described as "businesspeople" from the area around Sicily's main city Palermo - allegedly received help from Italy's most storied criminal group to receive construction contracts related to public works.
There was no immediate comment from the Virga family.
The Palermo division of Italy's dedicated anti-mafia police (DIA) said they had seized dozens of bank accounts, motor vehicles and some 800 buildings including houses and factories.
"Today's seizure is certainly one of the biggest the DIA has carried out in its 20-year history," vice chief of DIA operations Adelmo Lusi told a news conference.
"The (1.6 billion euro) sum is enormous for a family unit that until 30 years ago was made up of carpenters, manual labourers and housewives."
Italy has battled for decades against criminal organizations that run personal fiefdoms, especially in the poorer south, and three years of recession have helped corruption to flourish.
Cosa Nostra - or "Our Thing" - was the country's most powerful mafia group in the 1980s and 1990s, but has since been overtaken by the Naples-based Camorra and the Calabrian 'Ndrangheta organizations.
The Virgas allegedly collaborated with Cosa Nostra to share out public works contracts among their businesses, 30 of which have been seized, police said.
The family, which also had links to jailed mob boss Salvatore "Toto" Riina, had reported alleged mafia extortion attempts in the past, but the police said they believed this was a ruse aimed at covering their tracks.
"The attempt by the mafia to become the anti-mafia ... was pure strategy," Palermo DIA director Riccardo Sciuto said.
Italy ranked 69th of 177 countries in global anti-corruption group Transparency International's 2014 Corruption Perceptions Index. Italy, a founder member of the European Union, ranked joint worst among EU member states along with Greece, Romania and Bulgaria.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police search for identity of U.S. girl found dead in Boston Harbor</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/police-search-for-identity-of-us-girl-found-dead-in-boston-harbor</Link>
        <Description>In her computer-generated image, she is the picture of innocence: a four-year-old girl with long brown hair, chubby cheeks and expressive brown eyes. The image has reached a staggering 47 million people on Facebook as investigators try to identity the child whose remains were found on a Boston Harbor beach nearly two weeks ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Police search for identity of U.S. girl found dead in Boston Harbor 0
Denise Lavoie, The Associated Press
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       12:43:20 EDT PM
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BOSTON -- In her computer-generated image, she is the picture of innocence: a four-year-old girl with long brown hair, chubby cheeks and expressive brown eyes. The image has reached a staggering 47 million people on Facebook as investigators try to identity the child whose remains were found on a Boston Harbor beach nearly two weeks ago.
The mystery of Baby Doe began on June 25, when a woman walking her dog reported finding a trash bag containing the girl's body. The child was wearing white leggings with black polka dots. Inside the bag with her remains was a zebra-print blanket.
Police immediately appealed to the public for help in identifying the girl. Using photos of her remains, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children created a composite image of what the girl may have looked like when she was alive.
After that image and photos of the leggings and blanket were posted on the Massachusetts State Police Facebook page, investigators were astonished by the attention the posting received. As of Wednesday morning, the post had been liked by more than 50,000 people and shared more than 615,000 times.
But authorities still haven't identified the girl.
Adding to the mystery is that investigators still haven't been able to figure out how she died. There were no obvious signs of trauma to her body, and an autopsy performed by the state medical examiner's office did not determine the manner or cause of her death.
Prosecutor Daniel Conley said Tuesday that authorities are awaiting the results of toxicology tests to determine if the girl was poisoned or ingested drugs.
Conley said the outpouring of support by people who have shared the girl's image on social media is gratifying and gives him confidence that her identity eventually will be determined.
During a news conference Tuesday, Conley spoke directly to the girl's parents or caretakers: "Please step forward, clear your conscience and help us identify this young child."
Her death and the mystery surrounding her identity have touched a chord in many people. People from the U.S., Canada and Puerto Rico have shared the posting, with many of them expressing sorrow or anger over the girl's death.
"How can someone just throw a child away?" wrote one woman from Arizona.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:10:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boston science museum now says error caught by teen isn't an error</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/boston-science-museum-now-says-error-caught-by-teen-isnt-an-error</Link>
        <Description>A Boston science museum that praised a teenager for catching a mistake in the golden ratio at a decades-old exhibit now says it wasn't an error after all.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boston science museum now says error caught by teen isn't an error 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       12:10:03 EDT PM
In this June 23, 2015 photo, John Handley High School sophomore Joseph Rosenfeld poses for a photo at the school in Winchester, Va. Rosenfeld discovered a decades-old math error that had gone unnoticed at the Museum of Science in Boston during a visit in June, but the museum now says the equation is actually correct. Jeff Taylor/The Winchester Star via AP
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BOSTON -- A Boston science museum that praised a teenager for catching a mistake in the golden ratio at a decades-old exhibit now says it wasn't an error after all.
The Museum of Science released a statement Tuesday afternoon saying the equation in the 34-year-old "Mathematica exhibit" with minus signs instead of plus signs is actually the "less common -- but no less accurate -- way to present it."
The museum had initially written 15-year-old Virginia high school student Joseph Rosenfeld a letter acknowledging the error and saying it would be fixed. He noticed the minus signs June 4 on a family visit to the museum.
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Professor Emeritus Arthur Mattuck tells the Boston Globe that the two formulas are equal. He says Joseph presented the fraction upside-down.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
