<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:11:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>London's transit system grinds to halt as subway workers strike</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/londons-transit-system-grinds-to-halt-as-subway-workers-strike</Link>
        <Description>Many London commuters left work early Wednesday to beat the start of a strike that's expected to shut down the city's subway system.</Description>
        <MainBody>London's transit system grinds to halt as subway workers strike 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       3:11:10 EDT PM
Commuters at Earls Court underground station, awaiting the arrival of a train, attempt to complete their journey on Wednesday evening, in London, Britain, July 8, 2015. A strike by staff and drivers on London's underground train network later on Wednesday, which is set to chaos travel misery for millions of commuters, is "unacceptable and unjustified", a spokesman for Prime Minister David Cameron said.  REUTERS/Peter Nicholls
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
LONDON -- Many London commuters left work early Wednesday to beat the start of a strike that's expected to shut down the city's subway system.
Drivers and station staff were walking out for 24 hours from 6:30 p.m. in a dispute over pay and schedules when a 24-hour subway service starts on some lines later this year.
Subway operator Transport for London says so many drivers are expected to participate that it will be impossible to run any trains during the walkout. In past strikes, management managed to keep a few lines running.
The Underground handles 4 million journeys a day, and the strike by members of four unions will likely paralyze the capital's transport system, despite extra bus and river services.
Union officials accused management of failing to negotiate seriously, but London Mayor Boris Johnson branded the strike "totally unnecessary, cynically timed and politically motivated."
Prime Minister David Cameron's spokeswoman, Helen Bower, described the strike as "unacceptable and unjustified."
"It's going to hit families, workers and businesses across the capital," she said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:22:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italian police seize US$1.77B of assets in mafia bust</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/italian-police-seize-us177b-of-assets-in-mafia-bust</Link>
        <Description>Italian police seized assets worth more than 1.6 billion euros (US$1.77 billion) on Wednesday from five Sicilian siblings suspected of links to the island's Cosa Nostra mafia, in one of the biggest ever such operations.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italian police seize US$1.77B of assets in mafia bust 0
Wladimiro Pantaleone, Reuters
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       1:22:29 EDT PM
The Palermo division of Italy's dedicated anti-mafia police (DIA) have seized dozens of bank accounts, motor vehicles and 800 buildings one of the biggest the busts in the 20-year history of the DIA. REUTERS/Alessandro Bianchi
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
PALERMO, Italy - Italian police seized assets worth more than 1.6 billion euros (US$1.77 billion) on Wednesday from five Sicilian siblings suspected of links to the island's Cosa Nostra mafia, in one of the biggest ever such operations.
The three Virga brothers and two sisters - described as "businesspeople" from the area around Sicily's main city Palermo - allegedly received help from Italy's most storied criminal group to receive construction contracts related to public works.
There was no immediate comment from the Virga family.
The Palermo division of Italy's dedicated anti-mafia police (DIA) said they had seized dozens of bank accounts, motor vehicles and some 800 buildings including houses and factories.
"Today's seizure is certainly one of the biggest the DIA has carried out in its 20-year history," vice chief of DIA operations Adelmo Lusi told a news conference.
"The (1.6 billion euro) sum is enormous for a family unit that until 30 years ago was made up of carpenters, manual labourers and housewives."
Italy has battled for decades against criminal organizations that run personal fiefdoms, especially in the poorer south, and three years of recession have helped corruption to flourish.
Cosa Nostra - or "Our Thing" - was the country's most powerful mafia group in the 1980s and 1990s, but has since been overtaken by the Naples-based Camorra and the Calabrian 'Ndrangheta organizations.
The Virgas allegedly collaborated with Cosa Nostra to share out public works contracts among their businesses, 30 of which have been seized, police said.
The family, which also had links to jailed mob boss Salvatore "Toto" Riina, had reported alleged mafia extortion attempts in the past, but the police said they believed this was a ruse aimed at covering their tracks.
"The attempt by the mafia to become the anti-mafia ... was pure strategy," Palermo DIA director Riccardo Sciuto said.
Italy ranked 69th of 177 countries in global anti-corruption group Transparency International's 2014 Corruption Perceptions Index. Italy, a founder member of the European Union, ranked joint worst among EU member states along with Greece, Romania and Bulgaria.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police search for identity of U.S. girl found dead in Boston Harbor</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/police-search-for-identity-of-us-girl-found-dead-in-boston-harbor</Link>
        <Description>In her computer-generated image, she is the picture of innocence: a four-year-old girl with long brown hair, chubby cheeks and expressive brown eyes. The image has reached a staggering 47 million people on Facebook as investigators try to identity the child whose remains were found on a Boston Harbor beach nearly two weeks ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Police search for identity of U.S. girl found dead in Boston Harbor 0
Denise Lavoie, The Associated Press
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       12:43:20 EDT PM
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BOSTON -- In her computer-generated image, she is the picture of innocence: a four-year-old girl with long brown hair, chubby cheeks and expressive brown eyes. The image has reached a staggering 47 million people on Facebook as investigators try to identity the child whose remains were found on a Boston Harbor beach nearly two weeks ago.
The mystery of Baby Doe began on June 25, when a woman walking her dog reported finding a trash bag containing the girl's body. The child was wearing white leggings with black polka dots. Inside the bag with her remains was a zebra-print blanket.
Police immediately appealed to the public for help in identifying the girl. Using photos of her remains, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children created a composite image of what the girl may have looked like when she was alive.
After that image and photos of the leggings and blanket were posted on the Massachusetts State Police Facebook page, investigators were astonished by the attention the posting received. As of Wednesday morning, the post had been liked by more than 50,000 people and shared more than 615,000 times.
But authorities still haven't identified the girl.
Adding to the mystery is that investigators still haven't been able to figure out how she died. There were no obvious signs of trauma to her body, and an autopsy performed by the state medical examiner's office did not determine the manner or cause of her death.
Prosecutor Daniel Conley said Tuesday that authorities are awaiting the results of toxicology tests to determine if the girl was poisoned or ingested drugs.
Conley said the outpouring of support by people who have shared the girl's image on social media is gratifying and gives him confidence that her identity eventually will be determined.
During a news conference Tuesday, Conley spoke directly to the girl's parents or caretakers: "Please step forward, clear your conscience and help us identify this young child."
Her death and the mystery surrounding her identity have touched a chord in many people. People from the U.S., Canada and Puerto Rico have shared the posting, with many of them expressing sorrow or anger over the girl's death.
"How can someone just throw a child away?" wrote one woman from Arizona.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:10:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boston science museum now says error caught by teen isn't an error</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/boston-science-museum-now-says-error-caught-by-teen-isnt-an-error</Link>
        <Description>A Boston science museum that praised a teenager for catching a mistake in the golden ratio at a decades-old exhibit now says it wasn't an error after all.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boston science museum now says error caught by teen isn't an error 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       12:10:03 EDT PM
In this June 23, 2015 photo, John Handley High School sophomore Joseph Rosenfeld poses for a photo at the school in Winchester, Va. Rosenfeld discovered a decades-old math error that had gone unnoticed at the Museum of Science in Boston during a visit in June, but the museum now says the equation is actually correct. Jeff Taylor/The Winchester Star via AP
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BOSTON -- A Boston science museum that praised a teenager for catching a mistake in the golden ratio at a decades-old exhibit now says it wasn't an error after all.
The Museum of Science released a statement Tuesday afternoon saying the equation in the 34-year-old "Mathematica exhibit" with minus signs instead of plus signs is actually the "less common -- but no less accurate -- way to present it."
The museum had initially written 15-year-old Virginia high school student Joseph Rosenfeld a letter acknowledging the error and saying it would be fixed. He noticed the minus signs June 4 on a family visit to the museum.
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Professor Emeritus Arthur Mattuck tells the Boston Globe that the two formulas are equal. He says Joseph presented the fraction upside-down.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:55:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore police say three dead in shooting near University of Maryland</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/baltimore-police-say-three-dead-in-shooting-near-university-of-maryland</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen killed three people and wounded one overnight near the University of Maryland, police said on Wednesday, the latest killings in a city that has seen an upturn in homicides following the death of Freddie Gray.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cops face October trial for Freddie Gray death
Gunmen killed three people and wounded one overnight near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, police said on Wednesday, the latest killings in a city that has seen an upturn in homicides following the death of Freddie Gray in April.
Two gunmen emerged from two vans and began shooting just before 11 p.m. on Tuesday, campus police said in a statement.
A man died at the scene, Baltimore police said, and a man and a woman died while receiving medical treatment. The fourth victim, a woman, was hospitalized.
"Three to four suspects are believed to be involved at this time. This was not a random act of violence but was a targeted incident," police said in a statement.
The shooting was not related to the university, the statement said. The Baltimore Sun reported that shots had been fired into a vehicle traveling on the same block five days ago.
The shootings came as Baltimore is grappling with an upsurge in killings following the death of Gray, a 25-year-old black man, from an injury suffered in police custody.
His death triggered protests and a day of rioting and arson. Police said looting of pharmacies during the unrest and a subsequent drug turf war was behind a surge in killings in May.
Police had originally recorded 43 homicides in May, the highest number since 1972, but dropped the total to 42 when one killing was reclassified as justified. A police spokeswoman on Wednesday put the May homicide number at 41, the highest monthly tally since August 1990, without explaining the new total.
Baltimore, a largely black city of about 620,000 people, has notched 155 homicides this year, compared with 105 for the same period last year, the spokeswoman said.
Police said on Tuesday the Police Executive Research Forum, a non-profit policy group, would evaluate the department's performance during the April unrest.
Police had said the Forum and the International Association of Chiefs of Police would take part in the department's internal review. The Baltimore police union also released an after-action report on Wednesday.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:47:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>	Weapon used in San Francisco pier slaying belonged to federal agent: Report</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/mexican-in-san-francisco-pier-slaying-had-been-deported-five-times-sheriff-blames-immigration-authorities</Link>
        <Description>A law enforcement official says the weapon used in the shooting death of a woman on a San Francisco pier belonged to a federal agent -- the latest twist in a case that has become a flashpoint in America's debate over immigration.</Description>
        <MainBody>San Francisco shooter says gun fired 'on its own'
SAN FRANCISCO -- A law enforcement official says the weapon used in the shooting death of a woman on a San Francisco pier belonged to a federal agent -- the latest twist in a case that has become a flashpoint in America's debate over immigration.
The shooting has touched off criticism from leading Republican lawmakers and from top Democrats, including both of California's U.S. senators.
The official, who had been briefed on the matter, said Tuesday that a check of the gun's serial number shows it belonged to a federal agent. The official -- who was not authorized to speak publicly about the case and spoke on condition of anonymity -- declined to elaborate.
The San Francisco Police Department, which is investigating the case, refused to comment on the disclosure.
The suspect, Juan Francisco Lopez Sanchez, has been deported to his native Mexico five times and is suspected of living in the United States illegally when Kathryn Steinle, 32, was gunned down last week while strolling with her father along San Francisco's popular waterfront area.
Federal officials transferred Sanchez to San Francisco's jail in March to face a 20-year-old marijuana charge after he completed his latest prison term for entering the U.S. illegally.
The San Francisco sheriff, citing the city's "sanctuary city" policy, released Sanchez in April after prosecutors dropped the drug charge, despite an Immigration and Customs Enforcement request to hold him for federal authorities so deportation proceedings could begin.
Sanchez pleaded not guilty Tuesday to first-degree murder.
He told two television stations who interviewed him in jail that he found the gun used in Steinle's killing wrapped in a shirt on the pedestrian pier she was walking on. Sanchez said the gun went off in his hands, and his public defender, Matt Gonzalez, said Tuesday that the San Francisco woman's death appeared accidental.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:17:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gun-shaped phone case 'a disaster waiting to happen': N.Y. senator</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/08/gun-shaped-phone-case-a-disaster-waiting-to-happen-ny-senator</Link>
        <Description>New York Sen. Charles Schumer says a cellphone case that looks like a gun is a "disaster waiting to happen."</Description>
        <MainBody>Gun-shaped phone case 'a disaster waiting to happen': N.Y. senator 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Wednesday, July 8, 2015       11:17:28 EDT AM
A New York senator says that a phone case shaped like a gun (not pictured) is a bad idea. Charles Schumer says advertisements make the look like a real weapon when displayed in a pocket. (Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
New York Sen. Charles Schumer says a cellphone case that looks like a gun is a "disaster waiting to happen."
Schumer is urging online retailers to stop selling it.
Amazon told The New York Times on Tuesday night that the item was no longer listed on its site.
Law enforcers in New York and elsewhere have been expressing concerns about the foreign-manufactured product for weeks.
Schumer says the case lacks a required, highly visible orange marking that identifies it as harmless.
The senator says advertisements indicate it can be displayed in a pocket, as if it's a real weapon.
He says the case also can be used with a Russian roulette app that transforms the phone's screen into the image of a gun barrel.
I would NOT suggest purchasing this cell phone case, which was designed to look like a firearm. #BeSmart #BeSafe pic.twitter.com/swsWzD1sdY
 NYPD 112th Precinct (@NYPD112Pct) June 30, 2015
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:20:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Subway pitchman Jared Fogle a suspect in child porn case: CBS</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/subway-pitchman-jared-fogles-home-raided-in-child-porn-investigation-report</Link>
        <Description>Subway sandwich chain pitchman Jared Fogle is a suspect in a child pornography investigation that led to the raid of his home on Tuesday, CBS News reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
ZIONSVILLE, Ind. - Authorities conducted a day-long search inside the Indiana home of Subway sandwich chain pitchman Jared Fogle on Tuesday, two months after the executive director of Fogle's foundation was arrested on federal child pornography charges.
As authorities concluded their search for the day, a law enforcement source told CBS News that Fogle was a suspect in the child pornography federal investigation.
Subway said it was suspending its relationship with Fogle due to the investigation, which the company said it believed was linked to the probe of a former foundation executive.
"Jared continues to cooperate with authorities and he expects no actions to be forthcoming," Subway said in a statement. "Both Jared and Subway agree that this was the appropriate step to take."
Subway &amp; Jared Fogle have agreed to suspend their relationship due to the current investigation. Jared is cooperating with authorities.
 SUBWAY (@SUBWAY) July 7, 2015
By early evening on Tuesday, promotional references to Fogle had been removed from Subway's website.
Authorities were observed on Tuesday removing numerous items from Fogle's home, carrying them out in bags, boxes and briefcases. Fogle was present for part of the search, but he left his home in the Zionsville suburb northwest of Indianapolis around midday as the search continued.
Authorities, who first arrived at the home about 6:30 a.m., ultimately pulled out around 5 p.m.
It was not clear whether Fogle, a father of two, is a target of what authorities have said is a joint investigation by local, state and federal law enforcement.
FBI spokeswoman Wendy Osborne declined to comment about the activity at Fogle's home, other than to confirm investigative efforts in the area. She said she could not discuss whether the actions at Fogle's home were connected to the child porn case against Russell Taylor, the former foundation executive.
Fogle's attorney said Fogle has not been detained or arrested or charged "with any crime or offense."
"Jared has been cooperating, and continues to cooperate, with law enforcement in their investigation of unspecified charges and looks forward to its conclusion," attorney Ron Elberger said in a statement.
A neighbor who asked not to be identified by name said Fogle and his family had lived in their home for about four years and generally were very "private."
Fogle became a Subway spokesman after losing a reported 245 pounds (111 kg) in part by eating regularly at the sandwich chain. Fogle made his first Subway commercial in 2000 and appeared in a new one last year, according to Subway.
Along with the FBI, the Indiana State Police assisted the U.S. Attorney's Office for the Southern District of Indiana in the investigation, according to state police spokesman Sergeant Richard Myers. U.S. Postal Service agents also assisted in the investigation.
Taylor, the Jared Foundation's former executive director, is currently in federal custody facing seven counts of production of child pornography and one count of possession of child pornography. He has not yet entered a plea, said his attorney Brad Banks.
Banks would also not comment on the investigation.
Authorities said they found videos they believe Taylor produced by secretly filming minor children at his home. The investigators said they found more than 400 videos of alleged child pornography in his Indianapolis home.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 22:07:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Washington state's popular ice caves collapse, leaving one dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/washingtons-popular-ice-caves-collapse-leaving-one-dead-several-injured</Link>
        <Description>Rescue workers were preparing on Tuesday to recover the body of a woman killed in the partial collapse of an ice cave in Washington state that also injured five others, but the cavern was too dangerous to enter, an official said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Washington state's popular ice caves collapse, leaving one dead 0
Reuters
Tuesday, July 7, 2015       3:07:24 EDT PM
In this July 2010 photo, visitors examine the Big Four Ice Caves in the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest near Granite Falls, Wash. The Snohomish County sheriff's office says rescuers responded to a report of a partial collapse of the ice caves Monday, July 6, 2015. Mark Mulligan/The Herald via AP
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
Rescue workers were preparing on Tuesday to recover the body of a woman killed in the partial collapse of an ice cave in Washington state that also injured five others, but the cavern was too dangerous to enter, an official said.
The Snohomish County Sheriff's Office said two men and a woman were airlifted on Monday from the Big Four Ice Caves near Granite Falls, some 40 miles north of Seattle, to nearby hospitals with serious injuries.
Two girls with less serious injuries were driven to a local hospital. Sheriff's Office spokeswoman Shari Ireton said they believed everyone had been accounted for.
Officials had earlier warned that the caves, which host a popular hiking trail and are part of the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest, were too treacherous to explore due to unseasonably warm weather.
"They are essentially a frozen-over avalanche chute sitting over a waterfall sitting below a giant rock chute. It's incredibly dangerous," Ireton said.
She said rescue workers could not enter the cave safely and crews were planning how to recover the victim's body, which was at the back of the cave.
Ireton said because of poor cell phone reception in the area, the first call came in about 45 minutes after the collapse. The area will be closed to the public indefinitely, she said.
Chloe Jakubowski, 18, told the Seattle Times newspaper that she and her friends were inside the caves when they heard a loud crack before the ice started to fall.
"As soon as it stopped I looked up and looked around me and it was extremely gruesome, honestly," Jakubowski, who had only minor injuries, told the newspaper. "Everybody there, we grabbed everybody out and helped as best we could."
In May, the U.S. Forest Service warned hikers against entering the Big Four Ice Caves after several sections collapsed in unusually warm spring temperatures.
"The cave is in a condition that we would normally not see until at least September - large, inviting and collapsing," Lead Field Ranger Matthew Riggen said.
Falling ice has long been a danger to hikers in the region during warmer months, officials said. In 2010, an 11-year-old girl was killed near the caves when she was struck by a chunk of ice, forest officials said.
***WARNING: Video contains foul language***
On mobile? Click here to watch the video
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 20:14:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suspect in Charleston church shooting indicted on 9 murder counts</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/suspect-in-charleston-church-shooting-indicted-on-9-murder-counts</Link>
        <Description>Dylann Roof, the suspect in last month's massacre at an African-American church in Charleston, S.C., has been indicted by a grand jury on nine counts of murder and three counts of attempted murder, the prosecutor said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Suspect in Charleston, awaits bond hearing
Dylann Roof, the suspect in last month's massacre at an African-American church in Charleston, S.C., has been indicted by a grand jury on nine counts of murder and three counts of attempted murder, the prosecutor said on Tuesday.
Roof, a 21-year-old white man linked to racist views, is charged in the June 17 shooting rampage at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church, where nine black people were killed.
Roof had already been charged by state warrants with the nine murder counts and one count of possessing a weapon during the commission of a violent crime. Three additional attempted murder charges related to people who survived the shooting were presented to the grand jury, prosecutor Scarlett Wilson said in a statement.
Wilson declined to comment further.
Authorities say Roof spent an hour in an evening Bible study group at the church before opening fire.
Federal investigators have been examining a racist manifesto on a website that appears to have been written by Roof. The site featured a white supremacist screed and photos, apparently of Roof, posing with the Confederate battle flag at Civil War landmarks.
The massacre has brought fresh attention to the divisive issues of race relations and crime in the United States and reignited a debate over gun control in a country where the right to own firearms is protected by the U.S. Constitution.
On Tuesday, the South Carolina Senate passed legislation to remove the Confederate battle flag that flies at the statehouse grounds and has long been denounced by critics as a symbol of white supremacy. Supporters of the flag deny it has a racist meaning and say it symbolizes the South's heritage.
The bill must pass the state House of Representatives before it can be enacted.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 19:36:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Birds mysteriously disappear from largest colony on Florida's Gulf Coast</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/birds-mysteriously-disappear-from-largest-colony-on-floridas-gulf-coast</Link>
        <Description>Biologists are trying to find the reason thousands of nesting birds have abandoned Seahorse Key off Florida's Gulf Coast.</Description>
        <MainBody>Birds mysteriously disappear from largest colony on Florida's Gulf Coast 0
Jason Dearen, The Associated Press
Tuesday, July 7, 2015       12:36:35 EDT PM
In this Friday, June 19, 2015 photo, a variety of birds gather in branches at Snake Key, Fla., near Seahorse Key, off Floridas Gulf Coast. In May, Seahorse Key fell eerily quiet, as thousands of birds suddenly disappeared, and biologists are trying to find the reason why. (AP Photo/John Raoux)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
SEAHORSE KEY, Fla. -- Biologists are trying to find the reason thousands of nesting birds have abandoned Seahorse Key off Florida's Gulf Coast.
The little blue herons, roseate spoonbills, snowy egrets, pelicans and other birds left the island all at once in May.
U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service biologist Vic Doig said what was once the largest bird colony on the state's Gulf Coast is now a "dead zone." Scientists have found no indication that disease, contaminants or predators are to blame.
The abandonment concerns biologists because it could have a ripple effect: Many bird species here return year after year to the same nesting sites.
Biologists also don't know how the disappearance will affect the island's other animals, some of which rely on the birds to survive.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 19:33:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain pays tribute to 7/7 victims 10 years after London bombings</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/britain-pays-tribute-to-77-victims-10-years-after-london-bombings</Link>
        <Description>Britain held a minute of silence on Tuesday to mark the 10th anniversary of al-Qaida-inspired attacks in which four suicide bombers killed 52 people across London's transport system.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia identifies all 38 hotel attack victims
LONDON - Britain held a minute of silence on Tuesday to mark the 10th anniversary of al-Qaida-inspired attacks in which four suicide bombers killed 52 people across London's transport system.
The commemoration came just four days after the country came to a standstill to mourn a massacre of mainly British tourists at a resort in Tunisia last month.
The government and security services warned the threat of further attacks remains severe.
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly - the murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism," Prime Minister David Cameron said in a statement.
Relatives of the victims, survivors, royals and senior politicians fell silent as they remembered those killed in the bombings.
In the early hours of July 7 2005, less than 24 hours after it was announced London would host the 2012 Olympic Games, four young British Muslims travelled from northern England to the capital, where they detonated homemade bombs hidden in rucksacks on three underground trains and a bus during the morning rush-hour.
They killed themselves and 52 other people and wounded around 700 others. Citizens from Poland, Israel, Australia, France, Italy, Afghanistan, Nigeria, New Zealand and a Vietnamese-American were among the victims.
On Tuesday, Cameron and London mayor Boris Johnson stood silently, heads bowed, before laying wreaths at the 7/7 memorial in Hyde Park, where victims' families and survivors were later joined by Prince William, Queen Elizabeth's grandson.
The main service of remembrance took place at St Paul's Cathedral, where petals fell from the cathedral's dome and the names of those killed were read out.
SILENCE
At underground stations where victims were brought to the surface, floral tributes were laid on Tuesday on steps leading down to the platforms.
Esther Hyman, 46, whose sister Miriam was killed on the No. 30 bus when it was blown up at Tavistock Square, told Reuters many young people seemed unaware of the bombings.
"The events of 7/7 do seem to have slipped out of public consciousness," said Hyman, who with her mother last week launched a program to help teach school pupils about the attacks and to steer them away from violent extremism.
Britain is currently on its second highest alert level of "severe", meaning a militant attack is considered highly likely, mainly due to the danger the authorities say is posed by Islamic State fighters and Britons who have joined them.
Cameron's government is planning new laws to combat extremism among the country's 2.8 million Muslims and to give security services extra surveillance powers. Critics say these are an assault on freedoms.
Mark Rowley, Britain's most senior counter-terrorism police officer, said Islamic State was creating an "enormous" list of potential targets, focused on propaganda value rather than high-impact complex attacks.
"The terrible events in London on 7 July, 2005 are enduring reminders of the reality of what MI5 is striving every day to prevent," Andrew Parker, head of Britain's domestic spy agency, said in a statement.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 19:10:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lost dog walks 35 miles, nine days to find its way home</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/lost-dog-walks-35-miles-nine-days-to-find-its-way-home</Link>
        <Description>A lost dog made its way 35 miles (56.3 km) home from Los Penasquitos Canyon Preserve to find its owner asleep in bed.</Description>
        <MainBody>High-flying dog Bruno finally reunited with owners
CARLSBAD, Calif. -- A lost dog made its way 35 miles (56.3 km) home from Los Penasquitos Canyon Preserve to find its owner asleep in bed.
The San Diego Union-Tribune reports that Kris Anderson was told she should give up on finding her lost dog, Georgia, after it took off over a hill June 27. Anderson and her daughter drove to the preserve and home to Carlsbad every day in hopes of finding the eight-year-old Shar Pei mix.
But at 8:30 Monday morning, Anderson was asleep at home when Georgia burst into the bedroom and joined her in bed.
Veterinarian Luis Lizarraga, who examined Georgia says the dog is in remarkable shape for what it endured, including predators, traffic, a torrential rainstorm and Fourth of July fireworks.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 18:05:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two Americans gored in opening bull run of Spain's San Fermin festival</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/two-americans-gored-in-opening-bull-run-of-spains-san-fermin-festival</Link>
        <Description>Two Americans and a Briton were gored and eight others injured Tuesday in the first bull run of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, organizers said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Two Americans gored in opening bull run of Spain's San Fermin festival 0
Alvaro Barrientos And Ciaran Giles, THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Tuesday, July 7, 2015       11:05:33 EDT AM
People watch as Jandilla fighting bulls and revelers run during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival, in Pamplona, Spain, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Revelers from around the world arrive to Pamplona every year to take part in some of the eight days of the running of the bulls. AP Photo/Andres Kudacki
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
PAMPLONA, Spain -- Two Americans and a Briton were gored and eight others injured Tuesday as thousands of daredevils dashed alongside fighting bulls through the streets of this northern Spanish city on the first bull run of the San Fermin festival, organizers said.
The San Fermin press office said a 38-year-old American identified only by his initials, M.W.O., was gored in the armpit and a 27-year-old Californian identified by the initials D.M.O. was also gored. A 30-year-old Briton with the initials A.B.O. was gored in the groin area. None of the three was said to be in serious condition.
Three other Americans were among the eight others injured, most with bruises sustained in falls and crowd crushes during the nationally-televised run that lasted just over two minutes.
In its first report after the run, the Spanish Red Cross only had details of one person being gored and six people injured.
The daily run sees people dashing with six bulls along a narrow, 930-yard (850-metre) course from a holding pen to the city's bull ring. The bulls are then killed by professional matadors in bullfights each afternoon. The nine-day fiesta in Pamplona, which features 24-hour street partying, was made famous in Ernest Hemingway's 1926 novel "The Sun Also Rises" and attracts thousands of foreign tourists.
Bull runs are a traditional part of summer festivals across Spain. Dozens of people are injured each year in the runs, most in falls.
Two men have died recently after being gored by bulls in Spanish festivals -- one Saturday in the eastern town of Grao de Castellon and another June 24 in the southwestern town of Coria.
In all, 15 people have died from gorings in San Fermin since record-keeping began in 1924.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:59:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosives stolen from army base in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/explosives-stolen-from-army-base-in-france</Link>
        <Description>Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 attacks foiled in France since Hebdo killings
MARSEILLE - Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.
The theft came even though France has heightened security after a suspected Islamist beheaded his boss and tried to blow up a gas plant near Lyon on June 26. Six months earlier, gunmen killed 17 people at the offices of satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo and a Jewish foodstore in January.
The Marseille prosecution office has begun an investigation into the robbery, which was discovered on Monday. France's defence ministry ordered a review of the army's military supplies and the protection of ammunition storage units.
The Miramas site serves as a logistical base for the French army's external operations, the source said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
