<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="dailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:42:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hackers stole 21.5 million Social Security numbers in data breach, US says</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150709/hackers-stole-215-million-social-security-numbers-in-data-breach-us-says</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Hackers stole 21.5 million Social Security numbers in data breach, US says
By Jack Gillum, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
WASHINGTON &gt;&gt; The Obama administration says hackers stole Social Security numbers from more than 21 million people and took other sensitive information when government computer systems were compromised.
The Office of Personnel Management says more than 19 million who had applied for background investigations were affected. The government also said nearly 2 million people were also affected who werent applicants, but rather their spouses or other family members.
The number affected by the breach is higher than the 14 million figure that investigators gave The Associated Press last month. They said the government was increasingly confident that Chinas government, and not criminal hackers, was responsible for the extraordinary theft of personal information.
China has publicly denied involvement in the break-in.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turns out people get angry when you say white Americans are terrorists, too</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150709/turns-out-people-get-angry-when-you-say-white-americans-are-terrorists-too</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Turns out people get angry when you say white Americans are terrorists, too
A handout photo provided by the Charleston County Sheriffs Office Detention Center, shows Dylann Storm Roof after he was apprehended as the main suspect in the mass shooting at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church that killed nine people on June 18, 2015 in Charleston, South Carolina. Charleston County Sheriffs Office/Getty Images
By Timothy McGrath, GlobalPost
Let us run a headline by you.
White Americans are the biggest terror threat in the United States.
That was the headline of an article we published in late June about a new study that found non-Muslim extremists in the United States had killed nearly twice as many Americans since 9/11 as Muslim jihadists. Many of the non-Muslim extremists  whom well just call terrorists from now on  were motivated by right-wing anti-government beliefs or white supremacist ideologies. Nearly all of them were white US citizens.
Some readers saw what we were trying to do and applauded it. We were stating one of the studys key findings about who was actually committing deadly acts of terrorism on US soil. We chose to describe those terrorists as white Americans not just because they were Americans and they were white, but because we were highlighting how the study unraveled a common post-9/11 assumption about terrorism in the United States  that its mainly the work of Muslims and foreigners. Its not.
Other readers were mad. Really mad.
Some of them objected to our decision to call the terrorists white Americans instead of some white Americans or white American extremists. Without qualifying the term, they argued, we were claiming that ALL white Americans were a terror threat. Other readers worried that the headline, though correct, was unnecessarily divisive. Some thought it was unfair to focus on racial data when the studys summary didnt call attention to it.
Other readers reported us to Facebook for posting hate speech. They called us racists and race-baiters. They said we were ignoring white genocide. They asked why were werent talking about black-on-white crime. One person threatened to file a discrimination lawsuit.
It was a powerful reaction, and one we thought merited more discussion. So lets take a closer look at the study and why we framed our story the way we did.
What does the study tell us about terrorism?
The New America study, which defines extremist violence or terrorism as the use of violence in pursuit of any political ideology, drew on court documents and news reports to compile a database of information about individuals who had either carried out acts of terrorism in the United States or had been charged with a terrorism-related crime since 9/11.
Advertisement
The study split the terrorists into two categories. There were the jihadists  people who worked with or were inspired by Al Qaeda and its affiliated groups  and the non-jihadists, who were motivated by other ideologies that are non-Jihadist in character, for example right wing, left wing, or idiosyncratic beliefs. The vast majority of the non-jihadists were anti-government extremists and/or white supremacists.
New America identified 479 people who had been arrested or charged with plotting or carrying out an act of terrorism, or who had died while committing the act. The number included 296 jihadists and 183 non-jihadists. Looking at deadly terror attacks, the study found seven were carried out by jihadists, killing a total of 26 people. There were 19 attacks by non-jihadists, which killed 48 people. (These were the statistics when we published our article on June 24, 2015. New America has been updating the database.)
Like many other news organizations , GlobalPost chose to highlight in our report the finding that, since 9/11, terrorists motivated by anti-government or white supremacist ideologies have killed nearly twice as many people in the United States as terrorists motivated by radical Islamic beliefs.
When you start looking at the actual human beings lumped into jihadist and non-jihadist categories, two things become obvious.
First, the jihadists are all Muslims. You already knew that, of course, because the category implies it. But its quite a diverse group, actually, in terms of race, ethnicity and nationality. Its likely these individuals also have a range of beliefs and motivations that end up getting reduced to an abstract notion of Islamic jihad.
Just as clear is the fact that most of the non-jihadists are white  166 out of 183 of them. If religion is the thing that unites the racially and ethnically diverse group of jihadists, then its race that unites the cohort of non-jihadist terrorists.
It makes sense that white people would be responsible for violent acts motivated by white supremacist beliefs. Take Wade Michael Page, who shot and killed six people at a Sikh temple in Wisconsin on Aug. 5, 2012. Before the shooting, he publicly associated with neo-Nazi and white supremacist groups, and was vocal about his beliefs. It shouldnt come as a shock, then, to learn that Page was white.
But consider the case of Andrew Joseph Stack. He was an anti-government, anti-tax extremist who flew a small plane into the IRS building in February 2010, killing himself and an IRS employee. He was white, too. But unlike white supremacist violence, theres nothing that necessarily links anti-government violence with whiteness  except that nearly all the people who have carried out deadly attacks motivated by anti-government ideologies have been white, and many of them shared both anti-government views and racist ones.
These findings arent surprising to people who study extremist violence.
Theres an acceptance now of the idea that the threat from jihadi terrorism in the United States has been overblown, John Horgan, a terrorism expert at the University of Massachusetts Lowell, told The New York Times . And theres a belief that the threat of right-wing, antigovernment violence has been underestimated.
The Department of Homeland Security released an intelligence assessment in February warning about the violent threat of sovereign citizen extremists  anti-government radicals who consider any form of government encroachment into their lives, including things as routine as traffic stops, a violation of individual liberty.
The DHS warned that law enforcement would be the main target of sovereign citizen violence, which was most likely to occur during routine law enforcement encounters at a suspects home, during enforcement stops and at government offices.
Keep in mind, these arent people who become violent during police encounters because theyre trying to escape capture  theyre people committing acts of violence rooted in ideology. Theyre committing acts of terrorism.
The DHS wasnt saying anything that state and local law enforcement didnt already know. According to a DHS-funded survey published in 2014 by the National Consortium for the Study of Terrorism and Responses to Terrorism (START), law enforcement agencies considered sovereign citizen extremists the most dangerous terror threats in the United States  ahead of foreign Islamic extremists.
How many people associate themselves with a movement that law enforcement agencies consider the most dangerous terror threat in the United States? The Southern Poverty Law Center estimates that there are as many as 300,000 people affiliated with the sovereign citizen movement living in the United States, although its hard to know for sure, since its a very diffuse movement without centralized leadership and organizations.
According to the SPLC, the movement has roots in white supremacy and anti-Semitism, although its recently attracted people of color, too, and its anti-government ideology is a big tent that can fit people of all regions, classes, and races. That said, New Americas data show that the vast majority of lethal terrorist attacks carried out by sovereign citizens were carried out by white Americans.
So if sovereign citizens are the biggest terror threat facing the United States, in the view of law enforcement, then its worth acknowledging that the most deadly members of that cohort, thus far, have been white Americans.
Consider all these findings together:
Non-jihadist terrorists, nearly all of them white Americans, have killed more people in the United States than jihadists have since 9/11.
Non-jihadist terrorists, including those who failed to kill or who were arrested before committing an act of terrorism, were nearly all white Americans.
The deadliest of the countrys sovereign citizen extremists, whom some in law enforcement consider the most dangerous terror threat facing the United States, have been white Americans.
Terror threats posed by violent white supremacist and neo-Nazi groups can only, by the logic of their own ideology, be made up of white Americans.
Its fair to contend, then, that white Americans are the biggest terror threat facing the United States.
This is just one way of measuring terror threat, of course. If you decide to include the extraordinary attacks on 9/11, which New America did not, then everything changes. If you decide to focus just on arrests for terrorism-related crimes, everything changes, too. An attack could happen in the future that changes everything.
But if, as we have done, youre choosing to define terror threat in terms of the number of terrorists who have killed people since 9/11, in terms of the threat posed by ideologies that motivated them, and in terms of racial demographics  then the terrorist youre looking for is much more likely to be a white American than anybody else.
Why say white Americans are the terror threat?
Most importantly, its what the numbers say. It also runs counter to the accepted wisdom that weve gotten from law enforcement, news media, and popular culture that Muslims and foreigners are the main practitioners of terrorism and the gravest terror threat facing the United States.
Its easy to see how that happened. Al Qaeda killed almost 3,000 people on 9/11. The United States subsequent military operations in Afghanistan and Iraq  and more limited counterterrorism operations in Pakistan, Somalia, and Yemen  have meant the US public has spent over a decade imagining the enemy to be a foreign Muslim man with an AK-47 or a suicide vest. Combine that with a 24-hour news cycle that privileges simple narratives over nuance, and with policymakers who have too often shown a lack of knowledge about the history, politics, and cultures of the places where the US wages war and sees threats  and youre looking at some entrenched, perpetually reinforced stereotypes about Muslims, Islam, and terrorism.
These stereotypes have shaped how we understand terrorism in the United States, including how we defend against it and how we talk about it.
Take domestic counterterrorism policy. Even though law enforcement acknowledges the terror threat posed by sovereign citizen groups and white supremacists, its Muslim Americans who have been the primary targets of post-9/11 surveillance.
As a Pulitzer Prize-winning investigation by the Associated Press showed , the New York Police Department worked with the FBI and CIA to create a secret Demographics Unit tasked with monitoring and infiltrating mosques, spying on Muslim students and collecting data on Muslims living in the city. There was no probable cause, no reasonable suspicion of wrongdoing. This was profiling, pure and simple. After six years, the NYPD closed the unit. It had never produced a lead or an arrest.
That NYPD unit was just one part of a counterterrorism strategy focused on Muslim Americans. Law enforcement agencies have developed networks of informants in mosques that help them monitor community members for radicalization. The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) has been given legal latitude when it comes to using racial and religious profiling to screen airline passengers. And theres evidence in the documents leaked by Edward Snowden that the National Security Agency (NSA) spied on the communications of prominent Muslim Americans.
Weve also seen how Muslim stereotypes influence Americas public conversations about ideological violence.
Lets look back again at Andrew Joseph Stacks suicide attack on the IRS building. That was an act of ideological violence. It would be reasonable to call it terrorism. But news media and state officials didnt just neglect to call it that  they specifically suggested in early reports that it was not terrorism.
Two F-16 fighter jets were sent from Houston as a precaution, CNN reported , but federal authorities said preliminary information did not indicate any terrorist connection.
The DHS released an early statement to the public that, whatever else the attack might have been, it probably wasnt terrorism.
We do not yet know the cause of the plane crash, it read. At this time, we have no reason to believe there is a nexus to terrorist activity. We continue to gather more information, and are aware there is additional information about the pilots history.
You could say officials and journalists were doing the responsible thing not jumping to conclusions. But doesnt it seem possible the attack wasnt immediately suspected as terrorism because the man flying the plane didnt fit the profile of a terrorist?
A similar thing is happening in the aftermath of the church shooting in Charleston, South Carolina. Dylann Roofs internet paper trail has lead journalists and hate group monitors to his website The Last Rhodesian, a racist manifesto; photos of him posing with the Confederate battle flag and a gun; and comment threads on a neo-Nazi website called the Daily Stormer. Witnesses also heard Roof make racist statements during his rampage. And yet, Americans cant seem to agree on whether what he did was terrorism, in addition to being a hate crime.
Roofs mass shooting sparked renewed controversy over the continued importance of the Confederate battle flag to some white Southerners. While that debate has gone on, eight historic black churches have burned . At least two of the fires have already been ruled arson.
If it is what it seems to be, will we call it terrorism? Will we call the people who did it terrorists?
What the data collectors think
So what did New America think of how we framed our story about their work?
To find out, GlobalPost spoke with David Sterman, a program associate in New Americas International Security Program who works on the database.
It certainly gets at one striking aspect of the data, Sterman told GlobalPost: That many, or almost all, of the right-wing extremists we look at who have committed deadly attacks are white men, whereas looking at jihadist extremists more broadly, jihadist extremists tend to be a much more diverse grouping.
He did see some problems, though. He said our choice to highlight race as a category created a racial binary that didnt account for the racial diversity among jihadists.
Also, things change over time, he noted. Prioritizing a frame along racial lines can potentially miss that change.
Sterman also thought our choice of focusing on deadly attacks might have meant we missed other stories in the data.
Tracking deadly attacks is important and provides critical information, he said. But you cant really judge either the total threat from different groups or the character of the movement from the subset of deadly attacks.
In the end, GlobalPost was making a decision about how to interpret, frame, categorize, and label New Americas data, and thats a process Sterman knows well himself.
There are certainly lots of questions over how to label ideologies, he said when explaining how New America chose to categorize their own findings. The study of this form of extremism is really underdeveloped. Theres plenty of room for other ways of tallying up these counts and trying to determine what political ideology ties them together, whether the ideologies are all similar, whether they change over time. Certainly, theres a question there.
The headline
White Americans are the biggest terror threat in the United States is one of many reasonable ways to frame an interpretation of New Americas data. Its the one we chose at GlobalPost.
And Sterman is right. By prioritizing race, we limited the stories we could tell about the data. There are many stories that the data could help tell  about law enforcement, gender, guns, and other important things.
But that was the story we told, and we hope this article explains the facts underlying the frame  and why it was an important, if provocative, response to the stereotypes and assumptions about terrorism that saturate American news, culture, and policy.
This article originally appeared on GlobalPost .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:36:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Facebook makes it easier to tweak what you see in your feed</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/media/20150709/facebook-makes-it-easier-to-tweak-what-you-see-in-your-feed</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Social media
Facebook makes it easier to tweak what you see in your feed
This product image provided by Facebook shows the News Feed Preferences setting within the Facebook app for iPhone. Facebook via AP
By Barbara Ortutay, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; Facebook wants you to see more of what you want to see.
New tools will help you weed through the clutter of boring, unwanted information, often from long-forgotten acquaintances, and surface the gems from close friends and interesting pages.
Youll now be able to choose the friends and pages you want to see on your news feed first each time you log on.
To do this, go to the friends profile. Click on the box that says following and select see first.
Facebooks computer software uses a wide range of information you provide to decide what to show. This includes what friends you interact with and how often, or whether you tend to like photos, videos or text updates more.
In announcing the new tools Thursday, Facebook acknowledged that its automated system isnt perfect, so it wants to give users a way to set their own preferences.
In addition to selecting who or what page you will see first, youll still to be able to unfollow friends so you wont see them at all. This option has been available before to people who dont want to take drastic step of unfriending someone but would rather not read about their lives.
For the rest, though, Facebook will continue to use its software to choose what to show you. So unless you want to see someones posts all the time or not at all, youre stuck with what youve got.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:35:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NASA picks 4 astronauts to fly 1st commercial space missions</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/science/20150709/nasa-picks-4-astronauts-to-fly-1st-commercial-space-missions</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Space exploration
NASA picks 4 astronauts to fly 1st commercial space missions
Astronauts Robert Behnken, left, Eric Boe, Douglas Hurley and Sunita Williams have been selected by NASA to fly the first commercial space missions. (NASA via AP)
By Marcia Dunn, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. &gt;&gt; NASA has selected four veteran astronauts to lead the way back into orbit from U.S. soil.
On Thursday, NASA Administrator Charles Bolden named the four who will fly on capsules built by private companies  SpaceX and Boeing. Each astronaut has test pilot experience and has flown twice in space.
The commercial crew astronauts are: Air Force Col. Robert Behnken, until recently head of the astronaut office; Air Force Col. Eric Boe, part of shuttle Discoverys last crew; retired Marine Col. Douglas Hurley, pilot of the final shuttle crew; and Navy Capt. Sunita Williams, a two-time resident of the International Space Station.
These distinguished, veteran astronauts are blazing a new trail, a trail that will one day land them in the history books and Americans on the surface of Mars, Bolden said on his blog.
SpaceX and Boeing are aiming for test flights to the space station by 2017. It will be the first launch of astronauts from Cape Canaveral, Florida, since the space shuttles retired in 2011.
In the meantime, NASA has been paying Russia tens of millions of dollars per ride on Soyuz spacecraft to ferry astronauts; the latest tab is $76 million.
Bolden noted that the average cost on an American-owned spacecraft will be $58 million per astronaut, and each mission will carry a crew of four versus three, in addition to science experiments.
The four  who will work closely with the companies to develop their spacecraft  range in age from 44 to 50, and have been astronauts for at least 15 years. Each attended test pilot school; Williams specializes in helicopters.
NASA said the four were chosen for their spaceflight experience. They have a combined total of more than 400 days in space, thanks largely to Williams two station stints, and more than 85 hours of spacewalking time. Williams  the world record-holder for most spacewalking time by a woman  most recently lived on the orbiting lab in 2012.
NASAs contracts with SpaceX and Boeing for crew capsules  totaling nearly $7 billion  require at least one test flight with at least one NASA astronaut on board.
Bolden himself a former space shuttle commander  noted that July has always been a big month for NASA.
The first manned moon landing, by Apollo 11s Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin, occurred on July 20, 1969. NASA got its first close-up pictures of Mars, thanks to Mariner 4, on July 14, 1965, and the robotic Pathfinder landed on Mars on July 4, 1997.
Advertisement
And on Tuesday  the 50th anniversary of Mariner 4s flyby  the New Horizons spacecraft will sweep past Pluto on the first-ever close flyby of the dwarf planet.
John Holdren, director of the White House office of science and technology policy, said Tuesdays commercial crew selection will move America closer to President Barack Obamas goal of sending astronauts to Mars in the 2030s.
NASA already is hiring out supply runs to the space station and wants to do the same with crew transport, so it can focus on getting astronauts out of low-Earth orbit and on to Mars and other destinations. NASA is developing its own new spacecraft, the Orion, for those longer journeys.
The announcement comes just 1 weeks after SpaceXs failed launch to the space station with cargo. The Dragon capsule lost atop the Falcon 9 rocket that broke up shortly after liftoff on June 28 is a smaller, simpler version of what will be used to carry astronauts to the space station. NASAs other commercial shipper, Orbital Sciences Corp., also is grounded because of a failed launch dating back to last fall.
Boeings yet-to-fly craft is called the CST-100 for Crew Space Transportation and 100 kilometers, the threshold of space. A real name is forthcoming, according to Boeing officials.
Online:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:34:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>California Gov. Brown to meet with pope on climate change</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/environment-and-nature/20150709/california-gov-brown-to-meet-with-pope-on-climate-change</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>California Gov. Brown to meet with pope on climate change
By The Associated Press
# Comments
SACRAMENTO &gt;&gt; California Gov. Jerry Brown announced Thursday that he is heading to Vatican City to discuss climate change and modern slavery with dignitaries including Pope Francis.
Brown plans to attend a two-day event starting July 21 hosted by the Pontifical Academies of Sciences and Social Sciences.
The focus is on two issues highlighted in the popes recent teaching document, called an encyclical, in which he chastised international lawmakers for failing to adopt effective, long-term policies that would protect the environment and help those who suffer most from global warming.
Brown, a one-time Jesuit seminarian, has been pushing for greater efforts to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. This week he spoke at the Climate Summit of the Americas in Toronto, Canada.
In the spirit of the popes encyclical, this unprecedented gathering of global leaders is a wake-up call to face up to the common threats of climate change and human exploitation, Brown said in a statement. This is about the future of humanity and how we as human beings live and treat one another and the natural world around us.
The Vatican event will be attended by the pope, representatives of the United Nations and mayors and governors from around the world.
The meeting of local and regional officials comes as national governments attempt to reach an agreement to reduce emissions before they gather in Paris for the United Nations Climate Change Conference in December.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Now it's serious! Venezuela is almost out of beer</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150709/now-its-serious-venezuela-is-almost-out-of-beer</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Now its serious! Venezuela is almost out of beer
Crates of Venezuelas national beer could become the latest victim of shortages. Mario Tama/Getty Images
By Simeon Tegel, GlobalPost
# Comments
LIMA, Peru  Throughout their countrys descent into political and economic crisis , Venezuelans of all stripes have at least been able to rely on one thing: drowning their sorrows in beer.
Locals of the sweltering South American nation love to down the kinds of heavily chilled light lagers popular from Mexico to Argentina.
But pretty soon Venezuela could run dry. And that could be even more devastating than it sounds.
How did it come to this?
For one, brewery workers are on strike demanding higher wages.
Members of the Sintraterricentro union downed tools last week at two bottling plants belonging to the Polar brewery. It supplies roughly 80 percent of Venezuelas beer, including market leader Polar Pilsen . The union is tiny but its members hold key positions at the plant, meaning that production has ground to a halt.
The nations human rights ombudsman has stepped in to mediate. But Empresa Polar executives accuse him of a bias toward the union, which is allied with the socialist government of President Nicolas Maduro.
On top of that, theres a shortage of imported beer ingredients.
Add that to the list of basics in short supply, like medicines and food items, thanks to a raft of economic problems including a lack of dollars.
So far, store shelves are well stocked with beer bottles, according to the Associated Press . But that may change very soon. The national brewers association says raw materials for beer-making will run out by August .
The timing could hardly be worse.
Venezuela is suffering 615 percent inflation, says Johns Hopkins University economist Steve H. Hanke. The country also has one of the worlds highest homicide rates. And the governments been locking up critics.
So, you might say Venezuelans could use a drink.
This article originally appeared on GlobalPost.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In long-predicted shift, California Latinos outnumber whites</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/social-affairs/20150708/in-long-predicted-shift-california-latinos-outnumber-whites</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Demographics
In long-predicted shift, California Latinos outnumber whites
In this file photo, Oakland Raiders cheerleaders hold flags of the Hispanic countries of the Americas and Iberia as part of a Hispanic Heritage tribute before an NFL football game against the Pittsburgh Steelers in Oakland According to figures released in late June, 2015, by the U.S. Census Bureau, Hispanic Californians began to narrowly outnumber white Californians sometime in the first half of 2014. Tony Avelar  The Associated Press file
By The Associated Press
# Comments
In this file photo, a woman walks with children to the MacArthur Park Primary Center School in Los Angeles. According to figures released in late June, 2015, by the U.S. Census Bureau, Hispanic Californians began to narrowly outnumber white Californians sometime in the first half of 2014. Damian Dovarganes  The Associated Press file
LOS ANGELES &gt;&gt; The long-expected moment when Latinos surpassed whites as Californias largest racial or ethnic group has come and gone.
Hispanic Californians began to narrowly outnumber white Californians sometime in the first half of 2014, according to U.S. Census Bureau figures released in late June.
The state had some 14.99 million Latinos compared with about 14.92 million non-Hispanic whites as of July 1, 2014, the most recent data available. Together, the two groups make up nearly 80 percent of the states population.
Demographers had expected the shift for decades as the states Hispanic population boomed due to immigration and birth rates.
Many thought it would happen sooner than it did  the California Department of Finance had predicted 2013  but a slight decline in population pushed it to last year.
This is sort of the official statistical recognition of something that has been underway for almost an entire generation, Roberto Suro, director of the Toms Rivera Policy Institute at the University of Southern California, told the Los Angeles Times on Wednesday.
California joins New Mexico as the second state with a Latino plurality. Hawaii, with its large Asian population, is the third state where whites are not the largest ethnic group.
California saw an immigration boom from Mexico and Central America during the 1980s, a population surge that has since moved to other states, particularly in the Midwest and South.
As that happened, Californias Hispanic population has grown more rooted and settled.
Some 70 percent of the states immigrants, the majority of those Latinos, were living in the U.S. before 2000, a higher rate than any other state, according to 2012 census data.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:52:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>California regulators discuss water pricing in drought</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150708/california-regulators-discuss-water-pricing-in-drought</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>State governments
California regulators discuss water pricing in drought
In this file photo, a home with a swimming pool sits near a dried out hillside in Altadena The State Water Resources Control Board is hosting a workshop Wednesday  to discuss how to encourage Californians to save by hitting them in the wallet. Two-thirds of water districts use some form of tiered water pricing. Ringo H.W. Chiu  The Associated Press file
By Fenit Nirappil, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
SACRAMENTO &gt;&gt; California water regulators heard proposals for a statewide drought fee and hefty fines for water-guzzling homeowners as part of a Wednesday workshop discussing how to implement Gov. Jerry Browns order for water pricing to maximize conservation.
Officials at the State Water Resources Control Board said they werent looking at a total overhaul of water bills across the parched state dealing with its four-year dry spell.
The state is not rushing out here to supplant local authority and local control, said Max Gomberg, a senior scientist at the board.
Joe Grindstaff, general manager of the Chino-based Inland Empire Utilities Agency, suggested the California could set a state standard for reasonable residential water use and impose fines on local agencies whose customers use too much.
The truth is you can have a really nice lawn and really nice life living within those standards, Grindstaff told the board.
Members of the state water board appeared cool to the idea, with one quipping Grindstaff would need police protection because so many people would hate the idea.
The board didnt take any actions Wednesday and didnt indicate any future plans for increasing the price of water.
A law accompanying the California budget allows agencies to slap the worst water wasters with fines up to $10,000. Another bill, SB789, that would have allowed water departments to impose a 300 percent tax on the heaviest water users bills has stalled because it lacked support.
Conservation experts agree the price of water is among the best ways to encourage savings, but the legality of such tactics have come under scrutiny after a court struck down punitive rates in the Orange County city of San Juan Capistrano.
The 4th District Court of Appeal said charging heavy users incrementally more per gallon without showing it cost more to provide violated a 1996 voter-approved law that prohibits government agencies from overcharging for services.
Lester Snow, who leads the California Water Foundation, says that law, Proposition 218, should be reformed because its deterring water-saving efforts.
We are pushing people to conserve, and we have systematically withheld some of the tools they need, he said.
Two-thirds of water districts use some form of tiered water pricing to encourage conservation. Many say their rates are legal because higher water use requires them to tap more expensive supplies.
Advertisement
While the governors order calls for the board to help develop water rates and penalties to maximize conservation, the workshop discussion also veered into a statewide water fee that would help pay for infrastructure projects during the drought.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds of kids died in Gaza's war. The ones who survived are living a nightmare</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150708/hundreds-of-kids-died-in-gazas-war-the-ones-who-survived-are-living-a-nightmare</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>War and unrest
Hundreds of kids died in Gazas war. The ones who survived are living a nightmare
Palestinian children play in the rubble of houses in the Gaza Strip destroyed during the 50-day war between Israel and Hamas militants. July 7, 2015. SAID KHATIB/AFP/Getty Images
By Laura Dean, GlobalPost
# Comments
GAZA CITY, Gaza Strip  Out of my five daughters, the only one uninjured in the war was Nada, and now she doesnt talk, a mother in Gaza says of her young child. She cries a lot. She is exhausted all the time, suffers nightmares.
For Gazas children, last years war with Israel wasnt just a horrific summer of violence. It was the third conflict here children 7 and older have seen in their short lives.
They live with the effects every day.
Seven out of 10 children in the hardest hit areas of the Gaza Strip experience nightmares, according to a new Save the Children report. Three-quarters of them regularly wet their beds  a common issue for children that trauma can make worse. In al-Shoka, a neighborhood in the southern part of the Strip, half of the children interviewed wet the bed every night.
Save the Children collected data in April and May looking at the mental health of children ages 6 to 15. They found that those living in the hardest hit areas showed unexpectedly high levels of continued severe emotional distress and trauma.
A total of 2,205 Palestinians were killed during the fighting last summer, most of them civilians and 521 of them children, according to the United Nations. Seven civilians and 66 Israeli soldiers were killed in Israel.
Some children now say they are afraid to leave their homes; others feel unsafe in school buildings. Some who moved to new areas after their homes were bombed say they feel too anxious to try to make friends in their new schools.
At the start of the academic year, schools across Gaza spent the first few weeks providing psychosocial support to students who had endured 51 days of bombing. They were also learning to cope with the empty desks in their classrooms and deaths in their families.
Save the Children figures say 551 Gazan children were killed in the fighting, and 3,436 injured. Around 10 percent of the injured will be disabled for the rest of their lives. An estimated 1,500 lost parents.
One hundred thousand people remain homeless in Gaza. Significant reconstruction of health facilities, water networks and schools has not yet started because of the ongoing blockade, which restricts access to materials, and funding shortfalls.
For many children in Gaza, the war never ended. They continue to experience it in their nightmares, their games, silently, in quiet corners, in their memories, the report said.
Many young people saw things that would be hard for even seasoned adults to recover from.
My children were in the street [during the war] and saw the body pieces on the street after a shelling. My son is now traumatized, and my daughter has nightmares and wakes up frightened. I dont know how to help them, one mother told Save the Children.
Advertisement
In some areas children still play atop rubble that hasnt been cleared. Parents say their games are often violent and reflect scenes from wars they have seen. A particularly popular one is Israelis and Palestinians  which is a lot like Cowboys and Indians of the 1950s United States.
Even during peaceful times, the specter of bombardment lurks close by.
Drones and F-16s buzz overhead  children can tell you the difference between the sounds  and the Israeli security forces frequently shoot into border areas.
More than 70 percent of the children interviewed said they are afraid there will be another war.
Some reported feeling trapped, unable to escape. Our future is gone, one 14-year-old said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What Hemingway has to do with drunk foreign guys who flock to Spain to run with the bulls</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150708/what-hemingway-has-to-do-with-drunk-foreign-guys-who-flock-to-spain-to-run-with-the-bulls</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>News 
Nation and World
What Hemingway has to do with drunk foreign guys who flock to Spain to run with the bulls
Revelers run with bulls at Curva Estafeta during the third day of the San Fermin Running Of The Bulls festival, on July 8, 2013 in Pamplona, Spain. Pablo Blazquez Dominguez/Getty Images
By Emilie Munson, GlobalPost
# Comments
Ernest Hemingway likely had no idea what he was starting when he glorified the Spanish tradition of bull running in The Sun Also Rises.
The 1926 American literary classic brought international fame to the San Fermn festival bull runs, and used the tradition to redefine post-World War I masculinity.
Nobody ever lives their life all the way up except bull-fighters, says Jake Barnes, Hemingways desperately insecure protagonist.
Today, more and more foreigners are taking Barnes thoughts to heart and flocking to Pamplona, Spain to experience bull running themselves.
Last year, more than 17,000 people participated in the runs; 56 percent were from countries other than Spain, according to Pamplona city hall .
The United States, Australia, New Zealand and Britain provided the largest numbers of foreign bull runners. In these countries in particular, running with bulls is a YOLO-justified risk.
While the excitement appeals to many, the thrills come at a cost: hundreds of people are hurt in the runs every year, and fifteen people have been killed during them since 1910.
Many of the injured are the tourists who come to Spain to show their toughness.
In 1995, 22-year-old Matthew Peter Tassio from Glen Ellyn, Illinois was killed when he was gored by a bull in the town hall square of Pamplona.
Just on Tuesday, two Americans and a British man were gored by the running bulls in the streets of Pamplona. Three other Americans were lightly injured by the jostling crowds.
Its a macho thing. [At the end] youre standing around counting your parts, one American who had run with the bulls three times told the Chicago Tribune . Its like jumping out of an airplane.
Festival officials say that too often the tourists participate with little knowledge of the dangers and insufficient training, not to mention on little sleep and hungover. That leaves them ill-prepared to outrun six bulls charging over the narrow half-mile route at an average of fifteen miles an hour.
After Tassios death, Spanish television and radio talk shows held debates about whether foreigners should be allowed to participate in bull running at all.
Europeans and Spaniards see the running as a show or spectacle like bullfights and leave the performance to the professionals, Daniel Ross, the US vice consul in Bilbao, told The New York Times . Americans come here with the image of The Sun Also Rises and just dont realize how dangerous it is and how easy it is to trip up.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:48:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>California man, 27, among those gored in Pamplona, Spain, running of the bulls</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150707/california-man-27-among-those-gored-in-pamplona-spain-running-of-the-bulls</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>California man, 27, among those gored in Pamplona, Spain, running of the bulls
By Daniel Ochoa De Olza and Ciaran Giles, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
A reveler is tossed by a cow with dull horns Tuesday during a celebration held at the bullring after the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain. Revelers from around the world turned out here to kick off the festival with a messy party in the Pamplona town square, one day before the first of eight days of the running of the bulls. Daniel Ochoa de Olza  The Associated Press
PAMPLONA, Spain &gt;&gt; Two Americans and a Briton were gored and eight others injured Tuesday as thousands of daredevils dashed alongside fighting bulls through the streets of this northern Spanish city on the first bull run of the San Fermin festival, organizers said.
Mike Webster, a 38-year-old occupational therapist from Gainesville, Florida, was gored as he ran with the bulls in Pamplona for his 38th time over the last 11 years, he said from his hospital bed.
San Fermins media office said he was gored in the armpit, and Webster told The Associated Press that he hasnt decided whether hell run again because he first needs to discuss the issue with his wife.
 PHOTOS: Running of the bulls in Pamplona, Spain
Also gored was a 27-year-old Californian identified by the media office only by his initials, D.M.O. A 30-year-old Briton with the initials A.B.O. was gored in the groin area. None of the three was said to be in serious condition.
Three other Americans were among the eight others injured, most with bruises sustained in falls and crowd crushes during the nationally-televised run that lasted just over two minutes.
The daily run sees people dashing with six bulls along a narrow, 930-yard (850-meter) course from a holding pen to the citys bullring. The bulls are then killed by professional matadors in bullfights each afternoon.
The nine-day fiesta in Pamplona, which features 24-hour street partying, was made famous in Ernest Hemingways 1926 novel The Sun Also Rises and attracts thousands of foreign tourists.
Bull runs are a traditional part of summer festivals across Spain. Dozens are injured each year in the runs, most in falls.
Two men have died recently after being gored by bulls in Spanish festivals  one Saturday in the eastern town of Grao de Castellon and another June 24 in the southwestern town of Coria.
In all, 15 people have died from gorings in Pamplona since record-keeping began in 1924 for the San Fermin festival.
Ciaran Giles reported from Madrid. Associated Press Writer Alan Clendenning contributed to this report from Madrid.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:58:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mexico bans wild animals in circuses -- but there's no place for them to go</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150706/mexico-bans-wild-animals-in-circuses-x2014-but-theres-no-place-for-them-to-go</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Circuses
Mexico bans wild animals in circuses  but theres no place for them to go
Circus elephants, like this one performing in Paris, France, are banned in Mexico beginning July 8. Bertrand Guay/AFP/Getty Images
By Emilie Munson, GlobalPost
Circus workers perform as they take part in a protest against a law that prohibits the use of wild animals in their shows, in Mexico City on June 10, 2014. Alfredo Estrella/AFP/Getty Images
Lions and tigers and bears no more.
A new law in Mexico banning the use of tigers, elephants, zebras, lions and other exotic animals in circuses comes into effect next week.
The law, which was approved in March 2015, is aimed at preventing animal cruelty, and those who violate it will be fined nearly $225,000.
Some 3,000 to 3,500 circus animals will be freed from performing under the big top thanks to the law, according to the International Business Times .
The question remains, however, what will happen to all of these animals?
For many circus owners, the animals will be too expensive to keep. One Mexican animal tamer estimated that it costs around 3,000 pesos (almost $200) a day to feed circus tigers. When you add other costs like veterinary bills on top of that, keeping wild animals is a pricey expense.
An official from the Mexican environmental protection agency said the government is evaluating different facilities that could take in the animals. Privately owned zoos have also offered to house them.
Some circus owners claim that the new law, designed to protect circus animals, is actually putting the animals in worse danger.
A lot of owners dont want to give the government the animals that are their livelihoods, President of the National Association of Circus Owners Armando Cedeo told the Guardian . Some are looking to sell them, and you dont always know who is buying. Others are so desperate they are looking to put them to sleep.
The Associated Press reported that Mexican authorities had found six tigers, seven baboons, four camels and three dromedaries abandoned in cages last week. Theyd been left without food or water.
Circuses across Mexico are also worried about revenue. Without animal attractions to draw spectators, attendance could drop, and some smaller circus operations have been forced to shut down already.
Workers, naturally, are concerned about their jobs. Over 1,000 circus employees protested against the law in Mexico City a year ago, saying that the law will leave thousands unemployed.
Mexico is the 29th country to pass a nationwide ban on circus animals, according to Stop Circus Suffering , a campaign of the NGO Animal Defenders International. Other countries with nationwide bans include Austria, Croatia, Greece, Bolivia and Costa Rica.
Advertisement
The US has full or partial bans on circus animals in only 22 states .
Perhaps cock fighting and bull fighting will be Mexicos next legal targets.
This article originally appeared on GlobalPost .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:37:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek government racing against the clock as banks run out of cash</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150706/greek-government-racing-against-the-clock-as-banks-run-out-of-cash</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Greek government racing against the clock as banks run out of cash
Outgoing Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis puts his helmet on Monday as he is surrounded by media after his resignation in Athens, Monday. Greece and its membership in Europes joint currency faced an uncertain future, with the country under pressure to reach a bailout deal with creditors as soon as possible after Greeks resoundingly rejected the notion of more austerity in exchange for aid. Petros Karadjias  The Associated Press
By Elena Becatoros, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Greeces Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, center, leaves after a meeting Monday with Greek political party leaders at the Presidential Palace as Minister of State Nikos Pappas, left, and Government spokesman Gabriel Sakellaridis, right, follow him in Athens. With Greek banks running out of cash and facing the danger of collapse within days without new aid, the government is racing against the clock. Angelos Christofilopoulos  The Associated Press
ATHENS, Greece &gt;&gt; Greece and its membership in Europes joint currency faced an uncertain future Monday, with the country under pressure to restart bailout talks with creditors as soon as possible after Greeks resoundingly rejected the notion of more austerity in exchange for aid.
With Greek banks running out of cash and facing the danger of collapse within days without new aid, the government in Athens is racing against the clock.
In an effort to facilitate negotiations on a new aid program, Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis, who had clashed with European officials in the bailout talks, announced his resignation Monday.
But Greece and its creditors, who will meet again Tuesday to discuss how to keep the country in the euro, remain far apart on key issues, particularly the notion of debt relief.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras and Chancellor Angela Merkel spoke on the phone Monday ahead of the Tuesday summit, though no details were disclosed of what they discussed.
New negotiations will be complicated for the European creditors by Tsipras triumph in Sundays referendum. More than 61 percent of Greeks backed his call to vote no to budget cuts the creditors had proposed in return for rescue loans the country needs  even though those proposals were no longer on the table.
The vote was painted by opposition parties and many European officials as one on whether Greece should remain in Europes joint currency. In the aftermath, many European leaders softened their tone and said talks would resume, though Greeces chance of staying in the euro was looking increasingly shaky.
The countrys banks remained shut on Monday for a sixth working day and the government kept tight limits on cash withdrawals at ATMs and money transfers to limit the drain on deposits.
All eyes now turn to whether the European Central Bank will increase the amount of credit the banks can draw on to make up for the cash drain. Analysts expect the ECB to not provide more emergency assistance on Monday.
That means the banks would not be able to reopen and Greece might have to tighten its limits on cash withdrawals and transfers from the current 60 euros ($67) per day. Some banks may even face the risk of collapse in coming days as they continue to be drained of banknotes.
Greeces economy minister, Giorgos Stathakis, told the BBC that if the ECB keeps its support unchanged, the current cash withdrawals limits can stay in place until Friday without any banks collapsing.
Facing such urgency, the Greek government has vowed to quickly restart negotiations with creditors in other eurozone countries and with the institutions that oversaw the countrys bailout: the ECB, European Commission and International Monetary Fund.
Advertisement
Varoufakis appeared to be the first casualty of the Greek governments attempt to reach a deal with creditors.
With his brash style and fondness for frequent media appearances, Varoufakis had visibly annoyed many of the eurozones finance ministers during the past months debt negotiations.
Varoufakis said in a statement he was told shortly after the referendum result that some other eurozone finance ministers and the countrys other creditors would appreciate his not attending the ministers meetings.
The idea was one that the Prime Minister judged to be potentially helpful to him in reaching an agreement. For this reason I am leaving the Ministry of Finance today, he said.
As for his European negotiating colleagues, he said of them: I shall wear the creditors loathing with pride.
A replacement was to be announced later Monday.
With his high-stakes gamble to call a referendum with just a weeks notice, Tsipras aimed to show creditors that Greeks, whose economy has been shattered and who face spiraling unemployment and poverty, have had enough and that the austerity prescribed isnt working.
But everything hinges on European reaction.
European officials appear to be split on a key demand by Greece to have the burden of its bailout loans be made more manageable.
Frances finance minister, Michel Sapin, indicated that discussing Greeces debt is not taboo, saying the country could not recover with its current obligations in the months and years to come.
Sapin also called for the ECB to maintain liquidity assistance to Greek banks.
Germany, however, remains reluctant to discuss debt forgiveness.
Finance Ministry spokesman Martin Jaeger said Germanys position is well-known ... a debt cut is not an issue for us.
More broadly, Chancellor Angela Merkels spokesman said talks on a new bailout program for Greece would depend on what proposals Athens makes.
Steffen Seibert said Germany respects the clear no vote by Greeks against austerity measures.
However, he added that in view of Greek citizens decision yesterday, the conditions are not there at present to enter negotiations on a new program. He said the no vote is a vote against the principle  still supported by Germany  that solidarity requires countries to make their own reform efforts.
Besieged by a prolonged recession, high unemployment and banks dangerously low on capital, Greece defaulted on an IMF loan repayment last week, becoming the first developed nation to do so.
Now some analysts wonder if Greece is so starved of cash that it could be forced to start issuing its own currency and become the first country to leave the 19-member eurozone, established in 1999.
Tsipras was elected in January on promises to repeal the austerity demanded in return for its bailout and negotiations broke down late last month after dragging on unsuccessfully for five months.
Demetri Nellas and Menelaos Hadjicostis in Athens, Greece, Lori Hinnant in Paris, Raf Casert in Brussels and Geir Moulson in Berlin contributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 21:50:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Terminator,' 'Magic Mike' fizzle at July 4th box office</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150705/terminator-magic-mike-fizzle-at-july-4th-box-office</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Box office receipts
Terminator, Magic Mike fizzle at July 4th box office
This photo provided by Paramount Pictures shows, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the Terminator in Terminator Genisys, from Paramount Pictures and Skydance Productions. Melinda Sue Gordon  Paramount Pictures via AP
By Jake Coyle, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
This image released by Warner Bros. Pictures shows Channing Tatum in a scene from the film, Magic Mike XXL. Claudette Barius  Warner Bros. Pictures via AP
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; July 4th went off like a dud at the box office. Anticipated new releases Magic Mike XXL and Terminator Genisys fizzled, leaving the popular holdovers Jurassic World and Inside Out to top the holiday weekend.
Despite the brawny enticements of Channing Tatum and Arnold Schwarzenegger, the four-week rule of Universals dinosaur sensation Jurassic World continued with an estimated $30.9 million, according to studio estimates Sunday.
Pixars acclaimed Inside Out nearly caught up to the runaway dinos, taking in $30.1 million in its third weekend of release.
The strength of those June hits and the unfortunate timing of July 4th this year coming on a Saturday (rather than stretching out a long weekend) meant the sequels Terminator Genisys and Magic Mike XXL both failed to match previous installments.
Paramounts Terminator Genisys, the fifth film in the series which also marks Schwarzeneggers return to his most iconic character, took in $28.7 million over the weekend and $44.2 million since opening Wednesday.
Warner Bros. also tried to expand the weekend, opening Tatums male-stripper romp Magic Mike XXL on Wednesday. But after a strong start, the film managed just $12 million over the weekend. Over five days it made $27.1 million.
The openings were disappointing for the new releases, but each has a different makeup. Terminator Genisys, an attempted reboot in the 31-year-old, James Cameron-created franchise, was made for $155 million. Magic Mike XXL, a road-trip sequel to Steven Soderberghs 2012 hit original, was made for just under $15 million.
Megan Colligan, head of worldwide distribution for Paramount, said the weekend simply didnt play like a holiday weekend.
The weekend got off to a very sluggish start because people didnt have off until Friday, said Colligan. Our start was just not where it needed to be. Some of that does have to do with it is pretty severe competition. Jurassic is still such a powerhouse in the marketplace and it was hard to anticipate that that wouldnt have burned off a little more by now.
Genisys failed to come close to the previous Terminator film, the Schwarzenegger-less Salvation, which had a five-day debut of $65.3 million over Memorial Day weekend in 2009. Genisys, which critics have slammed, is finding better business abroad. It made $74 million international over the weekend.
Magic Mike XXL, however, had the benefit of largely positive reviews and tracking numbers that suggested a possible No. 1 opening of more than $40 million. The original debuted with $39.1 million.
Advertisement
But Magic Mike XXL failed to expand its audience. Whereas moviegoers for the first film were 73 percent female, Magic Mike XXL was a staggering 96 percent female, Warner Bros. said.
Dan Fellman, head of domestic distribution for Warner Bros., said the film performed worse than expected in the South, Midwest and in Canada. Such a girls-night-out release, he said, didnt materialize over the holiday weekend.
Our audience wasnt available to us, said Fellman. We might be down but were not out. Im in the wait and see mode.
Hollywoods summer has been inching close to equaling its record 2013 season, thanks partly to the unexpected success of Jurassic World. (Now with $558.2 million domestically, its already the fourth-best showing of all time in North America.)
The biggest potholes this summer have been holiday weekends, noted Paul Dergarabedian, senior media analyst for box-office firm Rentrak.
Those weekends usually are the tent poles to Hollywoods summer spectacle, but the lagging Independence Day weekend follows a lackluster Memorial Day, when Disneys Tomorrowland flopped.
These are the weekends everyones going, Wow, what happened? said Dergarabedian. Part of it was the calendar. Part of it, too, was you have two movies out there  Jurassic World and Inside Out  that are just dominating the marketplace. Both those movies have appealed to every audience segment imaginable.
This weekend was still up 6.9 percent over last year, when Melissa McCarthys Tammy and the sci-fi adventure Earth to Echo made for Hollywoods worst July 4 in decades.
Universals animated off-shoot sequel Minions will debut next weekend after a strong international performance. The film, which gives the pipsqueak henchmen of the Despicable Me movies the spotlight, has already grossed $124.2 million abroad, including $54.3 million this weekend.
Estimated ticket sales for Friday through Sunday at U.S. and Canadian theaters, according to Rentrak. Where available, the latest international numbers for Friday through Sunday are also included. Final domestic figures will be released Monday.
1. Jurassic World, $30.9 million ($42 million international).
2. Inside Out, $30.1 million ($18.6 million international).
3. Terminator: Genisys, $28.7 million ($74 million international).
4. Magic Mike XXL, $12 million.
5. Ted 2, $11 million.
6. Max, $7 million.
8. San Andreas, $3 million.
9. Me and Earl and the Dying Girl, $1.3 million.
10. Dope, $1.1 million.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 20:43:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NASCAR fans defend, display Confederate flags at Daytona</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/sports/20150705/nascar-fans-defend-display-confederate-flags-at-daytona</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Motorsports
NASCAR fans defend, display Confederate flags at Daytona
Confederate flags fly on top of a motor home at Daytona International Speedway, Saturday in Daytona Beach, Fla. NASCAR and the speedway offered to replace any flag a race brings to the track with an American flag. Phelan M. Ebenhack  The Associated Press
By Mark Long, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Confederate and American flags fly on top of motor homes at Daytona International Speedway, Saturday in Daytona Beach, Fla. NASCAR and the speedway offered to replace any flag a race brings to the track with an American flag. Phelan M. Ebenhack  The Associated Press
DAYTONA BEACH, Fla. &gt;&gt; Steven Rebenstorf has numerous flags flying atop his canopy tent inside Daytona International Speedway.
The Confederate flag is front and center.
Its been like that for years. And the 57-year-old Rebenstorf has no plans to take it down  not even if NASCAR decides to ban the embattled flag from its racetracks.
Theyd have to come and get it, Rebenstorf said Saturday, pointing out that his American flag purposely flies a few inches higher than the rest.
Rebenstorf and others staunchly defended their Confederate flags at NASCARs first race in the South since the racing series and its tracks urged fans to no longer wave the banner. Dozens were scattered throughout the vast infield all weekend leading to Sundays race.
It kills me that NASCAR is jumping on the bandwagon, said 55-year-old Paul Stevens of nearby Port Orange. They should just let it pass, let everything die down. But NASCAR is too quick to try to be politically correct like everybody else.
NASCAR took a stance on the Confederate flag after last months South Carolina church massacre. It backed Gov. Nikki Haleys call to remove it from the Statehouse grounds and noted it doesnt allow the flag on anything it sanctions. The series stopped short of banning fans from displaying the flag at its events, but Daytona and 29 other tracks asked fans to refrain from flying them.
Not everyone obliged. Daytona also offered to exchange Confederate flags for American flags this weekend, and track officials said a few made the swap Sunday morning.
I think the voluntary exchange program for us right now was appropriate with the limited window that we had coming into this event weekend, track president Joie Chitwood said. And more importantly, I think its important to trust our fans, asking our fans to display a flag that we should all be proud of. Everybody should be proud of the American flag.
Indeed, the American flag is prominently displayed all around Daytona  no surprise given the Fourth of July holiday and the patriotism that NASCAR routinely promotes.
But spotting a Confederate flag is easier than finding a souvenir shop, restroom or beer stand.
The first motorhome located inside the Turn 4 tunnel has one flying high above it, and it doesnt take long to reach double figures when counting them on a stroll through the infield. Theyre on clothing, coolers and cars, and even tattooed on skin.
Advertisement
Larry Reeves of Jacksonville Beach has a tattered Confederate flag on top of his motorhome. He initially thought NASCAR was banning the banner and didnt display it this week. But once he saw some flying around him and asked a few questions, he realized it was voluntary and quickly sent his back up the pole.
Its just a Southern pride thing, the 66-year-old Reeves said. Its nothing racist or anything. Ive been doing this for 30 years. My family is from Alabama and weve been going to Talladega forever. It isnt a Confederate thing so much as it is a NASCAR thing. Thats why I fly it.
Like others at Daytona, Reeves believes the flag flap is much ado about nothing.
Its not a big deal one way or the other, Reeves said. If I cant fly it, I wont. But if I dont have to take it down, Im just going to leave it up.
Rebenstorf plans to leave his up no matter what NASCAR mandates.
The St. Petersburg resident spent six years in the Navy, served in the color guard and has strong feelings about vexillology, the scientific study of the history, symbolism and usage of flags.
The Confederate flag has absolutely nothing to do with slavery. It has nothing to do with divisiveness. It has nothing to do with any of that, Rebenstorf said, pausing for a few minutes to pull off his floppy hat, stand at attention and salute during the national anthem Saturday. It was just a battle banner until the Ku Klux Klan draped it around themselves. Now, all of a sudden, it represents slavery and thats not at all true.
The Civil War-era flag has been under attack since nine black men and women were gunned down at a historic church in Charleston on June 17.
The suspect, 21-year-old Dylann Roof, had posed with a Confederate flag in photos posted on a website that displayed a racist manifesto attributed to him.
NASCAR, which has roots in the deep South, moved quickly to distance itself from the flag despite some backlash from fans. The sanctioning body could have done  and eventually might do  more.
I think what happens in this situation is you have people on both sides who feel very strongly about something and theyre very passionate about it, Chitwood said. You cant argue with someones passion or their opinion. That creates something that ends up on the front page of the newspaper or is the headline in the news. If were going to enter that discussion, youve got to be thoughtful and weve got to really think through it and be fair to both sides and make sure that whatever we come up can work.
In something like this, the more thoughtful we can be, understanding and really taking the time to really vet through, I think thats going to be the important thing moving forward.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
