<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="dailymail">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Londoners facing Tube strike travel chaos go Boris bike crazy with nearly DOUBLE the usual number being hired from special collection points
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154461/Millions-commuters-start-nightmare-journeys-work-Tube-shut-drivers-strike-row-pay-winners-cab-service-Uber-ramps-fares-300-cent.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Transport for London said it had seen double the usage on the Santander Cycles with more than 30,000 hired by 2pm today compared with 16,000 yesterday as people battled to get home.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
On your bike! Londoners facing Tube strike travel chaos go Boris bike crazy with nearly DOUBLE the usual number being hired from special collection points
London Underground workers are staging 24 hour strike in dispute over pay and introduction of new night services
Mayor Boris Johnson today slammed the unions' decision, branding their tactics 'disgraceful' and 'outrageous'
Dozens of frustrated commuters took to Twitter to criticise the industrial action, branding the unions 'ridiculous'
Have you got any pictures of rush hour chaos? Email pictures@mailonline.co.uk
Published: 06:15 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 20:39 GMT, 9 July 2015
4.1k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Missing couple Lamara Bell and John Yuill found in crashed car 3 days later
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154447/Dead-man-critically-injured-woman-crashed-car-THREE-days-accident-reported-police.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Lamara Bell, 25, and John Yuill, 28, were reported missing on Sunday after they disappeared from a weekend camping trip. Officers found them yesterday morning in a crashed blue Renault Clio.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'Because of some nice guy that phoned it in and was ignored by the incident room the messages were never passed on.
'Now my daughter is laying on life support.All I can ask from everybody is help tonight tell her to wake up!.
'Sorry as I write this I am crying my eyes out .Please make her wake up.'
Police Scotland today faced serious questions over why they did not attend the site when initially contacted by a passerby on Sunday.
A large police presence was seen at the site today after questions were raised over investigators' handling of the tragedy
Police Scotland faced serious questions over why they did not attend the site when initially contacted by a passerby on Sunday
A fire engine stands on call as police officers search the scene, where the crash occurred just off the M9
Miss Bell and her partner had not been seen since disappearing from their campsite in Loch Earn in the early hours of Sunday morning.
While her partner is believed to have died upon impact when they crashed, Miss Bell survived with serious injuries.
Today her mother Diane said her daughter was undergoing dialysis after becoming severely hydrated by the side of the road for three days.
'All I know is that when the fire fighters pulled her out they asked her how long she had been there and she said half-an-hour,' Ms Bell told Sky News.
People lying unattended at the side of the road for daysis something you'd be surprised to encounter in the Third World.
Murdo Fraser, Conservative MSP 
Police Scotland refused to answer questions on its handling of the tragedy today, telling MailOnline any added information could prejudice the outcome of an ongoing investigation into the incident.
The Police Investigations and Review Commissioner is now investigating why the initial call made on Sunday was never followed up.
It comes as Mr Yuill's father said an earlier response may have given his son's girlfriend a better chance at survival.
She is currently on life support at Glasgow's Southern General Hospital with her family by her bedside.
MSP condemns 'shocking' Police actions for missing couple
Mr Yuill, a father-of-two, is understood to have died on impact whereas Miss Bell fell in and out of consciousness for three days as she lay in the wreckage
Speaking of the fact police took three days to reach them, Gordon Yuill said: 'It wouldn't have made any difference for John.
'His injuries were such that he died on impact. But I feel it may have made a difference for Lamara,' he told The Daily Record .
Earlier in the week he assured friends he was 'sure police will be checking all the information available.'
Miss Bell is now fighting for left with a brain bleed and requires dialysis
Mr Yuill and Miss Bell had been camping at Loch Earn in Perthshire with Miss Bell's brother, Liam, his pregnant girlfriend and a friend, Paul Mooney.
They were reported missing by the group after a car was heard starting at around 4.30am on Sunday.
Police Scotland issued a missing persons appeal but did not follow up when a crash on the M9 was reported later that day, miles from their Falkirk home.
It was only when a second call was placed on Wednesday that officers attended the scene. 
Miss Bell has two children, a daughter aged nine, and a son aged five, while Mr Yuill was a father of two young boys. The couple had recently moved into a new home.
Mr Yuill had custody of his two sons who had been staying with their mother in Edinburgh.
Earlier this week, Mr Yuill's father, Gordon, told the Scottish Daily Mail he 'feared there has been an accident and they are lying there'.
He added: 'He's in contact with his family every day, he comes here every day. This is not like him at all. Lamara dotes on her kids, they wouldn't just leave them.'
Mr Mooney, who had been camping with the couple, said that they had heard the car early on Sunday, but thought the engine had been turned back off. The group then woke at 9am and noticed Mr Yuill and Miss Bell were gone.
On Monday. Mr Mooney said: 'We haven't slept at all, we are just waiting for the police to call. We're in shock.'
Miss Bell's mother, Diane, had also urged her daughter to come home and said she too feared the worst.
Today she would not speak beyond to confirm that her daughter remained in a critical condition.
Local politicians have slammed the police's handling of the incident, with one likening the scenario to something found in the developing world.
'This is a truly shocking incident,' said Murdo Fraser, Conservative MSP for Mid Scotland and Fife.
'People lying unattended at the side of the road for days is something you'd be surprised to encounter in the Third World.
WHY DID POLICE TAKE SO LONG TO DISCOVER TRAGIC COUPLE?
Sunday early hours: Miss Bell and Mr Yuill vanished from camp site where they were staying with friends
Sunday late morning: A car crash is reported to Police Scotland at Junction 9 on the M9
Monday: A police appeal is launched naming Miss Bell and Mr Yuill as missing
Wednesday 10.50am: More than three days after the crash police discover the couple in the wreckage of the car
'The circumstances leading to this must be investigated as a matter of absolute urgency.'
A neighbour at Miss Bell's home said said she was 'shocked' it had taken so long for her to be found.
'It's absolutely shocking what's happened. I saw on the news the car was lying there for three days and the police did absolutely nothing about it.
'What kind of country are we living in where the police feel they can choose to ignore a car crash where people are injured,' the neighbour, who did not want to be named, said.
'It makes me sick knowing they were they for all that time and she was lying there with his body.
'Thank God they were eventually found. I'll be praying for her. Something still has to be done about the police though. It's not acceptable at all for that to be allowed to go unpunished.
'I hope they get hung out to dry for this. It's as good as manslaughter.'
Outraged Scots flooded the Police Scotland page with complaints of its handling of the tragedy when it posted an update last night.
Siobhan Samson wrote: 'How can this happen? I regularly go to work via the M9 and the M876 and you seem to have plenty of vans to detect speeding and yet this emergency call seemed to have gone unexplored. How is that?'
Jackie Martin added: 'Absolute disgrace that these people have lay injured and dying for 3 days.'
The couple's car was left off Junction 9 on the M9 near Stirling for three days before police found them
A spokesman for the Scottish government said: 'Our thoughts are with the families of the couple concerned at this very difficult time.
'This matter has been referred by the Crown to the Police Investigations and Review Commissioner and will be taken forward appropriately.'
An investigation into the circumstances is to be carried out by the Police Investigations and Review Commissioner.
Assistant Chief Constable Kate Thomson of Police Scotland said officers had been called to the M9 southbound near Junction 9 at about 9.50am yesterday. That followed a report of a one-car crash involving a Renault Clio which had left the road.
The man driving the car had been pronounced dead at the scene, while the woman passenger was taken to the Queen Elizabeth University Hospital in Glasgow, where she is in a critical condition.' She added: 'We believe that this is connected to the ongoing missing persons search for John Yuill and Lamara Bell.
'As part of our investigation into this incident, it has come to light that a call was made to police late on Sunday morning regarding a car which was reported as being off the road. For reasons currently being investigated, that report was not followed up at the time.
'A full investigation is currently under way to establish the full circumstances of the incident.'
A PIRC spokesman said: 'The Crown Office and Procurator Fiscal Service has directed the Police Investigations and Review Commissioner to carry out an independent investigation into the circumstances surrounding the death of a 28-year-old man and serious injury of a 25-year-old woman following an incident at the M9 southbound near Junction 9 at Bannockburn on July 8.'
They were found near the M9 in Stirlingshire (file image above) on Wednesday morning after three days
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
825
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>
	South African boy decapitated after leaning out of school bus window
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154941/Boy-16-decapitated-fellow-pupils-leaning-window-school-bus-drove-past-electrical-pole-day-trip-South-Africa.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The teenager, from Lesotho, died instantly in front of nearly 50 stunned pupils on a school outing to Durban in South Africa, according to his deputy principal Kabelo Maqache (pictured).
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
A 16-year-old boy was decapitated after sticking his head out of the window of his school bus as it drove past a pole by the side of the road.
The teenager died instantly in front of dozens of fellow pupils on a school outing to Durban in South Africa.
One child had to be taken to hospital for traumatic stress after witnessing his friend's horrific death.
Scroll down for video
In shock: Kabelo Maqache, Deputy Principal of Molapo High School in Leribe, Lesotho, tells how one of his pupils was decapitated after sticking his head of a bus window and hitting a pole at the side of the road
The scene of the boy's death was cordoned off as emergency services carried out their work
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Rian Birtwell fined £100 after washing a 6 year old boy's mouth out with soap
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154840/Man-ordered-pay-100-washing-six-year-old-s-mouth-soap-youngster-kicked-pensioner-s-walking-stick-told-f-off.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Rian Birtwell, 23, pleaded guilty to assault at Sunderland Magistrates' Court after confronting six-year-old Alfi Forsyth and shoving a bar of soap in his mouth in Sunderland, Tyne and Wear.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
5.8k shares
'He fully accepts in hindsight that that was not the best way to react. All Rian was trying to do was teach the little boy some manners. Unfortunately, manners are in short supply nowadays.'
The court was told how a witness recalled hearing Alfi call Birtwell a 'gay boy' during the confrontation.
Prosecutor Glenda Beck said: '[Alfi] was playing in the park which is close to his home address. The defendant approached him and there was an exchange of words.
'The defendant went to a shop and returned with a bar of soap. He pinned the injured party down to the floor and pushed the bar of soap into his mouth.'
Birtwell, who works as a joiner, was given a 12-month conditional discharge and ordered to pay 85 court costs and a 15 victim surcharge at yesterday's hearing.
Speaking after the case, Birtwell said he committed the offence because Alfi 'needed to be taught a lesson' for swearing.
Alfi's mother Lynne Cook admitted her son had sworn at Birtwell but said 'kids do that king of thing'
He said: 'I know Alfi and his mum Lynne very well, I used to babysit for him when he was younger.
'I accept what I did was wrong, but I meant no harm I just thought he needed to be taught a lesson because he behaved so badly and used language no six-year-old should be using.
'An old man was walking across the park using a stick, he was very unsteady on his feet, but Alfi ran over to him.
'He was pretending to kick away the old man's stick and although he was aiming his kicks wide of the stick I was worried he'd make the old man fall over.'
'I went over and said "Alfi stop that or I will tell your Mam".
'If someone had said that to me at his age it would have been enough but he just reacted with a load of abuse.
'I told him I would wash his mouth out with soap and his response was "you wouldn't f****** dare".
Birtwell admitted he went and bought three bars of Imperial Leather soap before rubbing it against the boy's teeth.
He said: 'I didn't want to hurt him but I wanted him to remember not to speak like that. It happened to me when I was a kid.
'I swore in front of my mum and she chased me. I tried to get away and she dragged me back down the stairs and rubbed a bar of soap in my mouth.
'It didn't harm me and it taught me not to do it again. There's nothing wrong with old-fashioned discipline but I accept it wasn't my place to discipline Alfi, I went too far and that's why I pleaded guilty.'
Mrs Cook admitted that her son had sworn at Birtwell but said 'kids do that kind of thing' of condemned Birtwell for taking matters into his own hands.
The 36-year-old said: 'I admit that my son swore and he was wrong for that, but like I said to the police at the time, kids do that kind of thing.
'At the end of the day, he is a 23-year-old bloke who has assaulted a six-year-old. The sentence is a joke.'
She also denied that her son had kicked the elderly man's walking stick and said he had not been violent towards the pensioner.
She said: 'There was no old man at all. He was in a park at the time with his older brother and various other friends. There were quite a few people around him.
'I think he [Rian] has made up the old man to defend himself. I don't know where this old man has come from at all.
'He was just messing about as kids do. There were quite a few other children on the park, playing with his friends, as he does, older children watching out for him.
'Him and Rian were playing and messing about. Alfi called him a gay boy, which obviously I picked up on. I chastised him myself for that, and the police officers did.
'Rian has gone to the shop and got a bar of soap because of Alfi's swearing and rammed the soap in his mouth.'
The confrontation between Birtwell, 23, and Alfi occurred in this park inWashington near Sunderland, Tyne and Wear. Birtwell was given a 12-month conditional discharge and ordered to pay 100 in court costs
Mrs Cook has lived on the estate in Sunderland for 34 years and said she has never had any problems before because it is a 'tight knit community'.
She said she was friends with Birtwell's mother before the incident, but the pair no longer talk.
She added: 'I went down to see [Rian's] mother and I told her what happened and told her I was going to the police.
'My son has got a lot of allergies - asthma and eczema - soap and things aggravate him. He could have had a reaction. Who's to know?
'Yes, Alfi swore. He was chastised for swearing, which I don't condone, from any children, not just him. But, that's up to me to punish him, not someone on the park.
'He is actually the victim and not the villain.'
Peter Bradley, director of Kidscape, which tackles bullying and safeguarding issues in relation to children, said both Birtwell and Alfi could learn a lesson from the incident.
He said: 'I think the main message that people should take from this case is that adults are adults and they should act appropriately when dealing with children.
'If a child is acting in the wrong manner then it has to be dealt with in the appropriate ways.
'In this instance, without doubt Rian was wrong, but hopefully some support has been put in place so that this boy can learn from his actions too.'
The case also prompted a mixed response from members of the public on social media.
Many were quick to point out that children should not be physically assaulted in such a way, while others had sympathy for Birtwell.
Ash Lea wrote: 'You can't physically abuse a child for bad behaviour', while Zoe Lee said: 'If it was not his child then I think it's wrong.'
Sharon Humphries posted: 'If this wasn't his child then he's in the wrong. It was up to the parents to discipline him.
'Youngsters need to be reminded how to respect their elders, but having said that, at six-years-old he's still yet to learn.'
Meanwhile Leanne Askew said: 'That's an old method. A filthy mouth gets washed with soap.
'Maybe they should be asking why the kid is behaving in such a disgusting age and especially at the age of 6.'
Share or comment on this article
5.8k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Can't Buy Me Love star Amanda Peterson's downfall in mugshots
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154162/Sad-downfall-t-Buy-Love-star-Amanda-Peterson-revealed-mugshots-recent-arrest-coming-2012-DUI-narcotics.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Mugshots of teen star Amanda Peterson reveal the sad downfall of the former Hollywood star in the years before her death, having been arrested four times between 2000 and 2012.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
The tragic downfall of an 80s icon: Mugshots chart the decline of Can't Buy Me Love actress Amanda Peterson before she was found dead in her apartment aged 43
Former Hollywood star Amanda Peterson who was found dead in her home on Sunday had been arrested multiple times in the past few years
She was arrested four times between 2000 and 2012, in 2000, 2003, 2005 and 2012
The 2012 arrest was for DUI and possession of narcotic equipment
Results of her autopsy have still not been released, and a toxicology test is being performed as well
Her mother Sylvia said while her daughter had struggled with drugs in the past, she had been clean for years
Published: 10:06 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 18:05 GMT, 9 July 2015
854 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>
	NASA's NuSTAR telescope picture makes sun look like a giant marble
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154601/NASA-releases-breathtaking-new-image-sun-using-NuSTAR-telescope.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	This image, presented today at the Royal Astronomical Society's National astronomy meeting in Llandudno, Wales, was taken by NASA's NuSTAR telescope.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'Our sun is quieting down in its activity cycle, but still has a couple of years before it reaches a minimum.'
Those active areas of the sun are filled with flares, which are giant eruptions on the surface of the sun that spew out charged particles and high-energy radiation.
They occur when magnetic field lines become tangled and broken, and then reconnect.
Due to its extreme sensitivity, NuSTAR's telescope cannot view the larger flares.
But it can help measure the energy of smaller microflares, which produce only one-millionth the energy of the larger flares.
NASA video shows many colours of Sun invisible to naked eye
NuSTAR may also be able to directly detect hypothesized nanoflares, which would be only one-billionth the energy of flares.
Nanoflares -- which may help explain why the sun's atmosphere, or corona, is much hotter than expected -- would be hard to spot due to their small size.
However, nanoflares may emit high-energy X-rays that NuSTAR has the sensitivity to detect.
Astronomers suspect that these tiny flares, like their larger brethren, can send electrons flying at tremendous velocities.
As the electrons zip around, they give off high-energy X-rays.
'We still need the sun to quiet down more over the next few years to have the ability to detect these events,' said Hannah, explaining that, while our sun is approaching the tranquil end of its roughly 11-year activity cycle, it has been showing spurious bouts of high activity.
Astronomers are also excited to use NuSTAR's images of the sun to pinpoint where energy from flares is released.
NASA'S NEW TELESCOPE - 100 TIMES MORE SENSITIVE
The new telescope (right) offers deeper, crisper images of the sky - and will help Nasa hunt down 'hidden' objects such as black holes which could help unravel the mysteries of the universe.
The Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array, NuSTAR X-Ray telescope is 100 times more sensitive than any previous telescope operating in the same energy range
'We will see the hottest, densest and most energetic objects with a fundamentally new high-energy X-ray telescope that can obtain much deeper and crisper images than before,' said Fiona Harrison, NuSTAR's principal investigator at the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena, who first conceived of the mission 20 years ago.
The telescope has more than 10 times the resolution, and more than 100 times the sensitivity, of its predecessors operating in a similar energy range.
Studying black holes that are big and small, far and near, NuSTAR will endeavor to answer questions about the formation and physics behind these wonders of the cosmos.
The observatory will also investigate how exploding stars forge the elements that make up planets and people, and it will even study our own Sun's atmosphere.
While it is known that the energy is generally liberated in the upper solar atmosphere, the locations and detailed mechanisms are not precisely known.
Cosmologists are looking forward to using NuSTAR's solar observations, too.
There is a slim chance the telescope could detect a hypothesized dark matter particle called the axion.
Dark matter is a mysterious substance in our universe that is about five times more abundant than the regular matter that makes up everyday objects and anything that gives off light.
NuSTAR might be able to address this and other mysteries of the sun.
'What's great about NuSTAR is that the telescope is so versatile that we can hunt black holes millions of light-years away and we can also learn something fundamental about the star in our own backyard,' said Brian Grefenstette of the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena, an astronomer on the NuSTAR team.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>
	ISIS massacre of 770 in Iraq was so bloody it could be seen from space
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154710/The-ISIS-massacre-770-Iraq-bloody-seen-space-24-fanatics-sentenced-hang-satellite-evidence-helped-bring-justice.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT Satellite imagery (pictured) and footage of the massacre in Tikrit, Iraq, helped convict 24 ISIS militants behind the mass slaughter of 770 Iraqi soldiers last June.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>The ISIS massacre of 770 in Iraq that was so bloody it could be seen from space: 24 fanatics sentenced to hang after satellite evidence helped bring them to justice
WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT
Original death toll of 190 after ISIS seized Tikrit in June 2014 and executed captured soldiers has since been tripled
Satellite images,  footage of  massacre and an eyewitness account revealed two undiscovered mass execution sites
Crucial photographs and Islamic State's own propaganda video helped convict 24 fanatics behind the mass killing
They were sentenced to hang by an Iraqi court but four were acquitted for lack of evidence and 604 are still at large
Published: 13:28 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 17:45 GMT, 9 July 2015
2.1k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>
	London mansion with cinema, bowling alley and GOLF COURSE selling for £20m
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154753/Mansion-goes-sale-20million-complete-cinema-bowling-alley-spa-GOLF-COURSE-garden.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The 'exceptional private estate' just 20 minutes from central London has picturesque views, a lavish seven-bedroom house and two properties for staff boasting a further four bedrooms.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
Jeremy Gee, a director at Glentree, described Grovelands as 'a remarkable country estate in London'.
He said: 'There surely cannot be many London homes that are able to boast their very own golf course.
'Approached by a long and gated driveway the house is set in 11.5 acres of outstanding grounds all surrounded by beautiful countryside.
'It is a home of exceptional quality and beauty. Its proximity to Central London means that you can live the rural idyll whilst enjoying all that London has to offer.
Decorated in white, the modern home is in pristine condition, and is part of 11.5 acres of land surrounded by beautiful countryside
There's certainly plenty of room for guests at a dinner party, with this dining room offering the ultimate in elegance and interior design
'It is an immaculate home of lavish and expansive accommodation. It offers 16,664 square feet of elegant accommodation with cutting-edge design and technology as well as extreme attention to every detail.
'There is a games room complete with its own bowling alley as well as a leisure and spa complex.
'In addition there is a detached garage complex with a staff flat above it and a separate three bedroom detached cottage.
If the weather's bad, then the property's next lucky owners could opt for a game of ten pin bowling, rather than a round of golf in the garden
Either that or they could play a game of pool. The mansion is full of entertainment facilities, with a gym, sauna and spa also included
After a busy day working in the city, what better way to wind down than putting your feet up in this slickly designed home theatre
'The large swimming pool is complemented by a pool house, outdoor kitchen, seating areas and water features with the wide terrace leading onto the impressive gardens with a natural pond feature and stunning views across the valley.
'If that were not enough there is also a private five hole golf course which must be one of the only private golf courses in a house inside London.
'Grovelands is a remarkable family estate. At 19,950,000 it is not for the faint of heart but there really are not many opportunities to purchase a property such as this and I think it will appeal to a family who want the amenities usually associated with a country home but want easy access to Central London.
'This is truly a country estate in London.'
Grovelands is tucked away in leafy Totteridge, a very wealthy suburb of North London popular with celebrities and the super-rich
The house is on the market with Glentree International for 19.5 million - making it one of the most expensive homes for sale outside of central London

Share or comment on this article
193
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>
	North Korean's Kim Jong-Un has executed 70 officials since coming to power
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154426/Seoul-North-Korean-leader-executed-70-taking-power.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Among those killed since Kim Jong-Un took power in 2011 are his uncle, Jang Song Thaek (left), and military minister Hyon Yong-Chol who was reportedly shot by anti-aircraft cannons.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Those executed included two vice ministers who had allegedly answered the dictator back, and disagreed with his policies.
As recently as July, it was reported that Ma Won-chun, the designer behind North Korea's new airport terminal in Pyongyang, had also been brutally executed.
Seemingly displeased with the design for the new building, Kim had Ma removed from his post in November last year before being killed.
U Dong-chuk, first deputy director of the State Security Department, Kim Yong Chun, first deputy defence minister, and armed forces minister Kim Jong Gak are all also missing or banished.
Jang Song Thaek, once the second most powerful man in North Korean, is pictured with his hands bound being lead into court shortly before being executed last year
Ri Yong-Ho (far left), the former head of the North Korean army, was also killed in 2012, but not before having a firefight with soldiers, reportedly leaving dozens of them dead
Among the most brutal execution was that ofHyon Yong-Chol, former military minister, who was sources claimed was shot to death using an anti-aircraft gun after falling asleep in a meeting
And yesterday it was reported that a terrapin farmer near Pyongyang was hauled away and shot after Kim took a dislike to his 'defeatist' attitude.
According to reports, Kim became enraged after the farmer said he had been unable to breed any lobsters, and had also let several tanks became dirty while baby terrapins had starved to death.
The total of 70 officials executed does not include the countless thousands of regular citizens who are believed to have died in prison and work camps under the authoritarian regime.
North Korea has been ruled by the Kim family since 1948, when Kim Il-Sung came to power after the overthrow of Japanese rule.
Kim Jong Un has removed key members of the old guard through a series of purges since taking over after the death of Kim Jong Il.
Prince of Pyongyang: Appearances of Kim Jong Un
Other victims of Kim's short temper include a terrapin farmer, who the dictator accused of being 'defeatist' after he failed to breed any lobster (pictured, Kim inspects the terrapin farm)
The architect behind Pyongyang's second airport terminal (pictured) was also rumoured to have been shot after Kim disapproved of the building and ordered work to be halted while changes were made
Experts say Kim could be using fear to solidify his leadership, but those efforts could fail if he doesn't improve the country's shattered economy.
It was thought that Kim himself could have fallen victim to a coup last year when he disappeared from view for several weeks, cancelling an appearance at a public parade.
However, after a six-week absence in which experts suggested he may have been killed during a power grab by the military, he reappeared.
While little information was given about the absence, officials put it down to treatment for a medical issue after he was last seen limping, with some suggesting he had gout after becoming addicted to fine cheese.
Share or comment on this article
39
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Game Of Thrones video reveals tricks used to create Hardhome battle
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-3153908/Game-Thrones-amazing-scenes-footage-reveals-computer-tricks-used-create-epic-Hardhome-battle.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The breathtaking brawl between the Wildlings, Night's Watch and White Walkers was easily the most ambitious set piece of the series so far, and one of the most exciting to watch.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
No Wildlings were harmed in the making of this video.
An amazing behind-the-scenes film has been released revealing the computer wizardry employed to create Game Of Thrones ' stunning Battle of Hardhome.
The epic brawl between the Wildlings, Night's Watch and White Walkers was easily the most ambitious set piece of the series so far, and one of the most exciting to watch.
Scroll down for video
Only a game: An amazing behind-the-scenes film has been released revealing the computer wizardry employed to create Game Of Thrones' stunning Battle of Hardhome, such as the sprawling Wildling encampment which seems to home thousands
Fakers: But in reality, a green screen generated most of the camp... and blocked out the workers cars in the background
In the eighth episode of the recently finished season five, Jon Snow and Tormund Giantsbane take a a fleet of ships to the last Wildling garrison beyond the Wall, where they hope to convince the Free Folk to sail south before it is too late.
But while there the massive encampment is ambushed by a rabid army of undead wights lead by the Night's King, and what follows is a visually stunning fracas involving thousands.
Or so it seemed - the sneak peek video published by visual effects company El Ranchito Imagen Digital show there were far less people there, with much of the hordes of Wildlings added digitally afterwards.
Game of Thrones (HBO) - Hardhome (VFX Breakdown) from El Ranchito Imagen Digital on Vimeo .
Valar morghulis: The epic brawl between the Wildlings, Night's Watch and White Walkers in episode eight was easily the most ambitious set piece of the series so far, and one of the most exciting to watch
Longclaw: Jon Snow is seen fighting a White Walker in a pivotal scene where he - and fans - learn that Valyrian steel can kill the icy monsters, as one spectacularly shatters beneath his blow
Ice to see you: When broken down the shot shows the stuntman still standing,  expertly hidden by the digital effect
In one shot, what looks like sprawling camp at Hardhome stretching for miles actually stops a few dozen feet from the camera at a physically erected green screen.
Behind it, the very un-Westerosi sight of electrical generators and set workers cars can be seen parked behind it.
Another clip shows the giant Wun Wun as he wades through the water to escape the maurauding undead army. As Wildlings and Black Brothers stare up at him as he passes, an unaltered shot shows that they are actually gazing at a tennis ball on a stick.
Fe fi fo fum: The giant Wun Wun is played by real life giant Ian Whyte, who at 7'1" also playedGregor 'The Mountain Who Rides' Clegane in season two
Up here: When interacting with other characters, Wun Wun is replaced by a tennis ball on a (very) long stick
The 'giant' meanwhile is shown filming his scenes separately, stomping through the water in a far less awe-inspiring pair of fisherman's wader overalls.
While he is played by regular human Ian Whyte, he his hardly regular sized: the 7'1" actor also portrayed Gregor 'The Mountain Who Rides' Clegane in season two.
One of the most terrifying scenes in the sequence was legions of reanimated corpses hurling themselves over a cliffside as they scramble to get at the fleeing Wildlings - but the pre-production shot shows the stuntmen leaping onto a cushion floor just feet below.
Nice resume: The sneak peek video was published by visual effects company El Ranchito Imagen Digital
Painstaking: As the video runs in chronological order through the battle, it pauses and shows the intricate layering that goes into every single millisecond, making it look so realistic
Jon Snow is also seen fighting a White Walker in a pivotal scene where he - and fans - learn that Valyrian steel can kill the icy monsters, as one spectacularly shatters beneath his blow.
But then the shot is broken down, it shows the stuntman still lying on the floor, after being expertly hidden by the digital effect.
As the video runs in chronological order through the battle, it pauses and shows the intricate layering that goes into every single millisecond, making it look so realistic.
Not all CGI: There are plenty of oldschool tricks in there too, like the goo-filled mannequin head that gets stomped on when a wight tries to force its way beneath the gates.
But it's not all computerized wizardry - there are plenty of oldschool tricks in there too, like the goo-filled mannequin head that gets stomped on when a wight tries to force its way beneath the gates.
The breathtaking episode was the top ranked critically in the second half of the season according to Rotten Tomaotes , receiving a perfect 100% fresh score.
It's directorMiguel Sapochnik was subsequently put in charge of the final two episodes of the upcoming season six.
Rabid: One of the most terrifying scenes in the sequence was legions of reanimated corpses hurling themselves over a cliffside
Soft landing: But the pre-production shot shows the stuntmen leaping onto a cushion floor just feet below
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Millions of emergencies are MISSED through NHS online symptom checker
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3154458/The-danger-online-diagnosis-Millions-emergencies-MISSED-symptom-checker-websites-study-warns.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Scientists at Harvard Medical School in the US have warned one in eight emergencies are missed by the NHS Choices symptom checker website, casting doubt on the safety of the internet to spot illnesses.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
71 shares
In many cases, getting the exact diagnosis may not be as important as getting the correct advice about whether -or how quickly - to go to the doctor.
'It's not nearly as important for a patient with fever, headache, stiff neck and confusion to know whether they have meningitis or encephalitis as it is for them to know that they should get to an ER quickly,' Professor Mehrotra said.
The NHS Choices site was one of the 23 sites from around the globe that the team analysed.
The website, run by the British health service, asks patients a number of questions about their symptoms and then advises them about what action to take - whether it is calling 999, going to A&amp;E, or visiting a GP.
In many cases, users should be cautious and not take the information they receive from online symptom checkers as gospel
Professor Ateev Mehrotra
But the Harvard team found that the NHS Choices site correctly identified 87 per cent of emergencies - missing 13 per cent.
Overall the site gave the correct advice in only 52 per cent of cases.
NHS Choices performed better than the other sites assessed - overall the websites picked up just 80 per cent of emergencies.
Professor Ateev Mehrotra, who led the research, warned that internet advice should always be treated with caution.
These tools may be useful in patients who are trying to decide whether they should get to a doctor quickly, but in many cases, users should be cautious and not take the information they receive from online symptom checkers as gospel, he said.
His team found there was a great deal of variation between checkers, but none were without limitations.
For example, checkers with the most accurate diagnoses (Isabel, iTriage, Mayo Clinic, and Symcat) were not on the list of the programmes that did the best job of recommending the appropriate level of care for a given case (Healthychildren.org, Steps2Care and Symptify).
NHS leaders in Britain are determined to harness the power of the internet, as a cheap way to improve healthcare.
Among the other symptom checkers studied was that by the Mayo Clinic. This site was found to be among the checkers offering the most accurate diagnoses. But researchers said none of the sites were without limitations, for example, though accurate, the Mayo Clinic's tool did not offer the best advise for care
Just this week Professor Bruce Keogh, medical director of NHS England, launched a new digital strategy which will encourage increased use of computer software and mobile phone apps.
He said: The NHS stands on the cusp of a revolution in innovation.
At its heart, innovation is the will to better, to find solutions for existing needs or new problems through more effective products, processes, technology or even the way we deliver services.
And last month the NHS also announced an increased use of web-enabled devices such as Fitbit watches.
Tim Kelsey, National Director for Patients and Information at NHS England, said at the time: The NHS is embracing the offering of digital services to patients, with more than 55 million patients set to benefit from progress.
As well as giving patients more choice and control, better use of technology can save money.
The Harvard experts said that specially-designed health sites are still much better than simply typing symptoms into a search engine such as Google.
But researcher Hannah Semigran said: The tools are not likely to go away.
With symptom trackers, were looking at the first generation of a new technology.
'Its important to continue to track their performance to see if they can reach their full potential in helping patients get the right care.
A spokesman for NHS Choices said: A team of clinicians regularly review the content of the symptom checkers based on clinical evidence and any recommendations from national guidance and update the checker accordingly.
The development processes used within the NHS Symptom Checker are accredited by NICE.
Share or comment on this article
71
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Lowell Goddard's child sex abuse inquiry begins, 1 in 20 children may have been victims
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154578/Child-abuse-inquiry-led-Justice-Goddard-finally-starts-year-announced.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The independent inquiry, now headed by Justice Goddard, was initially set up last year amid claims of an establishment cover-up following allegations that a paedophile ring operated in Westminster in the 1980s
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
Justice Goddard was appointed to lead the inquiry following the resignation of two previous chairwomen.
She said today: 'Many victims and survivors have already waited for too long for recognition of the abuse they have suffered.
'Too many individuals and institutions have been sheltered from accountability by patterns of indifference or obstruction.'
But she vowed to take on 'powerful interests' if she needs to in order to get to the truth.
Justice Goddard said victims had been ignored for too long and vowed to examine the role of all institutions
She said: 'No one, no matter how apparently powerful, will be allowed to obstruct our inquiry and no one will have immunity from scrutiny by virtue of their position. We have the tools we need to get to the truth and we will not hesitate to use them.'
The judge added: 'The sexual abuse of children over successive generations has left permanent scars, not only on the victims, but on society as a whole.'
'This inquiry provides a unique opportunity to expose past failures of institutions to protect children.'
She said there were indications of systematic 'under-recording and mis-recording' of child sex abuse by the police and other agencies.
The New Zealand high court judge warned: 'The true figures may be worse than the official figures estimate.'
The inquiry was set up amid claims of an establishment cover-up of an alleged paedophile ring  in Whitehall
Baroness Butler-Sloss stood down as chair in July last year amid questions over the role played by her late brother, Lord Havers, who was attorney general in the 1980s.
Her replacement Dame Fiona Woolf then resigned following a barrage of criticism over her 'establishment links', most notably in relation to former home secretary Leon Brittan, who died earlier this year.
Home Secretary Theresa May officially reconstituted the probe under Justice Goddard in March and placed it on a statutory footing, meaning it has the power to compel witnesses to give evidence.
The inquiry's terms of reference state that its purpose will include considering 'the extent to which State and non-State institutions have failed in their duty of care to protect children from sexual abuse and exploitation'. It will cover England and Wales.
Also on Justice Goddard's panel are Professor Malcolm Evans, of Bristol University, child protection barrister Ivor Frank, Professor Alexis Jay, who led the inquiry into child sexual exploitation in Rotherham, and Drusilla Sharpling, of the police inspectorate.
The inquiry was opened at the Queen Elizabeth II Conference Centre in Westminster this morning.
Baroness Butler-Sloss quit as chairman  after questions were raised about her brother sitting in the Cabinet in the 1980s. Her replacement Fiona Woolf later resigned over her links to former home secretary Leon Brittan
It emerged this morning that public bodies have been ordered not to shred or destroy any documents which may be of relevance to the inquiry.
Labour MP Tom Watson said: 'It is a year since the Home Secretary announced there would be an independent inquiry into child sexual abuse.
'This inquiry must meticulously track down and analyse the evidence of failures not just within public services and the 'child protection system', but across all institutions whose failings contributed directly to what we can now see is an epidemic of abuse.'
JUDGE FLOWN IN FROM NEW ZEALAND TO LEAD THE TROUBLED INQUIRY

Ministers scoured the globe in search of a suitable chairman for the child abuse inquiry, after two previous appointees resigned over links to the British Establishment.
The Foreign Office approached all Commonwealth countries, and the decision was made to appoint Justice Lowell Goddard (right), a serving High Court judge in New Zealand.
The 66-year-old helped to establish the HELP Clinic for sexual abuse victims, and helped to change the way New Zealand police dealt with abuse cases.
In 2007 she was appointed chairman of the Independent Police Conduct Authority.
During her tenure the authority released a report on the outcome of its inquiry into police handling of child abuse cases, which had begun in August 2009.
She has also served as an independent expert to the United Nations Subcommittee on Prevention of Torture.
Home Secretary Theresa May said: 'She is an outstanding candidate with experience in challenging authority in this field, having led with distinction an inquiry into police handling of child abuse cases in New Zealand.'
Married to QC John Hodson, Miss Goddard has three step-children, and one daughter from her first marriage. She breeds and races horses.

Share or comment on this article
106
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Free runners at deserted Mojave Airport in California
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154635/Leap-faith-Daring-free-runners-jump-abandoned-aircraft-broken-wings-deserted-Mojave-Airport-California.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The dramatic footage shows the free runners sliding, jumping and back-flipping from the aircraft and broken wings in the deserted boneyard at Mojave Air and Space Port in California.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Plane graveyard turned playground: Daring free runners record tricks in the abandoned airstrips of the Mojave Airport
Free runners jump, somersault and back flip from used aircraft and broken wings at Mojave Airport, in California
More than 40 parkour athletes from 14 different countries leapt from scraps of metal and parts of disused planes
Many large Boeing, McDonnell Douglas, Lockheed, and Airbus aircraft owned by major airlines are kept at Mojave
Airlines that have reached the end of their operational lives are stored in the dry desert heat to prevent them rusting
Published: 09:52 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 16:14 GMT, 9 July 2015
26 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>
	RAIN tipped for a comeback this weekend for T in the Park revellers
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154743/Festival-revellers-prepare-fun-sun-d-better-quick-RAIN-tipped-make-comeback-weekend.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The T in the Park festival is being held for the first time at Strathallan Castle in Perthshire and more than 80,000 people are expected to attend the event over the weekend.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Festival revellers prepare for fun in the sun but they'd better be quick as RAIN is tipped to make a comeback this weekend
Thousands of music fans have begun arriving at Strathallan Castle in Perthshire for this year's T in the Park festival
But forecasters warned revellers who are hoping for fun in the sun to instead expect rain for much of the weekend
More than 80,000 people expected to attend new venue, with the Libertines, Kasabian and David Guetta performing
Across the rest of the UK rain is tipped to make a comeback on Sunday after last week's hottest July day on record
Published: 12:07 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 16:10 GMT, 9 July 2015
118 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Princess Charlotte in christening photos with Kate Middleton and the Royal Family
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3154787/Princess-Charlotte-official-christening-photos-Kate-Middleton-Royal-Family.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Taken by Mario Testino, the images show the Queen and three generations of royal successors – Prince Charles, Prince William and, of course, George – at Sandringham House.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Princess Charming! First official pictures of baby Charlotte's christening - taken by Diana's favourite photographer Mario Testino
Taken by legendary fashion photographer Mario Testino, who famously shot Princess Diana's last official shoot
William and Kate chose to release four photographs in all  one formal family shot and three more intimate pictures
Shows the Queen and three generations of royal successors - Prince Charles, Prince William and, of course, George
Snaps were taken at Sandringham House, the Queen's private Norfolk residence
Princess Charlotte was christened on Sunday at the Church of St Mary Magdalene in front of just 21 guests
Published: 14:08 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 16:05 GMT, 9 July 2015
14k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>
	George Osborne to unveil British Productivity Plan with more homes and roads
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154709/George-Osborne-unveil-Productivity-Plan.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The Chancellor will unveil a Productivity Plan to tackle low levels of output productivity which he blames on the fact ‘we don’t train enough or build enough or invest enough’.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
23 shares
Mr Osborne told BBC Radio 4s Today programme: Nows the chance to seize the opportunity to become the most prosperous major economy in the world in the coming generation, lets reach out with both hands and grab it.
'What I want to do at the beginning of this parliament is address some of the really big issues our country faces.
'The lack of skills in our workforce, the fact we don't build enough homes. The fact that our roads and transport system is not of sufficiently high quality, the fact that our universities need to be put on a more sustainable funding so they remain the best in the world.'
George Osborne, who today visited BAE Systems in Warton, will tomorrow set out his Plan for Productivity, which he says will tackle the major challenges Britain faces in the 21st century
EVERY FAMILY 21,000 BETTER OFF IFPRODUCTIVITYMATCHED U.S.
Productivity, which is usually measured by output per worker or output per hour, is seen as crucial to rising wages and living standards in the long-term.
Despite the economy growing strongly and returning to pre-crash levels, productivity has remained flat.
It means that while there are more people in work, they are producing less each hour in economic output.
While the UK was the fastest growing economy in the G7 in 2014, output per hour is 17 per cent below the G7 average and is still behind that of Germany, France and the United States.
Mr Osborne believes increasing wages will help drive up productivity, because it will lead to people earning more in more highly-skilled jobs.
In every major economy where average wages are above UK levels, productivity is also higher.
If the UK matched the productivity of the US, the economy would be 31 per cent bigger  equivalent to an extra 21,000 for every household.
The Conservatives are committed to building 200,000 Starter Homes by 2020, sold at 20 per cent below market value to first-time buyers aged under 40.
They have also promised to build 275,000 more additional affordable homes by 2020, while offering 10,000 new homes to rent at below market rates, to help people save for a deposit.
Ministers will create a Brownfield Fund to unlock sites which could be developed for new homes.
Councils will have to keep a register of brownfield sites which are available, and by 2020 they will have to secure planning permission on 90 per cent of plots.
Mr Osborne believes the planning reforms are key to tackling Britains productivity problem.
The Budget promised to create a dynamic, open, enterprising economy supported by long-term public and private investment in skills, science and infrastructure.
Mr Osborne warned that underinvestment in the nations roads was holding the economy back.
Four fifths of all journeys in this country are by road, yet we rank behind Puerto Rico and Namibia in the quality of our network, he said told MPs yesterday.
In the last 25 years, France has built more than two and a half thousand miles of motorway  and weve built just 300.
He announced an overhaul of Vehicle Excise Duty, creating a new 140 flat rate for most cars, with the money earmarked for a Roads Fund to pay for the sustained investment our roads so badly need.
On skills, Mr Osborne said it is to our national shame that Britain is the only advanced country in the world where the skills of 16  24 year olds are no better than those of 55-64 year olds.
He promised 3million more apprentices, after claiming British businesses have been taking the taxpayer for a 'free ride' by underpaying their staff and not investing in training.
The Budget yesterday included plans for an apprenticeship levy on large firms who ignore the skills of their workforce, in a move which one Cabinet minister described as a kick up the 'lazy a****' of British business.
Highlights of first Conservative budget in almost 20 years
The Chancellors blames low productivity on the fact we dont train enough or build enough or invest enough
Mr Osborne said he would use 'slightly more diplomatic language' but made clear that he expected firms to do more to support the recovery, including paying the new National Living Wage in return for cuts in business taxes.
He said: There are some really great British companies, I'm at one today in Lancashire, they are hiring apprentices, they're providing great skills for their workforce.
'And there are other businesses that frankly have taken a free ride on that because they are not training their own workforces, they use the training that others have provided.
'The new apprenticeship levy is a big change. We are going to say to companies pay a levy, but you get more than that money back if you train your workforce.
Mr Osborne will also promise to tackle the problem that 'too much of our economic strength is concentrated' in London.
'This is unhealthy and unproductive, and we must achieve a better settlement for the future,' he said.
Bill Robinson, chief economist at KPMG, said: The Chancellor has addressed the urgent need to boost productivity through investing in skills and infrastructure, measures which will be very much welcomed by business.
Looking ahead, the success this Budget will be measured on is whether it can deliver the productivity growth which underpins projections for the economy.
Share or comment on this article
23
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>
	People with type 2 diabetes can suffer 'memory loss and declining decision-making skills'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3154671/Could-diabetes-trigger-DEMENTIA-People-type-2-suffer-memory-loss-declining-decision-making-skills.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Scientists at Havard believe people with type 2 diabetes lose brain power as their ability to regulate their blood sugar levels falls, resulting in memory loss and declining cognitive function.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>89 shares
People with type two diabetes have impaired blood flow regulation.
Our results suggest that diabetes and high blood sugar impose a chronic negative effect on cognitive and decision-making skills.
The study involved 40 people with an average age of 66.
Of those, 19 had type two diabetes and 21 did not have diabetes.
How type 2 diabetes develops in the body (related)
Researchers tracked type 2 diabetics for two years and hope further studies will help explore whether diabetes could trigger dementia
At the beginning of the study the participants were tested for cognition and memory, given MRI scans to look at brain volume and blood flow, and blood tests to measure control of blood sugar and inflammation.
After two years, they were tested again  and those with diabetes showed marked decreases in their ability to regulate blood flow in the brain.
They also had lower scores on several tests of memory and thinking skills - and found it harder to carry out daily tasks such as bathing and cooking.
On a test of learning and memory, the scores of the people with diabetes decreased by 12 per cent, from 46 points to 41 points, while the scores of those without diabetes stayed the same, at 55 points.
Dr Novak said: Early detection and monitoring of blood flow regulation may be an important predictor of accelerated changes in cognitive and decision-making skills.
She said additional studies involving more people and extending for a longer time period are needed to better understand the relationship and timing with blood flow regulation and changes in thinking and memory skills.
The research could explain why people with diabetes are at an increased risk of dementia.
Dr Laura Phipps of Alzheimers Research UK said: We know that inflammation is being implicated in diseases like Alzheimers, and while its interesting to see it may also impact on the brains ability to divert blood flow, its hard to separate cause and effect in this kind of research.
Studies involving more people, tested over longer periods of time, will be needed before a clearer picture can emerge.
Share or comment on this article
89
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Amelia Earhart WAS taken prisoner by Japanese say Pacific islanders
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153107/I-know-saw-saw-lady-Revealed-Pacific-islanders-insist-Amelia-Earhart-taken-prisoner-Japanese-crashing-remote-atoll.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	EXCLUSIVE: Marshall Islanders say the aviator and her navigator crashed into the Mili atoll, 850 miles from her intended destination, before being picked up by the Japanese.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
'I know what I saw and I saw the lady!' Revealed, the Pacific islanders who insist Amelia Earhart WAS taken prisoner by the Japanese after crashing on remote atoll
Earhart and navigator Fred Noonan have not been heard of since July 1937 when they took off from New Guinea on 30th leg of round the world flight
Some claim they crashed into the sea near their intended destination - but  residents of the Marshall Islands say the plane came down on Mili atoll
Descendants recall stories of an American lady 'with short hair' and a man
Doctor claimed he treated duo on a Japanese ship before they left the area
Published: 09:22 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 15:44 GMT, 9 July 2015
1k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Apple Watch wearers share photos of rashes caused by device on Twitter
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-3154660/Apple-feeling-burn-Watch-wearers-Twitter-share-photos-rashes-claim-caused-wearable.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	A handful of Twitter users have shared pictures of rashes and 'burns' they say are caused by Apple's Watch.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>407
shares
Apple feeling the burn: Watch wearers take to Twitter to share photos of rashes 'caused by the device'
Handful of people have shared photos of rashes and 'burns' on Twitter
They say they are caused by wearing the Apple Watch
Apple has not yet commented on the images, but its support page warns some people may react to materials such as nickel, used in its timepiece
Published: 11:03 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 15:39 GMT, 9 July 2015
407 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Thomson flight attendants suffer fractures during plane turbulence
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154630/Two-flight-attendants-60-50-treated-hospital-suffering-fractures-spine-pelvis-turbulence-Thomson-flight-Manchester-Cyprus.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Four crew members were rushed to hospital after the Thomson flight carrying 328 passengers and 10 crew from Manchester landed at Larnaca airport at around 9pm last night.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The pilot sent an SOS to air traffic controllers who placed emergency services on standby to rush them to hospital when the plane landed Lanarka airport at around 9pm last night.
Sources told MailOnline the pair were both conscious and calm when they arrived.
Mr Bailey was due to have a scan to assess the extent of his injuries.
Mrs O'Shea is due to be examined by a neurosurgeon tomorrow.
Two other flight attendants were also taken to hospital, but later discharged.
There were no reports of injuries to any of the plane's passengers, although some were treated for shock by ambulance staff when the jet landed.
Emergency: Four crew members were rushed to hospital with injuries after landing at Larnaka airport (above) in Cyprus at around 9pm last night
Carl Gissing, Director of Customer Service for Thomson Airways told MailOnline: 'We can confirm that TOM2334 from Manchester to Cyprus on July 8 was affected by short-term unexpected turbulence.
'All customers had seatbelts on at the time so there were no injuries.
'Unfortunately, however, four cabin crew members did sustain injuries and were taken to hospital upon arrival in Larnaca.
'While we are unable to comment further on matters of employee wellbeing, we would like to remind everyone that the safety of our customers and crew is of paramount importance and we are providing full support to those affected.'
The flight returned to Manchester at 00.30am this morning.
Share or comment on this article
609
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Fears grow for 15-year-old mother who has gone missing from home with her 12-week-old baby daughter 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154553/Fears-grow-15-year-old-mother-gone-missing-home-12-week-old-baby-daughter.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Teenage mother Katie Kelly (pictured with her daughter Kiah-Mae) has not been seen since Tuesday when she vanished from the Standens Barn area of Northampton.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
DCI Foskett said Katie had not taken any money or belongings with her, leading police to believe she had not planned to leave home. She had also not taken any formula for her little girl.
On her Facebook page, Katie has posted dozens of pictures of her new baby along with her boyfriend Karl.
Karl, from Birmingham, tweeted in May 31: 'On the way to corby [sic] to see my baby #KATIE."
Both mother and daughter were last seen at around 7.30pm on Tuesday evening in the Standens Barn area of Northampton
On April 16, Katie posted a picture of herself lying in a hospital bed cradling her newborn daughter alongside Karlos.
Police today said that Karl is also missing, but said they do not know if he is with Katie and their little girl - although she may have gone to meet him.
'Katies boyfriend Karl Boyle, aged 18, who is Kiah-Maes father, is also missing, however, we have no evidence to confirm at this point that they are together,' said DCI Foskett.
'We think she may have travelled to Northamptonshire to meet up with him and we are pursuing that as a line of enquiry, but I do not want to speculate on that at the moment.'
DCI Foskett said that around 30 officers and detectives were involved in the search for missing Katie and Kiah-Mae. 
'My main concern is that she didnt take any money or baby formula with her and Im worried about her ability to look after her little one,' he said.
Police say Katie may have gone to meet her boyfriend before she disappeared
'Katie is vulnerable and the baby is going to need food and nappies.
'I have concerns that Katie doesnt have access to that.'
DCI Foskett ruled out the possibility that Katie may have had problems at home before she went missing.
'Weve been working very closely with her foster parents, who she has lived with for some considerable time. They very worried, as we are,' he said.
'We dont know what might have triggered her disappearance. We are not aware of any problems in her home life.
'She has been in a relationship with Karl for some time and they went missing before in January but they turned up safe and well. I dont want to go into the reasons behind that.
'It may be shes being sheltered by friends and is well looked after. But if thats the case, we just want her to let us know.
Katie and Karl had vanished in January, but turned up again safe and well, police said
'We dont believe she meant to leave home and go missing. There was no pre-planning. Her mobile phone is switched off and she has not been active on social media since she went missing.
'Her foster parents called us to report her missing and we have informed her natural mother.
'Weve had a lot of interest in our appeal on social media but no leads to pursue as yet. We need positive sightings.'
He added:'I want anyone who may have seen Katie or Kiah-Mae since Tuesday evening to contact us as a matter of urgency.
'We believe Katie is still in Northamptonshire, but we are keeping an open mind as to where she could be.'
Katie is described at 5ft 7ins tall and of a slim build, with long, dark brown, straight hair and green eyes.
When she was last seen, she was wearing a diamond effect bracelet and gold locket, and was dressed in a pair of black leggings, a white t-shirt and trainers.
Anyone with any information can call Northamptonshire Police on 101. Alternatively, they can call the independent charity Crimestoppers anonymously on 0800 555 111 or use the anonymous online form at www.crimestoppers-uk.org .
Both mother and daughter were last seen in the Daventry area, and police believe they could now be in Northampton (pictured)
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
1.5k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Hikikomori the condition causing Japanese men to lock themselves inside for YEARS
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154180/Pictured-sufferers-bizarre-condition-s-forcing-one-MILLION-Japanese-people-lock-inside-years-surfing-internet-reading-manga.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The sufferers of 'Hikikomori' – mostly young Japanese men - have such severe social withdrawal they isolate themselves in their bedroom, in some cases for years.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Yuto Onishi, 18, from Tokyo had not left his bedroom for almost three years before he sought treatment six months ago, ABC's 7.30 reported.
He spent his days asleep and nights surfing the internet and reading Japanese manga, and did not talk to anybody.
Mr Onishi said he believed his condition was triggered by an incident at junior high school when he failed as a class leader.
Hikikomori: A deafening silence documentary trailer
Sufferers, who withdraw from society and refuse contact with friends, are often 'intelligent and capable'
Yuto Onishi, 18, from Tokyo had not left his bedroom for almost three years before he sought treatment
He spent his days asleep and nights surfing the internet and reading manga, and did not talk to anybody
'Once you experience it, you lose reality,' Mr Onishi told 7.30.
'I knew it was abnormal but I didn't want to change. It felt safe here.'
The term hikikomori can refer to both the condition and the people who suffer from it.
Japan's Ministry of Health, Labor and Welfare defines hikikomori as people who do not participate in society - mainly work or study - and do not have any close non-familial relationships. Their symptoms must last for six months or longer, Tofugu reported.
Dr Kato said he believed many environmental contributed to hikikomori, with most cases arising in middle class families.
'Its very rare to find hikikomori in poor families,' he said.
'So middle class environment, middle class families, have a high risk of hikikomori.
One of the few hikikomori experts in Japan, Dr Takahiro Kato, suffered from the condition as a student and is now working to prevent it from having a widespread affect on the next generation
'Majority of hikikomori are graduated people, after graduating university they became hikikomori.'
Many hikikomori stay locked in the bedroom of the family home, and often parents will support their children.
'Japan is very different from western society, for example the mother-child relationship is strongly different to western society,' Dr Kato said.
'Japanese parents are overprotective to their children.For some people it can be difficult to be independent.
'Its one reason why Japan have many more hikikomori compared to western society.'
He added that: 'In Japanese society boys have very much more pressure to enter good university, good company and many - especially male - are under very, very strong pressure.'
Dr Kato said therapy is necessary for family members as well as sufferers in order to change the relationships and group dynamic.
Hikikomori and counsellors at Dr. Saito Tamaki's clinic at the Sofukai Sasaki Hospital near Tokyo
He is working with a team of experts at Kyushu University  to study the social and biological factors that contribute to hikikomori in order to come up with a 'multi-dimensional diagnosis'.
'Most case studies have only focused on the psychological aspect, but hikikomori is not just about mental illness,' he told 7.30.
Treatment for sufferers involves rebuilding communication skills as a first step, with some having not talked to loved ones for years.
'The main therapy approach is psychotherapy - especially group psychotherapy because many hikikomori people do not communicate with others so they need to have some communication experience in a group,' Dr Kato said.
But with many hikikomori reluctant to talk to their own families, let alone seek treatment, Japan faces serious challenges in identifying the problem for future generations.
'Its not only diagnosis, we also hope we can predict the risk of hikikomori,' Dr Kato said.

Read more:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Mentally ill Aaron Lane 'killed himself after being taken off disability benefits'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154760/Mentally-ill-musician-killed-taken-disability-benefits-ruled-fit-work.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Aaron Lane, who suffered from psychosis, was found dead at his home in Newark, Nottinghamshire, weeks after he was taken off Employment and Support Allowance.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Mr Lane was found dead in his flat on June 21 after police forced entry into the property.
The former Newark High pupil knew there was something wrong with him as a teenager. He sought medical help and was later diagnosed with psychosis.
His father said: 'It's hard looking back to pinpoint how and when the psychosis started. He started to become withdrawn.'
The troubled young man's musical ability earned him a place at the London Royal Academy of Music when he was 24.
Tragic: His family say Mr Lane, 31, feared he would lose all his benefits after he was moved from claiming Employment Support Allowance to Jobseeker's Allowance
However, he became homeless and ended up moving back home a year later, continuing to have what his parents described as deep psychotic episodes. Unable to cope, they had him sectioned under the Mental Health Act.
After his condition improved, Mr Lane got his own flat. He was on regular medication and found a temporary job over Christmas 2014.
'We don't blame anyone but Aaron was let down across the system. He was too often a box to tick
Steve Lane, Aaron Lane's father
His father said:'But then we began to notice he had started talking to himself again.
'He was given drugs to control it and to a degree he returned to normality. All he ever wanted was to be normal.
'There is a stigma attached to mental health issues that is as bad today as it has ever been.
'People are scared of what they can't see. If Aaron's story does anything, hopefully it will be to change just one perception.'
The Department for Work and Pensions said it had followed all the correct procedures in Mr Lane's case.
A spokesman said: 'Our sympathies are with Mr Lane's family. We provide tailored support to jobseekers and if we become aware of health changes that mean they can't work we can offer support. Mr Lane was still in receipt of Jobseeker's Allowance at the time of his death.'
Talented: The troubled young man's musical ability earned him a place at the London Royal Academy of Music when he was 24 but became homeless
A spokesman for Lincolnshire Partnership NHS Foundation Trust, which is responsible for mental health care in the area, said: 'Due to patient confidentially we are not able to comment on the circumstances of a specific patient death, or the care and treatment a patient was receiving from the trust's services.
'However, we are able to confirm that where there is a patient death, our thoughts are first and foremost with the family of the deceased.
'We will always seek to communicate directly with a bereaved family to ensure they are aware of support available, informed about the related investigation processes, and able to voice any related questions or concerns.
'We do investigate all such incidents to determine if there are lessons that can be learnt to support the continuous improvement of services in the future.'
An inquest into Mr Lane's death will be held in December.
For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Marie Buchan 'will lose her house' under George Osborne's £20k welfare limit
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154685/The-benefits-cap-make-homeless-Mother-eight-rakes-26-000-year-handouts-claims-lose-house-George-Osborne-s-20-000-welfare-limit.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Jobless Marie Buchan, 33, from Selley Oak in Birmingham says the Chancellor's new measures aimed at cutting welfare spending will leave her family on the breadline
      </Description>
        <MainBody>'The benefits cap will make me homeless': Mother-of-eight who rakes in 26,000 a year in handouts claims she will lose her house under George Osborne's 20,000 welfare limit
Marie Buchan, 33, says welfare cuts will leave her family on the breadline
Says if her handouts are cut she will be forced out of four-bedroom home
She receives around 2,000 a month in benefits, including child benefit, income support and housing benefit, and pays 137 a week in rent
Money is  equivalent to the take home pay of someone earning a salary of 34,500 a year before tax
Published: 10:43 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 14:39 GMT, 9 July 2015
10k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date/>
        <title>
	ISIS militants execute Iraqi tribal women and children in Anbar
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154672/Iraqi-tribal-chief-recalls-horror-women-children-burnt-death-ISIS-militants-five-brave-mothers-refuse-allow-children-child-soldiers.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The claim was described in graphic detail by tribal leader Sheikh Naim al-Kaoud, who said that the women and children were rounded up by ISIS gangs and set on fire in the streets.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The Albu Nimr tribe have been waging a longstanding war against jihadi militants, dating back to the start of 2007 when Al-Qaeda fighters attempts to secure territory in the province.
Human rights activists believe as many as 600-700 Albu Nimr tribesmen have been murdered by ISIS militants in retaliation for their continued resistance last summer.
The latest ISIS atrocities against the Albu Nimr tribe comes after a long campaign of clashes
The latest Iraqi government offensive has ambitiously targeted the re-capturing of the city of Fallujah
Shiite paramilitary groups continue to fight in co-ordination with the Iraqi army against ISIS
The Albu Nimr tribesmen were taken out into the desert by ISIS militants, ordered to lie on the ground and gunned down in a hail of bullets.
A similar massacre was carried out by ISIS fighters on members of the Shaitat tribe in the Syrian province of Deir ezZor. Video evidence emerged of piles of bodies lying in the desert last summer.
Despite watching a number of other high profile Sunni tribes pledging their allegiance of support to ISIS, the Albu Nimr tribe fights on.
ISIS seized control of Heet from Iraqi forces last October and immediately started to implement the group's radical interpretation of Shariah law.
As many as 90 Iraqi civilians were reportedly killed recently in clashes between ISIS and Iraqi coalition forces near the city of Fallujah
ISIS forces continue to clash with Iraqi forces in Anbar province and are looking to target the city of Haditha
The jihadi group have released numerous photographs of public floggings and brutal executions, with the most punishments coming from Iraq's largest province, Anbar.
Since seizing the Iraqi city of Ramadi, some 31 miles east of Hit, ISIS have faced several failed Iraqi army counter attacks on Ramadi.
Most recently, President Haider al-Abadi ordered a fresh offensive on the ISIS held city of Fallujah with the Iraqi army combining forces with Shiite militia groups.
Already the Fallujah offensive has led to heavy civilian casualties with coalition member MP Hamed al-Mutlaq confirming in a recent press conference that as many as 90 civilians had died in the fighting since the start of Ramadan on 18 June.
Share or comment on this article
108
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Ancient Chinese script may prove Asians discovered America 3,300 years ago
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-3152556/Did-China-discover-AMERICA-Ancient-Chinese-script-carved-rocks-prove-Asians-lived-New-World-3-300-years-ago.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Author and researcher John Ruskamp claims to have found pictograms from the ancient Chinese Shang Dynasty etched into rocks in New Mexico, California and Arizona.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>2.8k
shares
Did China discover AMERICA? Ancient Chinese script carved into rocks may prove Asians lived in New World 3,300 years ago
Author and researcher John Ruskamp claims to have found pictograms from the ancient Chinese Shang Dynasty etched into rocks in America
The symbols are carved into rocks in New Mexico, California and Arizona
He says the Chinese were exploring North America long before Europeans
He claims the symbols give details of journeys and honour the Shang king
Published: 09:13 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 14:26 GMT, 9 July 2015
2.8k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Woman is confused by how long it'd take to drive 80 miles at 80mph
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154659/How-long-drive-80-miles-80-miles-hour-Watch-mother-two-stumped-one-simple-question.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Lauren Macklin (pictured), of Hereford, asked fiancé Dave Mapp if he'd prefer 'someone brainy or someone like her.' He then put her mind to the test, asking how long it'd take to travel 80 miles at 80mph.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
He whipped out his mobile phone, already convinced his 'ditzy' 25-year-old fiancwas on the cusp of delivering something worth saving.
With the device's video camera recording, Lauren is then stumped for a full seven minutes as she first tries to answer the question - and then struggles with her labourer partner's explanation.
After being shared online, the hilarious video has since been viewed more than four million times.
In it, blonde Lauren can be heard saying 'how am I supposed to know that?', before asking: 'How long does it take to do a minute?'
'How long would it take you to travel 80 miles?'...'8 minutes'
Right, let's work this one out: Lauren's eyes dot side-to-side as she contemplates the answer to the question
The wheels are turning: Looking for help from above, the nail technician offers up two answers - eight and 80 minutes
But...wait: The mother-of-two offers up to guesses to the answer - eight minutes and 80 minutes
Her eyes darting from side-to-side, she's clearly focused on trying to find the correct answer - even though it is stated in the question.
Lauren's first guess is eight minutes, adding that she got there by dividing eight by ten.
She later gives up, insisting that she doesn't know and that the thinking is 'hurting my brain cells'. She then again concludes that it takes eight minutes to drive 80 miles.
When pressed once more for an answer, she has a stab at 80 minutes, before finally being put out of her misery.
Lauren - pictured with fianc Dave - said the 80mph question was particularly perplexing as she does not drive
The soon to be wed pair stand alongside their son George, and Lauren's daughter from a previous relationship, Ella-Rose
Thankfully Lauren doesn't drive herself yet. She estimates it could be five years before she passes her theory test as she finds if 'very tricky'.
The nail technician said: 'I am who I am and Dave loves me for who I am, which is the most important thing. He says it's exciting being with me as he never knows what I'm going to say next.
'I like making him laugh but it's never on purpose. I don't think it would be funny if I tried to make him laugh.
'I have to be careful with the kids. Sometimes Ella-Rose asks me spellings on the way to school. I just tell her it's too early in the morning. But she often laughs at me and says I don't know. I have to find an excuse if she needs help with her homework and make sure Dave is around instead!'
Lauren said that the 80mph question was particularly perplexing as she does not drive.
Lauren has been compared to reality star Joey Essex (pictured), who is known for lacking common sense
'So I was trying to figure out how quickly Dave could drive to somewhere 80 miles away,' she said.
'I came up with eight minutes, which sounded right at first but then I realised that was a bit quick. I thought it was a trick question to be honest.'
Dave, 28,  said: 'I knew she wouldn't know the answer but after she asked me that question, I thought what better time to have a laugh.
'She was completely baffled by it, even after I explained it to her. But she's always like that - things that the average person knows, she simply doesn't have a clue on.
'She's the female Joey Essex - there should be a show about her, Educating Lauren Macklin. It would be a hit, I'm sure.
Lauren was recently stumped by how footballer Wayne Rooney could play for both Manchester United and England
The mother-of-two also referred to a leopard as looking 'just like a big cat, when you think about it'
'She really is one in a million, I love her just the way she is and everyone who meets her does too. I wouldn't change her for the world as she is a laugh a minute.'
The couple met five years ago under unusual circumstances.
Lauren had spotted Dave on a night out in Hereford and took a liking to him but when he wasn't out the following week decided to ask his friends for his name.
She added him on Facebook that night and proceeded to ask if she could come over. They've been together ever since and have had two-year-old George together.
Dave also looks after Ella-Rose, six, from Lauren's previous relationship.
'Whenever I need cheering up I just ask her a general knowledge question and wait for what she says', said Dave.
'You can never predict the answers that come out.'
Another innocent victim gets stumped by the 80mph question
Lauren is happy being called 'ditzy' by her friends and says she always struggled at school with most subjects, in particular maths. She got an E in her GCSE of the subject.
Recently, she asked Dave how Wayne Rooney could get away with playing for both England and Manchester United, and while on a trip to the zoo pointed at a leopard and said she thought it 'looked just like a big cat when you think about it.'
Despite not being the brightest, Dave insists he's the fortunate one in the relationship - adding that Lauren is way out of his league.
I do think I'm punching above my weight. I'm very lucky for sure.
Lauren's fianc, Dave Mapp
He said: 'As you can see, she's very beautiful, so I do think I'm punching above my weight. I'm very lucky for sure.'
And although he's outed her online for being somewhat ditzy, Lauren doesn't mind.
'I couldn't believe it when I saw the video on social media,' said Lauren. 'I have no make-up on, it's very embarrassing.
'But once I saw how much it made him and his friends laugh I soon got over it. It's nice to make people smile and I do see the funny side.'
The 80mph question has stumped a number of unsuspecting victims online, with several similar videos posted in the past showing car passengers struggling to find the answer.
Share or comment on this article
5k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Brazilian store workers fight back after realising robbers' weapons are fake
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154886/Armed-robbers-force-shop-workers-hand-cash-gunpoint-Brazil-one-staff-realises-got-fake-firearms-s-payback-time.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	It all seemed to be going so well for three robbers, who were raiding a store in Brazil until their hostages realised they were only armed with replica weapons and fought back.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Another store worker listens to the chatting. She is wearing white cargo trousers and a dark pink t-shirt and can be seen checking boxed items off a clipboard.
In walks a second man, wearing a white t-shirt and a light blue netted baseball cap. The  video pauses on his face although it is not yet known if he has been arrested.
Robbery goes wrong when store worker realises gun is fake
Split second decision: The moment the store worker realises the weapons are fake, two of the robbers run for their lives, leaving behind their friend
Hammer blow: Trapped behind a desk, the robber is subjected to a considerable beating by one of the workers
Bonecrunching: Using an office chair, the store worker repeatedly hits the robber over the head
The third robber arrives, dressed in a white t-shirt with a distinctive red stripe across the chest.
At this point the man in the red tank top and the man wearing a baseball cap pull out handguns and start pointing them at the store workers, ordering them to the ground.
Whilst casually helping themselves to stock items and cash, one of the robbers suddenly sprint out of the store, leaving behind his fellow criminals.
A member of staff has realised the weapons are fake and quickly gets up as the second robber legs it outside.
Attempted escape: The third robber tries to make a break for freedom but is quickly apprehended
Busted in Brazil: It is unclear what happened to the three robbers although it is unlikely they will try to rob this store again
Enraged by the attempted robbery, the orange shirted store worker grabs an office swivel chair and raises it above his head. With all his might, he brings the whole chair down on the robber, who is sitting behind the desk.
Again the store worker clubs the robber several more times before the third robber manages to crawl and head for the door.
The purple shirted female member of staff wrestles with the robber as he desperately tries to escape out of the shop door.
Although it is unclear what happened to the three robbers, it is unlikely they will try to rob this store again.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Gold ring worth £30k once owned by 'Wolf Hall' advisor Thomas Cromwell 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154799/Jewel-encrusted-15th-Century-ring-worth-30-000-discovered-treasure-hunter-metal-detector-monastery-owned-Wolf-Hall-advisor-Thomas-Cromwell.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The 15th Century 'love ring' was uncovered near Launde Abbey in Leicestershire, a manor house once owned by Thomas Cromwell, the subject Hilary Mantel's Wolf Hall novels.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
982 shares
The land where the Abbey, now a Christian retreat and conference centre, stands had been home to a large and wealthy Augustinian Priory since the 12th century.
Cromwell was so impressed by the building and particularly its location that while he was surveying it as he oversaw the dissolution of the monasteries for the king that he presented it to himself, writing in his diary: 'Myself for Launde'.
Cromwell (left in a painting by Hans Holbein, and right as played by Mark Rylance in Wolf Hall) was so impressed by the building and particularly its location that while he was surveying it as he oversaw the dissolution of the monasteries for the king that he presented it to himself
Building work on a new house at the site was started in 1540, but Cromwell's execution that same year prevented him from ever moving in.
Instead his son Gregory and his wife Elizabeth Seymour, the sister of Henry VIIIs third wife Jane Seymour, lived there.
The ring is to go on sale at auction house Sotheby's in London this afternoon, along with several pieces of 15th century jewellery.
Erik Bijzet, Sotheby's Old Master Sculpture &amp; Works of Art specialist, said: 'The movement of wealthy patrons around a major monastery, the violence with which the rich institution must have been taken for the Crown, and the importance of the subsequent inhabitants are all reasons for a ring of this significance to have been deposited in its vicinity.'
Damian Lewis stars in BBC Two period drama Wolf Hall
The stunning piece of jewellery is an early example of a love and marriage ring, with the bond between husband and wife symbolised by two different gems - here a point-cut diamond and a rounded ruby
HENRY'S TRUSTED ADVISOR WHO PLOTTED THE RISE AND FALL OF ANNE BOLEYN, BUT ENDED UP SUFFERING A SIMILAR FATE
The son of a blacksmith, Thomas Cromwell was bornaround 1485, in Putney, and rose from humble origins to become asuccessful lawyer and politician - and one of Henry VIII's most trusted advisers.
As a young man, Cromwell, played by actor Mark Rylance in the BBC adaptation of Hilary Mantel's novel Wolf Hall, travelled to Europe, and is thought to have fought as a mercenary in the French army in Italy.
Cromwell had married Elizabeth Wyckes in 1515 and the couple had three children - Gregory, Anne and Grace.
Cromwell, played by actor Mark Rylance in the BBC adaptation of Hilary Mantel's novel Wolf Hall, played a key role in helping arrange the annulment of Henry's marriage to Catherine Aragon, enabling the monarch to marry Anne Boleyn
But his daughters did not survive childhood, and Elizabeth died in 1528 - during an epidemic of sweating sickness.
He rose to prominence after becoming an MP for Taunton, Somerset, and serving in the household of Cardinal Thomas Wolsey, andplayed a key role in helping arrange the annulment of Henry's marriage to Catherine Aragon, enabling the monarch to marry Anne Boleyn.
He was also an enthusiastic supporter of the Kings reform of the Church.
Cromwell fell from Henry's favour after arranging the monarch's marriage to Anne of Cleves (pictured) - which was annulled just six months after they married in January 1540
Anne had been one of Cromwell's strongest allies, but in 1536, the pair clashed over plans for the proceeds from the dissolution of the monasteries following reformation of the church.
The Queen instructed her chaplains to preach against Cromwell, leading to one - John Skip - to be called before the Privy Council and accused of various crimes including malice, slander,  lack of charity, sedition, treason, disobedience to the gospel, and inviting anarchy.
Anne had failed to produce a male heir, and was not popular at court, or among the people.
She was accused of adultery with musician Mark Smeaton, Henry Norris, the King's groom of the stool and one of his closest friends, Sir Francis Weston, William Brereton and even her own brother, George, Viscount Rochford.
In a letter to  Charles V, ambassador Eustace Chapuys, wrote that 'he himself [Cromwell] has been authorised and commissioned by the king to prosecute and bring to an end the mistress's trial, to do which he had taken considerable trouble ... He set himself to devise and conspire the said affair'.
Anne's marriage to Henry was deemed invalid, their daughter Elizabeth declared illegitimate, and on May 28, 1536, Anne was executed - with the King marrying Jane Seymour two days later.
During his career, Cromwell served England's monarch Henry VIII in a number of roles, including the Lord Privy Seal, Lord Chamberlain, Master of the Rolls, Secretary of State, Chancellor of the Exchequer and Earl of Essex.
But Cromwell fell from Henry's favour after arranging the monarch's marriage to Anne of Cleves - which wasannulled just six months after they married in January 1540.
He was beheaded for treason and herecy at Tower Hill on July 28, 1540 - the same day that Henry married Catherine Howard, but the King later came to regret Cromwell's execution, and accused his ministers of bringing about Cromwell's downfall by false charges.
Oliver Cromwell, who after the English civil war ruled as Lord Protector, was descended from Thomass sister, Katherine.

Share or comment on this article
982
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Luca Spencer who was punched by bullies told by teacher 'Don't be the victim'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154767/Mother-takes-nine-year-old-boy-school-punched-kicked-bullies-teacher-tell-Don-t-victim.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Luca Spencer, nine, claims to have been attacked in a garden  in the playground at St Catherines RC Primary School in Didsbury. Manchester.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'Luca said he walked away and went to the toilet. He went back to the peace garden because he could see the boys weren't playing there anymore.
'But they went back and carried on hitting him and kicking him.'
Ms Spencer says her son then told his teacher, who allegedly responded: 'Just go away, don't be the victim because you won't always be the victim.'
The schoolboy says he was given these injuries by a group of children who attacked him in the playground
The 31-year-old added she had heard the teacher saying 'the exact thing' to other children in the playground in the past.
'Luca needs to be confident he can tell teachers what has happened without being mocked,' she went on.
'He doesn't feel safe with that teacher and hes not going back into that class  hes intimidated and doesnt trust him. Im not unreasonable, I do want him to go back into school, just not in that class.
'But something needs to be done about the teacher and these bullies.'
A spokesman for the school said it was investigating the incident but would not comment further other than to say: 'We take all safeguarding incidents extremely seriously and we would like to reassure parents that the welfare of the children at our school is of paramount importance.'
The nine-year-old's mother said she would like to reintroduce him to the school but not to the same class

Share or comment on this article
58
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Alopecia sufferer embraces going bald after her hair fell out
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3147375/Blonde-brunette-love-changing-wig-suit-mood-says-teenage-alopecia-sufferer-18-embraced-going-bald.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Sian Pennant-Jones, 18, from Portishead, north Somerset, was diagnosed with alopecia totalis and feared she would have to give up her dream career as a dancer, but now loves changing her hair colour to suit her mood.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>'Blonde or brunette, I love changing my wig to suit my mood,' says teenage alopecia sufferer, 18, who has embraced going bald
Sian Pennant-Jones' hair began falling out after her exams, and within three weeks she was completely bald
Was diagnosed with alopecia and told she would need to wear a wig
She was due to start a job as a holiday club entertainer and was devastated as she knew the NHS wigs might slip off during a performance
Her mother set up a fundraising page and raised enough money to buy a non-slip wig so she can perform with pride
Published: 09:54 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 13:02 GMT, 9 July 2015
123 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Vegetarianism 'could save the world' by cutting greenhouse emissions
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-3154785/Could-vegetarianism-save-world-away-meat-cut-greenhouse-emissions-boost-biodiversity-study-claims.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Our insatiable appetite for everything from burgers to barbecued chicken (pictured) is having a serious effect on the environment, researchers from the UK and Germany claim.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>3.3k
shares
Could vegetarianism save the world? A move away from meat would cut greenhouse emissions and boost biodiversity, study claims
Researchersfrom the Universities of East Anglia andGreifswald, Germany believeenvironmentaldamage could be prevented by vegetarianism
Say livestock industry isresponsiblefor rising greenhouse emissions, deforestation, as well as a decline in biodiversity and water quality
Article says meat production is associated with 18 per cent of global greenhouse gas emissions and approximately one third of biodiversity loss
Published: 12:25 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 13:01 GMT, 9 July 2015
3.3k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Greece's creditors must make a 'realistic' proposal' says EU President
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154484/Ryanair-boss-blasts-Greece-electing-bunch-lunatics-hoping-away-austerity-country-forces-banks-stay-closed-rest-week.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Donald Tusk said that Greece's creditors must make a 'realistic' proposal for managing the country's huge debt, as Athens faces a midnight deadline to submit reform plans for an international bailout.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Europe backs down first as EU president concedes Greece's creditors must make a 'realistic' proposal for managing the country's debts
Donald Tusk said he hopes Athens will submit 'concrete and realistic proposals' for economic reform tonight
But heinsistedthat the creditors' terms for an international bailout must be an 'equally realistic proposal'
Greece has untilmidnightto submit formal plans for economic reform that will satisfy its creditors
The creditors then have until Sunday to review the plans and decide whether to bail Greece out once again
Published: 07:58 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 13:00 GMT, 9 July 2015
360 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Homeless Philippines boy uses McDonald's light so he can do his homework
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154589/The-inspirational-thing-today-Young-homeless-boy-uses-light-McDonald-s-restaurant-homework-street-Philippines.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Crouched low behind a improvised wooden desk, the young boy appears to be using the light from the nearby McDonald's restaurant to help see his homework in the darkness.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Crouched low behind a improvised wooden desk, the young boy appears to be using the light from the nearby McDonald's restaurant to help see his homework in the darkness.
This inspiring photo is believed to be of Daniel Cabrera, a young boy who dreams of becoming either a doctor or a police, who was spotted studying in the streets of the Philippines.
Medical student Joyce Torrefranca noticed the boy whilst walking home late at night and felt so moved, she took a quick photo and shared it on her social media page.
A lighting light: The young boy has been identified as nine-year-old Daniel Cabrera, a student in Mandaue city
Inspirational: Daniel lives with his mother and younger brother in a food stall without any walls
According to Rappler, Daniel, 9, is at a Grade 3 elementary school student in Mandaue City.
He only owns a single pencil after one of his fellow students stole his second pencil from him.
It is believed he lives with his mother and younger brother in a small, wall less food stall after his father died in prison and his old home burnt down.
Despite the difficult conditions, Daniel is committed to his studies and whilst his classmates are playing football in the streets, he is often spotted studying in the light of the restaurant.
Daniel was noticed by medical student Joyce Torrefranca, who posted the photo online, saying she felt 'inspired by a kid.'
The photo was quickly shared, with dozens of people commenting how impressed they were with the young boy's studying efforts.
Joyce later wrote: 'I didn't think that a simple photo can make a huge difference. Thank you guys for sharing the photo. With that, we were able to help Daniel in reaching his dreams.'
Giomen Probert Ladra Alayon also saw the boy studying in the street and managed to have a quick conversation with him.
Writing on his social media page, Giomen praises nine-year old Daniel:
'His example leaves us to ask ourselves, 'If this kid can do it, why can't we? Why do we need to go to coffee shops, study centers, etc. to pay much if studying only requires study materials and your own will power?'
Joyce Torrefranca saw the young boy and felt so touched by his efforts, she took a quick photograph of him
The photos have generated dozens of shares and comments with many people asking how they can help him
He praises the 'real star' of the story as Daniel Cabrera, 'whose determination inspired us and definitely sent an uproar in social media on what studying really means!'
Alayon also commented on how Daniel's attitude should be used as an example by more people.
He wrote: 'Daniel perseveres because he knows how it feels to have nothing. We should learn from him. Life's greatest lessons come not from famous personalities but from simple people. Keep your eyes and mind open.'
'We should learn from him. And with that discipline and focus, I'm sure he will become someone someday! God bless everyone! Good day!'
A fundraising page has been set up for Daniel, intended to reward the young boy's dedication to his studies by encouraging people to help fund the young boy's education.
The page has already generated 22,900 (around 329) and is nearly halfway towards its target of raising over 50,000 (over 700) for helping Daniel's school career.
Share or comment on this article
12k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Homeless Philippines boy uses McDonald's light so he can do his homework
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154589/The-inspirational-thing-today-Young-homeless-boy-uses-light-McDonald-s-restaurant-homework-street-Philippines.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Crouched low behind a improvised wooden desk, the young boy appears to be using the light from the nearby McDonald's restaurant to help see his homework in the darkness.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Crouched low behind a improvised wooden desk, the young boy appears to be using the light from the nearby McDonald's restaurant to help see his homework in the darkness.
This inspiring photo is believed to be of Daniel Cabrera, a young boy who dreams of becoming either a doctor or a police, who was spotted studying in the streets of the Philippines.
Medical student Joyce Torrefranca noticed the boy whilst walking home late at night and felt so moved, she took a quick photo and shared it on her social media page.
A lighting light: The young boy has been identified as nine-year-old Daniel Cabrera, a student in Mandaue city
Inspirational: Daniel lives with his mother and younger brother in a food stall without any walls
According to Rappler, Daniel, 9, is at a Grade 3 elementary school student in Mandaue City.
He only owns a single pencil after one of his fellow students stole his second pencil from him.
It is believed he lives with his mother and younger brother in a small, wall less food stall after his father died in prison and his old home burnt down.
Despite the difficult conditions, Daniel is committed to his studies and whilst his classmates are playing football in the streets, he is often spotted studying in the light of the restaurant.
Daniel was noticed by medical student Joyce Torrefranca, who posted the photo online, saying she felt 'inspired by a kid.'
The photo was quickly shared, with dozens of people commenting how impressed they were with the young boy's studying efforts.
Joyce later wrote: 'I didn't think that a simple photo can make a huge difference. Thank you guys for sharing the photo. With that, we were able to help Daniel in reaching his dreams.'
Giomen Probert Ladra Alayon also saw the boy studying in the street and managed to have a quick conversation with him.
Writing on his social media page, Giomen praises nine-year old Daniel:
'His example leaves us to ask ourselves, 'If this kid can do it, why can't we? Why do we need to go to coffee shops, study centers, etc. to pay much if studying only requires study materials and your own will power?'
Joyce Torrefranca saw the young boy and felt so touched by his efforts, she took a quick photograph of him
The photos have generated dozens of shares and comments with many people asking how they can help him
He praises the 'real star' of the story as Daniel Cabrera, 'whose determination inspired us and definitely sent an uproar in social media on what studying really means!'
Alayon also commented on how Daniel's attitude should be used as an example by more people.
He wrote: 'Daniel perseveres because he knows how it feels to have nothing. We should learn from him. Life's greatest lessons come not from famous personalities but from simple people. Keep your eyes and mind open.'
'We should learn from him. And with that discipline and focus, I'm sure he will become someone someday! God bless everyone! Good day!'
A fundraising page has been set up for Daniel, intended to reward the young boy's dedication to his studies by encouraging people to help fund the young boy's education.
The page has already generated 22,900 (around 329) and is nearly halfway towards its target of raising over 50,000 (over 700) for helping Daniel's school career.
Share or comment on this article
12k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Boko Haram 'agree to release 216 kidnapped Chibok schoolgirls in exchange for Nigerian government prisoners'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154557/Boko-Haram-extremists-agree-release-216-kidnapped-Chibok-schoolgirls-exchange-16-brutal-terror-leaders-imprisoned-Nigerian-government.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The offer is limited to the 219 students who were taken from a boarding school in the northeastern town of Chibok in April 2014, sparking global outrage and a campaign to 'Bring Back Our Girls'.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Boko Haram extremists 'agree to release 216 kidnapped Chibok schoolgirls in exchange for 16 brutal terror leaders who are imprisoned by the Nigerian government'
Human rights activist says Nigerian terror group have agreed to free girls
But they are demanding 16 senior jihadis are released by the government
Girls were kidnapped from a boarding school in Chibok in April 2014
Their abduction sparked global outrage and an international campaign calling for their release
But Boko Haram have used them as a bartering chip to free fellow militants
Published: 09:07 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 12:51 GMT, 9 July 2015
70 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Abbi Rigby finds venomous African Sac spider in Asda grapes
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154723/Mother-finds-venomous-African-spider-grapes-d-bought-Asda-feed-daughters.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Abbi Rigby bought the fruit from her local supermarket in Newcastle-under-Lyme, Staffordshire, on Tuesday and planned to give it to her daughters as an after-school snack before she found the spider.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'I saw something white and furry and it was a web. I looked inside the web and there was this spider.
'It was small but I panicked. I'm petrified of spiders. What if I had picked up the grape it was on and eaten it?'
The mother-of-three phoned Asda after returning home and was told to bring it back into the store along with the grapes.
Abbi Rigby had already eaten some of the grapes when she noticed the spider as it moved around in the packet
The mother-of-three returned the fruit to her local supermarket (above) and the chain is now investigating
The supermarket is now investigating how it came to find itself among the fruit. 
THE AFRICAN SAC SPIDER
Sac spiders bite more humans than any other spider in Africa, letting off the venom cytotoxin.
The substance kills cells, leading to blistering and tissue breakdown wherever they bite.
Though most are quite pale, some exhibit a light green colour.
All have long front legs which are used to hunt at night. During the day the species weaves itself a silk cocoon to rest in.
'Luckily I spotted it before my children got in the car, otherwise it could have bitten them,' added Ms Rigby.
'I have heard so many stories about these sort of things. It has put me off grapes forever now.'
A spokesman for the chain said checks had taken place but 'sometimes insects tag along to give us a fright.'
Wildlife experts however described the scenario as 'uncommon', with a spokesman for Staffordshire Wildlife Trust saying: 'With modern refrigeration, spiders and other invertebrates don't usually survive.'
The African Sac spider accounts for more than 70 per cent of bites in South Africa.Their venom causes the death of tissue around the bite, and symptoms normally become appear between two and eight hours afterwards.

Share or comment on this article
99
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date/>
        <title>
	British children should take 'Life in the UK test' says Tristram Hunt
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154694/Every-child-citizenship-test-prove-understand-British-values-immigrants-says-Labour.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Shadow education secretary Tristram Hunt called for a 'proper National baccalaureate qualification' in which all pupils are tested on British history and values before leaving school.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
School children should take a 'Life in the UK' test to ensure they have the same understanding of British values as immigrants, Labour's Tristram Hunt said today.
The shadow education secretary called for a 'proper National baccalaureate qualification' in which all pupils are tested on British history and values before leaving school.
He said because immigrants are required to take a UK citizenship test so should British school children.
School children should take a 'Life in the UK' test to ensure they have the same understanding of British values as immigrants, Labour's Tristram Hunt said this morning
Mr Hunt, speaking at the Education Reform summit in London today, called for all young people 'to come out of school with the new understanding migrants come to the country with'.
He said: 'A Great Debate should look at whether we need a proper National Baccalaureate qualification for all secondary school and college leavers.
'A framework which could balance important specialist academic, technical and creative qualifications, including traditional A levels, alongside a common core for all learners.
'And why not discuss whether we should make - as part of a new baccalaureate qualification or otherwise - all pupils take the 'Life in the UK' British Citizenship Test before leaving school?
'Surely it is only fair to expect our young people finishing full-time education to possess the same?
'Because if we are serious about nurturing a sense of national solidarity alongside pluralism and diversity, then it would seem sensible to me to recognise that formally in an educational setting.'
Mr Hunt also accused teachers of focusing on the 'easiest' subjects and targeting pupils 'on the cusp of passing' to help their school move up the local league table.
He said the joy for learning had been 'buried beneath an avalanche of bureaucracy'.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Ashington pensioner died while waiting five hours for an out-of-hours doctor
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154712/Ashington-pensioner-died-waiting-five-hours-hours-doctor.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Percy Edward Hardy, an 86-year-old of Ashington, Northumberland, spent his final hours with his family frantically speaking to nurses and doctors on the phone as he battled for breath
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Ms Hardy added: 'He was really fighting to breathe and he was saying he wished he could die.'
The family waited for help over the course of the next few hours but no GP arrived.
His daughter, 44, said: 'By about 2.45am, I looked in and he was half on the bed, half on the floor, so I went to try and lift him up. That was when I knew he'd died.
'A few minutes later the phone rang and a representative from the out-of-hours service said the GP had been delayed. I said it did not matter as my dad had died in the mean time. They then put me on hold.'
Mr Hardy's family are angry that an out-of-hours doctor they were told was on the way did not arrive
Ms Hardy said a GP did not attend the family home that night.
She said: 'The whole thing was a farce and a disgrace. They did not keep me updated during those five hours and I'd explained how ill my father was.'
She says the death of her father, known to friends as Eddie, has shattered the whole family, including brother Graham, 56, and sister Jean Dickinson, 59.
A spokesman for Northern Doctors Urgent Care (NDUC) said: 'Our deepest sympathies are with Mr Hardy's family during this extremely sad time.
'As is usual procedure in such circumstances, a full internal investigation has been carried out into this case. We are satisfied that the correct procedures were followed and would be happy to discuss further what happened with the family.'

Share or comment on this article
29
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Roman Abramovich's goes on Scottish holiday with best friend Eugene Shvidler
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153722/Revealed-Abramovich-s-great-bromanski-Chelsea-owner-goes-bizarre-boys-Scottish-holiday-best-friend-right-hand-man-bought-flock-sheep-75m-yacht.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Eugene Shvidler, 51, (left) has been best friend and business partner of Abramovich (right) since the 1980s. The Chelsea owner, 48, once gave him a £75million yacht as a thank you present
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Three years earlier Abramovich gave him the 371ft yacht Le Grand Bleu  with its 65-strong crew, diving centre, helicopter, aquarium and speedboat  as a thank you for all his hard work.
Some call Shvidler Abramovich's representative on Earth and others the 'bad cop' to Roman's 'good cop'.
They started out in business together making toys, women's hair clips and cheap accessories, which was Abramovich's first experience of capitalism in 1987.
'Roman brought him to work with us,' recalled Vladimir Tyurin, owner of the factory making plastic ducks and sailors.
'They made great plans together. They like each other and, more than anything, there is mutual trust.'
Tyurin is convinced they met at a Moscow synagogue, though they were both at the Gubkin Institute of Oil and Gas in Moscow in the mid-1980s, when Abramovich was in his 20s and where Shvidler distinguished himself more than his future business partner.
From there, Shvidler went to America, gaining US citizenship in 1994, and working for Deloitte Touche in New York before linking up with his old friend in the oil business in Russia.
Shvindler is a stickler for value for money, on record as saying his heart bleeds over the cash spent by his friend on football.
He was once asked whether his French chateau was a hobby or business. 'Business, of course,' Shvidler answered, 'I don't like feeding someone else. Enough of that, I'm already feeding one' - he nodded, laughing, in the direction of Abramovich's portrait on his wall.
Not bad for a present: Abramovich gifted Shvidler the 75million371ft yacht Le Grand Bleu in 2006 as a thank you for all his hard work. It came with 65 crew, diving centre, helicopter, aquarium and speedboat
Opulent: Shvidler's 24million Belgravia home, which has an underground swimming pool and leather floors
Stunning: Shvidler'sChteau Thnac in the Bergerac region near Bordeaux, which he bought for a few million after visiting France on a wine-tasting tour in 2000
One contemporary Alexander Lurie said: 'They trusted each other and this was the secret of their might.....Roman can make simple relationships with people and agree things.'
The pair hit the big time when they founded an oil-trading organisation and Shvidler eventually became president of the Sibneft oil company in 1998.
He and Abramovich built Sibneft into an oil giant and after it was sold for 7.36bn in 2005 the pair went on to found their investment and asset management company Millhouse, LLC, in 2001.
But it hasn't all been plain sailing for Abramovich and his loyal lieutenant.
In 2000 Swiss police raided the offices of Sibneft in connection with an investigation into allegations that International Monetary Fund aid to Russia in 1998 went astray.
The company claimed its Swiss affiliate, Runicom SA, had played no role in any diversion of IMF money and said allegations to the contrary were 'totally unfounded and ridiculous' as Runicom stopped trading operations in November 1997.
Then in 2003 Shvidler was called in for questioning by investigators from the Economic Crime Division of the Interior Ministry in Russia.
As president of Sibneft he was questioned about tax schemes used by Abramovich-linked companies.
These include 'tolling' - a money merry-go-round designed to exploit offshore tax loopholes - and using disabled people to win generous tax concessions.
It was revealed in the press that at one Sibneft-linked company, Olivestra, six out of seven managers were registered as handicapped.
A spokesman for Moscow business analyst Troika Dialog accused Sibneft of 'relying heavily on political connections for its successful tax planning.'
The company put large quantities of its sales through trading companies in Chukotka, the region in far eastern Siberia where Abramovich was governor from 2000 to 2008.
And in 2005 the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development sued Sibneft in an attempt to recover a $17.5million (11.4million) debt.
The EBRD launched a case in a Swiss court to recover the money it says it was owed by Runicom SA, a Switzerland-based oil trading company that was controlled by Abramovich and Shvidler.
Runicom SA was an oil trading company that handled oil exports for Sibneft, and had a debt to Russia's SBS Agro bank.
That debt was pledged as collateral on a loan provided by EBRD to SBS Agro as part of EBRD's efforts to stimulate the growth of small and medium-sized businesses in the country, but was never repaid after SBS collapsed following Russia's financial crisis in August 1998.
Enjoying the ride: Shvidler (far left) sits on the side of the speedboat as he chats to his old friend Abramovich The group have been staying on Abramovich's super yacht Eclipse during their Scottish islands tour
EBRD won a case in Russia's appeal court against Runicom SA in 2002, but the company failed to honour the ruling.
Sibneft hit back, claiming Runicom SA had repaid the debt to a bank nominated by SBS Agro and not be paying the money back twice.
Ultimately Abramovich and Shvidler weathered all these storms and remain a formidable duo.
Stepping off his super yacht in the Scottish Highlands among his 'bodyguards' was Russian billionaire Roman Abramovich's best friend, to whom he once gave a 75million yacht, bought a Ferrari  and marked his 45th birthday by buying him a flock of sheep.
The Chelsea supremo and Eugene Shvidler have been best friends since they were kids growing up in communist Russia.
The pair made millions trading oil together in the nineties  and this week their 'bromance' continued with a boys' holiday on the Scottish coast.

Share or comment on this article
17
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Woman who had ear bitten off reveals how violent attack left her anorexic
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3153493/Woman-ear-bitten-takeaway-shop-reveals-violent-attack-left-anorexic.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Katie Price, 26, from Castleford, West Yorkshire, said she was so traumatised after the incident that she struggled to eat, shrinking from a size 16 to a size eight in three months.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Kylie said: 'Anorexia really took hold of me. Psychologically I wanted people to look at my body instead of my injury which was just horrific.
'I was living on coffee and toast and the weight just fell off me. I became addicted to getting thinner and thinner, ignoring my family's pleas for me to eat.'
Kylie was attacked in March last year as she waited for her takeaway after a night out in her home town.
She had been out with a friend and her partner, council worker, Matthew Beckett, 30, when they decided to get a bite to eat.
Kylie pictured after two reconstructive surgeries on her ear, although she says she still hates the way it looks
Kylie recalled: 'Once we'd ordered our food, Matthew offered to go and get the car so we didn't have to walk very far as it was really cold.
'He had only been gone a few minutes when a woman in the queue behind me started getting mouthy. She was quite a big woman and had clearly had quite a bit to drink. She was with a few mates and quite cocky.
'She claimed I'd been wrongly served before her and started shouting at the guy behind the counter.
'Trying to calm the situation down, I told her there was plenty for everyone.
'But in that instant she just flipped. Before I knew what was happening, she launched at me knocking me backwards onto the hard counter and then to the stone floor.
'As she straddled over me, she was smirking. My friend was trying to pull her off me but she was getting dragged away by my attacker's mates.
'The woman was like a demented animal. She viciously tore at my hair as though she was trying to rip it from my scalp.
'Unlike with what had happened to my ear, I felt in control, and in my mind I was sure strangers would focus on my figure and not my injury.
'I was frantically trying to push her away, terrified of what she would do next, but she was bigger and stronger than me.
'Then without any warning, she plummeted down on me and sunk her teeth into my right ear.
'I heard this awful sound, like someone biting into a cucumber and realised she was ripping at my ear.
'Horrendous white pain soared through me. I'd never felt anything like it in my life. I started shaking uncontrollably.
'But as quickly as the attack started, it stopped. Suddenly she just stood up, started laughing and walked away.'
Unaware of the extent of her injuries, Kylie ran into the crowded street and stopped a passing taxi.
'I just asked the driver to take me home,' said Kylie. 'I had no idea where my friend and Matthew were but I just wanted to get as far away from that woman as possible before she attacked me again.
'It was only then I realised my ear was pouring with blood. I felt physically sick and thought I was going to collapse.
Kylie said: 'I became convinced that if I was thin then other people would look at my body and not my ear.'
'I don't even remember paying the driver but as soon as he dropped me off, I ran to my neighbour's house as I realised Matthew was probably still in town desperately looking for me.
'As soon as she saw me, she walked me to my house and sat me down, before calling for an ambulance and the police.
'She made me press a towel against my ear to try and stem the bleeding, but I could feel it dripping down me.
'Minutes later Matthew got home. He was stunned when he saw the state of me  he'd only left me for a few minutes.
'But it was only when the ambulance arrived and the paramedic asked where the rest of my ear was that I realised that the woman had literally bitten it off.
'I was horrified. How could anyone bit off another person's ear? And somehow it seemed worse that she was a woman. It just seemed so macabre.'
Kylie was rushed to Pinderfields Hospital where stunned doctor's cleaned up her nasty wound and gave her antibiotics to prevent infection.
The mother-of-one had part of her ear bitten off (above) by Nicole McGill. The 23-year-old attacker was given a 12-month suspended sentence after pleading guilty to unlawful wounding
The following day, Kylie's head was bandaged up and she was allowed home.
She recalls: 'I hadn't seen my ear  I couldn't bear to look at it, but I knew from everyone else's reactions that it was horrific.
'And I was in agony. I was taking the strongest painkillers I could, but still it hurt.
'When my little boy, Jayden, saw me, he was really worried. He was only four and had never seen me look so weak. I just told him I had an ear infection but he sensed something was very wrong and became clingy, barely leaving my side.'
Kylie gave a statement to the police and her attacker, local girl Nicole McGill, was arrested.
Kylie, pictured with a friend on a night out before the attack, said she was too scared to leave the house after sustaining her 'horrific' injury
'But I really struggled to come to terms with what had happened,' she said. 'I just couldn't understand why Nicole had so viciously gone for me.
'I knew she was out on bail, and was terrified she would come after me again.
'It was over five weeks before I dared look at my ear. And when I did I was devastated. It was so deformed and ugly. My mood became even lower  I'd never felt so down in my whole life.
'I became too scared to leave the house and for six weeks, I didn't go past my front door.
'The pain was so bad, that I couldn't eat. Even a slice of toast made me feel sick.
'I started losing weight. As it dropped off, I realised I quite liked being thinner.
'And the more that came off, I realised I was focusing more on my body than I was on my ear. I became convinced that if I was thin then other people would look at my body and not my ear.
Kylie shrank from a size 16, left, to a size eight, right, in three months. She says she couldn't eat because of the pain, and once she started losing weight, she couldn't stop
'I literally became addicted to losing weight. And as my clothes got looser, I didn't want to put the weight back on. I loved how skinny I was getting.
'I'd skip meals, and just eat the odd apple and boiled egg, and drink diet coke and coffee.
'Within three months I'd gone from 11st to under 8st. One of my friends came to visit. She begged me to start eating properly again, but I just couldn't.
'I knew my family were very worried about me but it wasn't enough to stop me.
'Unlike with what had happened to my ear, I felt in control, and in my mind I was sure strangers would focus on my figure and not my injury.
'When I did start going out I'd wear really skinny jeans to show off my new figure and trendy head bands to cover my injury.'
Kylie underwent two lots of reconstructive surgery but says her ear has been left permanently deformed.
She says: 'It looks completely different to my left ear. It's smaller and abnormal looking. I absolutely hate it.
Kylie has managed to get her weight up to 8st 7lb but she says every day is a battle to eat
'Whereas I could control how the rest of me looked physically.'
Last November Nicole McGill, 23, pleaded guilty to unlawful wounding at Leeds Crown Court. She walked free after being handed a 12-month suspended sentence and being ordered to carry out 150 hours unpaid work.
Kylie added: 'I felt like the justice system had completely let me down. She had left me disfigured for the rest of my life and was walking the streets free to attack the next unsuspecting victim.'
Sure enough, a month after she was sentenced, McGill was arrested again - this time for assaulting her then partner, Damian Tate, 33, after a Christmas night out.
When police arrived at the couple's home on December 20 last year, they found McGill licking her boyfriend's blood from her fingers.
Leeds Crown Court heard she had stabbed Damian in the thigh with a kitchen knife.
Last month McGill pleaded guilty to unlawful wounding and was jailed for two-and-a-half years.
Sentencing her, Judge Spencer said: 'You seem to be the kind of person who will resort to violence at the first resort in whatever circumstances you find yourself.
'I gave you a clear warning when you came before me in November last year and yet within weeks you have breached it.'
Although Kylie feels justice has finally been served, she expressed anger that it took another attack for McGill to be jailed.
She said: 'If only she had been put behind bars after the attack on me, she wouldn't have been free to hurt someone else.
'Although I'm glad she has finally been given a custodial sentence, my suffering hasn't ended. I don't go out with my friends anymore as I feel so self-conscious. I still struggle to eat. I've got to 8st 7lb but it's a battle.
'I don't know when I'll ever have another takeaway... wanting one that night has ruined my life.'
Share or comment on this article
6
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Pregnant woman 'see's her dead mother in ultra scan of her own unborn baby' 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154602/Pregnant-woman-convinced-seen-image-mother-lost-cancer-scan-unborn-baby.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Rebecca Melia, from Kirkby, Merseyside, spotted what appears to be an image (left) of her late mother Sharon (right) in the ultrasound scan last month.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'I was convinced it was something wrong with my boy. Not even thinking what was to come, the lady gave me the picture and she said "I think you might like this one" with a smile on her face. The nurse did know my mum had passed away.'
After looking more closely at the scan, Miss Melia, from Kirkby, Merseyside, said she saw her mother's face at the top of the photograph.
Presence: Miss Melia feels her mother is watching over her after spotting the image in the scan last month
Sharon (pictured) was just 49 when she died and the family say they still feel her presence months after her death
The mother-of-two never had the chance to tell her mother she was pregnant (scan pictured) again before she died following a battle with kidney cancer in February
She said: 'I couldn't believe it. I was shocked, happy and overwhelmed all at the same time. My mum's face, which I longed to see, was there as clear as day on my scan.
'And I wanted to share this story to bring comfort to others who have lost their loved ones and show this is proof that loved ones who have died may not be seen, but they are still here.'
Miss Melia, who has five sisters and two brothers, has two children, Charlotte, 10, and Peter, five.
She added: 'I have a little area in my room with pictures of my mum on and before I went for my scan I was talking to her, saying I wish she was coming with me.
'This is her 14th grandchild and she has been there for every one.'
Share or comment on this article
15
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Triplet Kerry Velloza dies in fall from flat 1 year after sister was paralysed
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154727/Triplet-dies-accidental-fall-second-floor-flat-one-year-sister-paralysed-pushed-window-sibling.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Kerry Velloza, 26, died after drunkenly clambering out of the window of her second floor flat in Skelmersdale, Lancashire, following a row with her boyfriend Steen Egan, 38.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
11 shares
'She started going mad. She then went to the kitchen and got a big knife and came out and said "I will f****** stab you if you don't find a lighter."
'I said: "I don't know where it is." I knocked on my next door neighbour's door to get a lighter. She had found one by the time I was back and had calmed down. She carried on watching TV then she flipped out and punched me. I was on the phone to the police when she attacked me with the knife.'
He said the pair continued to argue over the matter before she went over towards a window in their flat.
He said: 'She was saying: "you're a grass." I said: "you just tried to stab me with a knife. I cannot put up with this."
'I told her to go to a friends because the police were on their way but she said she wasn't going anywhere. When the police turned up she had gone to the window.
'I was in the living room and was told to stay away from her. By the time I realised she had gone out of the window, the police were there.'
Kerry's (right) death came less than two years after her sister Gillian (centre) pushed their other identical triplet sister Louise (left) out of a second-storey window in Liverpool leaving her confined to a wheelchair
Identical triplets Kerry (right), Louise (centre) and Gillian (left) before the incident and tragedy occurred
Detective Inspector Geoff Hirst, of Lancashire Police who investigated Kerry's death, said she fell to the floor awkwardly after hitting a windowsill as she lost her grip on the window frame.
He said: 'An argument occurred whereby Mr Egan rang up the police and Kerry had a knife.
'In interview Mr Egan said he took the knife from Kerry and threw it outside. He said she went out of the living room, kicked the bedroom door from its hinges and he phoned the police because she had threatened him.
'I think when the officer got there and was let in by Mr Egan he understood Kerry to be in the bedroom. When they went there  they saw her out the window.
'I came to the conclusion that she had hung out of the window with the intent of dropping down.
'But as she dropped she hit her foot on the windowsill on the first floor which threw her off balance preventing her from landing in the way she wanted because she had tilted when hitting that ledge.
'It is a tragic and unfortunate accident and it was probably in my view fuelled by alcohol.'
Toxicology tests showed that Kerry was twice over the drink driving limit when she fell.
Mr Egan was initially arrested over her death but was later cleared of any wrongdoing. He said he had previously dropped down from the second-storey flat on an earlier occasion after locking himself inside the building.
He added: 'I had hung and dropped to the grass below to kick the front door so I could get back in. I think she got it from me. She knew I had done that.
'Whether she thought she would get away with it or not I don't know.'
In November 2013, Gillian (right) was jailed for eight-and-a-half years for causing grievous bodily harm after pushing her sister Louise (left) from a bedroom window at a hostel they were both staying at in Liverpool
Gillian pushed her sister Louise from a window of theStep One Hostel in Liverpool less than two years ago
The inquest was told that just 10 days before the tragedy, Kerry had threatened to leave the flat by climbing out of the window after locking herself in but was freed by firefighters before she did so.
Coroner Claire Hammond recorded a conclusion of misadventure and said she was satisified that Kerry climbed out of the window on her own accord.
She said: 'I think it's likely she did so with the intent of hanging out of the window so as to be able to drop down to the ground below as Mr Egan had described he had done successfully on a previous occasion.
'I agree with the likely scenario that Kerry climbed out of the window with the intent of dropping down to the floor below safely but her foot struck the sill causing her to land the way she did.'
Kerry's death came less than two years after her sister Gillian pushed their other identical triplet sister Louise out of a second-storey window leaving her confined to a wheelchair.
In November 2013, Gillian was jailed for eight-and-a-half years for causing grievous bodily harm after pushing Louise from a bedroom window at a hostel they were both staying at in Liverpool.
Louise is now paralysed from the chest down.
Share or comment on this article
11
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Bookkeeper of Auschwitz Oskar Groening's murder trial comes to an end
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154739/The-Bookkeeper-Auschwitz-told-no-little-poor-sergeant-like-portray-victims-lawyers-murder-trial-comes-end.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	German prosecutor Suzan Baymak-Winterseel told Groening that he bears more than moral guilt for his role in Auschwitz, adding: 'You were a part of the mass murder of millions.'
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
On Tuesday prosecutors called for a sentence of three and-a-half years for his part in the murder of 300,000 Hungarian Jews shipped to Auschwitz in a 48-day period in 1944 when he was on duty.
On Wednesday Mrs. Baymak-Winterseel, representing some of those who survived the camp where 1.2 million people were put to death, said: 'It is not right that such a sentence is chosen for the crimes of which he stands.'
Groening was known as the Bookkeeper of Auschwtiz for his role in cataloguing the valuables of victims before sending them to the Nazis
Her remarks came in the closing stages of Groening's trial, who was known as the 'Bookkeeper of Auschwitz' for his role in cataloguing the valuables of victims before sending them to the Nazis.
Previously the trial has heard evidence from numerous co-plaintiffs - either people who survived their ordeal in the Third Reich's largest extermination camp, or those who lost loved ones in it.
Dr. Cornelius Nestler, another of the victims' lawyers, said: 'Mr. Groening took part in events and he will be sentenced for aiding and abetting mass murder. Much too late - but not too late.'
He observed that at previous charges for those who had worked at Auschwitz it was necessary under German law to prove direct involvement in mass murder.
However, that changed three years ago with the trial of former death camp guard John Demjanjuk.
He was found guilty of particpating in the murders of over 28,000 Dutch Jews at the death camp of Sobibor in Nazi occupied Poland because his service records placed him there.
There were no living witnesses as to what he did, no-one to say whether he was a cook or a man who pushed Jews into the gas chambers to die
However, he was found culpable because it was argued that the camp would have been unable to function without him and others like him, enough to secure a conviction for accessory to murder.
Dr. Nestler evoked the memory of the 9/11 attacks against America - planned by terrorists in Germany - to elaborate upon the guilt of Groening.
While none of the witnesses at Groening's trail saw him personally kill those at the camp, lawyers argue he is an accessory to 300,000 murders because Auschwitz would not have been able to function without him
He detailed how one of the 9/11 supporters was jailed because he transferred money to the account of terror pilot Mohammed Atta.
Dr Nestler then compared that to Groening's admission that he sometimes worked on 'the ramp' - the platfortm where vitimcs arrived at Auschwitz by train.
It was here that prisoners were divided by guards, either sent to die immediately in the gas chambers, or told to go and work as slave labourers instead.
Turning to the court, he asked: 'If this [transferring money to the 9/11 pilot] was aid, then is not the ramp service of the S.S. in Auschwitz also not aid?'
Dr. Nestler added: 'Mass murder did not only take placed in the gas chambers. It was present in the whole Auschwitz programme.'
Share or comment on this article
9
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Londoners refuse to let Tube Strike ruin their journeys
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154669/Today-got-boat-work-quite-liking-Tube-strike-Londoners-refused-let-striking-drivers-ruin-journeys.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Messages from those criticising the Tube strike in London today were met with a flurry of posts from those who were set on seeing the bright side - by boating, biking, walking and running into work.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
'Today I got a boat to work  quite liking the Tube strike': How Londoners refused to let striking drivers ruin their journeys
The 24-hour Tube strike caused travel chaos this morning as millions were forced on to crowded buses and trains
But while some slammed the unions on Twitter, others were determined not to let striking drivers ruin their journeys
Dozens of Londoners were set on seeing the bright side of the disruption - by sailing, biking and walking into work
They posted photographs of their re-routed trips on social media, showing the city bathed in summer sunshine
Published: 11:02 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 11:47 GMT, 9 July 2015
333 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Graeme Bryden facing hamesucken charge for which penalty was once death
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154510/Man-appears-court-facing-ancient-charge-hamesucken-penalty-used-death-attacking-robbing-93-year-old-woman-home.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Graeme Bryden 27, of Stevenston, North Ayrshire, has appeared at Kilmarnock Sheriff Court (pictured) accused of robbery and hamesucken. The latter would formerly lead to execution.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
It relates to the act of pursuing someone into their home with the intention of assaulting them.
Bryden is charged with doing such to an elderly woman  on June 25. He is accused of entering the pensioners home in Saltcoats, North Ayrshire, at 2am, assaulting her and stealing belongings.
Police described the woman's ordeal as a 'very distressing experience'.
John W. Cairns, professor of civil law at the University of Edinburgh, said hamesucken used to be 'punished severely'
Bryden made no plea or declaration when he appeared at Kilmarnock Sheriff Court, charged with robbery and hamesucken.
He is to appear again next week for further examination.
John W. Cairns, professor of civil law at the University of Edinburgh, explained the offence of hamseucken to Scottish Legal News .
He said: 'The offence is that of pursuing someone into their home to assault them. It was once a capital offence...[and] by the eighteenth century, the Crown usually, but not always, only sought a non-capital punishment, though individuals were still sometimes hanged for it.
'It was punished severely, because of its implications for preservation of the peace in a country of the blood-feud. Of course, it still resonates as a term, because individuals like to feel secure in their own home, and invasion of one's home seems particularly heinous.'
Speaking to the MailOnline, he added: 'The punishment anyone convicted might receive will vary with the seriousness of the actual assault, given that the assault is aggravated by place. So it could be a minor punishment to a lengthy prison sentence, at the discretion of the judge.
'I imagine it is rarely mentioned any more because prosecutors just choose to describe the fact pattern they are intending to prove as an assault rather than as hamesucken.
'Until 1887, prosecutors in Scotland had to give a name to the crime they were intending to prove in court; after 1887 this was unnecessary. One imagines the name, hamesucken, fell out of regular use, especially since this was no longer a capital crime.'
Gwynne Evans (left) and Peter Allen (right) were the last men to be executed in Britain more than 50 years ago
Gwynne Evans and Peter Allen were the last men to be executed in Britain.
At 8am on August 13, 1964, they were both hung at the gallows after walking from their cells at separate prisons in Manchester and Liverpool.
The duo were convicted of the murder of John Alan West, a 53-year-old laundry company driver who was bludgeoned and stabbed to death at his home in Cumbria on 7 April, 1964.
A year later the penalty was suspended and never reinstated.
HAMESUCKEN: PROFESSOR CAIRNS EXPLAINS THE HISTORY OF THE WORD
Hamesucken is a word of Germanic origin. The term came into Scottish legal usage through the Anglo-Saxon word 'Hamsocn'.
In Danish it is: 'hjemsge': in modern German: 'heimsuchen'.
The offence is that of pursuing someone into their home to assault them. It was once a capital offence, with the medieval law-book Regiam majestatem stating it was to be punished as was the ravishing of women, that is as a capital offence.
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
177
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Volcanic eruptions 'collapsed Roman empire allowing Muslims to spread'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-3153753/Volcanic-eruptions-caused-freezing-temperatures-crop-failures-famine-early-Roman-times-changed-course-history.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Scientists at the Desert Research Institute (DRI) in Reno have reconstructed the timing and climate forcing of 300 individual volcanic eruptions extending as far back as the early Roman period.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>142
shares
Did volcanoes cause the rise of Islam? Huge eruptions brought famine and disease to Roman empire allowing Muslim civilisation to spread
Experts studied 300 individual eruptions over the past 2,500 years
They found ash and aerosols thrown into the atmosphere in eruptions between 536AD and 626AD transformed the Northern Hemisphere climate
This brought plague and famine thatdecimatedthe Eastern Roman Empire
Published: 17:20 GMT, 8 July 2015 | Updated: 11:39 GMT, 9 July 2015
142 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date/>
        <title>
	London Tube passengers had secret biological warfare tests carried out on them
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154555/How-British-government-carried-secret-biological-warfare-tests-London-Tube-passengers-1960s-Cold-War.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Hundreds of thousands of Britons were subjected to 'mock' biological and chemical warfare tests in  750 secret operations, research by University of Kent's Professor Ulf Schmidt reveals.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
289 shares
Historians had previously thought that such tests in the UK were less extensive but new research has revealed how widespread they actually were.
For the first time, researchers have learned that British military aircraft dropped thousands of kilos of the potentially dangerous zinc cadmium sulphide chemical over several towns including Norwich in Norfolk, Salisbury in Wiltshire and Cardington in Bedfordshire, as well as over the English Channel and North Sea.
Historians had previously thought that such chemical tests in the UK were less extensive but new research has revealed how widespread they were, including the discovery of one of the Tube in the 1960s (pictured)
Scientists releasedlarge quantities of the bacteria Bacillus globigii - now known to cause food poisoning - on the Underground system in May 1964, in a bidto apparently discover whether 'long distance travel of aerosols' on London's transport network 'was due to transportation within trains' or through the air ventilation systems
While very little evidence exists on the dangers and health effects of the chemical, which can be easily detected under UV light, it is believed that its use in the 1960s did not cause immediate health problems.
WHAT IS ZINC CADMIUM SULPHIDE?
Zinc cadmium sulphide
Zinc cadmium sulphide is a fluorescent hard, sintered, crystalline compound used by the British government during chemical warfare tests between 1953 and 1964.
It is soluble in water and is now mainly used for photography purpoposes  particularly in radiographic imaging intensification screens because it emits a yellow-green light when excited by x-rays.
During the governments trials it is estimated that 250kg of Zinc cadmium sulphide was dispersed from land-based sites, mainly RAF Beaulieu airfield and Porton Down, and up to a further 4600kg from ships and aircraft mainly over BDE Cardington, Bedfordshire and over the English Channel and the North Sea.
While the health effects of zinc cadmium sulphide are not widely recorded, research indicates that it is relatively harmless.
Scientists state that the worst case exposure levels would give the same health effects as smoking 100 cigarettes - which may ultimately have led to lung disease later down the line.
However, tests concluded that exposure arising from the chemical trials did not significantly increase the level to which the population is normally exposed.
However, researchers state that the 'worst case' exposure levels would have given the same health effects as smoking 100 cigarettes - which may ultimately have led to lung disease at a later stage.
Professor Schmidt has revealed the full extent of the chemical warfare trials in a new book called Secret Science, published today.
He has also uncovered how more than 21,000 soldiers were used as 'guinea pigs' between 1939 and 1989 after participating in secret experiments.
The military personnel were apparently offered incentives such as free train passes, a day off, or some extra money for being exposed to potentially dangerous chemicals.
Professor Schmidt believes the men were misinformed about the then-unknown consequences of exposure to the chemical and instead thinks they were under the impression that they were taking part in trials to treat common colds.
The Ministry of Defence's Porton Down research centre on Salisbury Plain has been the subject of much controversy over the years.
In July 1999, an inquiry was opened into the deaths of servicemen allegedly used as 'guinea pigs' in secret military chemical warfare tests at the centre.
The men took part in tests during a 30-year period from the 1950s to the 1980s.
A Wiltshire Police investigation into their deaths revealed there was criminal liability arising out of the conduct of some former scientists but it was confirmed in 2006 that there was insufficient evidence to pursue a criminal prosecution.
Many servicemen and women who took part in the tests at Porton Down said they believed they were taking part in experiments to find a cure for the common cold but claimed they were actually exposed to CS gas, mustard gas and hallucinogens such as LSD.
The latest findings on the extent of chemical warfare tests in Britain come after it emerged last year that former Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher had considered arming Britain with chemical weapons to counter the Soviet threat during the Cold War.
A group of 100 supporters demonstrating against germ warfare at the government's Porton Down military research facility in Salisbury Plain, Wiltshire, which has been at the subject of controversy over the years
Secret documents emerged in December which revealed the then prime minister said it was potentially 'negligent' not to have them  as intelligence reports suggested the enemy could use chemicals against the West.
Officials believed the Soviets were storing hundreds of thousands of tons of nerve agents, and estimated an attack on a major British airport would leave thousands dead.
In a 1984 memo, Mrs Thatcher's private secretary, Charles Powell, summarised a meeting in which then defence secretary Michael Heseltine warned the lack of chemical weapons was a 'major gap' in Nato's defences.
'The defence secretary said that colleagues were aware of the threat posed by the Soviet Union in this file. The absence of an adequate retaliatory capability was a major gap in Nato's armoury,' he wrote.
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
289
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date/>
        <title>
	UK contributions to EU leap by £3.1bn over the next 5 years
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154628/Britain-punished-outpacing-Europe-contributions-Brussels-leap-3-1billion-five-years.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Figures from the Office for Budget Responsibility showed in next year alone there will be a £1.3billion jump in contributions to Brussels than previously expected.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
821 shares
Much of the change in contributions for next year come because Britain will get a lower than expected rebate on money paid in 2014 because it received more from EU structural funds than anticipated.
The higher the sum the country gets from the funding schemes, the less it gets from the rebate, which is paid in arrears.
Britain will make a net contribution to the EU budget of 10.4 billion this year, up from a forecast of 9.9 billion in March. Next year it is expected to pay 9.5 billion, compared to a previous forecast of 8.2 billion.
The figures relate to the money paid into the EU budget in taxes and membership fees, with the money received back in the form of EU spending subtracted.
Robert Oxley, campaign director of Business for Britain said: 'Britain hands over far too much money to Brussels and too often sees much of that squandered. Our increased contributions to the EU budget have effectively become a 'prosperity tax' as growth in the UK economy results in bigger bills from the continent.
'Britain is now the second largest net contributor to the EU budget, a fact that EU leaders should stop ignoring when they debate Britain's calls for renegotiation.'
The increased cost of the EU will renew pressure on David Cameron to win fresh concessions from EU leaders, including Jean Claude Juncker (left)
Pawel Swidlicki, of the think tank Open Europe, said: 'The rise in the UK's anticipated EU contributions will renew pressure on David Cameron to target the EU budget as part of his reform push.
'The mid-term review of the EU budget next year provides an opening to push reforms such as cutting spending on agriculture, eliminating the recycling of regional funds between richer states and refocusing the budget on areas where it can add value. This would benefit all European taxpayers but it will take time, and is therefore another reason not to rush the renegotiation.'
Yesterday's Budget warned the threat of a 'prolonged' and 'turbulent' stand-off over Greece's future in the euro is the 'biggest external risk to the UK economy'.
Although Britain only has minimal direct economic and financial links with the country, the Budget report noted 'the UK is highly exposed to wider market instability'.
The head of the Treasury Select Committee said the Greek could turn from a manageable challenge into a 'major catastrophe' for Britain.
Andrew Tyrie said the problems besetting the eurozone could hit bond markets which currently help to keep the cost of servicing Britain's massive national debt low.
Share or comment on this article
821
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Andy Murray fans' anger at empty Wimbledon 2015 seats as corporate fans stay in hospitality tents
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154362/Andy-Murray-fans-anger-seats-corporate-fans-stay-Wimbledon-hospitality-tents.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Thousands of tennis fans who missed out on tickets to watch Andy Murray triumph in the quarter-finals have been left fuming at the sight of rows of empty seats on the Centre Court.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
But while the seats lay empty for most of the match, hundreds of people were forced to cram onto Henman Hill to watch Murrays victory on the big screens while others were turned away at the gates.
A worker in the hospitality area at SW19 said that the area was so busy while the British number one was playing.
While the seats lay empty for most of the match, hundreds of people were forced to cram onto Henman Hill to watch Murrays victory on the big screens
Fans on Henman Hill (pictured) said it was 'ridiculous' that they had been forced to sit outside for Murray's match, while there were plenty of empty seats at Centre Court
Oysters and champagne! Check out Wimbledon's corporate suites
Yesterday they were all saying they hate tennis and how theyre only here to represent their firm - one had never heard of Djokovic.
Lunch often runs over onto pudding and once theyve had quite a lot of steak and booze they dont want to leave. Its about business more than tennis.
The source added that on Tuesday during the ladies quarter finals most of the guests stayed in the hospitality area all day.
They kept making sexist remarks about how they wouldnt waste their time watching womens tennis. They said why would I go and watch womens tennis?, the worker said.
Big firms including RBS, Nike, JP Morgan, Hertz and Aegon pay for on-site hospitality packages which allow their guests free tickets to the show courts  but they are under no obligation to fill them.
One guest  who did not want to be named  said that an hour into Murrays match against 25-year-old Pospisil, around 100 people were still milling around in the marquees.
The number of empty seats increased dramatically while Novak Djokovic took to Centre Court
William and Kate arrive at Wimbledon to support Murray
People dont necessarily come for the tennis, they are just here for the networking. They see tennis as a drop-in, drop-out sort of thing, he said.
Jamie Saunders, 34, from Guildford, said it was ridiculous that he and his friends had been forced to sit on the crammed hill in the rain and while there were hundreds of spaces on Centre Court.
It was disappointing to see loads of empty seats, not being utilised by fans but just being set aside for corporates who would rather eat lunch.
Im fine about corporate events, but they need to utilise the tickets. Maybe they should publish, at the end of the Championships, the capacity that was used.
Many viewers watching at home tweeted about their disappointment after seeing the empty seats  which were highly visibly behind the Royal Box  which by contrast was full throughout.
Tennis fans have become increasingly angry after spotting empty seats on screen, despite not being able to get tickets for the tournament
Complaints about the empty seats at Wimbledon have been pouring in since early in the tournament
Nothing more annoying than seeing empty seats at Wimbledon. Impossible to get tickets yet there are empty seats #logic, Scott Caldwell tweeted.
While Alison Jones said the empty seats for corporate free loaders for the entire Murray quarter final was a disgrace.
BBCs John Inverdale joined the angry chorus of fans and complained that the Grand Slams main show court was barely a third full during the womens quarter finals on Tuesday.
Following her match against Serena Williams, Victoria Azarenka suggested that perhaps spectators were spending more time enjoying the bars than watching the action on court. 
'When people are drinking, every time the announcer says, "Make sure you hydrate yourself", I think he means with water, not with alcohol,' the Belarus player joked.
Even matches with the worlds best players, including Roger Federer, Novak Djokovic and Serena Williams, were among those played in front of under capacity crowds.
A spokesperson for the All England Club insisted that Wimbledons policy was to ensure that tickets are allocated fairly.
Tennis fans took to Twitter to express their outrage over the number of empty seats during the crunch match
SOLD OUT EVENTS BUT SWATHES OF EMPTY SEATS: THE CURSE OF CORPORATE TICKETS
Empty corporate seats have been a feature of many sporting events in recent years, most notably during the London Olympic Games in 2012 where many who had missed out on tickets complained about vast swathes of unused seating, particularly during earlier events.
Tens of thousands of ticketholders failed to show up, with as many as 14 per cent - around 67,000 people - not using their seats on the second day of the competition.
Many of the stayaways were VIPs who were given their tickets by sponsors  including for sold-out events such as swimming and gymnastics finals  but couldnt be bothered to use them.
During the London Olympic games, Armed Forces personnel were drafted in to fill seats left empty by corporate ticket holders and members of the 'Olympic family' - much to the annoyance of fans desperate to get their hands on tickets
The problem was particularly noticable at the North Greenwich Arena, Earls Court, Horse Guards Parade and the Aquatics Centre.
Many of the empty seats were those intended for the 'Olympic family' which were often in prime positions - and therefore very visible on television - adding to the frustration of the thousands of fans desperate to get their hands on tickets.
Even French President Francois Hollande weighed in on the debate, claiming organisers were too concerned with making money.
'We dont talk of money, we talk of gold. The problem is that there are simply too many corporate seats,' he said.
'It will be up to French organisers to sort out this problem if a bid for a future games is to be successful.'
Some of the seats were even handed out to members of the Armed Forces, drafted in to help with security, but still the view empty rows blighted television coverage for those forced to watch at home.
The row eventually led to more tickets being made available on a daily basis online, or over the phone.
Organisers of the forthcoming Rugby World Cup said last month that corporate guests could be closely managed to ensure that stadiums were full, having taken advice from employees of the London Organising Committee of the Olympic and Paralympic Games (LOCOG).
Alongside the majority which are available through the public ballot, the LTA ballot, debenture holders and those for sale on the day to the queue, we allocate less than 10% of Centre and No.1 Court seats to the official hospitality market.
Seats may not be occupied for a variety of reasons, for instance there are matches on 17 other courts, and most often may just be the result of spectators taking a refreshment break which they are perfectly entitled to do, they added.
Visitors queued overnight for a chance to get one of the 500 tickets for the centre court for 50, while tickets being sold online were priced at 4,270 for a pair.
Ticket prices for Centre Court start at 50 during the first week, and rise to 160 for the final. Tickets to see the action yesterday, including Murray's game would have cost 119.
Grounds admission prices range from 8 to 25, depending on the day, and between 5 and 18 for entry after 5pm. Those inside the grounds also have access to resold tickets when the original ticket holders leave for the day.
Corporate packages start at 415 per person, rising to4715 - which includes a private booth with free bar, including Champagne, and a four-course meal designed by top chef Albert Roux, as well as the traditional strawberries and cream.
The last 600 face-value 133 Centre Court tickets for Friday's matches sold out in just 37 seconds after going on sale at 9am today on Ticketmasters website.
But the web sale was slammed by fans camping to watch on the Murray Mound big screen - as no Centre Court tickets are available for the queue after Wednesday.
Fan Stuart Bere, 39, a gardener from Lincolnshire, who is camping for two weeks for tickets, said: 'People with fast laptops can get tickets through Ticketmaster - but queuing fans only get to watch on the big screen. Ticketmasters seats should be given to the queue.'
Wimbledon spokesman Johnny Perkins said: 'Theres a good allocation for the queue during the tournament.'
Tickets for Sunday's men's singles final were going for 40,237-a-pair on online ticket reseller Viagogo, while eBays StubHub tickets arm was selling tickets for 34,444-a-pair, with the cheapest pairs of tickets at 13,381.
Viagogo reported a record 1.6million searches for tickets to todays semi-finals - which cost from 10,755 to 16,539-a-pair.
Viagogo said: 'We expect mens final prices to increase if Murray gets through.'
The re-sold tickets are debenture season tickets, which cost more per day than standard tickets.
Mr Perkins said: 'Debenture tickets are permitted to be resold. Other tickers are not.'

Share or comment on this article
140
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date/>
        <title>
	How skipping university is as deadly as SMOKING
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3154704/How-skipping-university-deadly-SMOKING-School-leavers-aged-18-risk-early-death-smokers.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	An estimated 145,000 deaths could have been prevented adults who left school early had left at 18 - the same number of deaths that could have been averted if smokers quit, Colorado scientists said.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
How skipping university is as deadly as SMOKING: School leavers aged 18 have 'same risk of early death as smokers'
Researchers looked at people who completed education at the age of 18 and compared life expectancy with those who went to university
Found those who missed higher education tended to live shorter lives
145,243 deaths in 2010 could've been prevented if adults who left school at 18 had gone on to complete their high school diploma (A levels)
Equivalent to number of deaths that could've been averted if smokers quit
Published: 11:12 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 11:20 GMT, 9 July 2015
69 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date/>
        <title>
	George Osborne says firms must now pay and train their staff properly
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154581/A-kick-business-Osborne-says-firms-free-ride-pay-train-staff-properly.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The Budget included plans for an apprenticeship levy on large firms who ignore the skills of their workforce, in a move which one Cabinet minister described as a kick up the ‘lazy a***s’ of British business.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
34 shares
The Chancellor saw inside inside the engine casing of a Eurofighter Typhoon fighter jet during his visit on the morning after the Budget
Mr Osborne signalled a series of major reforms to speed up housebuilding, transform the nation's roads and transport network and overhaul universities
Mr Osborne argues there is a 'new contract' between business, the public and the state to reach his aim of a low welfare, low tax, high wage economy.
He told Sky News: 'It says to businesses 'we are going to cut your taxes but you have to pay higher salaries'.
'It says to people 'we are going to make sure you get a proper wage, a National Living 'age, but there are going to be less benefits'.
'And it says to the country 'we are going to spend less but we are going to live within our means and have economic security'. And I think I think that new contract, that centre of British politics is going to be a settlement that the country is happy with.'
The Chancellor used his Budget to cast himself in the mould of great Conservative reformers who protected mill workers, created state education and gave women the vote
SUMMER BUDGET: KEY POINTS
Major announcements in George Osborne's Summer Budget included:
A new National Living Wage will force employers to pay 7.20-an-hour to over-25s from April 2016, rising to 9 by 2020
Britain will not be back in surplus until 2019-20, a year later than planned
Another 37billion needed to balance the books, including 5billion from tax avoidance, 17billion from spending cuts and 12billion from welfare reforms
Amount workers can earn before paying income tax to rise to 11,000 next year, before reaching 12,500 by 2020
40p tax rate to rise to 43,000 in 2016, taking 130,000 people out of higher rate
Top rate of tax for those on 150,000 will not be cut from 45p
Pension tax relief for people on more than 150,000 to be reduced
Working age benefits frozen for four years from 2016-17
Amount families can claim in benefits to be cut from 26,000 to to 23,000 in London, and 20,000 a year in the rest of the country
Child tax credits limited to the first two children in any family
18-21-year-olds to lose jobless benefits under 'earn or learn' scheme
Public sector pay to increase by only 1 per cent for four years from 2016-17
Rents for social housing cut by 1 per cent every year for four years
Corporation tax cut to 18 per cent by 2020
Tax relief for wealthy buy-to-let landlords to be cut
BBC to fund 650million bill for free TV licences for the over-75s
Inheritance tax allowance to rise to 1million for family homes, paid for by a tax raid on the pensions of the rich
A major clampdown on tax avoidance, including scrapping temporary 'non-dom' status
Student grants for poor young people to be axed and replaced with loans
Shops to be able to open for longer on Sundays to boost trade
Road tax overhaul creates 140 flat fee, while fuel duty is frozen
30million to speed up adoption of children in council care
Defence budget to rise 0.5 per cent above inflation every year, to meet Nato target to spend 2 per cent of GDP
10,000 annual payment to holders of the George and Victoria Cross
Mr Osborne said he was determined to make work pay, as he cut benefits and warned those without a job that they had to take work when it was offered.
But he also warned that Britain faces a major skills challenge which could stop it becoming the most prosperous nation in the world within a generation.
Almost 30million workers were promised an income tax cut, with Mr Osborne making clear: 'The best way to support working people is to let them keep more of the money they earn.'
Employers were told they will see taxes fall to help them pay for the new compulsory National Living Wage, which will start at 7.20 from next year before hitting 9 by 2020.
A delighted Work and Pensions Secretary Iain Duncan Smith was seen punching the air as Mr Osborne boasted 2.5million people will get a direct pay rise as a result of the plan.
In a complex Budget which took Mr Osborne more than an hour to deliver, tax cuts for workers and employers were matched by rises on buy-to-let landlords, wealthy pension funds, insurance premiums and non-doms.
The confident performance at the Despatch Box cemented his position as a frontrunner to replace David Cameron as Prime Minister when he quits Number 10 ahead of the next election.
Mr Osborne said he wanted to reward those in work, but wielded the axe on the welfare state including slashing tax credits available to people with a low paid job.
Public sector workers were warned they will see pay rises capped at only 1 per cent for another four years.
But some six million people across the country will see their pay increase as a result of the new National living Wage.
Those currently earning the minimum wage of 6.50 an hour will be 5,000 better off by 2020, Mr Osborne claimed.
Labour's acting leader Harriet Harman was left floundering, as the Tory Chancellor said he was following the Conservative tradition as the party that brought in protections for mill workers during the industrial revolution and gave women the vote.
Mr Osborne said: 'This is the first Conservative budget for 18 years. It was Conservatives who first protected working people in the mills, it was Conservatives who introduced state education, it was Conservatives who introduced equal votes for women.
It was Conservatives that gave working people the Right to Buy, so of course it's now the Conservatives who introduce the National Living Wage.
'For this is the party for the working people of Britain.'
Mr Osborne argued that he had taken difficult decisions to cut borrowing, make business taxes competitive and reform welfare.
He told MPs: 'In the last five years we've taken the tough choices to drive down our borrowing, make our business taxes competitive and reform welfare.
'It's because we've taken these difficult decisions, and overcome the opposition to them, that Britain is able to afford a pay rise.
'Because let me be clear: Britain deserves a pay rise and Britain is getting a pay rise.'
Unite union general secretary Len McCluskey said: 'The fear is that the promise of a national living wage does not go far enough or fast enough to plug the hole that many families face in their finances because of this Budget.
'Cutting help with low incomes and high housing costs will punish millions of households who have already seen their incomes fall by 40 per week since the financial crash, while the exclusion of younger workers from the national living wage is another reminder that this Government has little else to offer them but workfare exploitation or poverty pay.'
But employers also warned of the impact it will have on their business if they have to increase wages.
The Association of Convenience Stores said it was a 'reckless measure' that will have a significant negative impact on the sector.
Chief executive James Lowman said: 'The introduction of a compulsory Living Wage will have a devastating impact on thousands of convenience stores. This will lead to retailers having to reduce staff hours, work more hours in their business and ultimately cancel their investment plans.
'To introduce this measure with no consultation undermines the independent Low Pay Commission and is a reckless way to impose a massive burden on small businesses.'
Mark Littlewood, director general at the Institute of Economic Affairs, said the policy was 'intellectually bankrupt'.
'Almost a fifth of workers will now see their hourly rate of pay determined by a government quango,' he added.
Some of the cost of employers paying higher wages would be 'offset' by a plan to cut corporation tax to 18 per cent by 2020.
The Office for Budget Responsibility said it will have a 'fractional' effect on jobs, with 60,000 fewer posts as a result.

How Osborne's tax rises are set to pull in an extra 50billion
By Hugo Duncan
George Osborne yesterday announced plans to raise almost 50billion more in tax to drag Britain back into the black
George Osborne said the crisis in Greece vindicated his decision to press ahead with austerity
George Osborne yesterday announced plans to raise almost 50billion more in tax to drag Britain back into the black.
The Chancellor had appeared to deliver a giveaway Budget, following the confirmation of tax cuts worth 24.6billion for businesses, the low-paid and middle-class workers.
However, he also revealed a series of policies expected to raise an extra 47.2billion over the course of this Parliament  resulting in a net increase of 22.6billion for the taxmans takings.
These measures include a sharp increase in the tax on insurance, as well as higher levies on dividends and motorists excise duties.
However, Mr Osborne admitted that he will take one year longer than previously thought to wipe out Britains annual budget deficit, which is now expected to become a surplus in 2019/20. The Chancellor said this slower pace of deficit-reduction  equal to that seen in the last parliament  would create a smoother path to the same destination.
He stressed that the crisis in Greece vindicated his decision to press ahead with austerity, following an explosion of borrowing during the Labour years. You only have to look at ... Greece to realise that if a country is not in control of its borrowing, the borrowing takes control of country, he said.
The Treasury added that the prolonged stand-off between the Greeks and their creditors is the biggest external risk to the UK economy, as we remain highly exposed to wider market instability.
Gross domestic product was found to have risen by 3 per cent last year  the fastest rate since 2006, and the strongest in the G7. The Office for Budget Responsibility, the Treasurys watchdog, forecast growth of 2.4 per cent this year and 2.3 per cent next year  putting Britain on course to lead the G7 once again.
Borrowing, which reached a record 153.5billion under Labour in 2009-10, fell to 89.2billion (or 4.9 per cent of GDP) last year.
Yesterdays OBR projections forecast this to fall further to 69.5billion this year  6billion lower than first anticipated. However, the overall national debt has soared from around 500billion on the eve of the financial crisis to 1.5trillion today.
The OBR said Mr Osbornes new deficit-reduction timetable would represent less of a rollercoaster for public services facing cuts  but it will still be a bumpy ride.

Welfare cuts: Tax credits slashed and FOUR year benefit freeze
Tax credits slashed and benefits frozen for FOUR years: Osborne cuts 12bn from welfare but admits it will take TWICE as long as planned to make the savings
George Osborne froze benefits for four years and took an axe to tax credits, but admitted it would take twice as long as originally planned to find 12billion in welfare savings.
The Chancellor, delivering the first Tory budget in almost 20 years, said he wanted to turn Britain into a 'high wage, low welfare' economy.
Mr Osborne warned the scale of tax credits was not sustainable and major reforms and cuts were needed
He announced that tax credits would be cut by 9billion and limited to a family's first two children, while in-work benefits will kept at today's levels until 2019/20.
The amount households can receive in benefits will also be limited to a maximum of 20,000 a year outside London and 23,000 in the capital.
The Chancellor also stripped under 21s from receiving housing benefit and slashed Employment and Support Allowance for those too sick to work by 30 a week.
Taken together, the benefit cuts will save 12billion by 2019/20 - two years later than Mr Osborne promised in the Conservative manifesto.
The Chancellor insisted the benefit cuts were needed to secure Britain's 'economic security'. He told MPs: 'If we are to build a more productive economy, and our country is to live within its means, then we have to make this fundamental change.
'Welfare spending is not sustainable and it crowds out spending on things like education and infrastructure that are vital to securing the real welfare of the people.'
To make 12 billion in welfare savings Mr Osborne unveiled a series of benefit cuts, including plans to:
Force those aged between 18 and 21 to either 'earn or learn'
Strip housing benefit from under 21s
Cut Employment and Support Allowance  paid to people too ill to work  by over 30 a week.
Freeze working age benefits for four years
Cap the total amount of benefits a family can take home in benefits to 20,000 outside London and 23,000 in the capital
Mr Osborne said the cuts we designed to put the welfare budget 'on a sustainable footing'.
He said: 'In 1980, working age welfare accounted for 8 per cent of all public spending. Today it is 13 per cent.
'The original Tax Credit system cost 1.1 billion in its first year. This year, that cost has reached 30 billion. We spend more on family benefits in Britain than Germany, France or Sweden.'
The amount workless families can claim in benefits will be cut to 23,000 in London, and 20,000 for the rest of the country, well below the average annual salary of workers in every part of the UK
Mr Osborne said this was simply 'not sustainable'.
The Chancellor also reduced the benefit cap from 26,000 to 23,000 in London, and 20,000 in the rest of the country.
He said confirmed a crack down on middle class families living in council houses with cheap rent.
The Chancellor told MPs: 'We are also going to require those on higher incomes living in social housing to pay rents at the market rate.
'It's not fair that families earning over 40,000 in London, or 30,000 elsewhere, should have their rents subsidised by other working people.
WINNERS AND THE LOSERS: THE CHANCELLOR'S BUDGET
WINNERS
The lowest paid: Replacing the 6.50 minimum wage for over-25s with a 9 Living Wage delivers more than 5,000 a year extra for a full-time worker. Some 6million salaries will be increased  though some of this will be offset by tax-credit cuts. The threshold at which most people start paying tax will rise by 400 from 10,600 to 11,000.
40p taxpayers: The threshold at which 40p tax kicks in will rise from 42,385 to 43,000 next year  the Tories have committed to increasing it to 50,000 over the Parliament. It will lift 130,000 people out of the higher rate.
Armed Forces: The Tory Right was delighted by the Chancellors pledge to spend 2 per cent of GDP on defence  something he refused to commit to before the election. MPs will want to check for any double-counting of money from the aid or security-service budgets.
Anybody with a spare room to rent: A person can receive 7,500 tax-free for renting out a room from April  up from 4,250.
The NHS: Spending will increase by 10billion a year in real terms by 2020  the exact sum the head of the NHS says is required.
LOSERS
Tax-credit recipients: Working-age benefits such as tax credits will be frozen for four years. The income threshold for tax credits is to be reduced from 6,420 to 3,850.
Large families: From 2017, parents will not be able to claim tax credits for more than two children. Currently one in five families claiming tax credits have three or more children. Those already in the system will not lose out as the policy is intended to encourage parents to only have children they can afford to raise.
Less well-off students: Maintenance grants for those from the poorest backgrounds will be replaced with loans from 2016/17, which they begin paying back once they earn 21,000.
Public-sector workers: The 1 per cent cap on rises in public-sector pay  introduced in 2009  will stay for four years. With inflation (now 0.1 per cent) expected to hit 2 per cent over the Parliament, it is a real-terms pay cut that will infuriate union bosses at a time when MPs pay is being hiked by 10 per cent.
Buy-to-let landlords: Mortgage interest relief on residential property will be restricted to basic-rate tax  clobbering 40p taxpayers who bought an investment property.
Jobless benefit claimants: The benefits cap will drop from 26,000 to 23,000 in London and 20,000 outside the capital. Under-21s will not be entitled to housing benefit.
Families who buy a new car: Most new-car buyers will pay a 140 charge from 2017. Currently no Vehicle Excise Duty is paid on seven in ten new cars as they are eco-friendly. The money will be put in a special fund for road improvements.
Non-doms: Anyone resident in the UK for 15 of the past 20 years will pay full British taxes on all worldwide income and gains. People will no longer be able to inherit non-dom status.
Labour: The party was hit for six by the living wage announcement. Leaderless, it must now agonise over whether to repeat the mistakes of the last Parliament by voting against benefit cuts that are popular with most voters.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Gorilla driven quackers by ducks trying to make their home in his zoo enclosure
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154629/This-baby-gorilla-driven-quackers-family-ducks-trying-make-home-zoo-enclosure.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Two-year-old Indigo - a western lowland gorilla - was fascinated by the mother and her flock of ducklings after they waddled into the pond in his compound at Durrell Wildlife Park, Jersey.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
This baby gorilla is being driven quackers by a family of ducks trying to make their home in his zoo enclosure
Two-year-old Indigo - awestern lowland gorilla - couldn't keep his eyes off the feathered friends who share his home
As the mother duck and her ducklings built their own base in the water, excited primate watched on mesmerised
Young creature circled around the ducks and at one point squatted down on his haunches as if to dive in after them
Published: 09:46 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 11:13 GMT, 9 July 2015
33 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Toys 'R' Us founder Charles Lazarus puts Hamptons mansion on sale for $13.5m
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154699/The-ultimate-playground-Toys-R-tycoon-92-puts-waterfront-mansion-Hamptons-sale-13-5m-comes-complete-pool-boat-house-croquet-lawn.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The 92-year-old tycoon's six-bed abode in the opulent Hamptons in New York, USA, boasts a pool, boat house and croquet lawn.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
The ultimate playground! Toys 'R' Us tycoon, 92, puts waterfront mansion in Hamptons on sale for $13.5m... and it comes complete with a pool, boat house and croquet lawn
Family estate of Charles Lazarus listed for $13.5million - and buyers can look forward to a pool and croquet lawn
Waterfront property, in Hamptons, New York, sprawls across four acres and enjoys spectacular views over the bay
The estate includes the main house, the gate house, a windmill shaped guest room and a stunning boat house
Published: 10:59 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 11:01 GMT, 9 July 2015
47 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date/>
        <title>
	North Shields woman bitten by stranger 'who tried to gouge out her eyes'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154565/Grandmother-44-suffers-agonising-injuries-woman-bites-nose-tries-gouge-eyes.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Wendy Barber suffered horrific injuries when a stranger allegedly set upon her in the street in North Shields, in Tyne and Wear. She had gone to her daughter's house in an attempt to diffuse a row.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
'The pain was unbelievable.'
Ms Barber was at a friend's house on the night of Friday, June 19 when her daughter Gemma Elliott, 21, telephoned her and asked her to come and see her because she was upset after an alleged argument.
Attacked: Ms Barber had gone to her daughter's, who was upset after an alleged argument. It was there she was met by the stranger
She took a taxi to her daughter's flat on Balkwell Green and made an attempt to diffuse the row.
But she was instead greeted by a stranger, who allegedly set upon her without warning.
Ms Barber said: 'This lass just came flying down the stairs and wouldn't let go.'
A friend of Ms Barber, who was on the street, came to her aid.
Ms Barber's attacker let her go before the police and paramedics arrived.
The grandmother was taken to the new Northumbria Specialist Emergency Care Hospital, in Cramlington.
She was treated for her injuries before being sent to the Royal Victoria Infirmary in Newcastle where she received a tetanus jab. A plastic surgeon had to stitch her damaged nose back together.
The mother-of-three said: 'My face was in a right state.'
After the attack Ms Barber arranged for her 12-year-old son Kevin to stay with a friend so that he would not have to see her injured face.
This lass just came flying down the stairs and wouldn't let go
Wendy Barber
She said she was still struggling to get over the attack but thanked her family and friends for their support.
Ms Barber said: 'I think the shock has worn off and the reality has sunk in and I just keep crying and having little flashbacks and I'm just wary of everyone now.'
She added: 'The support I have had has been great. It has blown me away. I didn't know so many people cared.'
Donna Willis, 43, of Langley Road has been charged with wounding with intent to commit grievous bodily harm, and Louise Cook, 23, of Balkwell Green has been charged with assault occasioning actual bodily harm.
Both appeared before Newcastle Crown Court earlier this week where the case was adjourned until later in the year. Ms Willis was remanded in custody until the next hearing, while Ms Cook was released on bail.
Share or comment on this article
16
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date/>
        <title>
	One Direction back climate change campaign despite using private jets
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154523/One-Direction-accused-having-two-faces-climate-change-campaign-despite-using-TWO-private-jets.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The group, the richest boyband in British music history with a combined wealth of £70million, have launched action/1D to 'stop dangerous climate change' despite using two planes to travel the world.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
One Direction have denied being two-faced after throwing their weight behind a climate change campaign despite previously admitting they often use two private jets to travel the globe.
The group, who last last year were revealed to be the richest boyband in British music history with a combined wealth of 70million, have joined Save the Children in launching action/1D.
In a statement they said: 'Young people really do have the power to help end poverty, tackle inequality and stop dangerous climate change.'
It comes after the band racked up around 200,000 miles while travelling the world on their past two tours.
Scroll down for video
Mixed message: One Direction have denied being two-faced after throwing their weight behind climate change campaign action/1D despite previously admitting they often use two private jets to travel the globe
Carbon-burning: Last May, after performing at Radio 1's Big Weekend, Harry Styles and Niall Horan, both 21, boarded one plane, while Liam Payne, 21, Zayn Malik, 22, and Louis Tomlinson, 23, all boarded another
One Direction boys ask fans to help 'change the world'
Last May, after performing at Radio 1's Big Weekend,Harry Styles and Niall Horan, both 21, boarded one plane along with members of their security and styling team, while Liam Payne, 21, Zayn Malik, 22, and Louis Tomlinson, 23, all boarded another.
A spokesman for the band told MailOnline at the time: 'The band often take two planes and it just depends who gets on what plane.'
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Female transgender soldiers who were born male could serve on the front line
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154647/Female-transgender-soldiers-born-male-serve-line-reveals-Army-chief.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Lieutenant General Andrew Gregory said the Army had not yet faced a situation where a woman with all the strength of a man wanted to serve in the infantry.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Femaletransgender soldiers who were born male 'might well be able' to serve on the front line, an Army chief has said.
Lieutenant General Andrew Gregory said the Army had not yet faced a situation where a woman with all the strength of a man wanted to serve in the infantry.
But the Chief of Defence Personnel said it would make a 'very interesting test case'.
Female transgender soldiers who were born male 'might well be able' to serve on the front line, Lieutenant General Andrew Gregory (right). It comes after a report backed by the Defence Secretary Michael Fallon (left) recommended opening up the infantry to women soldiers
Women are currently barred from serving in the infantry and in armoured units, but combat roles could be opened up  by next year after a Government-backed report recommended the move.
Lt Gen Gregory admitted there were still pockets of homophobia in the military, but said he wanted to make the organisation as inclusive as possible.
He told the gay newspaper Pink News : 'We do not yet have any female transgender people serving in the infantry. We haven't had to address it because we haven't had the issue come up.
'It would be a very interesting test case if it did come up. If somebody - birth gender male who physically has all the physical strength and durability but had transitioned, they might well be able.'
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date/>
        <title>
	How checking your emails in meetings drives your colleagues mad
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154616/How-checking-emails-meetings-drives-colleagues-mad-Research-finds-workers-multi-task-makes-annoyed-distracted.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	A study, by Harvard Business School academics, found that those who use devices during meetings made 50 per cent more mistakes and 'distracted' and 'annoyed' their colleagues.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
34 shares
She even went as far to say that multi-tasking is 'simply a mythical activity', adding: 'The research finds that the more time people spend using multiple forms of media simultaneously, the least likely they are to perform well on multitasking abilities.
'In fact, studies show that a person who is attempting to multitask takes 50 per cent longer to accomplish a task and he or she makes up to 50 per cent more mistakes.'
7 TIPS FOR THE PERFECT MEETING
1. Keep it small
No more than seven people should be present at a meeting to enable all attendees to participate. Smaller groups make it easier for workers to pick up on their colleagues body language.
2. Ban devices
Mobile phones, tablets and laptops should be put away or turned off during the meeting unless they are being used to retrieve reference material. Devices are not only distracting to the user, but also colleagues.
3. Keep it as short as possible
Meetings should be no longer than one hour, to allow workers to stay focused. Problems are also solved much quicker when there are time constraints, with decision-making performed at a faster rate under higher pressure.
4. Stand up
Stand-up meetings are said to be 34 per cent shorter than sit-down meetings but produce the same solutions.
5. Make sure everyone participates
Make sure everyone speaks up and offers their point, instead of hanging back. Professor Axtell said: 'Some people may want to speak up but don't feel like they can unless they're asked.' Those who hold back often have the best perspective but it needs to be drawn out.
6. Never hold a meeting just to update people
Meetings held to update employees on a matter are deemed a waste of time by academics.Why take up valuable time saying something you can just email?
7. Set an agenda
Setting an agenda ahead of the meeting is critical. Lacking a clear plan of action often causes meetings to de-rail and sees less decisions made. Planning gives everyone the opportunity to clarify intentions and allows participants to attend prepared.
Paul Axtell, who has worked for 35 years as a personal effectiveness consultant, agrees that being on a mobile phone during a meeting can be 'hurtful'.
Writing on the Harvard Business School blog , he said: 'If you're presenting or talking about an idea and you see a senior manager on their phone, it hurts.'
He suggested that all devices should be switched off during meetings unless they are being used to retrieve reference material.
The research has been published by the Harvard academics alongside advice on how to get more out of work meetings.
They suggest that sessions should be kept 'as small as possible' with no more than seven workers in attendance in a bid to allow everyone to participate.
They also believe meetings should last no longer than one hour, to allow workers to stay focused, and be conducted while standing. This is because sessions taken while standing are 34 per cent shorter than sit-down meetings, yet produce the same solutions.
Other tips by the academics for sure-fire success meetings include making sure everyone speaks up and offers their point, instead of hanging back.
Professor Axtell said: 'Some people may want to speak up but don't feel like they can unless they're asked.
'This may be due to 'cultural reasons, or language barriers, or general disposition.'
'The people who hold back often have the best perspective on the conversation and definitely need to be drawn out.'
The academics also advise setting an agenda prior to the meeting, to show the clear purpose of the session, and never holding a conference just to update colleagues.
The advice comes after an industry body claimed that companies need to improve productivity in the workplace by introducing 'smarter working practices'.
The Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development (CIPD) found that fewer than half of British businesses consider increasing productivity to be a current priority, while a third do not use any measures of productivity.
Weak productivity has been a major problem in the UK since the financial crisis, and the economic recovery has not led it to pick up as much as the Bank of England expected, potentially weighing on how much Britons can expect to earn in the future.
Professor Francesca Gino, from Harvard Business School, said the brain 'can't handle multi-tasking' and found that workers believe it is 'rude' when their colleagues pick up a phone during a conference (file picture)
Last week, the CIPD warned that there needs to a strong focus on workplace productivity.
Peter Cheese, chief executive, said: 'We need a shift in focus towards increasing the value generated by the workforce and how work is organised.
'This will require a renewed focus on the way people are managed and developed to deliver smarter, more productive working.'
The CIPD said the government should give higher priority to investing in ventures such as the funding of vocational and further education and training.
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
34
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Couple drive TOWARDS a tornado as it tears through Italian town
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154563/Terrifying-footage-shows-couple-driving-tornado-tears-Italian-town-leaving-one-person-dead-slam-car-reverse-realise-danger-in.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The dramatic footage shows the car travelling towards the twister under darkened skies as debris clangs off the vehicle in the Italian town of Mira, on the outskirts of Venice.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The couple initially continue on, but quickly change their minds and also slam their car into reverse as a swell of panic rushes through them.
The footage ends with debris continuing to rain down, but it appeared they had successfully managed to avoid the twister's path.
The storm tore through the towns of Dolo and Mira, between Venice and Padua, yesterday, killing one driver after picking up their car and sending it crashing back down to the ground.
Other motorists slaming on their brakes and putting their cars into reverse as the tornado races ever closer
Out of danger: The couple initially continue on, but quickly change their minds and also slam their car into reverse as a swell of panic rushes through them. The footage ends (right) with debris continuing to rain down, but it appeared they had successfully managed to avoid the twister's path
An eight-year-old girl escaped death, but suffered burns after being struck by lightning in Carnia.
At least 50 buildings had their rooftops ripped off and more than 100 people suffered injuries, it was reported by The Local , which cited Corriere.
Pictures also showed cars crushed by trees, camper vans overturned and bricks and mortar strewn across streets.
Devastation: The storm tore through the towns of Dolo and Mira, between Venice and Padua, yesterday, killing one driver after picking up their car and sending it crashing back down to the ground. Pictures also showed a car being crushed by a tree (above)
Carnage: At least 50 buildings had their rooftops ripped off and more than 100 people suffered injuries
A crane topples onto a house. An eight-year-old girl escaped death in the storm, but suffered burns after being struck by lightning in Carnia
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
442
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date/>
        <title>
	British backpackers murder trial sees DNA evidence  'go missing'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154605/Vital-DNA-evidence-trial-Burmese-migrants-accused-killing-two-British-backpackers-Thai-beach-lost-produced-court-police-admit.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The evidence is key to the prosecution of Zaw Lin and Win Zaw Tun, both 22, who police say brutally murdered Hannah Witheridge, 23, and David Miller, 24 , on the island of Koh Tao last September.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Police say DNA evidence against suspects accused of raping and murdering British backpackers on Koh Tao cannot be retested by defence lawyers as it has been 'lost'
Hannah Witheridge was found deadwith fellow backpacker David Miller
Two 21-year-old Burmese migrants were arrested two weeks later
Initially confessed to the crime but then said they were tortured by police
DNA evidence recovered from scene is considered key to the murder trial
But the defence team cannot ask for the DNA to be retested as they had plannedbecausebunglingpolice officers have 'lost' it
Published: 09:43 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 09:52 GMT, 9 July 2015
6 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="60">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Buckingham Palace 'gunman' was artist carrying photos as armed police gathered
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154519/Armed-police-swoop-Buckingham-Palace-gunman-artist-carrying-photos-cardboard-tube.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Artist Ray Fiasco, 21, was stopped by 'about 10' officers wielding semi-automatic machine guns as he innocently wandered past Buckingham Palace.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Armed police swooped on photographer Ray Fiasco outside Buckingham Palace yesterday afternoon
An artist carrying photographs in a cardboard tube feared he mightget 'done like Jean Charles de Menezes' when armed police swooped on him outside Buckingham Palace yesterday.
Photographer Ray Fiasco feared the worst when 'about 10' officers wielding semi-automatic machine guns confronted him, believing he was holding a rifle outside the royal residence.
The Queen, who was due to return to the Palace at around the same time as the security alert, was kept away as the area was put into lockdown, it was reported.
Fine art photographer Ray Fiasco said he thought he might get killed like Brazilian Mr de Menezes, who was mistakenly shot dead by police in the wake of the 7/7 bombings in 2005.
The 21-year-old - real name Ranen Baynes Stephenson - tweeted: 'So I'm walking through London ... walking towards Buckingham Palace to go to my boy's house in Victoria.
'I was carrying my art with me, as you do when you are me... my artwork is in a tube, wrapped in plastic because it's London and it rains.
'Now someone saw me walking with a smile on my face and decided to conclude that I was carrying a rifle.
'So they called every form of police. Told them I was carrying a rifle walking towards Buckingham Palace.
'4 BMWs pull up, block off the whole road, about 10 men jump out, guns pointed at me. Bullet-proof vests... Tazers... everything.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="61">
        <date/>
        <title>
	David Cameron to water down the foxhunting ban without a full repeal
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154344/MPs-free-vote-easing-foxhunting-ban-Tories-confirm-plan-water-laws-believe-not-support-push-repeal.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The Prime Minister will make it legal to kill foxes for pest control and for those foxes to be flushed out by a full pack of hounds, but has stopped short of a repeal because he does not have enough support.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The Prime Ministers official spokeswoman said: Defra are planning to bring forward some technical changes before the summer recess. The objective is to give MPs the opportunity to vote to end a current anomaly in the system between what can happen in Scotland and what can happen in England.
The Prime Minister has made clear several times that he believes in the freedom to hunt.
At the moment, upland farmers in the Highlands of Scotland can use an unlimited number of dogs to flush out a fox, whereas those in the Welsh hills or the North York Moors are limited to two. This is about technical changes to how you resolve that anomaly.
She added that Mr Cameron was still committed to the manifesto promise to repeal the hunting ban  fuelling expectations that the government will go further in future.
Mr Cameron has said several times that he was opposed to the fox hunting ban and wishes to relax it
The interim compromise deal will be in line with rules in Scotland, making it difficult for the 56 Scottish Nationalist MPs to oppose.
The Prime Minister could amend legislation through a statutory instrument procedure, curtailing the debating time to 90 minutes.
If approved by MPs, the change would go to the Lords for debate this autumn. A new regime will be in place by winter if peers agree the compromise.
A Countryside Alliance spokesman said: This is a step forward and will mean that farmers and hunts will be able to use packs of hounds to find and shoot foxes. Traditional hunting will, though, remain illegal.
These amendments will bring the law into line with Scotland and ensure that farmers are able to choose how to manage the fox population in the most effective and humane manner.
We still believe that the Hunting Act needs to be scrapped, but in the circumstances these amendments meet the immediate needs of the rural community.
There is solid support for hunting amongst MPs and we believe that there will be a majority for these logical, evidence-based changes.
So far, 378 people have been convicted under the Hunting Act since it came into force in 2005, but 94 per cent of those convicted had no connection to registered hunts. Most cases involve poaching.
But Maria Eagle, Labours rural affairs spokeswoman, said the PM was resorting to desperate measures.
David Camerons proposals have more to do with controlling his back benchers than fox numbers in the countryside and Labour will oppose any such measures, she said.
Many Tory MPs want to overturn the fox hunting ban
Minister for sport Tracey Crouch, pictured believes that up to 40 MPs could abstain or vote against a repeal
Critics of the hunting ban have previously pointed out how MPs spent far more time debating a ban on hunting under Tony Blairs government a decade ago than the invasion of Iraq.
It has cost taxpayers millions with police deployed to try and enforce what has been a centuries-old British tradition.
Farmers in upland areas will be relieved at the move because it will allow them to better protect livestock from foxes.
It could also prevent foxes from dying a slow, painful death from mange.
At present, it is legal to hunt with two hounds to flush a fox but it must then be shot dead. The new exemption would allow hunters to use as many hounds as necessary for wildlife management.
Mr Cameron promised a free vote on hunting in the Tory manifesto before this years general election.
There was disappointed among supporters of hunting that the pledge was not enforced in the Queens Speech, the first under a Tory majority government.
However Number 10 wants to be confident that it will be successful in amending the existing ban and has instead worked on a compromise deal.
Tracey Crouch, the minister for sport, has warned that up to 40 MPs could abstain or vote against a full repeal of the Hunting Act.
Many of the new MPs are from metropolitan backgrounds and will not necessarily empathise with countryside campaigners.
But a compromise deal for the sake of wildlife management would be more likely to get their approval.
Nicola Sturgeon, the Scottish First Minister, has also said the SNP certainly dont agree with repealing the ban.
However the partys Westminster leader Angus Robertson said that that the SNP would want to study any proposed new legislation before taking a final decision.
Although Mr Cameron was once a keen hunter, he was hampered in repealing the hunting ban during his years of coalition with the Liberal Democrats.
More than 80 per cent of the public say they are against fox hunting and using dogs to hunt stags and hares.
When the Hunting Act was introduced in 2004, there were fears that thousands of rural jobs would disappear.
However, many hunts have adapted to the rules.
The Countryside Alliance has said that the ban was a badly drafted law that was motivated by class war.
Mr Cameron wrote in the Countryside Alliance magazine shortly before the election: I have always been a strong supporter of country sports. It is my firm belief that people should have the freedom to hunt, so I share the frustration that many people feel about the Hunting Act and the way it was brought in by the last government. The Hunting Act has done nothing for animal welfare.
Share or comment on this article
128
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="62">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Tonbridge Angels footballer Junior Dian dies on pitch after collapsing during trial
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154354/Footballer-24-dies-pitch-collapsing-trial-non-league-team.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Junior Dian, 24, collapsed during the second half as he played for Kent-based Tonbridge Angels at Whyteleafe FC in Surrey. Despite the efforts of paramedics, he died shortly afterwards.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
He said: 'This is devastating news and our only crumb of comfort is that Junior lost his life doing something he obviously enjoyed so much.
Club chairman Steve Churcher said the only crumb of comfort as 'Junior lost his life doing something he obviously enjoyed so much'
'All our thoughts and sympathies are with his family. Also, I would like to thank everyone at Whyteleafe FC for their support and professionalism during this very distressing incident yesterday evening.'
Messages of condolence poured in on Twitter for the player, including from former QPR boss Redknapp.
He wrote: 'Terrible news about Junior Dian who died playing football. Sending my thoughts to his family.'
Gillingham FC tweeted: 'Our thoughts are with the family of Junior Dian who tragically collapsed and died playing for @TAFConline last night. RIP.'
Tonbridge Angels said this weekend's match against the Gills would be dedicated to Mr Dian, and a one-minute's applause would be held.
The club said: 'Junior was associated with the club for only a very short time but in that time he became part of the Angels family and it is therefore right that we are all able to pay our respects to this young footballer who sadly is no longer with us.'
The club said those affected by the tragedy could approach the club chaplain Neil Durling for counselling.
The club will hold a one minute's applause during this weekend's match against Gillingham FC in tribute
Share or comment on this article
36
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="63">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Anaconda cut open swollen and ANOTHER snake found inside it's belly
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154530/Incredible-moment-villagers-cut-open-swollen-body-dead-anaconda-discover-fatal-meal-died-trying-eat-anaconda.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	This is the incredible moment villagers sliced open the bloated belly of a dead anaconda to discover its fatal last meal was another anaconda.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Anacondas are known for snacking on wild pigs, deer and caiman.
But when these villagers stumbled across the giant snake lying on the ground, they discovered its final meal had been something a little closer to home.
As they sliced open its bloated belly, they found it had feasted on another anaconda in what was its fatal last meal.
Gruesome moment dead snake is removed from anaconda's body
Villagers stumble across the bloated anaconda lying on the floor and start slicing its belly with a knife
As they forced open the body of the dead snake, they found another anaconda inside its swollen body
As they sliced open its belly, they unloaded another giant snake onto the ground which they pulled away with a wooden stick
The fearsome creature slumped on the ground had died while trying to eat another anaconda
The body of the anaconda was opened up by a man sporting a baseball cat as he unloaded the contents of its fatal last supper onto the scrubland.
He then separated the two fearsome creatures from one another using a wooden stick as animated onlookers watched on.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="64">
        <date/>
        <title>
	16 times more Britons know Harry Potter Quidditch rules compared with croquet
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3154515/Do-know-quaffles-Pirie-pokes-16-times-Britons-know-rules-Harry-Potter-game-Quidditch-compared-croquet.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Britons are far more likely to know the rules of Harry Potter's Quidditch than croquet according to a new survey which has warned that the traditional summer game could die out completely by 2037.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Only a few thousand people play croquet regularly. Worryingly for the future of the sport, people are 16 times more likely to understand the rules of Quidditch than croquet, the poll found.
Those that do play say they love the sport because it is slow and relaxing (40 per cent), sociable (37 per cent) and you could drink Pimms while playing (30 per cent)
According to the Croquet Associations latest report - which showed a 26 per cent decrease in numbers of under-50s playing over the last five years - the sport will not survive unless it attracts younger players.
It says the sport, whose average player is aged 68, will have disappeared from the UK in just 22 years unless more people start playing.
In a bid to revive interest in the sport, a crazy croquet course was unveiled at Heathrow Terminal 2.
Passenger Craig Simpson, 34, said: 'No other sport, apart from old school darts and snooker, lets you drink at the same time as playing, but with croquet its positively encouraged, so whats not to like?'
Real-life Quidditch
A version of Quidditch is played in the United States where they even have their own World Cup
The course, funded by Heathrow and Pimms, lets people bash balls through hoops shaped like flamingoes and teacups for the next two weeks.
Other quirks in the course include musical hoops and laser-guided mallets - and passengers can play a round in 15-minutes while they wait for their flight.
Kim Gray, of Heathrow, said: 'Despite being a classic summer pastime, our research revealed that croquet is in desperate need of a revival.
'The lawn will be based in the terminal for two weeks, enticing over 120,000 passengers to learn the rules, sip a Pimms and enjoy a quick game before flying out.
'By adding an injection of fun to the game with our Crazy Croquet course, we hope to raise awareness of this dying British sport and encourage a younger audience to give it a go.'
Miranda Garrett from Croquet East said, 'Many perceive croquet as an outdated game - this needs to change. In reality, its a marvellously social outdoor sport combining fierce strategy with gentle exercise.
'Its also one of the only sports where indulging in a tipple or two is actively encouraged!
'We really hope the fabulous Crazy Croquet course encourages passengers to pick up their mallets this summer and keep the game alive.'

Share or comment on this article
30
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="65">
        <date/>
        <title>
	DAILY MAIL COMMENT: Budget makes Britain a better place to work
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-3154170/DAILY-MAIL-COMMENT-Budget-makes-Britain-better-place-work.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	After such a Budget, it was almost possible to feel sorry for Labour’s acting leader Harriet Harman, who had the hopeless task of replying for her party.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
It was almost possible to feel sorry for Labours acting leader Harriet Harman, who had the hopeless task of replying for her party
After such a Budget, it was almost possible to feel sorry for Labours acting leader Harriet Harman, who had the hopeless task of replying for her party.
True, George Osborne blithely ignored crises in the rest of the world, speaking as if nothing in the eurozone or China could throw UK growth off course.
Its also unsettling that he put back his target for breaking even by another year, while planning to spend 83.3billion more than he suggested three months ago.
And while he didnt say so specifically, figures from the Office for Budget Responsibility reveal that over the lifetime of this Parliament there will be a net rise in taxes of an eye-watering 22billion.
Nevertheless, this was a virtuoso Budget. It was more than a masterclass in wrong-footing opponents  more, even, than the continuation of five years work to repair the public finances, free at last from obstruction by the Lib Dems.
This first all-Conservative package since 1996 was nothing less than a blueprint for transforming Britain into a better, more prosperous country  of self-reliant families, rescued from welfare dependency to enjoy the dignity and rewards of work.
As ever, the devil will be in the detail, and it may be days before the full impact of the changes becomes apparent.
But the guiding theme of the Chancellors measures  making work pay  shines through with perfect clarity.
Indeed, though this was Mr Osbornes Budget, credit must go to Iain Duncan Smith, who laid the groundwork for the welfare reforms that lie at its heart.
Inevitably, the Left howls against the lower welfare caps and moves to unravel Gordon Browns tax credits. Yet these labyrinthine subsidies for low wages were unsustainable from the start.
Introduced in 1999, costs have ballooned from 1.1billion to 30billion a year  13 per cent of all public spending  while making 4.5million families part-dependent on the State. Meanwhile, the chief beneficiaries have been the countrys worst payers, such as supermarkets.
Something had to be done to save us from ruin. It is much to Mr Osbornes credit that hes done it so skilfully.
Softening the blow for families on tax credits, he is raising the starting point for income tax. But his masterstroke is increasing the minimum wage, rebranded a living wage, to 9 an hour by 2020  with cuts in corporation tax and small firms national insurance to compensate.
Credit must go to Iain Duncan Smith, who laid the groundwork for the welfare reforms that lie at the heart of the budget
Highlights of first Conservative budget in almost 20 years
This is in the fine tradition of rabbits out of the Chancellors Budget hat, confounding his critics and thoroughly disarming Labour.
Showing similar political (though perhaps not economic) wisdom, he has resisted the Rights demands to cut the top rate of tax, while going to war against non-doms and the tax-avoiding rich.
But there is relief for middle-income families, with a welcome first move towards raising the threshold for the 40p rate to 50,000 by 2020. And the Right will be justly delighted by his decision to honour our Nato commitment to spend 2 per cent of national income on defence.
Add the boost for apprenticeships, the NHS and the 1million inheritance tax threshold, and this was a Budget for everyone with families interests at heart.
Of course, a downside is that the 9 living wage can only encourage yet more migrants to flock to the UK. Meanwhile, phasing out tax credits makes nonsense of David Camerons only policy for reducing EU migration. But that is a debate for another day.
Meanwhile, if the worst to be said is that Mr Osborne has made Britain a more attractive place to live and work, he can congratulate himself on a job well done.
He has set out a refreshing, aspirational vision of what Britain might become, freed from the dead hand of the state. For that, we should all be grateful.

Share or comment on this article
18
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="66">
        <date/>
        <title>
	The Tories have let the bloated BBC off the hook, STEPHEN GLOVER writes
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-3154255/STEPHEN-GLOVER-Ignore-wailing-Tories-let-bloated-BBC-hook.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The Beeb has been forced to take on the cost of free television licences for the over-75s, which will eat up about a fifth of its annual income, writes STEPHEN GLOVER.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
For this deal is in most ways much better than the BBC had any right to expect. Despite the caterwauling of its supporters, its not even clear that the Corporation will be any smaller, or less well-funded, in ten years time.
Lets first examine the cost to the BBC of funding television licences for the over-75s. The Corporations outraged defenders say that when it assumes full responsibility for this in 2020, it will suffer a budget cut of 650 million.
Yesterdays Budget revealed that the Beeb has been forced to take on the cost of free television licences for the over-75s, which will eat up about a fifth of its annual income
I agree that the plan to make it pay for a Government subsidy to the elderly is somewhat bizarre. But there is no reason to suppose it will continue to shoulder the full burden for many years.
As the proportion of television licence holders over 75 increases because people are living longer, the BBC will argue that it should restrict the perk to the over 80s or even, some years down the line, to the over 85s. Who is to say the Government of the day could or would stop such a move?
In other words, the Corporation will be able unilaterally to reduce its commitment to meet this financial obligation. This decision might earn it some unpopularity with older viewers, but I imagine it could live with that.
Lets look at the other side of the ledger. By way of compensation for accepting a burden likely to be less onerous than it looks, the BBC has been offered the prospect of an annual increase to the licence fee (at present 145.50 a year) from 2017 in line with inflation. Since 2010, it has been frozen.
In addition, the Beeb will be able to force viewers who are at present using its iPlayer without paying the licence fee to cough up. This might give it a further 150 million a year. The Government has also agreed that after 2020 the BBC will no longer have to pay its share of the roll-out of rural broadband.
Until it finds a way of reducing the cost of shelling out for free TV licences for the over-75s, the Corporation will probably be a little worse off, though not by very much. In time, it may be no worse off at all.
As the proportion of television licence holders over 75 increases because people are living longer, the BBC will argue that it should restrict the perk to the over 80s or even, some years down the line, to the over 85s
John Whittingdale on the future of the BBC licence fee
No wonder Tony Hall, director-general, and Danny Cohen, director of television, have seemed so chipper about the agreement over the past few days. Unlike the critics who have huffed and puffed in response to the headlines, they have examined the detail carefully, and realise that the BBC has secured a pretty favourable settlement in light of the cutbacks that will be visited on most government departments.
What is so extraordinary about this apparently cast-iron deal is that it has been made a year before the so-called Charter Review is due to take place. That process, in which the future of the BBC and the best method of funding it is supposed to be considered, appears to have been pre-empted.
Much that should have been discussed has been booted into the next-door field. The Corporation has grown too big, and should be encouraged to concentrate on its indispensable core services, for example Radio 3 and Radio 4, which the broadcasting market left to its own devices might not be guaranteed to supply.
And yet all such arguments have been put on one side, as has the question of the BBCs dominance as a disseminator of news, sometimes with a notably Leftist bias. According to various surveys, it accounts for around half of all the news coverage consumed by the general population, which gives it unrivalled influence.
Some us have argued in favour of replacing the licence fee  a blunt and anachronistic charge in the modern world  with a subscription whereby viewers would pay for those parts of the BBC which they use.
The Beeb will be able to force viewers who are at present using its iPlayer without paying the licence fee to cough up
When John Whittingdale was appointed Culture Secretary after the election, there was every reason to suppose that  as a reputed Thatcherite who only last October described the licence fee as worse than a poll tax  he would orchestrate a robust and far-reaching review.
I suppose its still possible that next years Charter Review will chew over some of these issues, but to judge by what Mr Whittingdale said in the Commons on Monday, and the response of BBC mandarins, it would seem the BBCs future has already been mapped out.
No doubt one is supposed to draw comfort from George Osbornes assertion on Sunday that the BBC should curb the imperial ambitions of its website, which is in effect an online newspaper funded by the licence payer, and supported by thousands of journalists.
Yes, but how? The BBC has undertaken to rein in its website in the past, without doing so. There is nothing I can see in the latest deal that will prevent it from continuing to devote its enormous resources to its website, which sometimes contains Leftist comments by its specialists.
One of Mr Whittingdales colleagues suggests to me that, for all his reputation as a Thatcherite, he is actually a fairly emollient and consensual fellow. If so, is he really likely to undertake genuine root-and-branch reform of the BBC?
I hope Im wrong, and that robust discussions about the future of the BBC lie ahead, but I fear they dont. Im afraid that in return for the quick fix of forcing the BBC to accept 650 million of government expenditure on its books, ministers have shelved long-term plans to adapt the organisation to the modern age.
Ironically, they have acted in a way that pays scant regard to the independence of the BBC. They have bullied Auntie shamelessly, but not so as to achieve anything worthwhile.
There has, indeed, been dirty work at the crossroads. But it is those who have argued and pressed for change  and not the BBC  who have been well and truly stitched up.

Share or comment on this article
63
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="67">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Office for National Statistics figures show married couple numbers have increased
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153713/Marriage-40-year-decline-New-ONS-figures-numbers-married-couples-increased-51-2-16s.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	In 2011, married men and women were almost a minority at just 50.7 per cent of the adult population. But last year 51.2 per cent of people over the age of 16 were found to have tied the knot.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Explanations for the changing trend include suggestions that partnerships are increasingly stable because couples are choosing to marry later.
Official recognition of so-called pre-nup deals is also thought to have had an effect, as it means couples are more willing to risk a wedding.
On the rise: Last year 51.2 per cent of people over the age of 16 were found to have tied the knot (file image)
Other factors could include the impact of immigration, which is bringing into the country people with a greater attachment to marriage than many of the existing population.
The ONS figures found 51.2 per cent of people over 16 in England and Wales were married in 2014. The figure went up to 51.5 per cent when civil partnerships were included.
It compared with 54.8 per cent of adults who were married in 2002.
The report showed that cohabitation continues to grow in popularity but mainly among young people.
Those under the age of 30 are increasingly likely to choose to cohabit rather than to marry, and fewer than a quarter of all those aged between 25 and 30 were married men or women last year.
Around one in eight of the adult population are now cohabiting with a partner. Three quarters of the cohabitees have never been married.
Cohabiting relationships are highly unstable compared to marriages and those that do not lead to a wedding are at least three times more likely to break up than a marriage.
Harry Benson of the Marriage Foundation think tank said: One of the paradoxes of our modern approach to marriage is that marrying later on tends to be more successful.
'But starting later means that if your marriage does go wrong, youre less likely to marry a second time because youre so much older.
Of course that doesnt stop older people marrying. It just becomes less common. In both cases, inertia plays a big part in making older marriages work and much older people less likely to remarry.
'When youre older youre more likely to stick with what you know.
'SILVER SPLITTERS' FUEL SURGE IN DIVORCEES
The number of divorcees in Britain is rising relentlessly, driven by silver splitters.
An analysis of living habits showed that 8.2 per cent of the adult population of England and Wales  almost one person in 12  was a divorcee last year, compared with 7.4 per cent in 2002.
The Office for National Statistics said of its findings: This [rise] is being driven by the population aged over 45, who have seen larger increases in the percentage divorced than younger age groups. Nearly one in ten people over the age of 65 are now divorced, twice the level at the beginning of the century.
The growing willingness of this age group to contemplate separation is said to be linked to longer life expectancy, which makes it more likely that older people will prove unfaithful.
Womens increasing financial independence is also said to have an impact. Experts in family law say the figures reflect a decline in the stigma surrounding separation.
Share or comment on this article
41
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="68">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Cardiff car thieves high on drink and drugs jailed over death of teenager
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153952/Two-car-thieves-high-drink-drugs-jailed-death-teenager-19-killed-60mph-horror-crash.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Sakhawat Ali, from Cardiff, was twice the drink drive limit and had taken cocaine and smoked cannabis before he crashed his uncle's car, killing passenger and aspiring beautician Xana Doyle.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Two car thieves high on drink and drugs jailed over death of teenager, 19, killed in 60mph horror crash
Sakhawat Ali, 23, was drunk and high when he crashed his uncle's car
He was twice drink drive limit, had snorted cocaine and smoked marijuana
Ali crashed when his cousin attempted to pull the handbrake during trip
Xana Doyle was killed in the crash and her friend suffered head injuries
Ali and his cousin were jailed for eight years and seven years respectively
Published: 19:34 GMT, 8 July 2015 | Updated: 20:43 GMT, 8 July 2015
40 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="69">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Swindow teenage bully filmed pushing victim to ground  blames peer pressure
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153970/Teenage-bully-filmed-pushing-victim-ground-forcing-kiss-friend-s-shoe-blames-peer-pressure-assault.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The 14-year-old thug from Swindon, who cannot be named for legal reasons, was convicted of assault after a video of the incident went viral.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
He was approached by a group of around seven youths, one of whom he knew from school.
Kate Prince, prosecuting, told the court at an earlier hearing: 'He was swinging an empty bottle he had tied a string around, and used that bottle to strike the victim on the legs.
'The younger boy then turned away shouting in the direction of the Link Centre where there were a large number of people, saying that [the victim] was getting mouthy.'
The victim then continued to walk away when he heard the voice of the defendant shouting 'get back here', at which point he started running away.
The moment the boy is punched in the side of the face (pictured left) before falling on to the pavement (right)
In the video the victim can be heard asking the attackers: 'Have I done anything?' as he is hit and kicked
He ran out of breath and was quickly surrounded by seven youths when the video recording began.
The 14-year-old is then seen threatening the lad before he swings a punch with his right hand, causing the victim to fly onto the concrete path.
In the video the older bully is heard saying: 'Get on your f***ing knees. Touch him I'll bang you. No, don't speak to him, kiss his shoe. Now. Kiss his f***ing shoe.
'Do you want a broken jaw? Do you want a broken jaw? Get on your f***ing knees and kiss his shoe.'
The victim can be heard pleading with his attackers: 'Have I done anything?'
He now feels scared to leave the house after the incident and feels 'belittled' about being forced to kiss his attacker's shoe, the court heard.
The 14-year-old pleaded guilty to common assault and a public order offence on Tuesday and was given an 18-month youth rehabilitation order.
On the morning of the incident he had appeared at Swindon Youth Court over an incident of theft from his own sister, the court heard.
While he is on the ground he is kicked and mocked by attackers before being told to kiss one of their shoes
Wayne Hardy, defending the boy, said: 'It made him feel uncomfortable [seeing the video back], and he is very embarrassed by his actions that day.
'He is very sorry for the humiliation and harm he caused to the person subjected to the assault. What happened was a combination of bravado, peer pressure, and stupidity.
'He has to accept responsibility for his actions.'
The younger bully has already received a nine-month referral order.
Acting Sergeant Ho Tsang, who led the investigation, said: 'This incident was filmed and went viral via the internet.
'This was a particularly nasty and unprovoked attack. The way in which it was carried out was not only humiliating for the victim, but it also caused him great distress.
'It is clear that the community as a whole has been distressed by the footage of the incident, and have voiced their concerns about the matter.
'As a result, Wiltshire Police dealt with the incident and the offenders robustly.
'A positive result was achieved which resulted in these two youth offenders being charged with assault and a public order offence.
Share or comment on this article
38
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="70">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Video shows a drunk driver smash through barriers blocking Surrey tunnel
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153647/Shocking-video-shows-moment-drunk-driver-smashed-barriers-blocking-closed-tunnel-causing-road-workers-fear-lives.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Lloyd Johns, of Oxshott, Surrey, was driving at nearly double the drink drive limit when he ploughed through barrier put in place to protect workmen at the entrance to the Hindhead Tunnel.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Surrey Police has released the CCTV footage of the moment the 23-year-old's BMW crashed through barriers on the southbound carriageway at the entrance to the Hindhead Tunnel on the A3.
Highways England employees and contractors were removing cones from behind the barriers in preparation for opening the road when the accident happened at 3.53am on February 17.
A Surrey Police spokesman said: 'Johns had, despite the numerous warning signs leading up to the tunnel, overtaken an HGV and pulled back in, making no attempt to stop.
Drink driver crashes through barrier closing A3 tunnel
Johns can be seen driving towards the barrier while roadworkers in fluorescent clothing lay out traffic cones
His car crashes through the barrier, popping it up into the air, as the motorway workers run for their safety
'He then crashed through the barriers causing the road workers to fear for their safety.
'The HGV put on its hazard lights in advance of approaching the barrier, but Johns had failed to notice.'
Johns admitted under caution that he was the driver and later provided a positive breath sample of 61 microgrammes of alcohol in 100 millilitres of breath - the legal limit being 35mg.
Johns sits with his lights off as he talks to the men he so nearly hit just moments earlier
The 23-year-old's BMW crashed through barriers on the southbound carriageway at the entrance to the Hindhead Tunnel on the A3
PC Tom Richardson said: 'This was a shocking incident which fortunately didn't lead to any serious injury or loss of life, as is sadly often the case when alcohol and driving are mixed.
'Driving while over the limit is simply unacceptable and severely affects a motorist's concentration levels which puts not only the driver at danger but other motorists and on this occasion the road workers who were lucky to escape harm.'
Surrey Police recently ran an anti-drink and drug driving campaign throughout June, during which 65 people were charged, with a further 31 drivers on bail pending further enquiries.
Share or comment on this article
MOST WATCHED NEWS VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="71">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Britain's most prolific thief Robert Knowles behind bars after stealing trousers
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153632/Britain-s-prolific-thief-committed-nearly-350-offences-bars-stealing-pair-trousers-small-him.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Homeless alcoholic Robert Knowles (pictured) has now been jailed for stealing an outfit worth £158 - including the pair of ill-fitting trousers - from Marks and Spencer in Plymouth.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Career criminal: Homeless Robert Knowles, 68, pictured, has been convicted of 271 thefts
A career criminal who has been charged with theft every year since 1959 has been jailed again after stealing pair of trousers that were too small for him.
Robert Knowles, 68, has been convicted of 271 thefts - earning him the title of the nation's most prolific thief.
The homeless alcoholic  is now back behind bars after stealing an outfit worth 158 - including the pair of ill-fitting trousers - from a Marks and Spencer store in Plymouth.
When officers caught him he was wearing the clothes, which still had the security tags attached, and was moaning about the size of the trousers, a court heard.
Knowles was first sent to a correctional school in 1959 and has been back in court charged with theft every year since.
His record is so long prosecutors have lost track of his expansive rap sheet and it is believed he is now heading for nearly 350 offences.
Knowles was jailed for four months after pleading guilty to theft of the jacket and trousers from Marks and Spencer and theft of alcohol, socks and cheese worth 61 from Sainsbury's, both on May 12.
He also admitted breaching a conditional discharge imposed by Exeter magistrates only three days before for threatening criminal damage in which he threatened to smash a shop window.
Sentencing Knowles at Plymouth Crown Court, Judge Paul Darlow said his previous convictions 'smashed the previous record' for anyone else he had sentenced.
He told the defendant's barrister: 'I do not know what I should do. There can be no realistic prospect of community disposal.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="72">
        <date/>
        <title>
	War veteran with PTSD killed himself after '6 Army friends also ended their lives'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153509/War-veteran-PTSD-serving-three-tours-Afghanistan-killed-six-Army-friends-ended-lives.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Father-of-two Dylan Jones, 37, of Llansawel, Carmarthenshire, was due to marry fiancée Shan Thomas but killed himself a month before the wedding after apparently suffering post-traumatic stress.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>4.2k shares
'You are broken then, and there's no one there to fix the pieces.'
Mr Jones then spent two years working as a private bodyguard in Afghanistan after leaving the Army before starting work in October last year at his fiance's pub The Pink Geranium Hotel in Pontardawe, south Wales.
She said he was 'loved by the locals' but behind his happy exterior was a tormented soul.
She said: 'When I met him I noticed his sleeping patterns were off and his memory was terrible.
'He was very distant some days and would be thinking, thinking, thinking.
Miss Thomas, 44, said more help was needed for veterans battling to cope with the horrors they have witnessed in war zones such as Afghanistan. She said her partner suffered from post-traumatic stress
Mr Jones joined the Royal Fusiliers aged 16 and served three tours in Helmand Province before leaving the Armed Forces in 2012 but struggled to cope 'with the outside world', according to his long-term partner
'He had flashbacks of the war and would wake up screaming and sweating.
'He had started to open up to me about the war. But you wouldn't think that Dylan suffered with PTSD because he just looked like a normal person.
'I didn't know the extent of the PTSD - it's a silent killer.'
The happy couple returned from a Mediterranean cruise a fortnight before Mr Jones took his own life - and were planning another cruise following their wedding in August.
She said: 'He said he felt the happiest he had ever been.
'I thought he was getting better because he started to open up to me about stories from out there. I thought he was coping with it.'
Mr Jones leaves behind his eight-year-old twin son and daughter Malachai and Faith, his mother Gloria and sister Amanda.
TAKING THE WAR HOME WITH THEM: SOLDIERS, SUICIDE AND PTSD
More than 200,000 British Service personnel were deployed to Iraq and/or Afghanistan.
Of these troops, it was predicted 20.1 per cent would develop symptoms of PTSD or a common mental health disorder while 4 per cent would develop PTSD, according to a report by the Kings Centre for Military Health Research.
While PTSD remains a problem for veterans, the rate of those reporting experiencing symptoms is very similar to the general population, according to veterans' mental health charity Combat Stress.
The charity said symptoms of trauma can include feeling isolated; angry or aggressive behaviour; and suicidal thoughts.
Some may feel numb or empty while others might experience work-related or relationship problems. Nightmares, flashback and insomnia can also present as symptoms.
In 2013, BBC Panorama reported that more British soldiers and veterans took their own lives in 2012 than died fighting the Taliban in Afghanistan over the same period.
The programme learned that 21 serving soldiers killed themselves, along with 29 veterans.
In contrast, the death toll in Afghanistan was 44, with 40 dying in action.
Combat Stress said suicide remains a 'rare occurrence' in both UK Regulars and Veterans - and that the rate is not significantly different to the rate among the general UK population.
The charityis currently supporting more than 970 Veterans who served in Afghanistan.
Veterans, Service personnel and their families can call the Combat Stress 24-hour Helpline on 0800 138 1619 or visit www.combatstress.org.uk for more information.
For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details.
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
4.2k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="73">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Twins Tiffany and Taliah Sanderson who terrorised neighbours are given ASBOs
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153243/Double-trouble-Teenage-twin-models-terrorised-neighbours-seven-years-loud-music-swearing-given-ASBOs.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Tiffany and Taliah Sanderson, aged 19, were ordered by magistrates in Stockport not to 'generate any music or loud noise including shouting or screaming' between 8pm and 8am.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The Sanderson sisters have since moved from the family home to a flat on Stockport Road, Marple.
But it has now emerged that they have been causing problems there, too.
Denise Edwards, who works in a nearby newsagents, said: 'They've been here since about April. I believe they're moving out in three weeks because somebody has already put a complaint in.
'Their language is atrocious and the music is very loud. Luckily I go to sleep early but if I heard that music they would know about it.
'The neighbour on the other side says she can't get to sleep. There's usually those two, a Scottish girl and a couple of lads. There are always comings and goings, but always in the night. You don't hear from them in the daytime.'
Another nearby resident, who did not wish to be named, said: 'I've heard about parties. They're becoming quite well known around here and they haven't been here long.'
It comes after one disgruntled former neighbour, who did not want to be named, claimed the twins were more likely to appear on Big Brother than be properly punished.
They said: 'I have a three-year-old and seven-year-old and these twin sisters have used bad language at all hours of the day and night. I obviously don't want my kids hearing it.
Posing for the camera: The twins are both former beauty students who have since moved from the family home to a flat on Stockport Road, Marple. Tiffany is pictured left and Taliah right
Ongoing problem: The twins, Tiffany is pictured second right and Taliah far left on a night out with friends, terrorised neighbours with loud music and rowdy behaviour for seven years
The family home where 19-year-old twins Tiffany and Taliah Sanderson were said to have been living with their mother. They are believed to have moved to a flat on Stockport Road, Marple, in April
'They were also coming in at all hours of the night. The police have been called out on numerous occasions and their records will show that the girls have been going in and out late at night for many years. Now that the house is up for sale, I hope that it will come to an end.
'Unfortunately, in the crazy world we live in now, these girls will probably end up on Big Brother rather than getting the punishment they deserve.'
Other residents said they were hopeful the saga was now at an end having been brought to court.
Under their ASBOs, the Sanderson twins were instructed by the court to adhere to a number of other strict conditions.
They must not use abusive, insulting, offensive, threatening or intimidating language to neighbours or their visitors.
The pair must also not behave in a way that causes harassment, alarm or distress to anyone they do not live with.
It is thought the sisters will fight the allegations after they were backed by other neighbours.
Old antics: It has now emerged the twins have been causing problems at their new flat, too. One of their new neighbours suggested the pair may be moving out in the next three weeks. Tiffany is pictured left and right
The mother of Taliah and Tiffany Sanderson (pictured) said the allegations against her daughter were false
No problems: Another neighbour Roger Wilkson, 51, a company director, said: 'Their garden backs on to ours and weve never heard any loud noises or parties.' The girls are pictured with friends
Today there was no answer at the models' apartment in Marple. But at the family home their mother, who refused to be named, said: 'They dont live here anymore. They wont want to say anything.
'Its all false allegations. Thats all I want to say. We know who has complained.'
Another neighbour Roger Wilkson, 51, a company director, said: 'Their garden backs on to ours and weve never heard any loud noises or parties.
'I dont know where the stuff about loud music comes from. It seems there is a serial complainer who has been complaining about them.
I have a three-year-old and seven-year-old and these twin sisters have used bad language at all hours of the day and night
An unnamed neighbour
'The family had lived here for about eight years and as far as Im concerned there hasnt been a problem. We have had complaints about our dogs barking and building a chimney and they are completely unfounded too.'
Another neighbour Claire Jackson said: 'The family have never really bothered us. Ive heard a bit of noise every now and again but never complained because its never been a big thing.
'I have three young children and theyve never been woken up. The girls seem alright. We smile at them and say hello to their mother. Theyre typical teens.
'Ive heard arguments every now and again and a bit of bad language but nothing out of the ordinary that would make me complain.'
The neighbour who is thought to have complained about the girls refused to give his name but said: 'Its an ongoing court case, I will comment when its finished. That will be in August. I dont want to comment while its ongoing.
'This is a nice quiet area. Apparently its the quietest in the Greater Manchester police area. You wouldnt expect whats happened, would you? We have young kids here. Would anybody want that?'
Inspector Jim Lockett, from Stockport east area neighbourhood police, said his officers had been called to the address in the early hours for incidents often involving loud music.
Modelling career: The Sanderson sisters (pictured is Taliah) are both former Stockport College beauty and make up media students and are on the books of Boss Model Management in Manchester
Unhappy: Residents on Windlehurst Road, High Lane (pictured), who lived close to the twins at their family home, have repeatedly complained about the sisters' rowdy behaviour to the police
He said: 'There is some kind of neighbour dispute between twin sisters at one address and a person at another.
'Staff have been made aware that there have been incidents at the location and we may be called there again.
'If we are and there is an anti-social behaviour order in place we would be looking at making arrests.'
The Sanderson sisters are both former Stockport College beauty and make up media students and are on the books of Boss Model Management in Manchester.
Both have online portfolios with a string of glamorous shots.
A council spokesman said: 'After a number of complaints of anti-social behaviour, we took legal action against Tiffany and Taliah Sanderson.
'This interim ASBO bans them from harassing people, including using insulting, offensive or threatening language.
'We are very pleased it has been awarded. Their victims have suffered from their actions and we want to see that end.'
Share or comment on this article
487
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="74">
        <date/>
        <title>
	James South choked to death after student nurse fed him sausage and mash 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153405/Nil-mouth-patient-choked-death-student-nurse-fed-sausage-mash.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	James South (pictured), from Aviemore, Scotland, was being fed via a tube through his nose and had a deliberately obvious sign where he lay warning ward staff that he shouldn't be served solid food.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>It was the student nurse who fed him the meal's first day on the ward.
A staff nurse, who was aware of Mr South's limitation, was assigned to oversee her.
'However the staff nurse became severely unwell and another staff nurse was assigned,' Mr Mayne told the court.
'An auxiliary, who had attended the handover but was unaware that Mr South was nil by mouth, asked him what he wanted [to eat] and she completed the menu card for him.'
Mr Mayne said the Health and Safety Executive concluded that NHS Highland had not effectively managed the risk to patients with dietary requirements and did not have an effective system in place for communicating the nil by mouth status of Mr South.
An auxiliary nurse helped Mr South fill out his lunch menu and a student nurse served him, soup and sausages and mashed potato (stock photograph) - followed by ice cream
The region's health board - NHS Highland - was fined 40,000 for the fatal blunder, which happened at Raigmore Hospital, Inverness
NHS Highland admitted a breach of Health and Safety.
Defence counsel Peter Gray QC said: 'This was an isolated failure at operational level. The failing relates to one ward in one hospital on one day.
'It is not a systematic failure and the organisation has no previous convictions.
'But it is accepted had the system which was in place been robustly applied on that day, the death would not have occurred.'
Had the system which was in place been robustly applied on that day, the death would not have occurred.
Defence counsel Peter Gray QC
Sheriff Margaret Neilson said: 'The penalty imposed is not meant to measure the value of someone's life. A significant financial penalty is appropriate here. A death has occurred due to a public body's failure, but I note that it has taken steps to rectify the failings. This was a tragic but isolated incident.'
Outside the court, Mr South's mother Sandra South told the BBC : 'I do not bear any grudges and want to say that the care he received in intensive care was wonderful.
'However, I wouldn't like to comment on what I think about ward 11.'
Dr Rod Harvey, Board Medical Director for NHS Highland, said: 'On behalf of NHS Highland I firstly want to acknowledge that this has been a tragic incident for the family.
'The systems we had in place were not consistently good enough and had they been more effective this death could have been avoided. This is something we deeply regret and for which we apologise unreservedly to the family.
'It is also important to emphasise that we have taken this extremely seriously from the outset. We carried out an immediate investigation, and reported the case to the Procurator Fiscal and Health and Safety Executive. We have fully cooperated with the investigation including making a plea of guilty at the earliest opportunity.'
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
274
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="75">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Richard Dickenson who blew up his home to get back at estranged wife is jailed
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3153348/Man-blew-home-estranged-wife-jailed-six-years.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Garage manager Richard Dickenson, 47, doused his one-bedroom bungalow in Leeds, West Yorkshire, with petrol before torching the property. The blaze created a explosion which tore the roof off.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The prosecution's case was that Dickenson had deliberately stored up to 12 gallons of petrol in the property and had moved his prized Harley Davidson motorbike and BMW sports car out of harm's way before starting the blaze.
During the hearing Dickenson disputed the claim. He said he had become stressed at work and was upset due to his wife being in poor health.
He said she had moved out of their home before the incident and her family were not talking to him.
Explosion: The garage manager doused his one-bedroom bungalow with petrol before torching the property.The blaze created an explosion which tore the roof off the property (pictured)
Damage: Six other properties had to be evacuated during the incident which was attended by 45 firefighters on May 28 last year. The scale of the damage done toDickenson's home in Leeds, West Yorkshire, is pictured
He told Leeds Crown Court: 'I just snapped, I was crying my eyes out. It was just one thing after another going wrong.'
Dickenson insisted that he only had three gallons of petrol in the property and didn't think he would place his neighbours in danger.
He said: 'I lit the paper and threw it onto the sofa. I sat down and watched the flames. I don't know how long for. It might have been only for a few seconds.
'Then there was this almighty bang.'
Sentencing Dickenson, Judge Cahill said she concluded that it was a planned act of revenge more than a momentary reaction.
She said she believed Dickenson had been upset at the situation he found himself in but at the same time he had relationships with two other women and his upset was more self pity.
Blown off: Eye-witnesses said they saw 10ft-high flames on the roof, which was destroyed (pictured), and fire crews from across West Yorkshire were called in to help control the blaze
Neighbour, Amanda Swift, 43, said: 'I was driving down the road at about half nine when I just heard this big bang, and saw these huge flames, and smoke everywhere. The roof had been blown off, it was horrific'
She added: 'This was a deliberately planned act for his wife and children turning their backs on him. I do not accept that he intended to kill himself.'
John Batchelor, mitigating, said Dickenson was 'emotionally volatile' at the time of the incident.
Detective Inspector Sean Duggan, of Leeds District CID, said: 'Dickenson's actions in deliberately starting a fire at his home caused an explosion which could have had far more serious consequences for people in proximity of his address.
'As it was, he was the only person who was injured.
'The incident required a significant response from the emergency services and Dickenson had to be rescued from the property by firefighters.
'It also caused understandable concern among local residents.
You are a manipulative and self-centred man who has little regard for the feelings of others
Judge Sally Cahill QC
'Arson is rightly treated as a very serious crime and the sentence he has received should remind people of the consequences of potentially lethal behaviour like this.'
Eye-witnesses said they saw 10ft-high flames on the roof, which was destroyed, and fire crews from across West Yorkshire were called in to help control the blaze.
Next-door neighbours Joyce and Barry Bedford heard the blast as they were sat watching television.
Mr Bedford said: 'I grabbed Joyce and pulled her out of the house and into the street where we could see huge flames and smoke everywhere.
'Everyone was out in the street, calling the fire brigade, looking to see what was going on.
'The roof tiles were all over the place, it was smoky and black and there were massive flames.'
Neighbour, Amanda Swift, 43, said: 'I was driving down the road at about half nine when I just heard this big bang, and saw these huge flames, and smoke everywhere.
'The roof had been blown off, it was horrific.'
Share or comment on this article
60
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="76">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Boy with Aplastic Anaemia will be saved by sister with donated stem cells
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3153295/The-life-saving-little-sister-Heroic-four-year-old-set-save-big-brother-s-life-donating-stem-cells-treat-rare-blood-disorder.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Scott Anderson, six, from  Newcastle, suffers from Aplastic Anaemia, a rare illness which means his bone marrow is not making red blood cells, leaving him at risk of catching killer infections at any time.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>The life-saving little sister: Heroic four-year-old is set to save her big brother's life by donating her stem cells to help treat his rare blood disorder
Scott Anderson was diagnosed with Aplastic Anaemia in May
Condition means his bone marrow is not producing red blood cells and he is in danger of catching an infection that could kill him at any time
Was desperately in need of a stem cell transplant to save his life
Tests found his sister Courtney, 4, was the perfect match, and now the pair will go into hospital in August for the life-saving operation
Published: 10:22 GMT, 8 July 2015 | Updated: 11:16 GMT, 8 July 2015
190 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="77">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Clarifications and corrections for extremism on university campuses graphic
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/home/article-3146759/Clarifications-corrections.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	To report an inaccuracy, please email corrections@dailymail.co.uk. To make a formal complaint under IPSO rules please go to www.dailymail.co.uk/readerseditor.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>By Daily Mail Reporter
Published: 02:53 GMT, 2 July 2015 | Updated: 03:18 GMT, 2 July 2015
The headline on a graphic which accompanied a report about extremism on university campuses in yesterdays paper wrongly stated that the individuals listed had spoken at the academic institutions concerned. In fact they attended them.

To report an inaccuracy, please email corrections@dailymail.co.uk. To make a formal complaint under IPSO rules please go to www.dailymail.co.uk/readerseditor where you will find an easy-to-use complaints form. You can also write to Readers Editor, Daily Mail, Northcliffe House, 2 Derry Street, London W8 5TT.
Share or comment on this article
933
Sorry we are not currently accepting comments on this article.
Bing
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
