<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="express">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece tables economic reforms to European leaders in last ditch attempt to get new loan</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/N5PqxWPmdDY/Greece-EU-loan-economic-reforms</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greece tables economic reforms to European leaders in last ditch attempt to get new loan
Greece tables economic reforms to European leaders in last ditch attempt to get new loan
GREECE has tonight submitted a plan for wide-reaching economic reforms to European leaders which are thought to include a radical shake-up of taxes and pensions.
PUBLISHED: 22:18, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:24, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
EPA
Greece have submitted a last ditch attempt to get a new loan from the EU
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras looks ready to cave in to pressure from the EU, with huge tax hikes and swingeing cuts to pensions apparently on the table as part of a package designed to slash 13billion of public spending.
The proposals would effectively amount to a return to austerity for Greece, and the left-wing leader may have trouble getting them past his own party tomorrow morning.
They are a last-ditch attempt by the Greek government to convince eurozone leaders to authorise new loans for the country, without which its banking system will collapse.
Greece would have to default on its debts and would almost certainly crash out of the single currency, sparking a Europe-wide financial crisis.
Greek MPs will debate the package at a special meeting of parliament tomorrow, with Mr Tsipras expected to face harsh criticism after the Greek people overwhelming voted to reject austerity in Sunday's referendum.
However, it has already been submitted to the leader of the Eurogroup, Jeroen Dijsselbloem, after he imposed a deadline of 9pm tonight.
REUTERS
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras looks ready to cave in to pressure from the EU
I have the sense that the dialogue is established, or restored, and that there is a way out
European Monetary and Economic Affairs Commissioner Pierre Moscovici
Media outlets in Athens were tonight reporting that the proposals include huge rises in VAT, with tourist-reliant businesses like restaurants set to be the worst hit.
More controversially still for the Greeks, it could include radical changes to the country's lavish pensions system including financial penalties for early retirement.
The plans will go before a scrutiny session at the European Stability Mechanism (ESM), which will be responsible for administering any new finance for Greece, tomorrow.
They will be evaluated and then passed on to Eurozone finance ministers, who will meet on Saturday.
Finally, the fully scrutinised plans will be put before all 28 European Union (EU) leaders at a crunch do-or-die summit in Brussels on Sunday.
In return for the concessions, Mr Tsipras will expect European leaders to agree on a significant restructuring of Greece's debt.
REUTERS
The proposals would effectively amount to a return to austerity for Greece
He hopes they will agree to reduce the amount of interest the country is paying on its outstanding loans, meaning his government can ease off on the savage programme of austerity imposed by its international creditors.
A deal seemed more likely tonight after Donald Tusk, the president of the European Council, conceded debt restructuring should be part of Sunday's negotiation.
He said that a realistic proposal from Greece will have to be matched by an equally realistic proposal on debt sustainability from the creditors.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boko Haram kidnap girls: New hope for 200 hostages who sparked global Twitter campaign</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/IkqNvUE5h2M/boko-haram-kidnapping-girls-twitter-michelle-obama-nigeria</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Boko Haram kidnap girls: New hope for 200 hostages who sparked global Twitter campaign
Boko Haram kidnap girls: New hope for 200 hostages who sparked global Twitter campaign
ISLAMIST fanatics have offered to free more than 200 Nigerian schoolgirl hostages in return for the release of 16 militant leaders.
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:05, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
GETTY
Thousands of activists have campaigned for the girls to be brought home safely
Boko Harams proposal could end the mass-kidnapping outrage that sparked the global Bring Back Our Girls Twitter campaign supported by more than five million people including Americas First Lady Michelle Obama.
The ISIS affiliate wants 16 of their senior fighters handed over in return for the 219 girls taken from a boarding school in the north-east 11 months ago.
Details have emerged through a human rights activist, Fred Eno, who has been negotiating with the militant leaders for more than a year.
Mr Eno said the fresh hopes follow the election of Nigerias new leader, President Muhammadu Buhari, five weeks ago.
He said relations had broken down with his predecessor, Goodluck Jonathan, but Mr Buhari could approach Boko Haram with a clean slate.
GETTY
Boko Haram kidnapped hundreds of girls and has shattered cities in Nigeria
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece crisis: Athens desperate for 11th hour deal as banks face running out of cash </title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/dQGS4BFk_xY/greece-crisis-european-union-finance-markets</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greece crisis: Athens desperate for 11th hour deal as banks face running out of cash
Greece crisis: Athens desperate for 11th hour deal as banks face running out of cash
GREECE is tonight racing to meet a midnight deadline to submit reform plans for an international bailout to prevent it from crashing out of the eurozone.
PUBLISHED: 18:24, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:25, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
GETTY
Greek banks are likely to run out of cash
If Athens submits its proposals on time they will be examined by the European Commission, the European Central Bank and IMF.
A final decision on Greeces future is expected to be made at an emergency summit of the EUs 28 leaders, including David Cameron, on Sunday.
It is feared that Greek Banks, which have been closed for a week, could start to run out of money on Monday.
Greeces calls for its debt to be tackled have been backed by the International Monetary Fund and US Treasury Secretary, but Germany leads a hardline group of eurozone nations that are strongly opposed.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said that the next hours will be crucial.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WATCH: RAF Reaper drone blasts ISIS armoured truck with Hellfire missile</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/cTOy0UvcFYw/WATCH-RAF-Reaper-drone-blasts-ISIS-armoured-truck-with-Hellfire-missile</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WATCH: RAF Reaper drone blasts ISIS armoured truck with Hellfire missile
WATCH: RAF Reaper drone blasts ISIS armoured truck with Hellfire missile
THIS is the moment a Reaper drone tracks an Islamic State (ISIS) armoured vehicle before launching a Hellfire missile at it to devastating effect.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 19:16, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
The dramatic video begins with the ISIS truck driving along a dusty road in Iraq.
Jihadis then try to hide it under a palm grove and a man is seen leaving the vehicle before fleeing the area.
A Hellfire missile is then launched from the unmanned plane. In a split-second the armoured truck explodes in a ball of flames before smoke engulfs the air.
The Ministry of Defence (MoD), which released the video that was shot on Monday, said the armoured pick-up truck had been converted to a large car bomb.
MOD
The ISIS truck was blasted by the Hellfire missile
GETTY
A Reaper drone pictured flying in Nevada, US
It was parked in a position where it would hamper Iraqi troops movements.
Reaper drones have regularly been used in the Middle East to fight ISIS.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British nationals told to LEAVE Tunisia over fears of ANOTHER terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/jhP1M1Z2VEY/British-nationals-told-to-LEAVE-Tunisia-over-fears-of-more-terror-attacks</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FCO
Brits have been told to avoid all parts of Tunisia unless travelling is absolutely necessary
Thomas Cook has revealed it has cancelled all future Tunisia bookings up until the end of October in light of the Mr Hammond's decision.
It was also sending teams to north Africa to help people back.
A spokeswoman said: "In response to the recent change in FCO advice we have taken this decision to bring all Thomas Cook customers back to the UK as soon as we can using third party carriers and on our 10 scheduled flights over the weekend.
"Thomas Cook is strongly advising its guests in the country to return on these flights.
"We are also sending our Specialist Assistance Teams to Tunisia to offer customers additional support in resort."
Those who have friends of family in the country can call Thomas Cook on 01733 224 536.
TUI, which owns Thomson and First Choice, said it had no customers currently in Tunisia but said it was working to bring back staff in the region "within the next 24 hours".
It is also cancelling travel to the country until October 31.
Monarch Airlines said it was in the process of bringing all customers back to the UK. It is also cancelling all flights to the Tunisian airport of Einfidha for the rest of the summer season.
The UK Government warning came just hours after the Tunisian president warned the country was on the bring of collapse.
Beji Caid Essebi declared a state of emergency and said there was a "continued threat".
Most Read Stories in World
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PICTURED: Inside Putin's new £3.8bn cosmodrome as he plans permanent base on the MOON</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/O2Ijf1A5adM/Russia-s-new-space-station-See-what-s-inside-Vladimir-Putin-s-3-8bn-cosmodrome</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>PICTURED: Inside Putin's new 3.8bn cosmodrome as he plans permanent base on the MOON
PICTURED: Inside Putin's new 3.8bn cosmodrome as he plans permanent base on the MOON
THESE startling photos show Russia's huge 3.8billion cosmodrome taking shape - as Vladimir Putin's frightening plan progresses to build a permanent base on THE MOON.
PUBLISHED: 16:53, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 17:09, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
SIBERIANTIMES
The Russian space station is on the eastern side of Siberia
The development is the leader's pet project and is poised to be as famous as the Cape Canaveral or Baikonur - the US and Soviet launch sites which were at the centre of the Cold War space race.
Putin wants the first unmanned launch at the space station to take place before December with the ultimate aim of having a constant presence on the Moon and getting astronauts to Mars.
The construction has been besieged by delays but these images show the development taking place at the site in the eastern side of Siberia.
So desperate is Putin to meet that deadline that 1,000 students have been drafted in to get the spaceport ready and CCTV cameras are being used to spy on workers to make sure they are pulling their weight.
SIBERIATIMES
Putin's cosmodrome is part of a larger plan to have a base on the Moon
The Siberian Times wrote of the huge scheme: "Some 10,000 workers are constructing the complex which includes 71 miles of roads and 76 miles of railways.
"The plans include a town with housing for 25,000 people."
Workmen told Putin they were four months behind in salary payments, while his minister in charge of the project, Dmitry Rogozin, threatened to "rip the heads off" embezzlers after a spate of corruption claims.
He has installed CCTV cameras around the mammoth building site, warning workers: "Layabouts who barely walk about the building site should be aware that they are watched."
Igor Marinin, editor of Space News magazine, said some corruption by workers in the development was almost inevitable but he believes construction targets will be met.
He said: "When there's a construction project and a lot of money is allocated, then there are major violations in how this money is used.
"The same goes for any construction project.
"The launch is set for December.
"I think that's realistic. Naturally, they'll be doing a lot of work to finish off what didn't get done on time."
The site is designed for the new Angara rocket, due to replace the ageing Proton workhorse in the coming years.
The cosmodrome, known as Vostochny, is seen as a money-earner for the Kremlin and it has already won contracts from a British project.
Between 650 and 720 microsatellites built by the UK's OneWeb, will be launched in Russia, with some blasting off into orbit from the new facility.
The deal is said to be worth up to 1.3bn in a major boost to the cash-strapped Russian space industry.
SIBERIATIMES
Workers are being watched using CCTV cameras installed at the site
SIBERIANTIMES
Putin wants the first unmanned fights to take off in December
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:54:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spend Spend Spend! Greeks go on buying binge amid fears EU will order bank account raid</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/46a64eQP9XY/Greek-debt-crisis-spending-binge-EU-bank-account-raid</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Spend Spend Spend! Greeks go on buying binge amid fears EU will order bank account raid
Spend Spend Spend! Greeks go on buying binge amid fears EU will order bank account raid
WEALTHY Greeks have gone on a buying binge amid fears cash will dry up if the cash-strapped country's Government is forced to dip into their personal bank accounts to help pay the national debt.
PUBLISHED: 13:54, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 14:09, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
GETTY
Greeks go on a buying binge
Sales of jewellery, computers and electrical goods stores have rocketed in the lead up to and following the historic 'No' vote in the Greek referendum on a European bailout deal on Sunday.
This spending spree has been sparked by Greeks' fears the EU will now force their Government to impose a "haircut" on their bank accounts, taking a percentage of depositors savings as a one-off tax - similar to conditions imposed on Cyprus following their own debt crisis in 2013.
And as Greeks embark on a luxury blowout, one shop assistant likened it to "Christmas".
Andrew, 30, who works at a electronic shop in Syntagma Square, said:" Thursday, Friday and Saturday were like Christmas.
"People are afraid that the bank will take their money and they came out to spend it ahead of the EU finance meeting in Brussels [on Tuesday].
"People are very scared. The majority thought they had three days to spend their money before the bank was forced to hand it over to the government.
"We sold almost twice as much as usual... People were buying laptops, PCs, tablets, iPhones, that was all.'
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Holiday warning: Britons flocking to sun in Spain at HIGH risk of ISIS attack</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/aLJUpK2HtKI/Spain-terror-alert-Islamic-State-ISIS-attacks-Britain-warning</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Holiday warning: Britons flocking to sun in Spain at HIGH risk of ISIS attack
Holiday warning: Britons flocking to sun in Spain at HIGH risk of ISIS attack
SPAIN is facing its highest level of terror threat for more than 10 YEARS - with sun-seeking Britons at serious risk of being attacked by Islamic State (ISIS) extremists, governments have warned.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 15:01, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
GETTY  IG
Holidaymakers heading to Spain could be at risk of terror attacks
Around 12 million Britons flock to Spain each year to soak up the sun in popular destinations including Ibiza, Majorca, Barcelona and the Costa Del Sol.
But UK holidaymakers have now been warned that they could be "high value" targets for terror attacks.
The Foreign Office (FCO) raised the terror threat level in Spain to "high" in June - before the Tunisia beach massacre which saw 30 Britons gunned down and killed on the popular resort of Sousse.
The terror threat was raised after security forces in Spain disrupted a number of groups who were recruiting people to join extremists in Syria and Iraq.
It is also believed by the Spanish government that they were plotting deadly attacks across Europe.
GETTY
Spain was targeted by an al-Qaida-linked cell in 2004
The FCO said on their website: "There is a high threat from terrorism. Attacks could be indiscriminate, including in places visited by foreigners."
And a spokesman added: "The situation in Iraq and Syria means there is considered to be a heightened threat of terrorist attack globally against UK interests and British nationals, from groups or individuals motivated by the conflict."
Spanish Interior Minister Jorge Fernandez Diaz warned last week that the country faces its highest level of terror threat since the 2004 train bombing in Madrid.
We are at the maximum alert level since the attacks of March 11, 2004, in Madrid
Spanish Interior Minister Jorge Fernandez Diaz
A total of 191 people were killed and nearly 2,000 injured when a series of bombs were detonated on four commuter trains.
An official investigation into the incident determined that the attacks were directed by an al-Qaeda-inspired terror cell.
Mr Fernandez Diaz said: "We are at the maximum alert level since the attacks of March 11, 2004, in Madrid."
He added that the "level 4 alert [out of a maximum of 5] corresponds to a reality".
The raised terror threat in Spain has come following a year of ISIS attacks across Europe - including neighbouring France.
More than 12 people were killed earlier this year by Islamist gunmen who had stormed the office of satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo in Paris.
Then last month a man was beheaded and his head impaled on a spiked fence near Lyon by an ISIS fanatic.
More than 110 people have fled Spain to fight alongside ISIS in Syria and Iraq over the past year.
GOV.UK
The travel advice for Spain on the Foreign Office website
Last year a group of extremists claiming to be associated to ISIS vowed to invade Spain.
One said, in a video posted online: "I tell you, Spain is the land of our forefathers, and, Allah willing, we are going to liberate it, with the might of Allah.
"I say to the entire world as a warning: We are living under the Islamic banner, the Islamic Caliphate.
"We are going to die for it until we liberate all the occupied lands, from Jakarta to Andalusia."
Other popular holiday hotspots that currently face a high risk of terror threats include France, Tunisia, Turkey and Egypt.
A number of destinations are also on a general threat level, including Greece, Italy and Morocco.
Holidaymakers deciding where to take their next break have been urged to follow a set of guidelines when assessing any risks for their intended destination this summer.
Britons have been told by HolidayTravelWatch to research the current state of affairs of your destination, as well taking a virtual Google Maps tour of any hotels and resorts.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Roman Abramovich's 10billion dog walkers club </title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/SeUfwwPiFnI/Roman-Abramovich-millionaires-Russian-oligarchs-corgis</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Roman Abramovich's 10billion dog walkers club
Roman Abramovich's 10billion dog walkers club
THEY'RE among the worlds wealthiest men accompanying Roman Abramovich on his Scottish holiday but to look at them you would never know it.
PUBLISHED: 12:11, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 12:46, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
SWNS
Despite their dishevelled appearance, these are some of the worlds most powerful men
If your owner regularly appears on the Worlds Richest list that gives a dog certain privileges.
The Queen is famously devoted to her corgis (currently down to two from past high points of eight) but even she doesnt insist on her dogs being taken for walks by people of equal financial status.
Its different if youre the much loved pet of a Russian oligarch. When multibillionaire Roman Abramovich took his corgi for a walk on the Isle of Arran it was assumed that his five toughlooking escorts were bodyguards. In fact they are five of his closest (and richest) friends holidaying with the 48-year-old owner of Chelsea football club on his cruise around the Scottish islands.
Despite looking as if theyd dressed in the dark in clothes from a budget supermarket not one of them is worth less than half a billion and their combined worth adds up to a jaw-dropping 10billion. Though they seem to favour simple pursuits such as walk ing and cycling when they call at remote spots, aboard the 557 ft Eclipse (the worlds biggest yacht when built in 2010) all is ultra-luxurious with swimming pools, hot tubs and a cinema.
So who are these mega-rich dogwalkers?
From left to right:
Evgeny Shvidler
The son of two mathematicians, Shvidler, 51, is Abramovichs best friend and chairman of his investment company Millhouse LLC.
When the Russian oil industry was privatised in the 1990s Shvidler and Abramovich founded oil-trading company Runicom.
In 1995 they bought oil company Sibneft and three years later Shvidler became president. For most of his tenure Sibneft was the most profitable oil company in Russia.
It was sold in 2005 for 7.36 billion. He owns a 22million house in Belgravia , an estate in Cobham, Surrey, a chalet in Aspen, Colorado and a French chateau with a vineyard which he bought in 2001 because he had enjoyed a wine-tasting trip so much the year before. He also has a private jet and his yacht le Grand Bleu was a present from Abramovich .
For his 45th birthday Abramovich gave him a flock of sheep. Shvidler is married to Zara and has five children aged eight to 19.
Worth: 1.6billion
Alexey Polezhaev
His father Leonid was formerly governor of the Omsk region of Russia and Alexey advised Abramovich when the latter was governor of the Chukotka region.
The 10,000-seater Omsk Arena, costing 50million, was a gift from Abramovich to the Avangard hockey team. It is believed Polezhaev made his fortune from gas and oil.
Worth: 1billion
David Davidovich
As project manager of Millhouse LLC the 52-year-old father of two is one of Abramovichs most trusted right-hand men.
He trained as an electrician and engineer and first worked with Abramovich when he joined Runicom in 1995 and later became one of the main oil traders at Sibneft.
In 2000 he became deputy head of Russky Aluminy, buying aluminium refineries. He is a shareholder in Millhouse and in 2010 he bought Chukotka coal mines from Abramovich, later selling them to Kinross Gold. Since 2004 he has owned Prodo, the second biggest meat processing company in Russia, which he bought from Abramovich.
Worth: 1billion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oops! Greek finance minister reveals secret negotiating strategy.. scrawled on notepad</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/C2uFf7TQtuU/Greece-debt-crisis-finance-minister-notepad-secret-negotiating-strategy</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Curiosity abounds as to the word obscured by the minister's thumb in the statement "mostly I _ on viability grounds".
Mr Tsakalotos' slip up comes after he replaced the country's former finance minister Yanis Varoufakis on Monday.
His departure was an effort to help Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras reach a deal, the controversial politician had riled euro leaders with his outspoken views during previous talks and is thought to have been a barrier to finding an agreement.
However Mr Tsakalotos now faces ridicule, with some branding it a "schoolboy error", as he revealed his secret negotiating strategy to the the world as the media assembled in Brussels.
And although he is Greek's Finance Minister, Mr Tsakalotos is said to speak English mch better than Greek as he was born in the Netherlands, raised in Britain, and educated at the same elite London school that Chancellor George Osborne attended, St Paul's School.
REUTERS
Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos attends a euro zone finance ministers meeting
Mr Tsakalotos also attended Oxford University, where he studied Philosophy, Politics and Economics at Queen's College and later completed a masters at the University of Sussex's Institute of Development Studies and a doctorate at Oxford under Polish Communist economist Wlodsimierz Brus.
This comes as Greece caved into demands to slash its lavish state pensions and begin collecting taxes last night in a desperate last-ditch attempt to stay in the euro.
Mr Tsipras promised to rush through emergency legislation meaning wide-reaching reforms could be in place by next week.
The last-minute plea could be enough to convince European leaders to authorise a three-year loan, which could stop the country defaulting on its debts and crashing out of the eurozone.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
