<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:36:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Yemen al-Qaida leader says United States remains his group's only rival</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/kheEheQIAGw/</Link>
        <Description>The new leader of Yemen's al-Qaida branch says his group's main enemy remains the United States and is urging Sunni militants to keep up their war against America, which he claims is "reeling" from terror attacks.</Description>
        <MainBody>New Yemen al-Qaida leader says United States remains his group's only rival
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
CAIRO  The new leader of Yemen's al-Qaida branch says his group's main enemy remains the United States and is urging Sunni militants to keep up their war against America, which he claims is "reeling" from terror attacks.
Qassim al-Raimi assumed the leadership of Al-Qaida in the Arabian Peninsula after a U.S. airstrike last month killed his predecessor, Nasir al-Wahishi, who was also the global terror network's second-most important figure.
In an audio message Thursday on social media, al-Raimi eulogized his predecessor, saying al-Wahishi got his wish to die fighting. The recording was posted by the AQAP's media arm.
Al-Raimi, who previously was the Yemeni branch's military commander, praised al-Qaida affiliates' recent victories in Syria and elsewhere.
Yemen's al-Qaida branch is widely seen as al-Qaida's most dangerous offshoot.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:02:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guatemala arrests the son-in-law of President Perez Molina for alleged influence trafficking</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/GMf_Vx0hMbc/</Link>
        <Description>Authorities in Guatemala have arrested the son-in-law of President Otto Perez Molina for alleged influence trafficking.</Description>
        <MainBody>Guatemala arrests the son-in-law of President Perez Molina for alleged influence trafficking
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
GUATEMALA CITY  Authorities in Guatemala have arrested the son-in-law of President Otto Perez Molina for alleged influence trafficking.
The arrest of Gustavo Martinez was announced Thursday. He had served until April as Perez Molina's private secretary.
Martinez was arrested based on investigations by the federal prosecutors' office and the U.N. International Commission Against Impunity in Guatemala.
Prosecutors say several arrests have been made in the scandal, which involves bribes and influence trafficking aimed at favoring a private power generation company.
Perez Molina's vice president, Roxana Baldetti, was forced to resign over a customs scandal involving kickbacks for lower import duties. The corruption ring was allegedly headed by her private secretary and no charges have been filed against the former vice president.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:41:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>T.B. Joshua's church rejects coroner's call for prosecution; building collapse killed 116</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/f7f3sJXSlq4/</Link>
        <Description>The Synagogue Church of All Nations of Nigerian televangelist T.</Description>
        <MainBody>T.B. Joshua's church rejects coroner's call for prosecution; building collapse killed 116
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
FILE - In this Wednesday, Sept. 17, 2014 file photo, rescue workers search for survivors in the rubble of a collapsed building belonging to the Synagogue Church of All Nations in Lagos, Nigeria. The Synagogue Church of All Nations of televangelist T. B. Joshua on Thursday, July 9, 2015 rejected a coroners report recommending prosecution of the Nigerian church and two structural engineers in the collapse of a church building that killed 116 people, most of them visitors from South Africa. (AP Photo/Sunday Alamba, File)(The Associated Press)
LAGOS, Nigeria  The Synagogue Church of All Nations of Nigerian televangelist T. B. Joshua is rejecting a coroner's report recommending prosecution of the church and two structural engineers in the collapse of a church building that killed 116 people in September.
A statement calls the report "unreasonable" and "biased."
Coroner Oyetade Komolafe on Wednesday said the building collapsed because of "structural failure."
Eighty-five South Africans were among the victims of the tragedy that soured relations between the two countries.
The church said Thursday it maintains the collapse in Lagos was caused by the overflight of a plane possibly connected to Islamic extremists.
The coroner has recommended prosecution for "criminal negligence" for the engineers, and that the church be prosecuted for its failure to obtain building permits.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:25:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis changes in Burger King before Mass in Bolivia </title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/0-lSqTk8KZQ/</Link>
        <Description>Burger King has long been providing quick meals. Pope Francis has now used it for a quick change.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis changes in Burger King before Mass in Bolivia
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Pope Francis is shown in this AP photo.(Associated Press)
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia  Burger King has long been providing quick meals. Pope Francis has now used it for a quick change.
With hundreds of thousands of Catholic faithful waiting, Pope Francis needed a place to don his vestments to celebrate Mass at the Christ the Redeemer square in Santa Cruz. He had just spent more than 30 minutes in his popemobile waving to thousands lined up on the streets as he drove to the square for the service.
Enter the restaurant known for Whoppers and fries.
The famously unpretentious pope used the fast food joint, which was closed for the morning for the papal visit, before walking to the nearby altar and beginning the Mass.
Alfredo Troche, manager of the Burger King, said the papal entourage approached the restaurant and "asked for help because this was an appropriate place and we had closed" to customers.
Minutes later, during his homily, Francis blasted consumerism. He said that by materialistic logic, everything becomes an object that can be consumed and negotiated.
The company wasted no time in letting the world know of the papal visit. Even before Mass had ended, the restaurant put a post on Facebook thanking the pope "for choosing the BK restaurant as your sacristy."
It also included an advertisement-like image showing the pope beneath a Burger King logo and the words: "There are visits that don't just bring joy to your spirit, but also feed it."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:00:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vatican: "Communist crucifix" given to pope by Morales is a symbol of dialogue, not ideology</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/YvdizP-v5ng/</Link>
        <Description>Bolivian President Evo Morales' controversial gift of a "Communist crucifix" to Pope Francis threatened to overshadow the pope's visit to Bolivia on Thursday, with the Vatican and Bolivia both insisting that no offense was intended or taken.</Description>
        <MainBody>Vatican: "Communist crucifix" given to pope by Morales is a symbol of dialogue, not ideology
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia  Bolivian President Evo Morales' controversial gift of a "Communist crucifix" to Pope Francis threatened to overshadow the pope's visit to Bolivia on Thursday, with the Vatican and Bolivia both insisting that no offense was intended or taken.
Morales gave Francis the crucifix carved into a hammer and sickle upon Francis' arrival in Bolivia Wednesday, immediately raising eyebrows given Morales' past attacks on the church and his socialist bent.
It turns out, the crucifix was originally designed by a Jesuit activist, the Rev. Luis Espinal, who was assassinated in 1980 by suspected paramilitaries during the months that preceded a military coup. Francis, a fellow Jesuit, stopped his motorcade to pray at the site where Espinal's body had been dumped.
The Vatican spokesman, the Rev. Federico Lombardi, said Thursday the pope had no idea that Espinal had designed the crucifix and was surprised to receive it  a reaction clearly visible in the footage of the encounter. Some reports suggested the pope told Morales "This isn't good;" one of Francis' friends sent a tweet quoting him as saying such. But Lombardi said it wasn't known what the pope had said.
Lombardi said Espinal had designed the crucifix as a symbol of dialogue and commitment to freedom and progress for Bolivia, not with any specific ideology in mind. Lombardi said he personally wasn't offended by it.
"You can dispute the significance and use of the symbol now, but the origin is from Espinal and the sense of it was about an open dialogue, not about a specific ideology," Lombardi said.
He noted the context in which Espinal was living: as a priest working for social justice in Bolivia during a period of instability that preceded a right-wing dictatorship known for human rights abuses.
However, one of Espinal's friends and fellow Jesuits, the Rev. Xavier Albo, said Espinal's intent was for the church to be in dialogue with Marxism, and said Espinal had altered his crucifix to incorporate the Communists' most potent symbol: the hammer and sickle.
"In this he clearly wanted to speak about the need to permanently dialogue not just with Marxism but with peasants and miners etc.," Albo told The Associated Press earlier this month.
The Vatican launched a harsh crackdown on Liberation Theology in the 1970s and 1980s, fearing that Marxists were using its "preferential option for the poor" to turn the Gospel into a call for armed revolution.
The Bolivian government insisted the gift wasn't a political maneuver of any sort, but was a symbol that Morales thought the "pope of the poor" would appreciate.
"That was the intention of this gift, and it was not any sort of maneuver ... It was really from great affection, a work designed by the very hands of Luis Espinal," Communications Minister Marianela Paco told the Patria Nueva radio station.
The Catholic blogosphere was buzzing Thursday with the "Communist crucifix" and what, exactly, Morales intended by giving it to the pope.
The Rev. James Bretzke, a theologian at Boston College in Massachusetts, said there is no church legislation that addresses whether Christian imagery is sacrilegious since Christian art is often portrayed in a variety of ways.
But, he continued: "Is this in good taste? Does this seem to be using the Crucifix for political agenda? And I would say the answer is probably yes. Therefore, I would judge it personally in bad taste and especially manipulative to present it to the Holy Father in a situation like that where it clearly hadn't been cleared ahead of time."
The Rev. Robert Gahl, a moral theologian at Rome's Pontifical Holy Cross University in Rome, said it all boils down to Espinal's intent in designing the cross and Morales' intent in giving it to the pope.
"I'd suppose that, given Morales' warm welcome and Espinal's personal convictions, the intent was not to offend but rather to indicate potential for dialogue and even synergy," he said in an email. "Christians tend to see our symbols from the perspective of universal love, redemption, and even Christ's triumph over evil. Indeed, that is what the cross is all about!"
___
Associated Press reporters Frank Bajak and Paula Flores in Santa Cruz and Rachel Zoll in New York contributed to this report.
___
Follow Nicole Winfield at www.twitter.com/nwinfield
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:57:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Officials say hot, dry weather could cause wildfires in western Canada to spread</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/aZrhKrEVaYk/</Link>
        <Description>Officials say drought conditions and shifting winds in Saskatchewan could lead to further wildfires as troops battle blazes raging across western Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>Officials say hot, dry weather could cause wildfires in western Canada to spread
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
MONTREAL LAKE, Saskatchewan  Officials say drought conditions and shifting winds in Saskatchewan could lead to further wildfires as troops battle blazes raging across western Canada.
Steve Roberts, a Saskatchewan wildfire management official, said Thursday that the warm, dry conditions could cause more trouble in the province that already has 118 wildfires burning.
Air advisories have been issued in western and central Canada, as well as the western United States.
Officials estimate more than 10,000 people have been forced from their homes in recent days. Fires also continue to burn in British Columbia and Alberta.
Roberts says the province is seeking more firefighters and equipment from across Canada and the U.S.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:28:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi officials say bombings in Baghdad, town south of Iraqi capital  have killed 9 people</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/WGRt62ugvuY/</Link>
        <Description>Iraqi officials say bombings in Baghdad and a town south of the Iraqi capital have killed nine people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraqi officials say bombings in Baghdad, town south of Iraqi capital  have killed 9 people
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BAGHDAD  Iraqi officials say bombings in Baghdad and a town south of the Iraqi capital have killed nine people.
Police officials say a sticky bomb attached to a pickup truck carrying Shiite militiamen exploded in Baghdad's southeastern suburb of Zafaraniya, killing two militiamen.
Earlier Thursday, a blast at a commercial street in Baghdad's western district of Bayaa killed three people and wounded nine. And a bomb near an outdoor market killed two people in Baghdad's western al-Furat suburb.
The officials say that a bomb went off near a cafe on Thursday night in the town of Madain, just south of Baghdad, killing two people and wounding 11.
All officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they are not authorized to talk to reporters.
No one immediately claimed responsibility for the attacks.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:18:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saud al-Faisal, former Saudi foreign minister, dies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/C7cthuaY9j4/</Link>
        <Description>Saudi Arabia's Foreign Ministry spokesman says Prince Saud al-Faisal, who was the world's longest serving foreign minister with 40 years in the post until earlier this year, has died. He was 75.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saud al-Faisal, former Saudi foreign minister, dies
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Jan. 5, 2014: Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal waits to greet U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry as Kerry arrives at King Khalid International Airport in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.(Brendan Smialowski, Pool Photo via AP, File)
RIYADH, Saudi Arabia  Saudi Arabia's Foreign Ministry spokesman says Prince Saud al-Faisal, who was the world's longest serving foreign minister with 40 years in the post until earlier this year, has died. He was 75.
The spokesman, Osama Nugali, announced Saud's death on his official Twitter feed, saying, "The eye tears, the heart saddens. We all are saddened to be separated from you." He did not elaborate on the cause of death.
The tall, stately Saud was a fixture in Mideast diplomacy since he was appointed to his post in 1975. He retired in April, citing health reasons, just three months after the death of King Abdullah.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:16:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saud al-Faisal, former Saudi foreign minister with 40 years in the post, dies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/VBrEVQW8Gl4/</Link>
        <Description>Saudi Arabia's Foreign Ministry spokesman says Prince Saud al-Faisal, who was the world's longest serving foreign minister with 40 years in the post until earlier this year, has died.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saud al-Faisal, former Saudi foreign minister with 40 years in the post, dies
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
FILE - In this Monday, Nov. 4, 2013 file photo, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, left, speaks with Saudi Arabia's Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. The country's Foreign Ministry spokesman said Thursday, July 9, 2015, that the prince, who was the world's longest serving foreign minister with 40 years in the post until earlier this year, has died. He was 75. (Jason Reed, Pool Photo via AP, File)(The Associated Press)
FILE - In this Sunday, Jan. 5, 2014 file pool photo, Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal pauses as he makes a statement to the media in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. A Saudi spokesman said Thursday, July 9, 2015, that al-Faisal, Saudi Arabia's longtime foreign minister until this year, has died. (Brendan Smialowski, Pool Photo via AP, File)(The Associated Press)
FILE - In this Sunday, Jan. 5, 2014 file photo, Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal waits to greet U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry as Kerry arrives at King Khalid International Airport in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. A Saudi spokesman said Thursday, July 9, 2015, that al-Faisal, Saudi Arabia's longtime foreign minister until this year, has died. (Brendan Smialowski, Pool Photo via AP, File)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
RIYADH, Saudi Arabia  Saudi Arabia's Foreign Ministry spokesman says Prince Saud al-Faisal, who was the world's longest serving foreign minister with 40 years in the post until earlier this year, has died. He was 75.
The spokesman, Osama Nugali, announced Saud's death on his official Twitter feed, saying, "The eye tears, the heart saddens. We all are saddened to be separated from you." He did not elaborate on the cause of death.
The tall, stately Saud was a fixture in Mideast diplomacy since he was appointed to his post in 1975. He retired in April, citing health reasons, just three months after the death of King Abdullah.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:06:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU ministers fail to reach agreement on relocating 40,000 refugees who landed in Greece, Italy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/4JD-UyCM3xs/</Link>
        <Description>European Union ministers have failed to agree on relocating 40,000 of the refugees making risky boat trips from North Africa to Italy and Greece and will try again later this month to broker a deal on how many people each country will accept.</Description>
        <MainBody>EU ministers fail to reach agreement on relocating 40,000 refugees who landed in Greece, Italy
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BRUSSELS  European Union ministers have failed to agree on relocating 40,000 of the refugees making risky boat trips from North Africa to Italy and Greece and will try again later this month to broker a deal on how many people each country will accept.
The stalemate came a day after the UN refugee agency announced that data from Greece, Italy, Malta and Spain showed 137,000 people arriving in those countries between January and June, 83 percent more than the same time last year. The United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees said 1,867 people died making the crossing, up from 588 a year earlier.
Luxembourg Foreign Minister Jean Asselborn, whose country hosted the ministerial meeting Thursday, says ministers will meet again July 20 to try to reach an agreement.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
