<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:36:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guinea's ex-junta leader indicted for deaths of more than 156 people at 2009 stadium rally</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/_ei-g_BMwFQ/</Link>
        <Description>The lawyer for Guinea's ex-junta leader in exile in Burkina Faso says Moussa "Dadis" Camara has been indicted for the deaths of more than 156 people who had gathered at an opposition rally in 2009.</Description>
        <MainBody>Guinea's ex-junta leader indicted for deaths of more than 156 people at 2009 stadium rally
Published July 08, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
OUAGADOUGOU, Burkina Faso  The lawyer for Guinea's ex-junta leader in exile in Burkina Faso says Moussa "Dadis" Camara has been indicted for the deaths of more than 156 people who had gathered at an opposition rally in 2009.
The lawyer, Jean-Baptiste Haba, said Guinean magistrates arrived in Ouagadougou and met with Camara for about three hours Wednesday. The lawyer says hearings likely will continue into next week.
The indictment could not be independently confirmed.
Camara seized power in a 2008 military coup. In September 2009, soldiers sealed off the stadium where protesters had rallied to insist Camara step down and killed more than 156 people. Over 100 women were gang-raped by soldiers.
Camara was shot in the head a few months later, and went to Burkina Faso as part of a peace deal.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:13:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Yemen's government, Houthi rebels disagree over terms of truce in UN-sponsored talks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/97STZJJ4oZs/</Link>
        <Description>The spokesman for Yemen's exiled government says it has informed the United Nations that a truce to halt more than three months of fighting would hold if guarantees are in place to ensure Shiite rebels withdraw from major cities and release prisoners &amp;mdash; demands the rebels have rejected.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen's government, Houthi rebels disagree over terms of truce in UN-sponsored talks
Published July 08, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
SANAA, Yemen  The spokesman for Yemen's exiled government says it has informed the United Nations that a truce to halt more than three months of fighting would hold if guarantees are in place to ensure Shiite rebels withdraw from major cities and release prisoners  demands the rebels have rejected.
Rebel leader Zeifullah al-Shami told The Associated Press late Wednesday those conditions are "unacceptable" because they don't address the country's humanitarian crisis.
Despite the disagreements, al-Shami says the U.N.-sponsored talks that began Sunday are continuing in the capital, Sanaa.
Government spokesman Rajeh Badi says any truce should be observed by the U.N.
More than 3,000 people have been killed since March, when a Saudi-led and U.S.-backed coalition began launching airstrikes against the rebels and their allies.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:32:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nicaraguan police beat and arrest opposition protesters, harass journalists at demonstration</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/mIKzsQJ_YiY/</Link>
        <Description>Nicaraguan police have beaten and detained opposition demonstrators and harassed journalists outside the country's top electoral council.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nicaraguan police beat and arrest opposition protesters, harass journalists at demonstration
Published July 08, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
An anti-government protester is pulled between police and fellow protesters during a demonstration demanding fair elections, near the Supreme Electoral Council in Managua, Nicaragua, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. Demonstrators are demanding clean elections for Nicaragua's 2016 general elections slated for November. (AP Photo/Esteban Felix)(The Associated Press)
Nicaraguan Congressman Augusto Valle, of the Liberal Independent Party, is detained by riot police during an anti-government protest demanding fair elections near the Supreme Electoral Council in Managua, Nicaragua, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. Demonstrators are demanding clean elections for Nicaragua's 2016 general elections slated for November. (AP Photo/Esteban Felix)(The Associated Press)
Nicaraguan Congressman Augusto Valle, of the Liberal Independent Party, is detained by riot police during an anti-government protest demanding fair elections near the Supreme Electoral Council in Managua, Nicaragua, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. Demonstrators are demanding clean elections for Nicaragua's 2016 general elections slated for November. (AP Photo/Esteban Felix)(The Associated Press)
Anti-government protesters and police face off moments before clashing near the Supreme Electoral Council in Managua, Nicaragua, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. Demonstrators are demanding fair elections for Nicaragua's 2016 general elections slated for November. (AP Photo/Esteban Felix)(The Associated Press)
An anti-government protester is pulled between police and fellow protesters during a demonstration demanding fair elections, near the Supreme Electoral Council in Managua, Nicaragua, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. Demonstrators are demanding clean elections for Nicaragua's 2016 general elections slated for November. (AP Photo/Esteban Felix)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
MANAGUA, Nicaragua  Nicaraguan police have beaten and detained opposition demonstrators and harassed journalists outside the country's top electoral council.
The demonstrators were attending a weekly demonstration in Managua on Wednesday to demand fair election rules and a change of electoral magistrates ahead of the 2016 presidential election.
Police initially tried to block protesters from reaching the electoral council offices, but they pushed past a police barricade.
Police roughed up several photographers and broke the lens of an Associated Press photographer.
Police also detained but later released nine lawmakers from the opposition Independent Liberal Party.
Government opponents contend the ruling Sandinista party has skewed electoral rules and oversight in its own favor.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:23:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colombia arrests 15 alleged rebel collaborators in investigation of bomb blasts in capital</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/vgMUnTeHVOg/</Link>
        <Description>Colombian police arrested 15 presumed collaborators of the country's second largest rebel group in connection with simultaneous bombings that shook the capital last week.</Description>
        <MainBody>Colombia arrests 15 alleged rebel collaborators in investigation of bomb blasts in capital
Published July 08, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BOGOTA, Colombia  Colombian police arrested 15 presumed collaborators of the country's second largest rebel group in connection with simultaneous bombings that shook the capital last week.
The arrests took place Wednesday in coordinated raids on residences throughout Bogota. Among those taken into custody were two individuals who worked as contractors for the city government while others have ties to student groups.
President Juan Manuel Santos blamed the National Liberation Army for detonating the homemade explosives outside two offices of a pension fund owned by Colombia's richest businessman. Ten people were injured in the blasts, one which went off in a wealthy district unaccustomed of late to such violence.
The motive for the attacks is unclear but the ELN has been blamed for several small attacks in the capital the past year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:18:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqis recount ISIS burning to death mothers with their sons for resisting caliphate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/6B9TqAXpEa8/</Link>
        <Description>Even women and children are not safe from ISIS.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fighters of the Islamic State recently burned to death five women and their sons, according to reports from Iraq. (Reuters)
Even women and children are not safe from ISIS.
A tribal leader whose group has been fighting the Islamic State in Central Iraq recently described in gruesome detail how the terrorist groupburned five women along with their sons in the Anbar Province, because they refused to hand over their children to the caliphate. Sheikh Naim el-Kaoud, leader of the al-Bounmar tribes in Anbar told Asharq al-Awsat, a Saudi newspaper published out of London, that gangs of ISIS fighters burned the women and their sons in front of residents in the Al-Jamiya neighborhood of Heet, a city 31 miles west of Ramadi.
ISIS could argue that jihad--meaning joining ISIS--is obligatory of all Muslims, so the civilians' refusal qualifies them for execution as apostates, Ryan Mauro, a national security analyst for the Clarion Project, told FoxNews.com. Acts like these are also effective for ISIS because it reminds [local Muslims] of the price they'll pay for standing up to the group.
As the Islamic State is getting locked down, they are squeezing the local population.
- Scott Stewart, Stratfor
The international community is likely to see more of these horrific acts from ISIS in the future, Mauro said.
The story from the tribal leader shows that burning civilians alive and ripping sons away from mothers is now accepted practice among ISIS members, Mauro also said. ISIS justified the burning of [captured] Jordanian pilot [Moath al-Kasasbeh in January] by arguing that Islam justifies the immolation of those who burn Muslims, such as by dropping bombs.
The report also comes amid other accounts of the Islamic State brutally killing civilians in both Iraq and Syria. In the area of al-Kaim, ISIS militants allegedly killed two women by drowning them in the Euphrates River after accusing them of cooperating with Iraqi security forces.
Activists in Syria released video footage showing dozens of men crucified for violating the terror groups strict regulations during the holy period of Ramadan. And on Wednesday, reports surfaced out of Mosul of ISIS forces killing civilians for violating Ramadan.
A report on Monday by t he Clarion Project charged that the terror group has even started selling women into forced slavery.
Related Image
Expand / Contract
The reports of 5 women and their sons being burned alive by ISIS is similar to the execution of Jordanian fighter pilot Muath al-Kasasbeh.
Nearly 50 Yazidi girls, some as young as 10, were sold at slave markets and in auctions in Syria. Some were sold for as little as $80, according to the report.
Global intelligence analysts say these reports, like many that come out of the region, can be hard to verify.
Some of it is hard to tell, but in general, this stuff is happening, Scott Stewart, vice president of tactical analysis at Stratfor , told FoxNews.com. Its logical, as they have lost the East to Kurdish forces and, dealing with a large increase of Turkish forces at the border, they are really trying to gain back more ground.
Coupled with coalition forces coordinating attacks against the terror group, it appears that ISIS is trying to bolster its numbers.
As the Islamic State is getting locked down, they are squeezing the local population, Stewart said, not just for more fighters, but for resources and money for funding.
And thats going to build resentment among the people in the region eventually, he said.
Perry Chiaramonte is a reporter for FoxNews.com. Follow him on Twitter at @perrych
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:07:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Officials report some progress in quelling raging wildfires in western Canada</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/VBS3-qoANPI/</Link>
        <Description>Officials say some progress has been made in quelling wildfires that are threatening thousands of people in western Canada and triggering quality warnings across the U.S. West and Midwest.</Description>
        <MainBody>Officials report some progress in quelling raging wildfires in western Canada
Published July 08, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
LA RONGE, Saskatchewan  Officials say some progress has been made in quelling wildfires that are threatening thousands of people in western Canada and triggering quality warnings across the U.S. West and Midwest.
Steve Roberts, a Saskatchewan wildfire management official, said Wednesday that better visibility has allowed aircraft to dump water on the flames. Several hundred troops are involved in the efforts.
Authorities estimate between 10,000 to 12,000 people have been forced to leave their homes in the province in recent days.
Wildfires are also burning in parts of British Columbia and northern Alberta.
A northern Saskatchewan aboriginal community is also seeking volunteers to help fight the fires.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:15:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Founder of euroskeptic Alternative to Germany quits party after losing leadership to rival</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/FjWEA7UWDaA/</Link>
        <Description>A founder of Germany's upstart Alternative for Germany says he is leaving the party after losing the leadership to a bitter rival who places greater emphasis on an anti-immigration stance than on opposition to the euro currency.</Description>
        <MainBody>Founder of euroskeptic Alternative to Germany quits party after losing leadership to rival
Published July 08, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
In this July 4, 2015 picture Alternative fuer Deutschland party co-chairs Bernd Lucke , left, and Frauke Petry  attend  the party conference in Essen, Germany.  The upstart Alternative for Germany party has replaced its euroskeptic leader with a conservative from the east who wants to place greater emphasis on immigration. A majority of AfD members backed Frauke Petry in the leadership vote Saturday against Bernd Lucke, who led the party during its successful bids in the past two years to enter the European Parliament and five German state assemblies.(Frederico Gambarini/dpa via AP))(The Associated Press)
BERLIN  A founder of Germany's upstart Alternative for Germany says he is leaving the party after losing the leadership to a bitter rival who places greater emphasis on an anti-immigration stance than on opposition to the euro currency.
Under economics professor Bernd Lucke, the party narrowly missed the 5 percent threshold needed to enter the national Parliament in 2013. It has since entered the European Parliament and won seats in regional legislatures, but became increasingly mired in infighting.
Lucke, who lost the leadership to rival Frauke Petry last weekend, said in a statement Wednesday that "the party has fallen irretrievably into the wrong hands." He said he hasn't yet decided whether to found a new party, news agency dpa reported.
He complained of ever-stronger anti-Islamic and anti-foreigner views in the party.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:14:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gambia parliament passes bill that imposes expensive deposits for presidential candidates</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/tqVrtdk2fa4/</Link>
        <Description>Gambia's opposition says the recent passing of a bill that imposes high deposit amounts for political candidates makes it difficult for opposition members vying for the office.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gambia parliament passes bill that imposes expensive deposits for presidential candidates
Published July 08, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
DAKAR, Senegal  Gambia's opposition says the recent passing of a bill that imposes high deposit amounts for political candidates makes it difficult for opposition members vying for the office.
Opposition leader Ousainou Darboe said Wednesday that the new law ensures only those who have money can participate in political life in Gambia.
The bill was passed Tuesday by parliament. It says candidates must deposit about $10,000 to be a presidential candidate. Fees for council and parliament seats range from $50-$1,000.
The tiny, poor West African nation is surrounded by Senegal. Human rights activists accuse President Yahya Jammeh of targeting political opponents, journalists, and gays and lesbians.
Jammeh came to power in a military coup in 1994 and he's since survived several coup attempts, the most recent occurring last December.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:03:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WikiLeaks publishes new list of German numbers allegedly showing NSA targeted chancellery</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/JRDOdQVV8hI/</Link>
        <Description>WikiLeaks has published a new list of German phone numbers that it claims shows the U.S. National Security Agency targeted for surveillance a string of connections at the chancellery and close aides to Chancellor Angela Merkel.</Description>
        <MainBody>WikiLeaks publishes new list of German numbers allegedly showing NSA targeted chancellery
Published July 08, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BERLIN  WikiLeaks has published a new list of German phone numbers that it claims shows the U.S. National Security Agency targeted for surveillance a string of connections at the chancellery and close aides to Chancellor Angela Merkel.
Wednesday's publication came a week after WikiLeaks released a list of numbers it said showed the NSA targeted officials at various ministries. That rekindled concerns over U.S. surveillance in Germany after reports two years ago that Merkel's cellphone was targeted.
Merkel's chief of staff last week asked the U.S. ambassador for a meeting and told him that German law must be adhered to.
There was no immediate comment from the German government on the latest publication. It's unclear when exactly the partially redacted list of 56 numbers dates from.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:03:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Cowards who kill the innocent': Iranian song, video blast US amid nuclear talks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/YdTSKVLQybY/</Link>
        <Description>A new hit song in Iran probably won't find its way onto John Kerry's iPod.</Description>
        <MainBody>A new song in Iran takes aim at President Obama and warns not to trust the "wolves" of the U.S. (FARS screengrab)
A new hit song in Iran probably won't find its way onto John Kerry's iPod.
"Hotel Coburg" and the accompanying video savages President Obama and the U.S., calling Americans "wolves" and warning Iranians to be skeptical of the ongoing talks between Tehran and six world powers over the Islamic Republic's nuclear program. As Secretary of State, Kerry has represented the U.S. at the talks, which have dragged on since late 2013, blowing past several deadlines as Iran balks at proposed conditions for eliminating economic sanctions against the hardline regime. The song takes its name from the Vienna venue where talks are ongoing.
I am skeptical of the wolfs smile, goes the chorus backed by a warbling synthesizer, as the video shows a montage of Kerry, President Obama and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. I am skeptical of big lies. As the talks warm up, their siege on us tightens.
"We are being pressured under insurmountable threats.
- Lyrics from Iranian hit "Hotel Coburg"
The song was produced by the hardline paramilitary group Basij, through its "Basij House of Music." But airplay on the regime-backed FARS news service is a sure sign it has the blessing of Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei and President Hassan Rouhani. If it represents the Iranian government's true negotiating posture, it explains why striking a deal has been so elusive.
What kind of games are they playing? Is this chess?" goes another portion of the song, as the video shows footage of leaders around the negotiating table and then cuts to IAEA inspectors. "We are being pressured under insurmountable threats.
Related Image
Expand / Contract
Secretary of State John Kerry, shown on left in an exchange with his Iranian counterpart, probably prefers James Taylor's music. (FARS screengrab)
In November, 2013, the P5+1, comprised of the five permanent members of the UN Security Council plus the rotating nation, began negotiating with Iran to gain assurances the regime won't pursue nuclear weapons in exchange for dropping of international sanctions. They started with a basic agreement, but the effort to hammer out details has been frustrating as Iran has refused to allow international inspectors to verify its future compliance and has demanded that all sanctions be immediately dropped when the deal is signed. The deadline was extended Nov. 24, 2014, then again on April 2 and more recently on June 30.
Critics in the U.S., including Republican and Democratic lawmakers, have questioned why the Obama administration has pressed on with the talks, given Tehran's past refusal to comply with international agreements and statements from Khamenei indicating the regime has no intention of allowing inspections or dropping its pursuit of nuclear weapons.
The song highlights some of the historical grievances Irans government has against the U.S., calling these scars that have remained, including a 1953 CIA-backed coup, the mistaken downing by the U.S. military of an Iranian passenger plane in 1988 and the assassination of four nuclear scientists, whose killers are unknown.
What can I do when I cannot seem to forget, the singer wails, calling the U.S. cowards who kill the innocent, as a dead child is shown in the video.
The Basij is a notoriously brutal paramilitary volunteer militia that was formed in 1979 when the Shah was toppled by the Revolution that brought the Islamic Republics leader, Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, to power.
Near the end, a montage of pictures appear of Obama, former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton, President George W. Bush, Netanyahu, former Israeli President Shimon Peres and former Israeli Prime Minister Ariel Sharon.
The last refrain repeats, In the end, its all up to God, and in a soft whisper the singer ends the song with, We are under their threats."
Lisa Daftari is a Fox News contributor specializing in Middle Eastern affairs.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
