<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Global News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:57:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10-year-old boy seriously hurt after farming accident</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2102303/10-year-old-boy-seriously-hurt-after-farming-accident/</Link>
        <Description>A 10-year-old boy has serious injuries after an accident in southern Saskatchewan on Wednesday afternoon.
</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
REGINA  A 10-year-old boy has serious injuries after an accident in southern Saskatchewan on Wednesday afternoon.
The boy was driving an open cab utility tractor pulling a hay rake on a gravel road close to Chaplin/Parkbeg when the tractor entered the ditch and rolled on its side into a deep slough.
An adult male was driving ahead of the boy and residents nearby helped with his injuries until EMS arrived.
The youth was transported to a hospital in Moose Jaw and then flown to Saskatoon via STARS Air Ambulance.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:52:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>5 unique accommodations to add to your travel bucket list</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2101380/5-unique-accommodations-to-add-to-your-travel-bucket-list/</Link>
        <Description>Get out of your hotel rut and make your trip more memorable with a stay in one of these five unique accommodations. </Description>
        <MainBody>July 9, 2015 5:52 pm
Updated: July 9, 2015 5:53 pm
5 unique accommodations to add to your travel bucket list
By Patricia Kozicka Lifestyle and Special Projects Reporter Global News
Spruce up your trip and stay in a tree house for a night.
Airbnb
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
TORONTO An easy way to make your trip more memorablecan be to find a fun place to stay. So weve put together a top five list to help get you out of your hotel rut.
1. Boat
If youre in western Canada, you know that houseboating in theShuswaps isa popular summer activity. But now, theres an app that makes it easy to rent a boat or charter a yacht pretty much anywhere.
GetMyBoat bills itself as the worlds largest and fastest growing peer-to-peer boat rental marketplace. Think of as the Airbnb for boats. It has 32,000 boats for you to choose from in 135 countries.
In Canada ,the average weekly price for a charter will set you back an average of$2,700. The average daily rate is around $500.
For a lot less than that, you can livein a yellow submarine with seven of your friends on board in Liverpool, England.
Channel your favouriteBeatle on this yellow submarine in Liverpool.
GetMyBoat
Houseboats in Amsterdam and Boston are a couple other interesting options.
And on Airbnb, a sleep in a century-old houseboat on the Seine will only set you back $174 CDN a night. It also just happens to be parked under the Eiffel Tower.
The houseboat features  a private entrance and private deck with table and chairs.
Airbnb
The houseboat is set on two levels with a private bathroom, bathtub and shower, with a panoramic view.
Airbnb
Check out this nautical-meets-Parisian-chic decor.
Airbnb
View of the Seine river from the houseboat.
Airbnb
2. Treehouse
Indulge your inner child and sleep in a treehouse. Spend a restful night with the birds at Camping Miramichi in New Brunswick or experience an enchanted coastal rain forest from ahand-craftedtreehouse sphereat Qualicum Beach, B.C.
Hand-crafted treehouse sphere at Qualicum Beach, B.C.
Free Spirit Spheres
There are dozens of other treehouses you can sleep in around the world .
If youre willing to go to Atlanta, Georgia, considerthis charmingtreehouse listed on Airbnb .Itsdeck, living room and bedroom are each connected by rope-bridges. And the bedis equipped with wheels, so it can be rolled out onto a platform that overlooks astream below.
Spruce up your trip and stay in a tree house for a night.
Airbnb
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:36:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Speed reductions in Lethbridge</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2102242/speed-reductions-in-lethbridge/</Link>
        <Description>LETHBRIDGE- It&amp;#8217;s not something anyone really loves, but it is something most drivers just have to deal with &amp;#8211; construction. Lethbridge currently has several major routes undergoing heavy duty overhauls and the City is asking all drivers to watch for those zones. Darwin Juell, Transportation Manager for the City of Lethbridge, says safety is the...</Description>
        <MainBody>July 9, 2015 5:36 pm
Speed reductions in Lethbridge
By Quinn Campbell Videographer Global News
Construction on Scenic Drive in Lethbridge
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
LETHBRIDGE- Its not something anyone really loves, but it is something most drivers just have to deal with  construction.
Lethbridge currently has several major routes undergoing heavy duty overhauls and the City is asking all drivers to watch for those zones.
Darwin Juell, Transportation Manager for the City of Lethbridge, says safety is the Citys number one concern.
You throw in a construction zone, you change that normal driving habit for people and that is part of the reason we slow it down, said Juell.
Story continues below
When dealing with high risk areas, the City can set the speed limit to what it feels is safe. The width of the road, machinery being used and traffic volume are just a few factors.
The province allows us to set our own speed limits. We do that through bylaws as well as setting construction limits, construction zones and temporary speed limit reductions, adds Juell.
We wanted to see just how much of a difference a speed reduction could make during a commute, so we travelled the same distance, roughly a kilometer, first at 30 Km/h then at 60 Km/h.
At 30 Km/h our time was 1:35
At 60 Km/h our time was :57
Whoop Up Drive is a classic example. When you went from 90 down to 50 for a long time, its a difference of 120 seconds, just a minute or two, depending on if its congested or not, adds Juell.
Even though the construction can be a headache, he also reminds drives its short term pain for long term gain.
When you see construction happening, slow down. We are doing this for you. We are trying to make your commute, whereever you are trying to go, better in the future.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:35:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Save-On-Foods opening its first location in Regina</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2102228/save-on-foods-opening-its-first-location-in-regina/</Link>
        <Description>Canada’s largest western-based grocery retailer Save-On-Foods plans on opening stores in Regina, Saskatoon, Moose Jaw and Yorkton.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
REGINA  A new grocery chain is opening its doors in Saskatchewan.
Canadas largest western-based grocery retailer Save-On-Foods plans on opening stores in Regina, Saskatoon, Moose Jaw and Yorkton.
The first grocery store in the province will be in Regina at the old Canadian Tire location on South Albert.
In total, Save-On-Foods plans to open 40 stores across Saskatchewan and Manitoba in the next five years  creating nearly 4,000 jobs.
READ MORE: Save-On-Foods coming to Saskatchewan
Were very excited to be here today to meet our new neighbours in Saskatchewan, says Save-On-Foods president Darrell Jones.
For us, as we start construction, it is as much about building relationships with the community as it is about the building of the store itself. We have a commitment to customizing our locations to best suit the needs of each neighbourhood were in. What better way to find out what that means to residents than to come and invite them to tell us first hand.
The stores will be a combination of existing buildings and new construction and will range from 40,000 to 65,000 square feet on average.
The first store in Regina should open in the spring of 2016.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:34:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confederate flag coming down, but what about symbols offensive to Native Americans?</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2102127/confederate-flag-coming-down-but-what-about-symbols-offensive-to-native-americans/</Link>
        <Description>There are plenty examples of racist symbols that remain in public view in the U.S. — including those that are offensive to the Native American population. </Description>
        <MainBody>July 9, 2015 5:34 pm
Confederate flag coming down, but what about symbols offensive to Native Americans?
By Nick Logan World Reporter/Global National Web Producer Global News
Protestors gather outside of AT&amp;T stadium voicing their stand against the Washington Redskins logo and name before an NFL football game between the Redskins and the Dallas Cowboys, Monday, Oct. 27, 2014. (File photo)
Brandon Wade/AP Photo
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Friday will be a historic day as the Confederate flag, long considered a symbol of racism and oppression in the United States, will be taken down from outside the South Carolina state house.
Gov. Nikki Hayley signed the legislation Thursday afternoon that will see the flag come down at 10 a.m. on Friday, after more than 50 years.
READ MORE: Confederate flag to be removed from South Carolina Statehouse on Friday
The flags removal, which comes after the murder of nine black congregants of Charlestons Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church on June 17, is being applauded. But its far from the only step that needs to be taken to resolve racial inequality and hatred in the United States.
There are many more examples of racist symbols that remain in public view  in particular, those that are offensive to the Native American population.
Among those that have been the most galvanizing is the name and logo of the Washington Redskins football team. The U.S. capitol is a football town and the logos are everywhere, especially on a home game day.
Washington, D.C.-based tribal rights attorney Tara Houska said the Confederate flag may be different than a football teams name and mascot, on the surface, but she believes theres no difference when it comes to perpetuating racism.
Football in the United States is like a religion, she said. So for people to see that imagery and dress up in headdresses, for love of their team, at the same time theyre simultaneously dehumanizing an entire race of people.
Houska, who spoke to Global News Thursday while attending the first-ever Tribal Youth Gathering hosted by the White House, is a founding member of Not Your Mascots .
Its a non-profit organization dedicated to addressing the misappropriation of Indigenous identity and imagery through the acceptance of mascots, stereotypes and racist behaviours. The group argues such representations have a harmful effect on indigenous children and communities.
READ MORE: Tears, family memories part of debate on removing Confederate flag in South Carolina
The legal battle to get the football team to drop the name and mascot has been going on for decades.
But, there was a big victory on Wednesday when a federal court upheld a ruling that invalidated the Washington Redskins trademark registrations because the name may disparage Native Americans . That doesnt spell an end for the team name, but the ruling is seen as a move in that direction. The team plans to appeal.
Houska thinks the removal of the Confederate flag will help people further understand how powerful some symbols can affect the way people think and the way that people respond to one another.
People just brush it off like Oh, it doesnt matter. Its not important,' she said.
WATCH: South Carolina representative gives emotional plea to take down Confederate flag from capitol grounds
If you were to argue that the name and logo of a football team isnt as big a deal as a flag, take a look up the East Coast to Massachusetts, where the state flag is seen by some as depicting the historic oppression of Native Americans.
The flag depicts a Native American holding a bow in one hand and an arrow in the other. But above that is an arm bearing a sword; below is the motto, By the sword we seek peace, but peace under liberty, in Latin.
It depicts oppression, John Peters Jr., a member of the Mashpee Wampanoag tribe and executive director of the Massachusetts Commission on Indian Affairs, told the Boston Globe on June 25. To have the sword over our head . . . it signifies a policy that has affected all tribes.
Then theres the tiny community of Whitesboro, New York, about 160 kilometres west of state capital Albany, where the village seal shows a white settler wrestling (some say strangling) a Native American.
Is it just me, or should Whitesboro, New York, maybe change its seal? pic.twitter.com/SUkZ6ZZkr6
 Aura Bogado (@aurabogado) June 25, 2015
Mayor Patrick OConnor, in an interview with the Village Voice on Tuesday, disagreed with the assessment that the seal is racist, describing it as depicting a friendly wrestling match  something that was apparently commonplace when the village was settled in the 1700s.
I think you have to take all the facts into consideration. And if people take the time to do that and they reach out to us, or they do the research themselves, its actually a very accurate depiction of friendly wrestling matches that took place back in those days, OConnor said.
I would argue that you will find supporters to change the seal and you will find supporters to keep the seal. It absolutely is not meant as a sign of disrespect, and, as you look at the seal in totality, with the story that the seal represents, I dont believe that its offensive.
READ MORE: Canadian retailers pulling confederate flag from stores following Charleston shooting
If youve followed the debate over the removal of the Confederate flag, proponents have argued passionately that the banner is an important part of American history and a source of pride.
But Houska said if you need to make the effort to explain why such symbols arent racist, you probably need to take a closer look at them.
Its the same thing with Native American symbols like here in D.C. Were surrounded by the Washington football team everywhere, the caricature of the Native American everywhere. This is why people dont think were real people, Houska said. I hope that these conversations continue and people realize this is wrong.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:33:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hackers steal 21 million social security numbers in the U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2102217/hackers-steal-21-million-social-security-numbers-in-the-u-s/</Link>
        <Description>Hackers stole Social Security numbers, health histories and other highly sensitive data from more than 21 million people, the Obama administration said Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 9, 2015 5:33 pm
Hackers steal 21 million social security numbers in the U.S.
By   Jack Gillum And Josh Lederman The Associated Press
Hackers stole Social Security numbers, health histories and other highly sensitive data from more than 21 million people, the Obama administration said Thursday, acknowledging that the breach of U.S. government computer systems was far more severe than previously disclosed.
File/Getty Images
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WASHINGTON  Hackers stole Social Security numbers, health histories and other highly sensitive data from more than 21 million people, the Obama administration said Thursday, acknowledging that the breach of U.S. government computer systems was far more severe than previously disclosed.
Story continues below
The scope of the data breach  believed to be the biggest in U.S. history  has grown dramatically since the government first disclosed earlier this year that hackers had gotten into the Office of Personnel Managements personnel database and stolen records for about 4.2 million people. Since then, the Obama administration has acknowledged a second, related breach of the systems housing private data that individuals submit during background investigations to obtain security clearances.
READ MORE: FBI, Justice Department officials pressing encryption concerns before U.S. Congress
That second breach affected more than 19 million people who applied for clearances, as well as nearly 2 million of their spouses, housemates and others who never applied for security clearances, the administration said. Among the data the hackers stole: criminal, financial, health, employment and residency histories, as well as information about their families and acquaintances.
The new revelations drew indignation from members of Congress who have said the administration has not done enough to protect personal data in their systems, as well as calls for OPM Director Katherine Archuleta and her top deputies to resign. House Oversight and Government Reform Committee Chairman Jason Chaffetz, a Utah Republican, said Archuleta and her aides had consciously ignored the warnings and failed to correct these weaknesses.
Such incompetence is inexcusable, Chaffetz said in a statement.
Yet Archuleta insisted she would not step down. I am committed to the work that I am doing, she said in a conference call with reporters.
READ MORE: CSIS websites back online after 2 cyberattacks in 24 hours
Archuleta said the hackers also got hold of the user names and passwords that prospective employees used to fill out their background investigation forms, as well as the contents of interviews conducted as part of those investigations. Yet the government insisted there were no indications that the hackers have used the data they stole.
Still, the government declined to say who was behind the attack.
Numerous U.S. lawmakers, including Senate Democratic leader Harry Reid, have said China was behind the attack. But Michael Daniel, President Barack Obamas cybersecurity co-ordinator, said the government wasnt yet ready to say who was responsible.
Just because were not doing public attribution does not mean that were not taking steps to deal with the matter, Daniel told reporters.
READ MORE: Study finds login, passwords for 47 US government agencies online
While officials would not point the finger at China, they acknowledged that the same party was responsible for both of the breaches, which took place in 2014 and early 2015. Investigators previously told The Associated Press that the U.S. government was increasingly confident that Chinas government, and not criminal hackers, was responsible for the extraordinary theft of personal information.
China has publicly denied involvement in the break-in.
Earlier Thursday, during a round-table discussion with reporters, FBI Director James Comey described the scope of the OPM breach as huge and called it a very big deal from a national-security perspective and a counterintelligence perspective.
Its a treasure trove of information about everybody who has worked for, tried to work for, or works for the United States government, he said.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:25:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WATCH: House explodes moments after firefighters enter</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2102188/watch-house-explodes-moments-after-firefighters-enter/</Link>
        <Description>Cameras captured the incredible moment an Arkansas house exploded only moments after firefighters had entered the front door.</Description>
        <MainBody>Firefighters from Mexico arrive in Edmonton to help battle Alberta wildfires
Local station KSLA reports that a mother and her one-year-old baby were asleep inside the home when neighbours noticed smoke pouring out of her attic.
According to the Texarkana Fire Department, they managed to alert the mother and child by banging on their door, and both were able to evacuate the home without any serious injury.
READ MORE:Firefighters from Mexico arrive in Edmonton to help battle Alberta wildfires
Local news cameras had just set up on the scene as firefighters entered through the front door.
Then without warning, a massive explosion seemingly consumed the house, with pieces of insulation raining down on the street like a bizarre snowfall.
But incredibly, none of the firefighters were seriously hurt.
We were in the front room, the living room making our way to the rear of the house, when we heard not a loud boom and then the ceiling fell, firefighter Brian Henry said.
WATCH:Firefighters discuss house explosion in Arkansas
Authorities say the explosion was the result of a backdraft blowing out the insulation once firefighters opened the front door.
Theyre calling the fire  and the resulting explosion  suspicious, since there was no gas or electricity connected to the house at the time.
The two residents were treated for smoke inhalation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:18:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>All-time summer peak record set for electricity in Alberta during heat wave</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2102115/all-time-summer-peak-record-set-for-electricity-in-alberta-during-heat-wave/</Link>
        <Description>Albertans sweltering in 30 Celsius heat have broken a record for amount of electricity used during the summer. </Description>
        <MainBody>July 9, 2015 5:18 pm
All-time summer peak record set for electricity in Alberta during heat wave
By   Staff The Canadian Press
Edmonton soared to 32 Celsius Thursday afternoon as Alberta broke an electricity record.
Emily Mertz, Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
CALGARY  Albertans sweltering in 30 Celsius heat have broken a recordfor amount of electricity used during the summer.
The Alberta Electric System Operator says 10,441 megawatts ofpower was used between 1 p.m. and 2 p.m. local time Thursday.
The operator says its confident the system can handle the highdemand.
It says more than 1,700 MW of supply has been added to the systemsince the start of 2014, including nearly 350 MW of wind and morethan 1,000 MW of gas-fired generation.
There has been a 0.3 per cent growth in demand for poweryear-over-year in Alberta.
Summer peak demand was previously set at 10,419 MW on July 30,2014.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:06:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British government tells UK tourists to leave Tunisia over terror risk</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2102069/british-government-tells-uk-tourists-to-leave-tunisia-over-terror-risk/</Link>
        <Description>The British government on Thursday told all U.K. tourists to leave Tunisia because a terrorist attack is "highly likely," saying the North African country's government has not done enough to enhance security.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 9, 2015 5:06 pm
British government tells UK tourists to leave Tunisia over terror risk
By   Jill Lawless The Associated Press
Mounted police officers patrol on the beach of Sousse, Tunisia, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Tunisia's top security official says 1,000 extra police are being deployed at tourist sites and beaches in the North African nation after Friday's attack.
(AP Photo/Abdeljalil Bounhar)
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
LONDON  The British government on Thursday told all U.K. tourists to leave Tunisia because a terrorist attack is highly likely, saying the North African countrys government has not done enough to enhance security.
The Foreign Office said it is advising against all but essential travel to the North African country. It said that British tourists in Tunisia should contact their travel agents, who will arrange flights to bring them home. Independent travellers were advised to return on scheduled commercial flights.
READ MORE: Tunisia plans to build wall along Libya border after beach resort attack
While we do not have any information suggesting a specific or imminent threat, since the attack in Sousse the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably leading us to the view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely, Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said.
In a statement, his office said: On balance, we do not believe the mitigation measures in place provide adequate protection for British tourists in Tunisia at the present time and we have therefore changed our travel advice accordingly.
Following the Sousse attack, Tunisian authorities on Saturday announced a state of emergency and enacted new security measures such as sending more than 1,300 security forces to patrol hotels, beaches and other tourist sites.
READ MORE: Britons mark 10th anniversary of London transit attacks
Hammond, speaking on the sidelines of talks about Irans nuclear program in Vienna, said British authorities were in close contact with tour operators, who were arranging to get their customers home as quickly as possible.
To those travelling independently, our advice is to return on commercial flights which are operating normally, he added.
Travel company Thomas Cook said it would be bringing customers back on its 10 scheduled flights this weekend, and use other airlines if needed. Spokesman Ian Benjafield said the company would get people home whatever way we can.
Tour firms Thomas Cook, Thomson and First Choice all cancelled trips to Tunisia through Oct. 31.
The U.K. decision amounts to a major new blow to Tunisias tourist industry. Hundreds of thousands of British tourists visit Tunisia each year. Many Britons left after the Sousse attack, but some 3,000 are still in Tunisia.
READ MORE: Tunisia declares state of emergency after beach massacre
Germanys Foreign Ministry said it was observing the situation very closely and adjusting travel advice regularly.
As of now, however, there was no immediate change to its travel advice last updated five days ago. Two Germans were killed in the Sousse attack.
On its travellers advice Web site, Frances Foreign Ministry on Wednesday renewed its recommendation for French nationals in Tunisia to be particularly vigilant in the wake of the Sousse attack.
It stopped short of advising French nationals to return home. A ministry spokesman was not immediately available for comment following the British Foreign Office statement.
Tunisias hospitality industry has already felt a major impact.
At the Riu Palace Hammamet Marhaba in coastal Hammamet, southeast of Tunis, receptionist Hamdi Mohsen said that since the attack in Sousse, business is down like hes never seen before in his 34 years working at the resort.
Its all because of Sousse, he said. He noted that the hotel now has only about 100 visitors, far short of the 800-850 person capacity  and no Britons at all. The hotel, which was nearly full in early June, tends to host about 300 Britons a day at this time of year, he said.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:01:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Montreal police investigate “fake grandson” fraud case</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2101944/montreal-police-investigate-fake-grandson-fraud-case/</Link>
        <Description>Police are searching for an important witness in connection with a fraud case that had a young man posing as an elderly woman's grandson.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 9, 2015 5:01 pm
Updated: July 9, 2015 5:09 pm
Montreal police investigate fake grandson fraud case
By Tim Forster Intern Global News
Montreal police are hoping to speak with the man who collected the money, seen here in a photo.
Montreal police/Handout
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
MONTREAL  Police are searching for an important witness in connection with a fraud case that had a young man posing as an elderly womans grandson.
According to Montreal police, the 79 year-old victim received a phone call on June 18 from a man masquerading as her grandson.
The suspect reportedly told her that he was in prison, that heneeded cash to post bail and that somebody would come over tohouse to collect the money.
A man latercame to the womans house and she handed money over to him.
The man who came the house is described as Caucasian, in his twenties, standing 59 and weighing about 140 pounds with brown hair and brown eyes.
Montreal police are hoping to speak to him, but insistedhe isan important witness and not a suspect as he could have beenan unwilling participant in the crime.
The grandson method is a somewhatcommon fraud tactic targeting seniors, although Montreal police said they have not encountered anyother similar cases recently.
Anyone with information about this incident is urged to contact police.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
