<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Google">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:33:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina Governor Signs Law Removing Confederate Flag From Capitol - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGh1lTpoxr0LULAZmx_KgsWUTcOgA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778897977096&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/10/us/relief-and-resentment-after-confederate-flag-vote-in-south-carolina.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:13:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hackers stole Social Security numbers from 21.5 million, gov't admits - Fox News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFLNiD8FQpD02V0xuqMScd_Sza9Qw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778897864900&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/07/09/hackers-stole-social-security-numbers-from-215-million-govt-admits/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Hackers stole Social Security numbers from 21.5 million, govt admits
Published July 09, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Hackers swiped Social Security numbers from 21.5 million people -- as well as fingerprint records and other information from background check investigations -- in the massive breach earlier this year of federal personnel files, the government acknowledged Thursday.
The Office of Personnel Management included the findings in a statement Thursday on the investigation into a pair of major hacks believed carried out by China.
"The team has now concluded with high confidence that sensitive information, including the Social Security Numbers (SSNs) of 21.5 million individuals, was stolen from the background investigation databases," the agency said of the second breach, which affected background investigation files.
OPM said it is "highly likely" anyone who underwent a background investigation through the agency since 2000 has been affected. The 21.5 million number mostly includes those who applied for one, but also 1.8 million others, "predominantly spouses or co-habitants of applicants."
OPM said these records include "findings from interviews conducted by background investigators and approximately 1.1 million include fingerprints." The agency said they have no information at this point to suggest "any misuse or further dissemination of the information that was stolen from OPM's systems."
Despite agency pledges to help those affected with credit monitoring and other assistance, the latest numbers are sure to deepen concerns about the risks those affected face.
More on this...
Millions of fed workers' information exposed in cyber breach
The OPM statement Thursday pertained to a second breach, discovered in May -- separate from one discovered in April which affected more than 4 million people.
The larger breach impacted background investigation records of current, former and prospective federal workers and contractors. OPM acknowledged a wide range of information is potentially at risk:
"OPM has determined that the types of information in these records include identification details such as Social Security Numbers; residency and educational history; employment history; information about immediate family and other personal and business acquaintances; health, criminal and financial history; and other details.Some records also include findings from interviews conducted by background investigators and fingerprints. Usernames and passwords that background investigation applicants used to fill out their background investigation forms were also stolen."
The number affected by this breach is higher than the 14 million figure that investigators gave reporters last month. They said the government was increasingly confident that China's government, and not criminal hackers, was responsible for the extraordinary theft of personal information.
China has publicly denied involvement in the break-in.
A former senior intelligence official also told Fox News that the attack is not an isolated incident, but part of a broader campaign by China to build a massive database that can be used to earmark and index the intelligence for future use. This information is being aggregated, and the level of organization points to backing of Chinese military units. 
The numbers are so high because a high-level security clearance requires a review every five years. Each time, the individual must supply three new references -- meaning a single official could easily have personal information for over a dozen people in the system.
The extent of, and response to, the breach has already led to calls for the firing of top officials at OPM.
House Oversight and Government Reform Committee Chairman Jason Chaffetz, along with 17 other Republican lawmakers, last month called on President Obama to fire Director Katherine Archuleta and Chief Information Officer Donna Seymour
"Simply put, the recent breach was entirely foreseeable, and Director Archuleta and CIO Donna Seymour failed to take steps to prevent it from happening despite repeated warnings," they said in a letter. 
Fox News' Matthew Dean and Catherine Herridge and The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece seeks bailout totaling $55 billion, offers painful spending cuts - Washington Post</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHEZg5RA0n_Y_RH0aE7e2ycqLp0tA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778898800711&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/greek-government-finalizes-details-on-last-ditch-request-for-bailout/2015/07/09/f7871f18-25ba-11e5-b621-b55e495e9b78_story.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:59:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Second top chef drops out of Trump's hotel deal - Fox News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEqDRUE0V9U67u6xyFcDQItIOyfMg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896853968&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=http://www.foxnews.com/leisure/2015/07/09/second-top-chef-dumps-trump/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Second top chef drops out of Trump's hotel deal
Published July 09, 2015
Zakarian announced he too is dropping out of Trumps new hotel in Washington, D.C.(AP)
Another celebrity chef has chopped ties with Donald Trump over his controversial anti-immigrant comments.
Celebrity chef Geoffrey Zakarian, a regular on the Food Networks cooking competition show Chopped, announced Thursday he too is dropping out of Trumps new hotel in Washington, D.C, a day after celebrity chef Jose Andres pulled out of the same project.
"The recent statements surrounding Mexican immigrants... do not in any way align with my personal core values, Zakarian, who runs a string of restaurants including The Lambs Club and the National in New York City, said in a statement. In light of this, I am unable to move forward with a restaurant in the Trump International Hotel, slated to open in Washington, D.C.s Federal Post Office building.
He added that, Zakarian Hospitality employs many immigrants from nations all over the world, and I look forward to continuing this business culture in my future restaurants. We are a nation built from immigrants, my family included.
In May, Zakarian had announced plans to open his restaurant, The National, in the Trump International - a $200 million project in the capitals historic Old Post Office Pavilion.
But following comments made by the Republican president hopeful on the campaign trail that Mexicans crossing the U.S. border arebringing drugs. Theyre bringing crime. Theyre rapists, many brands, such as Macy's, NASCAR and NBC, have cut ties with Trump.
Trump said in a statement that the chefs move has absolutely nothing to do with his core values.
Zakarian has put up a non-refundable $490,167 deposit and has fully guaranteed the lease. Construction at Trump International Hotel, Washington D.C. is under budget and ahead of schedule. Donald Trump is investing hundreds of millions of dollars to restore this national treasure and employing many hundreds of people in the process. Zakarians foolish decision will be his loss and will have no effect on the completion and success of this project.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:16:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Think Trump has a chance to snag GOP nomination? Analysis gives him just 1% - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNE4lhd8RylR3WI6aCf5Kbx34QQzHA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778898799158&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/07/09/politics/donald-trump-data-pivit-2016-election/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>NBC to Donald Trump: 'You're fired!'
Story highlights
Pivit combines polls, predictive analysis, wagering markets and social sentiment to create odds on the outcome of world events
The platform said Trump has a 1% chance to win the GOP nomination, even though in the last CNN/ORC poll on June 28, 12% of Americans surveyed said they would like Trump for the nomination
Washington (CNN)
Here's one 1% figure billionaire Donald Trump likely wants no part of: His odds of winning the Republican nomination for President.
That's according to a new analysis performed by an interactive data collection platform called Pivit , which combines polls, predictive analysis, wagering markets and social sentiment to create odds on the outcome of world events, the company says. The co-founders of Pivit also co-founded Intrade, a similar company that was a web-based trading exchange for political futures.
CNN has a partnership with Pivit to predict outcomes of the 2016 presidential election .
The platform said that the real estate mogul and Republican presidential candidate has a 1% chance to win the GOP nomination, even though in the last CNN/ORC poll on June 28, 12% of Americans surveyed said they would like Trump for the nomination, second among all GOP contenders.
RELATED: Trump denies RNC chief chastised him
The data also concluded that Trump has an 85% chance of being included in the first GOP debate hosted by Fox News in Cleveland next month, but that the percentage has decreased.
The chances that Trump makes it to the CNN-hosted debate in California in September are lower, at 70%.
However, by Pivit's predictions, if the numbers don't change, Trump will be included in both debates, ranking as 8th and 9th for each, respectively.
Pivit says the public is skeptical that Trump will continue to tolerate the financial losses that have ensued since he announced his campaign, which included incendiary remarks about Mexican immigrants.
"The number of Trump sponsors also shorting the Trump brand is growing: NBC Universal, Univision, Televisa, Macy's, NASCAR, Serta, ESPN, PGA of America and others have either terminated or are evaluating their commercial deals," the release said. "At the same time, the public's confidence that he is willing to take continued pain has decreased just as quickly."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:22:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Indigenous group in Bolivia frustrated - Washington Post</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEfSiS1oCJWnRt65Za7UoPdcXXSmQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778898033120&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/the_americas/the-latest-marales-has-politically-charged-gifts-for-pope/2015/07/08/8709655e-25d1-11e5-b621-b55e495e9b78_story.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jeb Bush and allies hit their mark, raise $114M for 2016 bid - Washington Post</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEpSCmu1Tm7YTVJtWe_U1YC_oIqfg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778898225888&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/bushs-2016-campaign-says-it-raises-114-million-in-16-days/2015/07/09/6b5ed894-2661-11e5-b621-b55e495e9b78_story.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments 0
FILE - In this June 27, 2015, file photo, Republican presidential candidate former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush waits in a hallway after a campaign event in Henderson, Nev. ush raised $11.4 million in 16 days after formally launching his campaign for president, his campaign said Thursday. The total is a fraction of what he has pulled in overall to support his White House ambitions. (John Locher, File/Associated Press)
By Julie Bykowicz and Thomas Beaumont | AP July 9 at 5:48 PM
WASHINGTON  Fulfilling ambitions to raise a historic amount of money in pursuit of the White House, Republican presidential candidate Jeb Bush and his allies took full advantage of the nations evolving campaign finance laws to collect more than $114 million in the first six months of the year.
No candidate for president has benefited from so much money so early in a campaign.
While the total is sure to widely eclipse the fundraising hauls of Bushs 16 major competitors for the GOP nomination, the ambitious $100 million goal  and Bushs success at reaching it on schedule  has yet to scare any challenger from the race.
The total announced Thursday includes $103 million raised by Right to Rise, a super PAC that will support Bush in the crowded GOP contest. The rest came into Bushs formal campaign.
More than the symbolism of surpassing $100 million, the totals demonstrate Bushs success charting new territory, said Bush donor Mark Jacobs, a former Texas energy executive who now lives in Iowa. Its that Right to Rise has raised more and been more successful than any political organization ever.
The former governor of Florida is taking a unique approach to a presidential bid by delegating many operations to Right to Rise, which as a super PAC is free of the limits placed on how much money a traditional campaign can raise from individual donors.
Designed with longtime aides Sally Bradshaw, Mike Murphy and others, its a strategy untested in modern politics, the outgrowth of court decisions in 2010 that led to the creation of the super PAC.
Based in Los Angeles, Right to Rise will handle a huge part of the costly work of running for president, including buying TV, online and radio commercials, conducting polling and even doing some organizing tasks such as voter outreach in early primary states.
By law, it cant take direction from Bushs Miami-based campaign, and the two operations have limits on how they can communicate. Bushs official campaign and its markedly smaller bank account will pay for his travel and employee salaries, and give him a pot of money from which to craft messages exactly as he sees fit.
Right to Rise already is advertising on Bushs behalf. It has spent $47,000 so far on digital media, according to documents filed this week with the Federal Election Commission. The group has also inquired with broadcast and cable stations in the early primary states about booking TV ad time.
Bush isnt alone in counting on significant support from a super PAC. Texas Sen. Ted Cruz has raised $14.2 million for his campaign, while supporters have given his affiliated super PACs an additional $38 million.
The campaign of former technology executive Carly Fiorina has raised $1.4 million, but much of her day-to-day political messaging is coming through a super PAC that has pulled in more than twice as much.
Thursdays announcement proved Bushs strategy will set fundraising records.
Right to Rises haul of $103 million in six months exceeds the $79 million Priorities USA Action raised during the two-year 2012 election cycle to support the re-election of President Barack Obama, and is two-thirds of the $154 million raised by the super PAC backing Republican Mitt Romney in those years.
The son and brother of presidents, Bush said in December he planned to explore a campaign and then immediately set out to tap his and his familys deep roster of experienced fundraisers and likely donors. With their help, he traveled the country raising money at events at which the suggested donation was often as much as $100,000 a person. At one point in the fundraising spree, Bush limited contributions to Right to Rise to no more than $1 million.
But Bill Kunkler, a Chicago private equity executive and Bush donor, said that while the Bush name may have opened some doors, its Jeb Bush who closed the deal.
People have been willing to take a look, and hes overcome the people who have said, Not another Bush, Kunkler said Thursday. People are looking at him as a guy who did it on his own, and who stands on his own.
In announcing its fundraising Thursday, Right to Rise said it had about 9,400 donors who had given $25,000 or less, and about 500 whod given more. Several major donors to Romney began turning toward Bush in January, and some would later raise $1 million at an event in Chicago that lasted just an hour. And in February, those same donors put together an event that brought in $4 million for the super PAC.
Bushs formal campaign operates in far more restrictive territory. Individual donors cant give more than $2,700 to the primary elections and, if Bush wins the GOP nomination, $2,700 he can spend in the general election.
After making his candidacy official on June 15, Bushs campaign super-charged fundraising with a contest called 27 in Fifteen, in which top supporters were encouraged to gather $27,000 worth of donations in the first 15 days of the campaign. Those who succeeded were being rewarded with a retreat this weekend at the Bush family compound in Kennebunkport, Maine.
The private gathering features an evening picnic with Bush and his parents, former President George H.W. Bush and Barbara Bush, and a morning political and campaign briefing with senior campaign officials.
In all, Bushs campaign raised $11.4 million  or an average of $710,000 per day  through the end of June. They touted that daily average as more than the average of $562,000 per day raised by Democratic front-runner Hillary Rodham Clinton since she launched her campaign April 12. Clintons haul in that time totaled $45 million.
___
Associated Press writer Steve Peoples contributed to this report.
___
Follow Julie Bykowicz and Thomas Beaumont on Twitter at: http://twitter.com/bykowicz and http://twitter.com/tombeaumont
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
politics
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:30:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nasa's New Horizons spacecraft ready for Pluto fly-by - The Guardian</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFfrGSNgEFrqBhvP63_zFToMbPszA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778898577815&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=http://www.theguardian.com/science/2015/jul/09/nasa-new-horizons-spacecraft-pluto-flyby-probe</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Spacewatch
Nasas New Horizons spacecraft ready for Pluto fly-by
Scientists have regained contact with the probe before its encounter with the dwarf planet, after a nine-year journey from Earth
Image of Pluto taken by the New Horizons spacecraft from 8 million kilometres away. Photograph: Nasa-JHUAPL-SWRI/Reuters
Nasa is all set for next weeks historic Pluto fly-by having reactivated the New Horizons spacecraft following a malfunction last weekend .
The 14 July fly-by will take place on the 50th anniversary of Mariner 4s visit to Mars, which was Americas first successful planetary fly-by.
New Horizons was launched on 19 January 2006, and has been travelling through space for the past nine years. Just over a year after launch, it passed Jupiter and used the giant worlds gravity to boost its velocity, as well as making scientific observations. This boost shortened the time to reach Pluto by years but last weekend, just 10 days before the encounter, the mission was suddenly cast into doubt. Contact was lost with the spacecraft for about 90 minutes. When communications were established, ground controllers found the spacecraft had entered safe mode, a low-power sleep designed to protect the spacecraft when something goes wrong.
Related: Pluto: Nasa probe set for fly-past of frozen dwarf planet
The problem was diagnosed as an operator error, in which the ground staff had asked the spacecraft to do too many things at once, crashing the onboard computer. This will not happen during the fly-by itself, and science operations resumed on 7 July.
At closest approach, New Horizons will be less than 12,500km above the dwarf planets icy surface, but 4.5bn kilometres from Earth. The radio connection is so weak at that distance that the data recorded by its instruments will take more than a year to trickle back. However, Nasa expects the first close-up pictures on 15 July.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:19:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Andrews-Sharer Sisters Found After Vanishing in Wyoming Wilderness: Officials - NBCNews.com</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHzNjVblWWDQ--6Zi1ht9rl9pbOlg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778897970402&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=http://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/andrews-sharer-sisters-found-after-vanishing-wyoming-wilderness-n389381</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Three sisters who disappeared while backpacking in the Wyoming backcountry were found alive Thursday  cold and hungry but healthy, search and rescue officials said.
The young women  Megan, Erin, and Kelsi Andrews-Sharer  have since been reunited with their father after a helicopter spotted them in a remote part of the Bridger-Teton National Forest just after 10 a.m. local time.
"We're so pleased with the outcome of this search and the safety of the missing hikers and all the rescue personnel," Teton County Sheriff Jim Whalen said in a statement.
Sisters Kelsi, 16, Megan, 25, and Erin Andrews-Sharer, 22, with their father after their rescue in Grand Teton National Park. Sarah Durant
The sisters, originally from Milwaukee County, Wisconsin, left for their extended camping trip in Grand Teton National Park on June 28 and were supposed to return home Tuesday, the Teton County Sheriff's Office said.
advertisement
The women's car was discovered Wednesday, about 15 miles south of the resort town of Jackson. Their disappearance prompted a search by ground crews, including sniffer dogs, and by helicopter on Wednesday.
The effort got a fortuitous break when a guide noted seeing a person in a white rain jacket in an area with no trails on Wednesday. On Thursday morning, realizing a search was in progress, he phoned in a tip to the sheriff's office.
Officials said the guide's accurate description of the location proved critical  and a search team redirected a helicopter to the coordinates provided. The sisters were found within 20 minutes.
The sheriff's office credited the trio for staying together, using their tent and having the proper clothing to weather through their ordeal.
Authorities earlier said the sisters were experienced backpackers and believed they "may have simply made a wrong turn."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:56:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Army To Cut 40000 Troops Over 2 Years At 6 U.S. Bases - NPR</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFYdwtXDGiQbgqYpH-xbse_NAULRQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896588082&amp;ei=E_CeVaHoO6iUaZj7k-AK&amp;url=http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/09/421561723/army-to-cut-40-000-troops-over-2-years-at-6-u-s-bases</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Army To Cut 40,000 Troops Over 2 Years At U.S. Bases
July 09, 2015 5:37 PM ET
Twitter
Updated at 5:55 p.m. ET
The Army confirmed Thursday that it will cut 40,000 troops at several domestic bases over the next two years in a cost-saving move. If the White House and Congress are unable to avert another round of sequestration cuts, the troop reductions could be even deeper, according to Army officials.
The Army Times reported earlier this week that the cuts were planned. The newspaper said an additional 17,000 civilian employees of the Army would also be laid off.
The Associated Press says: "The decision to shrink the Army from 490,000 active-duty soldiers to 450,000 was made months ago, but details on how it would be accomplished were briefed to Congress only in recent days."
In 2012, the Army had 570,000 active-duty personnel.
The AP writes:
"Army officials said the plan calls for cuts at nearly every installation in 2016 and 2017, with Fort Benning, Georgia, and Joint Base Elmendorf-Richardson, Alaska, taking the largest reductions. Benning is to lose 3,402 soldiers, or 29 percent of its current personnel, as the Army converts the 3rd Brigade of the 3rd Infantry Division to a smaller unit known as a battalion task force. Elmendorf-Richardson is to lose 2,631 soldiers, or 59 percent of its personnel, as the 4th Brigade of the 25th Infantry Division undergoes the same conversion, according to figures released by the Army.
"Fort Hood, Texas, the Army's largest base, would lose 3,350 soldiers, or 9 percent of its personnel. Among others, Fort Bliss, Texas, would lose 1,219 soldiers, or 5 percent; Joint Base Lewis-McChord, Washington, would lose 1,251, or 5 percent, and Schofield Barracks, Hawaii, would lose 1,214, or 8 percent."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
