<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:33:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Museum's 'Kimono Wednesdays' Cancelled After Claims Of Racism</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fd6286/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cmuseums0Ekimono0Ewednesdays0Ecancelled0Eafter0Eclaims0Eof0Eracism0In0I776570A20Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Museum's 'Kimono Wednesdays' Cancelled After Claims Of Racism
"It's not racist if you look cute &amp; exotic in it."
Priscilla Frank Arts Writer, The Huffington Post
Posted: 07/09/2015 | Edited: 22 minutes ago
"Kimono Wednesdays" sounds more like an ill-advised sorority ritual than sanctioned museum programming. And yet, this month, at the MFA Boston , museumgoers lined up to touch and try on kimonos in front of Claude Monet's " La Japonaise ."
It wasn't long before protestors spoke out both on social media and on the museum grounds, dubbing the initiative to be culturally insensitive and racist. Critics pointed out that, even worse, the garments on display were actuallyuchikake,not kimonos. Insert forehead slap.
As a result of the outrage, the MFA swiftly canceled "Kimono Wednesdays," which was scheduled to continue until July 29.
White model posing with kimono and fan, mimicking Monet's orientalism, as a study. #mfaboston #whitesupremacyskills pic.twitter.com/xu6IITKItO
 Amber Ying (@diabola) July 1, 2015
Originally imagined to accompany Monet's " La Japonaise ," a painting of the artist's wifeCamille Doncieuxposing with a fan and kimono, the program encouraged visitors to"channel your inner Camille Monet" by posing in similar garb.
What's strange is that Monet's piece is often interpreted as a satirical response to the absurd, fetishistic craze of the Japanese aesthetic sweeping Paris around1876, at the time of the work's creation. Instead of sparking a dialogue around the problematic Orientalism of the time, it seems the MFA engaged in a little fetishism of its own.
In an extensive tumblr post from " Stand Against Yellow Face ," protestors elaborated on the many supremacist aspects of the work's presentation. "What is the value of inviting the public to then dress up and participate in the very thing Monet was critiquing? Why not choose a print from the Hokusai exhibit to highlight the experience of Japanese women? Or why not provide a discussion on the historical context and criticality about the 1870s obsession?"
Protestors who gathered in person held signs reading messages such as: "It's not racist if you look cute &amp; exotic in it besides the MFA supports this!"
Protestors front and center, next to the painting and the rotating white model. #mfaboston #whitesupremacykills pic.twitter.com/zFAJPqMQlx
 Amber Ying (@diabola) July 1, 2015
" There is no education on the garments origin, history, uses, or importance in Japanese society at the time, " Stand Against Yellow Face explained on Facebook. "The act of non-Japanese museum staff throwing these kimonos on visitors as a 'costume' event is an insult not only to our identities, experiences, and histories as Asian-Americans in America, but affects how society as a whole continues to typecast and deny our voices today  A willingness to engage thoughtfully with museum employees and visitors on the bullshit of this white supremacist costume event are [sic] welcome.
Stand Against Yellow Face's tumblr memorandum also elaborates on why the choice to exhibit traditional Japanese dress in this way, even if not meant to be offensive, is damaging and hurtful. " Orientalism exoticizes (read: others, demeans and obscures) many cultures including South Asian, East Asian and Middle Eastern traditions, and resulting aggressive attitudes (both micro and macro) towards Orientalized peoples persist to this day."
. @mfaboston wonderful dialogue last Wed about why dressing Japonaise really shouldn't be happening #mfaboston pic.twitter.com/Mex9pynILg
 Pampi (@thirdeyefell) July 1, 2015
On July 7, the MFA released a statement announcing a shift in programming,where visitors will be allowed to touch with and interact with the historically accurate kimonos on display, but not try them on.
As Katie Getchell, deputy director of the museum, told the Observer , the MFA thought "Kimono Wednesdays" would be a success in part due to the popularity of similar programs in Japanese museums including the Setagaya in Tokyo, The Kyoto Municipal Museum, and The Nagoya/Boston Museum of Fine Arts, when "LaJaponaise"was on loan.
In its July 7 statement, the museum apologized for offending any visitors. Despite this, protestor Aparna "Pampi" Das told the BBC that despite the MFA's statement, protests will continue until the museum issues a formal apology and opens a panel including protestors to discuss the incident in public.
The MFA wrote in an email to the Huffington Post that the museum is not making any statements in relation to the protestor's new demands.
See more Twitter reactions to the controversy as well as the full list of FAQs from Standing Against Yellow-Face below and let us know your thoughts in the comments.
Just because you don't think it's racist or cultural appropriation it does not make the impact on those who see it any different #MFABoston
 Aaron P. (@ish_ajay) July 7, 2015
People are just lining up to wear the kimono now. Erasing all the historical and orientalist context. #mfaboston #whitesupremacykills
 Amber Ying (@diabola) July 2, 2015
We feel handling the kimonos is still inappropriate, since it still subjects art to orientalist examination. #mfaboston #whitesupremacykills
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Submits Reform Proposals To European Creditors</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fd845e/sc/25/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cgreece0Esubmits0Ereform0Eproposal0In0I77649640Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>By Renee Maltezou and John O'Donnell</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece Submits Reform Proposals To European Creditors
Reuters
Updated:
26 minutes ago
A man waves a Greek flag and uses a megaphone in front of the Greek parlaiment during a pro-european rally on July 9, 2015 in Athens, Greece. (Christopher Furlong/Getty Images) | Christopher Furlong via Getty Images
reddit
By Renee Maltezou and John O'Donnell
ATHENS/FRANKFURT, July 9 (Reuters) - The Greek government sent a package of reform proposals to its euro zone creditors on Thursday in a race to win new funds to avert bankruptcy and will seek a parliamentary vote on Friday to endorse immediate actions.
The chairman of Eurogroup finance ministers, Jeroen Dijsselbloem, confirmed receiving the documents and said through a spokesman that he would not comment until they had been  assessed by experts from the European Commission, European Central Bank and International Monetary Fund.
A Greek official said lawmakers would be asked to authorize the leftist government to negotiate a list of "prior actions" it would take before any fresh aid funds are disbursed, a key step to convince skeptical lenders of its serious intent.
Leftist Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras spent the day with his cabinet drafting a last-ditch package of tax rises, pension reforms and economic liberalization measures on which Greece's survival in the euro zone hinges.
A further vote would be needed to turn them into law next week if euro zone leaders agree at a summit on Sunday that the proposals are a basis for starting negotiations on a three-year loan and releasing some bridging funds to keep Greece afloat.
Greek banks have been closed since June 29, when capital controls were imposed and cash withdrawals rationed after the collapse of previous bailout talks. Greece defaulted on an IMF loan repayment the following day and now faces a critical July 20 bond redemption to the ECB, which it cannot make without aid.
The country has had two bailouts worth 240 billion euros from the euro zone and the International Monetary Fund since 2010, but its economy has shrunk by a quarter, unemployment is more than 25 percent and one in two young people is out of work.
Germany, Athens biggest creditor, meanwhile made a small concession by acknowledging that Greece will need some debt restructuring as part of the new program to make its public finances viable in the medium-term.
The admission by hardline German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble came hours before the midnight deadline for Athens to submit its reform plan.
Schaeuble, who makes no secret of his doubts about Greece's fitness to remain in the currency area, told a conference in Frankfurt: "Debt sustainability is not feasible without a haircut and I think the IMF is correct in saying that.
But he added: "There cannot be a haircut because it would infringe the system of the European Union."
He offered no solution to the conundrum, which implied that Greece's debt problem might not be soluble within the euro zone.
But he did say there was limited scope for "reprofiling" Greek debt by extending loan maturities, shaving interest rates and lengthening a moratorium on debt service payments.
Schaeuble also complained that he had not seen any sign of "prior actions" by the Greek government. Friday's vote should go some way towards disarming such criticism, although a further vote will be required to turn the "prior actions" into law next week if an agreement is reached, the Greek official said.
DEBT RELIEF CHORUS
European Council President Donald Tusk, who will chair an emergency euro zone summit on Sunday to decide Greece's fate, joined growing international calls for Athens to be granted some form of debt relief as part of any new loan deal.
Tusk said a realistic proposal from Greece will have to be matched by an equally realistic proposal on debt sustainability from the creditors.
"Otherwise, we will continue the lethargic dance we have been dancing for the past five months," he said.
Failure to reach a deal on Sunday, including releasing some money to enable Athens to cover debt service over the next few weeks, could lead to a collapse of Greek banks next week.
If there is no agreement, all 28 European Union leaders will discuss measures to limit the damage from a Greek collapse, including humanitarian aid, possible border controls and steps to mitigate the impact on neighbors, EU officials said.
Just how uncertain the coming days are was highlighted when ECB President Mario Draghi voiced highly unusual doubts about the chances of rescuing Greece.
Italian daily Il Sole 24 Ore quoted the ECB chief, under growing fire in Germany for keeping Greek banks afloat, as saying he was not sure a solution would be found for Greece and he did not believe Russia would come to Athens' rescue.
Asked if a deal to save Greece could be wrapped up, Draghi said: "I don't know, this time it's really difficult."
The ECB is keeping shuttered Greek banks afloat with emergency liquidity capped until the weekend.
Even France, Greece's strongest supporter in the euro zone, acknowledged it was working on scenarios for a Greek exit from the currency area if weekend efforts to clinch a deal fail.
Under the agreed timetable, the three creditor institutions will deliver their initial assessment by Friday evening. If it is broadly positive, Eurogroup finance ministers will decide on Saturday whether to recommend opening negotiations with Athens on a conditional loan from the European Stability Mechanism bailout fund. The decision requires the assent of countries representing 80 percent of the ESM's capital, so talks can go ahead even if one or two smaller member states vote against it.
Having won a thumping referendum majority to reject the austerity terms of a previous bailout plan, fired his turbulent finance minister and secured support from opposition party leaders, Tsipras is in a stronger position to impose tough measures and face down resistance at home.
But in a sign of the some of the challenges he will face, the leader of the far-left wing of his Syriza party came out to denounce any imposition of harsh measures on Greeks.
"We don't want add to the past two failed bailouts a third bailout of tough austerity which will not give any prospects for the country," Energy Minister Panagiotis Lafazanis said.
According to Athens daily Kathimerini, the reform package will be worth 12 billion euros over two years, more than previously planned to offset a return to recession after months of difficult negotiations with creditors.
Instead of growing by 0.5 percent this year, months of uncertainty and almost two weeks of capital controls mean "there are estimates of a recession of about 3 percent," Kathimerini said. Greece emerged only last year from a deep recession that shrank its economy by a quarter over six years.
European officials told Reuters on Wednesday that some large Greek banks may have to be shut and taken over by stronger rivals as part of a restructuring of the sector that would follow any bailout of the country.
One official said Greece's four big banks - National Bank of Greece, Eurobank, Piraeus and Alpha Bank - could be reduced to just two, a measure that would doubtless encounter fierce resistance in Athens.
German Bundesbank chief Jens Weidmann said capital controls should remain in force in Greece until there was any deal, and that the ECB should not increase its liquidity assistance for Greek banks, without which they may collapse next week.  (Additional reporting by Alastair Macdonald in Brussels, Agnieszka Flak in Milan, Deepa Babington, Angeliki Koutantou and Michele Kambas in Athens, Balasz Koranyi and Frank Siebelt in Frankfurt, Julien Ponthus and Laurence Foster in Paris; Writing by Paul Taylor; Editing by Catherine Evans, Toni Reinhold)
live blog
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:09:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>These Photos Will Make You Want To Put Your Phone Down Forever</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fd845f/sc/15/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cdeath0Eof0Econversation0In0I77639360Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It looks like smartphones really have killed the concept of "idle time."</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
It looks like smartphones really have killed the concept of "idle time."
Last year, photographer Babycakes Romero captured an array of images showing people glued to their mobile devices when they could otherwise be having a conversation, enjoying dinner or simply staring into space. The series, titled "The Death of Conversation," was published on Bored Panda and ultimately led to a TEDx Talk this Tuesday.
In the time that's passed since he first published the photo series, Romero says the smartphone problem -- as he sees it -- has only gotten worse.
"As smartphones encompass more and more of people's lives everyone is turning to them more and more as every aspect of their existence has been digitized and made accessible to them 24/7," Romero told The Huffington Post via email.
You've probably noticed something like this in your own life: You're at dinner with someone, there's a lull in the conversation, and suddenly both of you are checking your smartphones. Romero says the devices become an excuse to hide a "lost connection" between people.
"It is sad that this technology which was supposed to connect people is making them disconnect from each other in person," Romero told HuffPost.
Agree or not, his photos offer pretty striking evidence that people everywhere are hooked on their smartphones. Take a look for yourself:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:46:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Reckless Diplomacy Disguised as Caution Cost Lives in Srebrenica. And It's Happening Again, This Time in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fd397e/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cambassador0Emuhamed0Esacirbey0Creckless0Ediplomacy0Esrebrenica0Esyria0Ib0I77641160Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>This week, Bosnians and Herzegovinians will commemorate the 20th anniversary of one of the 20th century's most heinous war crimes. On July 11, 1995, </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
This week, Bosnians and Herzegovinians will commemorate the 20th anniversary of one of the 20th century's most heinous war crimes. On July 11, 1995, more than 8,000 men and boys were separated from their mothers, daughters and wives and systematically executed in a genocidal attack in the Bosnian "safe area" of Srebrenica.
Srebrenica was an act of genocide. It was also an act of betrayal by the international community. For three years, the people of Bosnia demanded protection from slaughter, rape and starvation. For three years, cautious diplomats heard the cries but refused to take decisive action. It was only after Srebrenica and the subsequent shelling of Sarajevo's Markale marketplace that NATO, led by the United States, intervened decisively to stop the Bosnian-Serb onslaught and force the belligerent parties to the negotiating table.
Reckless diplomacy camouflaged as caution cost lives in Bosnia. And it's costing lives once again -- this time in Syria.
The parallel example for Syria is not Iraq, Afghanistan or Libya -- it's Bosnia.
As Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina's first Ambassador to the UN and the Syrian opposition's first Ambassador to the UN, we are struck by the painful parallels between our two conflicts, and how indecision and a lack of moral courage are once again leaving innocent civilians to pay the ultimate price. Diplomats have both the capacity -- and the duty -- to learn from the past and to take the actions that can prevent atrocities from happening again. But today's diplomats are applying the wrong lessons to Syria.
The parallel example for Syria is not Iraq, Afghanistan or Libya -- it's Bosnia. Like the Syrian conflict today, Bosnia saw horrific atrocities, unprecedented numbers of refugees and an exorbitant death toll. Terms like "genocide" and "ethnic cleansing" became familiar, just as "barrel bombs" and "chlorine gas" are becoming familiar today. In both Syria and Bosnia, we saw state and non-state actors unafraid of using violence against civilians. And we saw calculating elites eager to exploit ethnic and religious differences and foment religious extremism on all sides.
We also saw an international community divided. Like Syria, the crisis in the Balkans was thought to be unsolvable and intractable. Bosnia's strongest allies worried that action to protect civilians could escalate the conflict regionally and even globally.
Like Syria, the crisis in the Balkans was thought to be unsolvable and intractable.
But the international community overcame those fears. Despite their reluctance to call for military intervention, prominent human rights organizations like Human Rights Watch ultimately rallied to civilians' side and demanded effective protection. Despite divisions and worries of mission creep, in August 1995, NATO launched retaliatory strikes against Bosnian-Serb strongholds, effectively ending the siege of Sarajevo and forcing Milosevic to Dayton.
The intervention in Bosnia saved lives. It dampened extremism. And it ultimately brought the conflict to an end. Intervention -- in the form of a no-fly zone -- could offer similar benefits in Syria by stopping what is now the leading killer of Syrian civilians: Assad's barrel bombs.
Nearly 200 Syrian civilians die each week because of Assad's indiscriminate aerial bombardment. A no-fly zone could bring that death count to zero by doing for Syria precisely what it could not for Bosnia -- stopping the Syrian regime's helicopters.
A no-fly zone would also help dampen extremism by denying terrorist groups like ISIS a key recruiting tool: the West's perceived indifference to their suffering.
A no-fly zone would also help dampen extremism by denying terrorist groups like ISIS a key recruiting tool: the West's perceived indifference to their suffering. Bosnia's no-fly zone was not a panacea, but it was the first key step in giving civilians hope and humanitarian relief. That relief helped moderate Islamists counter the appeals of radical extremists and it helped preserve the core of Bosnia's multiethnic and multireligious society. It could achieve a similar feat in Syria.
Finally, a no-fly zone could help force Assad to the negotiating table, much as NATO's intervention ultimately forced Milosevic to Dayton. By altering the dynamics on the ground, a no-fly zone could change Assad's calculations and apply the pressure needed to force him to negotiate peace. Of course, there are differences between Bosnia and Syria, three of which are critical. First, in Syria, a no-fly zone alone would be enough to stop the leading killer of civilians -- without the need for bombing. This is because, unlike in Bosnia, a no-fly zone operated from the seas rather than the skies would not require military strikes to preemptively target Assad's military assets.
Second, unlike in Bosnia, in Syria human rights organizations have failed to unite behind the need for international protection. Third, the Security Council has failed to back a no-fly zone.
Bosnia's no-fly zone was not a panacea, but it was the first key step in giving civilians hope and humanitarian relief.
These failures have been used to justify inaction in Syria. They should not. The anniversary of Srebrenica offers a stark reminder of what can and does happen when States abdicate their responsibility to protect. It shouldn't have to take another Srebrenica for the world to act on Syrians' behalf.
Four years into Syria's crisis, cautious diplomacy has become reckless. A uniformly applicable no-fly zone will fill the diplomatic and humanitarian void on Syria. Most importantly, it will save lives.
Close
Let us not celebrate a fifth anniversary of the Syrian conflic
of

A displaced child in Aleppo, Syria. (Jesuit Refugee Service)
Distribution of winter clothes to internally displaced children in Damascus. Humanitarian access to war affected populations within Syria is an urgent issue, while the inability to provide adequate assistance to meet the basic needs of refugees and host populations in Lebanon, Jordan and other countries of first asylum is a growing threat to both the protection of vulnerable people and the stability and security of the region. (Jesuit Refugee Service)
Distribution of winter clothes and hygiene kits in Homs to internally displaced people. (Jesuit Refugee Service)
Distribution of winter clothes to internally displaced children in Damascus. (Jesuit Refugee Service)
Distribution of winter clothes and hygiene kits in Homs to internally displaced people. (Jesuit Refugee Service)
The JRS distribution center in Aleppo provides emergency support to thousands of families every month. Here, displaced families can come to collect food baskets, mattresses, blankets, hygiene kits and other essential items. Displaced people are often displaced multiple times because of the changing conflict lines or scarcity of resources, and when they relocate multiple times they leave behind the most basic items, taking only the clothes on their back or a few supplies. (Jesuit Refugee Service)
The field kitchen in Aleppo, Syria provides up to 8000 meals a day for internally displaced people who have no way of preparing their own cooked food. (Jesuit Refugee Service)
A crisis of this magnitude has placed unprecedented stress on the humanitarian system. It is not only a matter of funding; traditional approaches to handling the conflict have proven insufficient after four years of increasing violence.(Jesuit Refugee Service)
Displaced people living in Aleppo are forced to live in incomplete buildings, with little or no protection from the elements. This past winter was the most harsh winter in all four years of the conflict. There was no way for families to stay warm or provide adequate food or fuel for themselves in temperatures that were below zero degrees (Celsius) and Aleppo was covered in snow for weeks at a time. (Jesuit Refugee Service)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:25:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>When Tired Politicians Are Called On To Make Important Decisions</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fc98f5/sc/25/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cstress0Eimportant0Edecisions0Egreece0In0I7764390A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
On June 26, European Commission President Jean Claude Juncker declared that he was exhausted. I dont like this way of working, which leaves me sleepless," he said. "We cant make the right decisions when we are tired.  Since then, the meetings, conference calls, Eurogroup meetings and press conferences have continued unabated, even after midnight.
We have become witnesses to tired -- even exhausted -- politicians who, under conditions of intense stress, are being called upon to make historic decisions that will influence the direction of the country. Alexis Tsipras, Angela Merkel, Wolfgang Schaeuble and Jean Claude Juncker are just some of those responsible for making important decisions for Greece, as well as for the eurozone.
Psychologist Eleni Tarvara explains to us how fatigue and intense stress can influence the decision-making process.
One of the many definitions of the word stress is demand. According to this definition, stress results from a clash between the demand for something and the possibility of meeting the demand. To the extent that an individual is unable to meet the demand, stress increases -- bringing abnormal reactions to the fore. These reactions can be especially knee-jerk, so that the individual can leave his internal struggle behind.
Jean Claude Junker at a press conference relating to the European Union and Greece.
A number of studies have connected the lack of sleep with reduced brain activity and lack of concentration . A study conducted by the University of Texas on two groups of soldiers showed that lack of sleep makes it difficult to reach a logical decision and influences an individuals judgement.
The most up-to-date studies focus on the consequences stress can have on making important decisions. Some studies have shown that stress-producing factors, such as increased noise and time constraints, negatively affect people -- putting them into situations with a lot of pressure, and without the ability to plan and examine alternative choices that might be available to them.
Angela Merkel in Paris, getting ready to meet Francois Hollande to discuss the Greek referendum.
To study precisely what influence this stress-producing demand has on an individuals judgement, scientists designed an experiment in 1993. They asked 40 participants to take part in an electronic game involving a gunfight in a forest. For half of the participants,  stress-producing conditions, such as an annoying noise, were employed. For the other half of participants, there was no stress-producing condition. Then, the stressed-out group and the composed group competed in the game. The researchers found important differences in the ways the two groups overcame difficulties. The stressed-out group concentrated more on the overall view of the operation, without giving much thought to the consequences of their decisions, in an attempt to get this over with. The calmer group, on the other hand, concentrated on a greater analysis of the problems, examining choices and dividing up responsibilities. The stressed-out group had difficulty coping with the game, but the other group was able to control the movements of the game.
Studies subsequently based on this data point to the presence of three basic behaviors in the movements of individuals experiencing stress. Individuals can assert themselves, attack or be passive. Individuals who exhibit assertive behavior are those who negotiate for what they need, what they desire and for their opinions without trying to impose them on others or thinking it self-evident that they'll get their way. In the second category of reaction, we find the aggressive individuals. Here, while the individuals systematically defend their rights, they disregard or are indifferent to the rights of others. They easily anger, want to dominate the discussions and continue to attack and criticize even when others back down. Conversely, because they feel anxiety and guilt, passive (non-assertive) individuals find it difficult to ask that their demands be met, while they very often meet the demands of others. They often assume an apologetic stance, feel melancholy and judge themselves in the same negative way.
Angela Merkel and Wolfgang Schaeuble in discussion.
The aforementioned studies link the decision-making process within those groups that act under intense stress ( anxiety, fatigue, pessimism ) with a mainly aggressive or passive manner.
Thus, it seems that individuals who act under stress aren't unaware that the most balanced choice is being assertive, which gives them the chance to defend their rights in a more systematic, non-directional and independent way. On the contrary, they resort to aggressive or passive behavior so they can to get out of the impasse they have fallen into, with a desire to return to a balanced state of calm as quickly as possible.
In collaboration with Helen Tarnaras, FIGHTSTRESS.
This article originally appeared on HuffPost Greece and was translated into English.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:24:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bridging Generations for Peace, a Passage for the Future of Diplomacy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fc98f7/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cjoshua0Ew0Ewalker0Cbridging0Egenerations0Efor0E0Ib0I77566580Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
Every year citizen diplomats, business influencers, municipal leaders and other luminaries from around the world converge at Sister Cities International's annual conference. Building on President Eisenhower's original vision, Sister Cities International is an organization dedicated to fostering world peace by building global relationships one city at a time. As technology and innovation are changing the landscape of how cross-cultural connections are made, there has never been a more important time to empower the next generation of leaders. This vision to the future includes understanding how new technology is disrupting and transforming the way these relationships are founded, built, and sustained. Governments, federal and local, are no longer the sole-proprietor of international relations but each individual is empowered to be a global citizen ambassador. In this modern era of diplomacy, we are witnessing what was once a top-down trickle of information closely curated by a few, to what has evolved into a two-way conversation that is had by many.
As a National Executive Committee Board Member and Chair of the Young Professional Taskforce, this year's 59th iteration being held in Minneapolis, Minnesota July 16-18 under the theme of "Bridging Generations for Peace" could not be timelier or more personally engaging, especially during these final days of Ramadan, a holy month of contemplation and peace for Muslims around the world. As evidenced by Minneapolis' most recent sister city Bosaso, Somalia these interfaith and intergenerational bridges of peace begin with each of us. While this pairing might seem random at first, Minnesota is actually home to the largest Somali population outside of Somalia. Famed for its Midwestern hospitality and easygoing nature, the Twin City will be hosting one of the most diverse and global gatherings of citizen diplomats at a critical juncture in world affairs. The hard work of building cultural and global bridges has never been more necessary in a world in which refugees from Somalia and now Syria continue to seek a better life outside of their homes.
Building on the success of last year's conference in San Jose, the heart of Silicon Valley, the role of technology in bridging generations and geography from new immigrants or foreign exchange students to their homes oceans away is undeniable. In addition, focusing on the next generation and instilling them with the pluralistic values of bridge-building between ethnic, faith, or national communities is ultimately the best investment for peace. Personally hearing the stories of what local Sister Cities communities are doing from elementary pen-pals that have never met but share a special bond to high-school homestay exchange always renews my faith in the power of citizen diplomats in an age of deeper international uncertainty. While questions about America's leadership role in providing international order continue to be main areas for presidential debate, American business, civil society, and educational leaders continue to embrace and lead us towards a more interconnected 21st century.
As evidenced by the tremendous growth of the parallel Youth Leadership Summit convened for high school students around the theme of "Peace through International Service," there is no shortage of interest from the next generation. The Summit is designed to engage the next generation of leaders and expose them to important global challenges that they will be facing. Often the highlight for many international dignitaries and leaders is meeting with these change makers of the future. Therefore as the world comes to Minneapolis, I hope all citizen diplomats that come through Sister Cities International can leave infused with the Midwestern hospitality and diversity of our Minnesotan hosts.
Joshua W. Walker, PhD is a proud Board Member of Sister Cities International, former Senior Advisor at the US Department of State, and current global citizen diplomat.
Follow Joshua W. Walker on Twitter: www.twitter.com/drjwalk
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:58:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shahidullah Shahid, Pakistani Defector To ISIS, Killed In U.S. Drone Strike In Afghanistan: Kabul Spy Agency</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fcc92d/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cshahidullah0Eshahid0Ekilled0Eafghanistan0In0I77648440Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KABUL, July 9 (Reuters) - The Afghan intelligence agency on Thursday said a third top Islamic State commander in Afghanistan was killed in a U.S. drone strike in the country's East this week.</Description>
        <MainBody>Previous Story
Next Story
Shahidullah Shahid, Pakistani Defector To ISIS, Killed In U.S. Drone Strike In Afghanistan: Kabul Spy Agency
Reuters
Updated:
2 hours ago
Shahidullah Shahid speaks during a press conference at an undisclosed location in Pakistan on February 21, 2014. (NASEER AZAM/AFP/Getty Images) | AFP via Getty Images
reddit
KABUL, July 9 (Reuters) - The Afghan intelligence agency on Thursday said a third top Islamic State commander in Afghanistan was killed in a U.S. drone strike in the country's East this week.
Shahidullah Shahid, a former member of the Pakistani Taliban who defected to the Islamic State and was operating in Afghanistan, was killed along with five militants on Tuesday, an official said.
"He wanted to expand IS operation in the country and with his death, it will have an impact on their activities," Hasib Sediqi, spokesman for the Afghanistan National Directorate of Security (NDS), told Reuters.
Shahid was killed in the same strike that killed Islamic State number two in Afghanistan Gul Zaman, along with 49 militants in the eastern Achin district of Nangarhar province where Islamic State militants have recently gained ground after pushing out the Taliban. One other commander was also killed.
A foreign official, who asked not to be named in order to be able to speak freely, has said the number of dead was believed to be closer to 25.
The Pentagon has confirmed several strikes in the Achin district of Nangarhar Province in the past week, with one precision strike on Tuesday, and two others on Monday.
"All of these strikes were conducted against individuals threatening U.S. and coalition forces," said Captain Jeff Davis, a Pentagon spokesman, without disclosing the identities of targets or the number of suspected dead.
Bordering lawless areas inside Pakistan, Nangarhar is one of the provinces where Islamic State militants are most active.
Islamic State loyalists, mostly former Taliban disillusioned by the movement's unsuccessful bid to return to power in Kabul, are often accompanied by dozens of foreign foreigners, hoisting black flags in several districts in the province.
A small but increasing number of mostly ex-Taliban militants are pledging allegiance to the Islamic State in Afghanistan, making them a target of deadly strikes there by the U.S. unmanned aircraft.
(Reporting by Jessica Donati and Hamid Shalizi, additional reporting by Phil Stewart in Washington Editing by Nick Macfie and Cynthia Osterman)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:49:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkey's President Finally Asks Premier To Form New Government Month After Election</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fcc934/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cturkey0Enew0Egovernment0In0I77646260Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>By Ercan Gurses</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkey's President Finally Asks Premier To Form New Government Month After Election
Reuters
Updated:
1 hour ago
Turkey's President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, right, and Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu salute the people after Erdogan showed a copy of Islam's holy Quran, in Kurdish language during a ceremony in Hakkari, Turkey, Tuesday, May 26, 2015.   (AP Photo) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
reddit
By Ercan Gurses
ANKARA, July 9 (Reuters) - Turkish Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu vowed a quick start to coalition talks on Thursday, after President Tayyip Erdogan instructed him to form a new government more than a month after an election deprived their AK Party of a parliamentary majority.
Opposition lawmakers had accused Erdogan, a founder of the AKP and Turkey's most popular -- and polarizing -- political figure, of deliberately delaying the process to push for a snap election he hopes might see the AKP regain a majority.
Erdogan gave Davutoglu the mandate to form a new government during a meeting in his palace in Ankara, the presidency said. Political parties now have 45 days to form a new government or face the prospect of a re-run.
The June 7 vote left the AKP unable to rule alone for the first time in over a decade, plunging Turkey into political uncertainty not seen since the 1990s and thwarting, for now, Erdogan's ambition to amass greater power.
Davutoglu told AKP members in parliament that he planned to hold a first round of coalition talks next week. Sources in his office said he would meet all three opposition parties and that the first round would be concluded by next Wednesday.
It is unclear whether the Islamist-rooted AKP is leaning toward forming a coalition with the rightist Nationalist Movement Party (MHP) or the main opposition left-leaning Republican People's Party (CHP).
Davutoglu said he planned to speak to CHP leader Kemal Kilicdaroglu first, CNN Turk reported on Twitter, adding talks could go into a second round following the Eid holiday this month.
While the nationalists are closer to the AKP ideologically, an alliance would likely scupper a peace process with Turkey's Kurdish minority, something Erdogan sees as part of his legacy.
Sources have told Reuters some of the AKP's top brass are leaning towards a grand coalition with the secularist CHP, although it remains to be seen whether that would be palatable to the AKP's rank and file, many of whom are devout Muslims.
Turkish Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu speaks at the Grand National Assembly of Turkey in Ankara, Turkey, on June 30, 2015. (AFP/Getty Images/Adem Altan)
'STICKING POINTS'
MHP leader Devlet Bahceli said on Thursday his party would do "whatever it takes" to avoid political instability, in an apparent sign of readiness to negotiate.
Apart from the Kurdish peace process, analysts say the AKP is likely to face two other key "sticking points" in the coalition talks: potential military intervention in neighboring Syria and the powers of the presidency in Turkey.
While the nationalists oppose talks with the Kurds, the CHP has come out against intervention in Syria. Ankara has been boosting its security presence along the Syrian border, where pro-government newspapers have said it is looking at creating a "buffer zone."
Neither the CHP nor the MHP has expressed support for the idea of a strong presidency championed by Erdogan and the AKP. Under Turkey's current constitution the president has relatively limited powers, a situation Erdogan has vowed to change.
Davutoglu said last month he would not accept any coalition negotiations that questioned the legitimacy of Erdogan's role.
The pro-Kurdish Peoples' Democratic Party (HDP), which entered parliament for the first time after breaching a 10 percent voting threshold in the June election, has ruled out joining a coalition with the AKP.
Speaker of the Grand National Assembly of Turkey and AKP member Ismet Yilmaz and Prime Minister Davutoglu wave at the Turkish Grand National Assembly in Ankara, Turkey, on July 1, 2015. (AFP/Getty Images/Adem Altan)
(Additional reporting by Ece Toksabay; Writing by Ayla Jean Yackley and David Dolan; Editing by Nick Tattersall and Catherine Evans)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:32:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>If You're Trying To Join ISIS Through Twitter, The FBI Probably Knows About It</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fcc93f/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cisis0Etwitter0Efbi0Eislamic0Estate0In0I77639920Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON -- Twitter has been "very cooperative" with FBI agents looking into individuals affiliated with the Islamic State and other terrorist organizations that use the social network to organize and inspire people within the U.S. to commit terrorist acts, FBI Director James Comey said Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>If You're Trying To Join ISIS Through Twitter, The FBI Probably Knows About It
Posted:
Updated:
2 hours ago
A Twitter sign hangs at the offices of Twitter Inc. in San Francisco. (AP Photo/Jeff Chiu, File) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
reddit
WASHINGTON -- Twitter has been "very cooperative" with FBI agents looking into individuals affiliated with the Islamic State and other terrorist organizations that use the social network to organize and inspire people within the U.S. to commit terrorist acts, FBI Director James Comey said Thursday.
Comey said many terrorist recruits first interact with overseas terrorists on Twitter. Affidavits filed by FBI agents in many recent terrorism cases have seemed to indicate that defendants charged in terrorism-related cases first came to the attention of federal authorities based on their Twitter activity.
"Someone signs up to be a Twitter follower of one of the ISIL feeds, and then one of the ISIL tweeters will follow them back. And then you'll frequently see them move to direct messaging on Twitter," Comey said Thursday of the Islamic State militant group also known as ISIS or ISIL. From there, they trade information so they can communicate in a separate forum that is encrypted and more secure, Comey said.
"Obviously Twitter is in the clear, direct messaging is not. But it's not encrypted," Comey said. "So we can, through the legal process, get access to it and see it."
The FBI director said Twitter has been "very good and thoughtful and hardworking at trying to shut down accounts" and said there is an ongoing discussion within the counterterrorism community about whether it makes sense to shut down Twitter accounts affiliated with terrorist organizations or to allow them to operate as a way to gather intelligence.
"Our experience is that Twitter has been very cooperative, and that cooperation has grown -- I say only half facetiously -- after ISIL threatened to kill their CEO , after they saw some of the darkness I see," Comey said. "They don't want people using Twitter to engage in criminal activity, especially terrorism."
Comey said the Islamic State has been very effective in using Twitter and other social media to communicate with potential recruits and spread its message online.
"They have a highly sophisticated media effort that utilizes all the tools and techniques of modern-day, social media Internet-based advertising," Comey said. "They're actually quite good at what they do."
That effectiveness, Comey said, has resulted in what he described as a "temperature change" in discussions with the technology sector about whether companies should have a way to break the encryption on their products to allow access for law enforcement officials. Comey has been pushing for a discussion about encryption since last fall, and on Wednesday testified before Congress about the challenges that encryption poses for law enforcement.
"What we're seeing now is living proof that social media works. It's the reason Twitter is worth billions of dollars. It is an extraordinarily effective way to sell shoes, or vacations, or terrorism," Comey said.
"Your grandfather's al Qaeda, if you wanted to get propaganda, you had to go find it. Find where Inspire magazine was and read it. If you want to talk to a terrorist, you had to send an email into Inspire magazine and hope that Anwar al Awlaki would email you back. Now all that's in your pocket. All that propaganda is in your pocket, and the terrorist is in your pocket. You can have direct communication with a terrorist in Syria all day and night, and so the effect of that -- especially on troubled minds and kids -- it works! It's buzz, buzz, buzz, buzz, buzz. It's the constant feed, the constant touching, so it's very, very different and much more effective at radicalizing than your grandfather's al Qaeda model."
Comey described the phenomenon as "the devil on your shoulder all day long, saying, 'Kill, kill, kill.'" He said what the federal government is doing to combat that messaging in social media is "clearly not enough," but added the FBI isn't in the messaging business.
Comey also told reporters on Thursday that the FBI disrupted potential terrorist attacks that could have been connected to the Fourth of July.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:21:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why This News Reporter Wants To Change The Way We Talk About Fertility</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fcc946/sc/14/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cegg0Edonor0Ewendy0Eburch0In0I76924740Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Why This News Reporter Wants To Change The Way We Talk About Fertility
Posted:
reddit
Before the sun even rises in Los Angeles, television news reporter Wendy Burch is often rushing down a freeway in her car, headed to report live at a developing scene. She is accustomed to working on the fly and pushing past yellow tape. She often ad-libs her report if theres not enough time to write a script.
But these days, if shes waiting around before going on the air, instead of talking to her peers about the crime investigation at hand, she says she talks to them about egg freezing.
Burch is 46-years-old and spent five years trying to conceive -- first the old fashioned way starting when she was 41, and then with the help of traditional in vitro fertilization (IVF) . But she was unsuccessful.
When you go through the world of fertility, you start off with a preconceived idea. You think you will maybe do one or two IVF rounds and before you know it, you will be pushing the baby in the stroller, she told The Huffington Post in an interview in L.A.
And then it doesnt work. I dont think any woman walks into a fertility clinic and says, You know, I think Ill have a donor egg and a surrogate. Its a process of elimination.
Despite discussing her long, frustrating process, Burch is outrageously funny. She jokes about hair extensions and breast augmentation and Botox. She is tall and has a deep laugh. The cadence of her voice gives away her 20-plus years on the air -- she speaks for a living.
When she arrives at The Huffington Post offices she is dressed in chic, black pants and black and gold high heels, but carries something much more expensive with her: her five-month old son, Brady.
Wendy Burch's son, Brady, at 16 weeks old.
Adopted as an infant and raised Mormon in Salt Lake City, Burch was a pageant girl. She was crowned Miss Salt Lake City in 1989 when she was 20-years-old but did not go on to win Miss Utah.
I lost out to the bitch that played the classical harp. How do you beat the classical harp? You dont, she said.
Her true talent was always storytelling. Long before she visited a local television station with her high school class, Burch was at the dinner table giving her family a full daily report on the neighborhood. I was probably the only 12-year-old who used the word allegedly, she said.
Touring the local TV station as a teen only strengthened her passion. She remembers walking away knowing that it was what she wanted to do for a living.
Fast forward 24 years and Burch has had jobs reporting the news in Salt Lake City, Eureka, Reno, Cincinnati, Dallas, Denver, Phoenix, New York and Los Angeles. She was 22-years-old in her first job when the news director of the station quit, making her one of the youngest news directors in the country.
Burch reporting on the California wildfires for KABC in Los Angeles, 2002.
Having children was always part of the plan. It was just a matter of meeting the right guy and having the right job and the perfect life, she laughed. But there was never a moment that I thought, 'Ill be one of those ladies that has nice shoes and no children.'
When her doctor talked to her about freezing her eggs at 36, Burch considered it but ultimately decided against it. It was much more expensive at the time and the success rate for pregnancy with frozen eggs a decade ago was only about 20-25 percent, she said.
She kept working and kept dating. She met Bradys father soon after she turned 40. He was tall, handsome and even though he was already a father, he was open to having more children.
When she was 41, they began trying to get pregnant -- but to no avail. Burch eventually started traditional IVF treatment, which is a procedure that uses the womans own eggs and either the sperm of her partner or the sperm of a donor to conceive. She was determined to make it work. But after a few years, money stretched thin.
An embryologist works on embryo at the Create Health fertility clinic in south London.
IVF fertilization can cost $12,000 or more per round. Thats before the necessary medications, which can be an additional $3,000 or $4,000.
I had very little left. I quit counting how much money Id spent after $50,000, Burch said. At this point she was 45.
According to Burch, the odds of a successful pregnancy using her own 45-year-old eggs were 2-3 percent. The odds of having a child with Down Syndrome was 1 in 30, and the odds of a miscarriage were 40-60 percent.
Adoption is something she thought about, but couldn't commit to.
Burch was adopted when she was only five days old. As an adult, she attempted to find her biological mother but with no success. Having a baby with her genes was something she had always craved. I wanted to feel that connection and I wanted it to be a part of me, she said.  I wanted the baby bump, the ultrasound and the first kick. I wanted the terror of labor and delivery. I wanted the whole thing.
One of the biggest problems Burch sees in the way that our society deals with fertility today is the silence.
I would look at a cover of a magazine with celebrity X, Y or Z at age 40-something and the headline would say: Miracle babies! I would think if it can happen to them, it can happen to me, Burch said.
Never in those articles did they mention IVF, frozen eggs or a donor egg. The odds are it wasnt just a miracle conception but that she sought out fertility specialists. There shouldnt be shame in that.
The donor egg entered the picture as a last resort. If she couldnt have a baby with her own eggs, Burch was warming up to the idea that she could still carry and give birth to a baby with the help of a donor.
There are two main ways to go about getting a donor egg. Egg donation agencies actively recruit young women who are willing to donate their eggs -- this is common on college campuses and there is a strong screening process in place.
Once the young woman decides that she wants to proceed, she goes through an in vitro cycle and has her eggs removed. They are either kept fresh or frozen. The person buying the eggs (usually in lots of six) covers all of the costs of the drugs and procedure. The donor is paid anywhere from $8,000 and $12,000.
If a woman buys the eggs fresh, the whole process can cost up to $30,000. Burch simply did not have that money. Buying a set of six eggs that have been frozen, however, was significantly cheaper. It would cost $10,000.
At this point, Burchs relationship was strained. She felt her fianc was running out of patience after nearly five years of trying to conceive. He had been through the weight gain and the shots and the hormones that made my head spin around. Anyone who has tried to get pregnant aggressively knows it is a huge strain on any couple, she said.
She scraped together the last $10,000 and promised her partner that this would be the last time they tried. She thought of it as her Hail Mary.
Choosing an egg is a lot like online dating, she joked. You go online and look at profiles but in this case, someone is definitely getting knocked up.
She looked through the profiles, sorting by height and ethnicity so that the baby would hopefully look like her -- but said she was looking for a more powerful sign.
She found a 22-year-old donor who was 5 feet 11 inches tall. When she read that the donor was studying to be a broadcast journalist, just like Burch, she felt that it was her sign. She compared the donors provided baby photo to her own and saw a sweet resemblance. Burch remembers feeling an overwhelming sense of peace and did not look at another profile.
She placed her order for six frozen eggs over the phone with a receptionist in Atlanta, Georgia, and they shipped out right away. But when they arrived, instead of finding six in the lot, there was one extra egg with no explanation. This would turn out to be lucky number seven.
The doctor fertilized all seven eggs with the male sperm and then monitored them over the next five days. Typically not all of the eggs will successfully fertilize. In Burchs case, six died off. And only one remained.
Today that one Hail Mary sits cooing in her arms and occasionally puts his whole mouth around her chin -- she is his favorite teething toy.
Wendy and Brady on a family trip to Las Vegas in June 2015.
"I look at him and no one can tell me hes not mine. I carried him. I gave him life, Burch said. Yeah its not my genes, but it doesnt matter. He was inside of me. Maybe his chin is going to be hers, but those are the things that are going to make him unique and will make me remember this person who I never knew who gave me the greatest gift Ill ever have.
Burch and her fianc split shortly after she became pregnant and she is raising Brady on her own.
"Is it perfect? No. Im a 46-year-old single mother who gets up at 3 a.m. and is on the air at 5 a.m. But Im home with Brady before noon. People always talk about motherhood turning their lives upside down. I look back now and I think my life was upside down. Brady and motherhood turned it right side up. Everything is where its supposed to be," she said.
The decision to have children is something every woman has to consider on her own. For Burch, the answer was easy -- but the journey certainly was not. Her biggest mission today is helping to educate young women about the benefits of freezing their eggs when they are young.
The cost of freezing eggs can vary greatly from doctor to doctor and amongst fertility centers. The Southern California Reproductive Center , where Burch was a patient for five years, says the general ballpark for freezing eggs runs just under $10,000 and that the medication required for treatment can cost an additional $3,000-$5,000.
Companies like Apple and Facebook made headlines in 2014 when they announced that the cost of egg freezing would be a covered benefit. While many celebrated the decision and what it means for women in the workplace, many critics summarized the decision as just a way to keep women working tirelessly through their childbearing years .
Others wrote about the risks associated with the procedure and the factors that people aren't talking about .
Two years ago, the American Society for Reproductive Medicine (ASRM), an organization representing hundreds of fertility clinics in the U.S., lifted the experimental label from the procedure, but stated that there was still not enough known about the egg freezing procedures safety, efficacy, cost-effectiveness, and emotional risks. They suggested that widespread use may "give women false hope and encourage women to delay childbearing."
Despite the conflicting reports, Burch still wishes she had frozen her eggs -- even at age 36, even when it was more expensive and often less successful than it is today.
The hope is that one day, when ambitious career-driven women graduate from college, the gift from their families isnt going to be a nice watch or a car. Its going to be a gift certificate to go freeze their eggs, she said.
As women, we are afforded so many more opportunities now. We should take advantage of each one. But the thing that hasnt changed is our internal mechanical engine. Your body hasnt changed to keep up with the opportunities out there. This can give everyone a little bit more time.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:12:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Through Your Lens: Beautiful Beaches Around The World</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fc5a7f/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cbeautiful0Ebeaches0Earound0E0In0I77614480Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
The WorldPost's " Through Your Lens " series brings you stunning photos taken by social media users in a different country around the world every week. This week, we explore beautiful beaches around the world.
From the white sands of Saint Martin, to a surfer's heaven in Australia or an urban retreat in England, everyone has ways to make their beach experiences their very own. Whether you're preparing for your upcoming beach holiday or chained to your desk, these photos are bound to spark your wanderlust.
Check out the WorldPost on Instagram for more vibrant photography from across the globe. Tag your Twitter and Instagram photos with #WorldPostGram so we can feature them in our next post.
Jul 5, 2015 at 9:58am PDT
Turks and Caicos
Jul 5, 2015 at 10:40pm PDT
Maho Beach, Saint Martin
Jul 8, 2015 at 3:19am PDT
Surfer's Paradise, Queensland, Australia
Mar 18, 2015 at 10:26am PDT
Zandvoort Beach, The Netherlands
Jul 7, 2015 at 5:28am PDT
Sanasana, Fiji
Nov 14, 2014 at 5:45am PST
Red Beach, Santorini, Greece
Jul 7, 2015 at 2:05pm PDT
Bondi Beach, Australia
Jul 8, 2015 at 6:31am PDT
Kubu Beach, Bali
Jan 27, 2015 at 1:25am PST
Maya Bay, Thailand
Jul 8, 2015 at 5:39am PDT
Vila Nova de Gaia, Portugal
Jul 3, 2015 at 4:35pm PDT
Pink Sands Beach, Bahamas
Jul 6, 2015 at 9:23am PDT
Pantai Tirang, Indonesia
Jun 23, 2015 at 12:10pm PDT
London, England
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:55:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saudi Prince To Donate 10,000 Houses And 10,000 Cars As Part Of Major Charitable Commitment</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fbfc40/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cprince0Ealwaleed0Ebin0Etalal0Ehouses0Ecars0E0In0I77621320Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Days after Saudi Prince </Description>
        <MainBody>10 Charity Apps That Make Giving Part of Living
of

VolunteerMatch"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
Like an online dating site, VolunteerMatch pairs your volunteer interests with similar opportunities in your area. From grant writers to pro bono jobs, you can browse the variety of options or tailor your search for a specific cause or organization.
Cause.it"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
A nifty rewards program for volunteering, Cause.it give you a certain amount of points for an everyday act of advocacy, volunteering, or social activism. In return, you can redeem your points at the participating local businesses, scoring shopping deals for your good deed.
PayItForward"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
A small action can have a big impact. Thats the idea behind this app, which suggests a daily act of altruism and encourages you to pay it forward, by inspiring others when you share good deed through Twitter, Facebook, or email. To see the impact of a single act of kindness, you can view the apps worldwide map, a feature which demonstrates completed good deeds all over the globe.
Kiwanis International"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
A networking app that connects you to local Kiwanis clubs, this program provides a variety of service projects in areas such as education, poverty, and disaster relief. User-friendly, this app tracks both your time volunteered and dollars raised; with its fun Piggy Bank option, it also allows you to record virtual dollars you could donate by giving up luxury expenditures (like that extra chai latte).
Maranatha Volunteers International"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
Making global service more accessible, the Maranatha app utilizes videos and photos to broadcast available projects across the world. Primarily dedicated to constructing high-demand buildings, such as hospitals and schools, the Maranatha organization successfully mobilizes volunteers through its app.
The Salvation Army Bellringer"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
This musical app lets you virtually experience the bell ringing tradition by inventing your own Salvation Army song. Use the 12 musical notes to create a unique tune or play a favorite holiday jingle. As a fun option for those too busy to ring in person, the Salvation Army Bellringer app also includes an option to make a donation to the Salvation Army.
Charity Miles"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
Giving you extra incentive to exercise, the Charity Miles app rewards your workouts by donating 10 per mile when you bike, and 25 when you walk or run to the charity of your choice.
Donate A Photo"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
Johnson &amp; Johnsons creative app harnesses the charitable potential of our shutter-happy society. For every photo you share through the app, Johnson &amp; Johnson donate $1 to the charity you choose from its trusted list of causes.
Shout For Good"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
This self-described micro donation platform from Australian creators allows you to shout, or virtually pledge, an everyday item to the non-profit or cause of your choice. For example, shouting a cup of coffee donates its actual dollar amount, making giving a simple part of your everyday routine.
Sidekick Cycle"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
Partnering with the Global Gaming Initiative, a company that connects mobile games with charity causes, Sidekick Cycle is an obstacle course game where you ride a bike through an African landscape, earning coins for tricks and stunts. 50 percent of in-app purchases contribute to the nonprofit World Bicycle Relief, which provides much-needed bikes to people in South America, Africa and Southeast Asia. Charity Miles
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:47:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>$500 Million Down the Drain in Syria, and McCain Keeps Flailing</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fcc948/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cjon0Esoltz0Cfive0Ehundred0Emillion0Edown0Ib0I7764280A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>You, the American taxpayers, paid approximately $8.3 </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
You, the American taxpayers, paid approximately $8.3 million dollars per "moderate" Syrian fighter that the U.S. could train to fight ISIS.
That's right.  Yesterday, Secretary of Defense Ash Carter admitted that, despite the $500 million appropriated by Congress to find and train moderate Syrian opposition, the United States was only able to find 60 fighters they believed were ready to fight solely against ISIS, with no possibility of defecting or taking their fight to Bashar al-Assad instead.  Sixty fighters.  Some $8.3 million per fighter.  Half a billion dollars total.  You want to talk Pentagon waste?  Try that one on for size.
Of course, most of the media, as the media are wont to do, will praise the "foresight" of John McCain (and Lindsey Graham), who panned the idea in January of this year.  According to The Hill at that time:
"It's very weak and will not have significant impact," Sen. John McCain (R-Ariz.) told reporters following an hours long, closed-door briefing on the program.
He also criticized Defense Department officials for telling potential recruits that they could only fight ISIS and not the regime of Syrian President Bashar Assad, calling it the "most ridiculous thing."
"This strategy makes Pickett's Charge look well thought out," Sen. Lindsey Graham (R-S.C.) told reporters. He called the training effort "militarily unsound" and "immoral."
Indeed, if that's all Sen. McCain ever said, he'd be 100-percent right.  The whole concept of finding Syrian rebels who purely want to fight ISIS and forget about Bashar Assad and everyone else, like Iraqi security forces, is a pipe dream.  This was bound to be a failure.
But it is that exact point that unravels every other stupid argument that John McCain (and Lindsey Graham) have made about Syrian rebels and why we needed to aid them.
Namely, they aren't pure.
McCain either didn't consider that, ignored that, or was just flat-out ignorant of that when he incessantly whined about sending heavy arms to those rebels.
As early as 2012, Senators McCain, Graham, and Joe Lieberman (remember him?) were calling for arms to be shipped over to Syrian rebels via other Arab states.  In a Washington Post op-ed , the trio wrote that we should "directly and openly provide robust assistance to the armed opposition, including weapons, intelligence and training. ... American help should go to those groups that reject extremism and sectarianism in both word and deed."
Take note: McCain (and Graham and Lieberman) argued not only that we should send arms and more but that it is possible to send it to those with pure hearts who won't join extremists.
About a year later, my former division commander in Iraq, Gen. Martin Dempsey, warned of the complicated nature of Syria in a letter to Rep. Eliot Engel, who was taking John McCain's position.
Gen. Dempsey, who has always refused to be bullied by McCain, wrote :
Syria today is not about choosing between two sides but rather about choosing one among many sides. It is my belief that the side we choose must be ready to promote their interests and ours when the balance shifts in their favor. Today, they are not.
Indeed, Gen. Dempsey had good reason to be wary.  In 2013, the CIA began shipping arms.  Shortly thereafter, reports began to surface that the some of the arms mistakenly ended up in the hands of ISIS.  Meanwhile, other Syrian insurgents were reportedly defecting to or forming alliances with al-Qaeda's al-Nusra Front.   As VoteVets.org long argued, in the region, the enemy of my enemy is sometimes my enemy.
And it pierced McCain's core argument: that we, the U.S., could actually find and help moderate groups who would never, ever embrace extremists.  Here were his beloved "moderates" joining an al-Qaeda group.
All of this mess and confusion led to a very uncomfortable exchange that Sen. McCain had with Sean Hannity, of all people:
Hannity: Let me ask you about what your colleague Rand Paul said about it this morning. He said, "It's a mistake to arm them. Most of the arms that we've given the so-called 'moderate' rebels have wound up in the hands of ISIS because ISIS simply takes it from them or it is given to them and we mistakenly actually end up giving it to some radicals."
McCain: Has Rand Paul ever been to Syria? Has he ever met with ISIS? Has he ever met with any of these people?
Hannity: I'm not trying to cause a fight, sir.
McCain: No, no, we're going to have a fight because it's patently false. This is the same Rand Paul that said we didn't want to have anything to do with anything to do in the Middle East, by the way. I don't want to get in a fight with him at all, but it's not true. I know these people. I'm in contact with them all the time, and he is not. He is not.
Take note again.  Right here, despite all the evidence, John McCain says it's preposterous to think that "moderate" Syrian rebels would shift alliances.  He assures us that anyone who claims that is a liar.
Yet, just days before, McCain was pressed on whether we could trust that Syrian moderates would focus on fighting ISIS for us and not joining them to fight Assad. McCain said :
Obviously, there are some risks, but what's our other option here? If someone who says they ... don't want to do it, because we can't trust the Free Syrian Army, then what is your option, sir and ma'am, in how we are going to attack ISIS in an effective fashion?
That's quite a shift from the other interview!
Days later, President Obama signed a bill to arm the rebels and spend half a billion dollars to train them.  Not long after, even more elements of the "Free Syrian Army" disbanded, then joined up with Islamist groups , reportedly including ISIS .
And that brings us all the way back to the beginning of this year, with John McCain grandstanding, saying it is "ridiculous" to think that you can tell Syrian moderates whom to take the fight to or, by extension, whom they should fight alongside with.
Quite literally, "2015 John McCain" and "2012 John McCain" have opposing views of the Syrian rebels.  First, "2012 John McCain" swore to us that we could find rebels who would not embrace extremists. Then "2014 John McCain" swore to us that he knew these rebels, and that they would direct their fight where we needed them to -- namely, against ISIS.  Then "2015 John McCain" said anyone who thinks we can tell Syrians whom and where to fight is "ridiculous."
Well, "2015 John McCain," say hello to "ridiculous" "2012 John McCain."
I hope the media remember all of this when Sen. McCain gets up on his soapbox in the coming days.  Sen. McCain isn't prescient.  He consistently contradicts his own past statements and beliefs, depending on what's happening at any particular time.  He's a flailing mess.
All that said, this isn't a partisan issue.  There are Democrats, like Rep. Engel, who unwisely join with John McCain.  And there are Republicans and Democrats who consistently were against this kind of ill-conceived involvement. I recommend that the media contact them: Senators Rand Paul, Chris Murphy, Mike Lee or Tom Udall .
Follow Jon Soltz on Twitter: www.twitter.com/jonsoltz
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:13:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek Voters Present Obstacle to Unelected Authorities' Efforts to Transform Europe</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fbfc42/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cmark0Eweisbrot0Cgreek0Evoters0Epresent0Eobst0Ib0I77639460Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The landslide "No" vote of the Greek people to reject further austerity marks a turning point in a battle over the future of Europe that has been going on since the world financial crisis and recession. Of course the European authorities (which include the European Central Bank, the European Commission, the IMF, and the eurogroup of finance ministers) still have the power to wreck the Greek financial system and economy, and force Greece out of the euro. But this is something that they </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
The landslide "No" vote of the Greek people to reject further austerity marks a turning point in a battle over the future of Europe that has been going on since the world financial crisis and recession. Of course the European authorities (which include the European Central Bank, the European Commission, the IMF, and the eurogroup of finance ministers) still have the power to wreck the Greek financial system and economy, and force Greece out of the euro. But this is something that they do not want to do , and that Washington (which has influence in European capitals) does not want them to do either.
As a result of this dilemma for the creditors, they have opted for a strategy of regime change , which they have pursued since shortly after the Syriza government was elected. In the run-up to the referendum, they deployed their most destructive weapon in this war to topple the elected government: For the first time in six years of austerity-prolonged depression, the European Central Bank (ECB) forced a closure of Greek banks. This was a deliberate decision made on Sunday, June 28, and combined with the statements of European officials, it was clear that the purpose of this move was to intimidate Greek voters into voting "Yes," i.e., to accept the creditors' last offer.
By voting "No" with a large margin (61-39 percent), Greek voters demonstrated several important things. First, that they were not easily intimidated. Second, that despite a massive propaganda campaign by what the New York Times described as "the oligarch-dominated news organizations," they were not easily fooled, either: they knew who was to blame for their suffering in the run-up to the vote. Third, they understood who was responsible for the never-ending depression, and that the European authorities were not offering a way out of it. The European authorities had severely underestimated Greek national pride and solidarity, and the Greek people's understanding of basic economics.
With no sense of irony, the creditors are now trying to blame the Greek government for the serious damage to the Greek economy caused by the ECB's forced closure of the banking system. But this is a continuation of what the European authorities have been doing for more than five years. The reason that the Greeks need so much debt relief is because the European authorities have shrunk the economy by more than 25 percent and drastically reduced Greece's ability to pay. Now that the European authorities -- not the Greek government -- have pushed the economy back into recession, it will make Greece's debt situation even worse. The IMF just published a paper showing that the Greek debt is not sustainable, yet the European authorities have refused to discuss debt relief.
The European authorities are demanding more pension cuts and regressive tax increases, as well as primary (excluding interest) budget surpluses that would make it difficult, if not impossible, for the Greek economy to have a recovery any time soon that would be strong enough to make a serious dent in Greece's 26 percent unemployment rate. In short, they are not offering Greeks any light at the end of a long tunnel. This is more evidence, if any were needed, that they are not bargaining in good faith.
The Greek government is in a tough spot. Since they are committed to remaining within the eurozone, their only option is to change Europe. But the eurozone officials have their own vision for a new Europe, and it is one with less of a social safety net, and with lower pensions, less spending on health care, weaker unions, and a smaller welfare state. Hence the collision: Greece is an obstacle on their path to a New Europe. But it is proving to be a stubborn one.
This article was distributed by Tribune Content Agency on July 9, 2015 and published by the Bradenton Herald and other newspapers. If you would like to reprint it, please let us know by replying to this message.
Follow Mark Weisbrot on Twitter: www.twitter.com/MarkWeisbrot
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:04:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S.-Venezuela Dtente Still Going -- for Now</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fbfc43/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cmark0Eweisbrot0Cus0Evenezuela0Edetente0Estil0Ib0I7763880A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>For a couple of months I have </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
For a couple of months I have noted the unprecedented diplomatic thaw between the U.S. and Venezuela. Now it is getting some attention in the major media.
"The United States and Venezuela have embarked on their most extensive dialogue in years in an attempt to improve their acrimonious relations, according to a senior U.S. administration official," Reuters reported this week, citing an unnamed source.
On Thursday afternoon, July 2, just as everyone (including much of the media) was skipping town for the three-day holiday weekend, Secretary of State John Kerry issued a statement sending his "best wishes to the people of Venezuela as you celebrate 204 years of independence on July 5."
"I am pleased that we have found common cause in our support for Haiti's elections, reconstruction, and development, as well as in our shared commitment to the Colombian government's ongoing efforts to achieve a lasting peace," Kerry said. "I look forward to further cooperation between our people and governments as we seek ways to improve a historically strong relationship that has endured for nearly two centuries."
Remarkably, the statement contained no criticisms or remarks that might be seen as insulting to the Venezuelan government.  I cannot remember seeing a comparable statement about Venezuela from the U.S. Secretary of State for at least 14 years.
Of course, not everyone is happy with this sudden onset of the Age of Aquarius. As I noted last month, efforts to sabotage the diplomatic effort were under way rather soon after it began. There will be more such efforts, and some of the reactions of the right to the Obama administration's opening to Venezuela could provide a preview.
Carl Meacham, director of the Americas Program at the well-funded, center-right think tank Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) was a senior foreign policy advisor and staffer for former Senator Richard Lugar, the six-term Republican from Indiana who was very influential on foreign policy. It was Lugar's office that torpedoed President Barack Obama's 2010 attempt to restore ambassadorial relations with Venezuela. So Meacham, who is well connected with State Department officials and others in Washington who are involved in Latin America, is likely to have a good idea what the strategy is for people within and outside the Obama administration who do not want normal relations with Venezuela.
This article was published by Al Jazeera America on July 8, 2015. Click here to read the complete article.
Follow Mark Weisbrot on Twitter: www.twitter.com/MarkWeisbrot
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:00:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>John Kerry Says No Deal Yet In Iran Nuclear Talks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fc3151/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cjohn0Ekerry0Eiran0Enuclear0Etalks0In0I776320A80Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Iran and six world powers still have not reached a deal on Tehran's controversial nuclear program, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry said Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Iran and six world powers still have not reached a deal on Tehran's controversial nuclear program, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry said Thursday.
"We will not rush, and we will not be rushed," Kerry told reporters at a press conference in Vienna, where negotiators are meeting to try and agree on limits to Iran's nuclear activities in exchange for sanctions relief.
"Some of the tough issues remain unresolved," he said. "But those decisions must be taken very soon."
If negotiators fail to reach a deal by 12 a.m. EST Thursday, the amount of time that the U.S. Congress can take to review any final accord will double to 60 days, which would delay the lifting of U.S. sanctions on Iran. A longer waiting period would also give opponents of the deal more time to marshal their arguments and win new allies, which could weaken the deal's overall odds of survival.
"We are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever," Kerry told reporters on Thursday. "But we should not get up and leave simply because the clock strikes midnight."
Kerry did not specify whether the deadline would be extended if negotiators fail to reach an agreement by midnight. The deadline has been extended several times in recent days.
Iran and the so-called P5+1 group -- the U.N. Security Councils five permanent members, plus Germany -- have been negotiating for months over the terms of a nuclear deal. The sides are still wrangling over the the pace and scope of sanctions relief to Iran, as well as how the deal will be monitored, Reuters reported earlier Thursday.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius told journalists in Vienna on Thursday that the talks would continue at least into Thursday night and Friday morning, according to France 24. It wasn't clear whether Fabius was referring to Friday morning in Vienna or in Washington, D.C. Vienna is six hours ahead of Washington.
Federica Mogherini, foreign policy chief of the European Union, indicated in comments to CNN that the deadline still looms over the negotiations. "We are very close but if the important historical, political decisions are not made in the next hours, we won't (have) an agreement," she said. "That moment of truth will come extremely soon, next hours I think."
Iranian President Hassan Rouhani said Thursday the talks had entered their final stages." But Iranian Foreign Minister Javad Zarif, like Kerry, said that negotiators were not rushing to meet a deadline. "We're working hard, but not rushed, to get the job done. Mark my words; you can't change horses in the middle of a stream," Zarif wrote on Twitter ahead of Kerrys remarks.
In Washington, Sen. Bob Corker (R-Tenn.), the chairman of the U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee, said the continuation of talks would not pose any problems for Congress.
"I'm very happy that we're not rushing to a place and taking shortcuts on the remaining issues that are left," Corker told reporters. "That is, to me, a very good thing."
White House spokesman Josh Earnest said the talks can continue "as long as there's tangible evidence that there's a constructive effort underway."
"The fact that we've been very clear about our expectations for a final agreement makes it unlikely that the talks will drag on for many more weeks," he told reporters in Washington. "But, again, I wouldn't speculate on the outcome."
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:43:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>If You Love Animals, Here Are 5 You Shouldn't Ride</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fbe054/sc/32/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Canimals0Eyou0Eshouldnt0Eride0In0I77622860Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Trekking through the jungle atop an elephant or frolicking through the waves on the back of a dolphin can seem like the epitome of adventure, joy and harmony with nature. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Trekking through the jungle atop an elephant or frolicking through the waves on the back of a dolphin can seem like the epitome of adventure, joy and harmony with nature.
Unfortunately, for many animals forced into the tourism industry-- or assaulted in the wild by thrill-seeking humans --  the experience is quite the opposite. Here are a few animals that you shouldnt be riding.
Elephants
Shutterstock
Riding an elephant is a bucket-list item for tons of animal lovers drawn to the majestic, intelligent creatures, but elephant fans are frequently unaware of the cruelty behind their picturesque Instagram photos.
Elephants used for rides are so overworked theyre dropping dead from stress and exhaustion, a veterinarian for Vietnams Dak Lak Elephant Conservation Center told The Dodo in May .
Captive elephants in other countries don't fare any better. In 2011, photojournalist Brent Lewin photographed two workers in Burma beating a restrained baby elephant during a training session before the animal was transported to Thailand. Workers regularly tie up, abuse and starve young wild elephants in a process known as the crush -- intended to "break the elephants spirit and make them submissive to humans, according to NBC. The photographer noted that the elephants mother was nearby and had to be restrained because she charged over, trying to aid her offspring.
Sometimes, the parents of young elephants are just killed altogether. Poachers frequently gun down the adult elephants in a herd to make capturing the calves easier, according to a 2014 report by wildlife trade monitoring network TRAFFIC.
Even after the initial training, life as an elephant used for rides can be grueling. Overworked captive elephants are regularly deprived of social contact with other animals, chained up for long hours and left with untreated injuries, according to Humane Society International.
Even travel agents are realizing that elephant riding isnt all its cracked up to be. Last year, Intrepid Travel cut elephant rides out of its tour packages after conducting extensive research into the industry through a partnership with the nonprofit group World Animal Protection.
If you want to see elephants up close on your travels, consider visiting a wildlife sanctuary, where elephants live in a setting that resembles their natural habitat.
Dolphins
Shutterstock / Volodymyr Krasyuk
Swim-with-the-dolphins (SWTD) attractions -- some of which allow participants to ride a dolphin by holding onto the animals dorsal fin -- have been decried by numerous animal welfare groups as unsafe and inhumane for the highly intelligent marine mammals. For animals that swim over 40 miles a day in the wild and engage in complex social interaction with other dolphins, captive life in the entertainment industry is miserable.
Captive dolphins are forced to swim in endless circles in artificial habitats, interact with unfamiliar dolphins and other species and perform behaviors that are unnatural and in some cases painful, writes World Animal Protection. Captive dolphins can often be seen exhibiting clear signs of psychological stress, like swimming in circles or floating unmoving near the water's surface, the organization notes.
Outside of the U.S., most SWTD programs use dolphins captured from the wild, a process so traumatic that it can result in dolphins dying from stress, according to Humane Society International.
Thats not to say life is better for captive-bred dolphins. A former trainer from the Bahamas, speaking with The Dodo , said he witnessed mothers in captivity intentionally drowning their newborn offspring. He said his colleagues suspected the mother dolphins did this to prevent their young from living a life in captivity.
Manatees
Getty Images
While its illegal to disturb or harass a manatee under the Florida Manatee Sanctuary Act , people occasionally attempt hitch a ride on the gentle sea cows anyway.
Getting caught doing so can land you a $500 fine or up to 60 days in jail , but those arent the only reasons you should refrain from hopping aboard a manatee. Humans attempting to interact with manatees can alter the creatures behavior for the worse, says the Florida nonprofit Save the Manatee Club .
The animals might end up changing their regular routes to avoid humans, potentially traveling to dangerous areas where they can be hurt or injured by boats, the group says. Additionally, by swimming after a manatee, you could be unintentionally chasing a mother away from her baby, or vice versa.
Ostriches
ELizabethHoffmann
Ostrich racing and riding is a major tourist attraction in South Africa, but the Association of British Travel Agents says tour operations should not offer or support this activity.
Ostriches simply arent built to support the weight of a human being, and this practice is likely to harm the physiology of the animals and have negative welfare implications, according to ABTA animal welfare guidelines.
Dogs
VirtualWolf/Flickr
OK, so dogs arent wild animals, but they also arent equipped to carry the weight of a human rider -- even a child. While YouTube is filled with plenty of videos of kids riding dogs, and it can look cute,  it also poses a risk for your pup.
"Children riding on the back of their family dog is very dangerous for the animal, and the child, even if you have one of the giant breeds as your family pet, Dr. Sarah Bassman of Cornell Universitys College of Veterinary Medicine told The Stir in 2010. The muscles in a dog's back are not strong enough and not designed to carry a passenger and could be damaged by this activity.
Supervise young children around dogs, and teach your kids that dogs arent horses.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:41:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>James Comey Says FBI Disrupted Plans To Kill Americans Likely Over July 4th Holiday</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fbfc45/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cjames0Ecomey0Ejuly0E40In0I77630A520Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON -- The FBI arrested more than 10 people over the past four to six weeks in an effort that Director James Comey said disrupted plans to kill people on American soil, likely in connection with the July 4th holiday.</Description>
        <MainBody>James Comey Says FBI Disrupted Plans To Kill Americans Likely Over July 4th Holiday
Posted:
reddit
WASHINGTON -- The FBI arrested more than 10 people over the past four to six weeks in an effort that Director James Comey said disrupted plans to kill people on American soil, likely in connection with the July 4th holiday.
Comey told reporters at FBI headquarters on Thursday that all of the people arrested were connected in some way to the Islamic State. But not all of them were necessarily charged with terrorism-related offenses, he said. Comey declined to provide further details or give out specific names or locations of potential attacks.
Also on HuffPost:
FBI Directors Through The Years
of


Federal Bureau of Investigation Director James Comey addresses the Intelligence and National Security Summit at the Omni Shoreham Hotel September 19, 2014 in Washington, DC. After one year on the job, Comey outlined his vision for the future of the FBI, including a bigger focus on cyber and the creation of a new intelligence office within the bureau.  (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)
Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) Director Robert Mueller testifies during a hearing before the Senate Judiciary Committee June 19, 2013 on Capitol Hill in Washington, D.C. (Photo by Alex Wong/Getty Images)  Source: FBI
Former FBI director Louis Freeh stands on Capitol Hill on April 13, 2004 in Washington, D.C. (Photo by Alex Wong/Getty Images)  Source: FBI
Former FBI Director William Sessions (right) testifies about the 1993 raid on the Branch Davidian compound in Waco, Texas as former Associate Attorney General Webster Hubbell (left) looks on during congressional hearings on Capitol Hill in Washington, D.C. (LUKE FRAZZA/AFP/Getty Images)  Source: FBI
(Photo By Bill Peters/The Denver Post via Getty Images)  Source: FBI
William H. Webster, former director of both the FBI and CIA, poses on the red carpet upon arrival at a salute to FOX News Channel's Brit Hume on January 8, 2009 in Washington, D.C. (Photo by Brendan Hoffman/Getty Images)  Source: FBI
John Edgar Hoover, Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) of the United States, gives a speech during a testimony before the senate internal security committee, on November 17, 1953, in Washington. (BOB MULLIGAN/AFP/Getty Images)  Source: FBI
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:35:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>German Official Jokes About Trading Greece For Puerto Rico</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fbe057/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cgermany0Egreece0Epuerto0Erico0In0I77632960Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble on Thursday joked about offering U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew an exchange of Greece for Puerto Rico. </Description>
        <MainBody>Served from: Jan. 26, 2009 to present   Served under: President Barack Obama
Served from: July 10, 2006 - Jan. 20, 2009  Served under: President George W. Bush
Served from: Feb. 3, 2003 to June 29, 2006  Served under: President George W. Bush
Served from: Jan. 30, 2001 to Dec. 31, 2002  Served under: President George W. Bush
Served from: July 2, 1999 to Jan. 20, 2001  Served under: President Bill Clinton
Served from: Jan. 10, 1995 to July 2, 1999  Served under: President Bill Clinton
Served from: Jan. 22, 1993 to Dec. 22, 1994  Served under: President Bill Clinton
Served from: Sept. 16, 1988 to Jan. 17, 1993  Served under: Presidents Ronald Reagan and George H.W. Bush
Served from: Feb. 3, 1985 to Aug. 17, 1988  Served under: President Ronald Reagan
Served from: Jan. 22, 1981 to Feb. 2, 1985  Served under: President Ronald Reagan
Served from: Aug. 6, 1979 to Jan. 20, 1981  Served under: President Jimmy Carter
Served from: Jan. 23, 1977 to Aug. 4, 1979  Served under: President Jimmy Carter
Served from: May 8, 1974 to Jan. 20, 1977  Served under: Presidents Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford
Served from: June 12, 1972 to May 8, 1974  Served under: President Richard Nixon
Served from: Feb. 11, 1971 to June 12, 1972  Served under: President Richard Nixon
Served from: Jan. 22, 1969 to Feb. 11, 1971  Served under: President Richard Nixon
Served from: Dec. 21, 1968 to Jan. 20, 1969  Served under: President Lyndon B. Johnson
Served from: April 1, 1965 to Dec. 20, 1968  Served under: President Lyndon B. Johnson
Served from: Jan. 21, 1961 to April 1, 1965  Served under: Presidents John F. Kennedy and Lyndon B. Johnson
Served from: July 29, 1957 to Jan. 20, 1961  Served under: President Dwight D. Eisenhower
Served from: Jan. 21, 1953 to July 29, 1957  Served under: President Dwight D. Eisenhower
Served from: June 25, 1946 to Jan. 20, 1953  Served under: President Harry S. Truman
Served from: July 23, 1945 to June 23, 1946  Served under: President Harry S. Truman
Served from: Jan. 1, 1934 to July 22, 1945  Served under: Presidents Franklin D. Roosevelt and Harry S. Truman
Served from: March 4, 1933 to Dec. 31, 1933  Served under: President Franklin D. Roosevelt
Served from: Feb. 13, 1932 to March 3, 1933  Served under: President Herbert Hoover
Served from: March 4, 1921 to Feb. 12, 1932  Served under: Presidents Warren G. Harding, Calvin Coolidge and Herbert Hoover
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:33:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia Released Selfie PSAs, And They're Oh-So-Russian</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47fbe05a/sc/14/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A90Crussian0Eselfie0Epsa0In0I7754480A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>If Russia has one thing to say about the </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
If Russia has one thing to say about the selfie revolution sweeping the globe, it's: stop with the duck face, or die.
The Russian Interior Ministry released a series of selfie PSAs earlier this month, warning the photo-happy about the dangers of the documentarian trend. The ads, which look like caution signs often found near construction sites or on machinery, warn against (apparently?) commonplace practices like taking a selfie with a firearm, from the top of an electrical tower or in front of an oncoming train.
"The Russian Interior Ministry is concerned about the increasing incidence of trauma and even death when trying to make a unique selfie," a website featuring the new advertisements reads. "We have tried to visualize, in the form of icons, the most high-risk cases in the creation of selfies... to warn citizens against the undue risk of a memorable picture."
"When a person tries to photograph himself, his attention wanders, he loses his balance, he doesn't look around and doesn't feel danger," the Ministry continues.
The country has seen hundreds of injuries due to selfies since the beginning of the year, an aide to Russia's interior minister told Agence France-Presse . Russian police said at least ten people have been killed taking selfies in 2015.
Shockingly, even the most inventive selfie methods featured in the ads have some solid footing. The Verge notes that a woman accidentally shot herself in the head while taking a photo in May. Two Russian teens were electrocuted while taking the "ultimate selfie" on top of a train, with one girl catching on fire "as if she had exploded."
Take a look at at some of the PSAs below. And remember, safety over selfie, even if you do lose a few Instagram followers.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
