<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="irishtimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:48:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge in Irish nanny case calls for baby autopsy explanation </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/judge-in-irish-nanny-case-calls-for-baby-autopsy-explanation-1.2279714</Link>
        <Description>Aisling Brady McCarthy  charged over death of baby in her care in Massachusetts    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Judge in Irish nanny case calls for baby autopsy explanation
Aisling Brady McCarthy  charged over death of baby in her care in Massachusetts
Aisling Brady McCarthy, from Co Cavan, is accused of killing a 1-year-old Massachusetts girl in her care two years ago. She has pleaded not guilty. Photograph: AP Photo/Charles Krupa, Pool
Beverly Ford
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 22:49
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 22:48
A judge in the case of Irish nanny Aisling Brady McCarthy told prosecutors she wants to speak with the attorney for the Massachusetts Medical Examiners Office to find out why an autopsy review that could clear Ms McCarthy of murder has been delayed.
Friends and relatives embraced a smiling Ms McCarthy (37) outside the courtroom after hearing the news but declined to comment.
Ms McCarthy, who is originally from Co Cavan , has pleaded not guilty to attacking 12-month-old Rehma Sabir at her familys home in Cambridge near Boston on January 14th, 2013, leading to her death two days later.
Nanny accused of babys murder in new bail plea
Were hopeful, Ms McCarthys attorney, Melinda Thompson said after she was asked whether the delay indicated that there was a problem with the initial autopsy report on Rehma.
A change in that report could clear the way for a murder charge against Ms McCarthy to be dropped.
A trial in the case is set for October.
The nannys defense team claims the infant was seriously ill and suffered broken bones in the weeks before her death when she was not in Ms McCarthys care.
It was the second time in two months that a review of the autopsy performed on the child has been delayed.
A prosecutor told the court it was unclear when that report would be completed, prompting Judge Maureen Hogan to request that an attorney for the state medical examiners office appear before her within the next 10 days to two weeks.
There have been a number of delays throughout the case.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:38:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Defence Forces emails to security firm leaked</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/defence-forces-emails-to-security-firm-leaked-1.2279605</Link>
        <Description>Italian company Hacking Team had 400GB of data downloaded from its files    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Defence Forces emails to security firm leaked
Italian company Hacking Team had 400GB of data downloaded from its files
Among the leaked emails, files and digital records were four emails sent between members of the Defence Forces and employees of the company. Photograph: Getty Images/iStockphoto
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 21:38
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 21:38
Emails sent between members of the Defence Forces and a company specialising in hacking and eavesdropping have been leaked online.
A Defence Forces spokesman said it could not comment on the matter but confirmed goods or services had been bought from the Italian-based company, Hacking Team.
The firm was hacked and 400GB of data downloaded from its files, some of which has since appeared online.
The companys Twitter account was also hacked in what appears a deliberate attempt to undermine or embarrass it.
Among the leaked emails, files and digital records were four emails sent between members of the Defence Forces and employees of the company.
The first leaked email is dated July 3rd, 2012, and relates to organising a meeting between Defence Forces personnel and the companys account manager in Prague, Czech Republic , following an earlier meeting,
Other emails were exchanged in April 2014 in which a meeting at the end of 2013 was mentioned. In the most recent email, dated May 28th last, a named Defence Forces member tells a Hacking Team employee he looked forward to meeting him the following week.
While the emails relate mostly to the logistics around organising meetings, the company employee at one point queries whether the Defence Forces planned to purchase solutions as previously suggested.
The emergence of the material brings into the spotlight the Defence Forces contacts with entities in the private sector from which hacking and spying technology can be purchased.
The leaked material makes references to what are purported to be Hacking Team clients, including the FBI, US Drug Enforcement Administration and security agencies in Egypt , Morocco , Nigeria and Kazakhstan .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:20:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman killed after Galway road traffic crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/woman-killed-after-galway-road-traffic-crash-1.2279564</Link>
        <Description>Three other people taken to hospital with non life threatening injuries   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Woman killed after Galway road traffic crash
Three other people taken to hospital with non life threatening injuries
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 21:20
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 21:20
Garda are appealing for witnesses after a woman was killed in a road crash in Co Galway on Thursday.
Garda in Oranmore are investigating the incident which occurred on the N6, approximately 3kms from Craughwell on the Oranmore to Craughwell Road, at approximately 4.20pm.
The woman who was killed was in her mid-50s and was the sole occupant of the car she was driving when it collided with another car.
She was pronounced dead at the scene.
The three occupants of the other car were removed to University Hospital Galway with what were described as non life threatening injuries.
The road is currently closed to facilitate Garda Forensic Collision Investigators. Local diversions are in place.
Garda are appealing for witnesses to the collision to contact them at Oranmore Garda Station on 091-388 030 or on the Garda Confidential Line 1800 666111 or any Garda Station.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:41:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stagg’s view on lone parent’s change shared by  Labour figures</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/stagg-s-view-on-lone-parent-s-change-shared-by-labour-figures-1.2279529</Link>
        <Description>Very mixed views in  party on Joan Burton’s policy over    job activation measure    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Staggs view on lone parents change shared by  Labour figures
Very mixed views in  party on Joan Burtons policy over    job activation measure
Video
There were heated exchanges in the Dil in a row over lone parent welfare cuts and comments by Labour chief whip Emmet Stagg in an email criticising the cut introduced by his party leader, Tnaiste Joan Burton.
In a leaked email that caused embarrassment to the Labour leadership, party whip Emmet Stagg expressed the view that the policy initiative of his party leader was a bad decision. Photograph: Dara Mac Dnaill/The Irish Times
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 20:46
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 20:41
Labour whip Emmet Staggs opposition to Tnaiste Joan Burtons policy of transferring 30,000 single parents from the lone parents allowance is shared by other Labour TDs and Senators.
Parliamentary party members said on Thursday there are very mixed views within the party on the policy. Like Mr Stagg, other TDs and Senators have received complaints in correspondence and at their clinics from constituents who have lost the lone parents allowance.
In a leaked email that caused embarrassment to the Labour leadership, Mr Stagg expressed the view that the policy initiative of his party leader was a bad decision.
Burton in heated exchanges with SF over lone-parent cuts
Seized upon
The email was seized upon by Opposition parties and was brought up by Fianna Fil leader Michel Martin during Leaders Questions in the Dil.
Both Fianna Fil and Sinn Fin have said the design of the job activation measure was flawed as there was a lack of childcare for parents who wished to return to work.
In addition, they argued that to qualify for the two allowances that would bring their incomes substantially up, lone parents needed to work 19 hours each week. Many faced situations where their employers were unwilling to give them extra hours.
In his email, Mr Stagg stated: I simply fail to see how cutting the income of the very ones who are making a real effort to improve the lot of their families and themselves helps in some way to get out of the poverty trap.
It clearly has the opposite effect. I will continue to press for a reversal of this bad decision.
Strongly defended
However, other members of the party have strongly defended the measure as a positive one, including the Dublin Mid West TD Joanna Tuffy .
She said on Thursday that the initiative was a good one and that many of those working parents could increase their allowances by a substantial amount if they succeeded in working 19 hours.
Ms Burton, for her part, accused Fianna Fil of spending 1 billion each year on the allowance without bringing forward any activity measure that would help single parents to escape poverty.
Senior Labour sources pointed out on Thursday that Mr Stagg and all of the parliamentary party had voted for the lone parent changes that they were now railing against. So they were for them before and then they are against them now.
Separately, a spokesman said the previous scheme had simply not worked.
Prior to these reforms, a lone parent could have received the payment until their youngest child turned 18, or 22 if in full-time education.
That was the State effectively saying it had no ambition for these parents, no desire to take the necessary steps to help them return to work, training and education and build a better financial future for themselves, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:31:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Call for inquiry into HSE’s handling of vulnerable teen’s legal action</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/call-for-inquiry-into-hse-s-handling-of-vulnerable-teen-s-legal-action-1.2279524</Link>
        <Description>€1 million spent on legal fees in case of girl  detained  in English psychiatric unit   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Call for inquiry into HSEs handling of vulnerable teens legal action
1 million spent on legal fees in case of girl  detained  in English psychiatric unit
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 20:36
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 20:31
Independent senator Jillian van Turnhout has called for an investigation into the Health Service Executives handling of a case involving a teenage girl who was detained in a specialist psychiatric unit in England against her wishes for more than a year and a half.
Ms van Turnhout said the public had a right know why in the region of 1 million was spent on legal proceedings, which could have provided an appropriate placement for the young woman in Ireland .
It is very important that we investigate the handling of this case and ask the Minister and relevant authorities why these decisions were taken and in whose best interests were they acting? Ms van Turnhout said.
Woman (18) detained in UK psychiatric facility makes poetic appeal
State agencies continually highlight legal costs as an issue, but you need only go to court to see some of the cases they are challenging, she said.
Earlier this week a High Court judge has granted the womans plea for her return to Ireland following a series of court hearings.
Ms van Turnhout, a member of the Joint Oireachtas Committee on Health and Children, said she will ask the committees chairman Jerry Buttimer TD that relevant authorities be held to account over the case.
The young woman, who has a borderline personality disorder, is understood to have returned home and will reside in a psychiatric facility on a voluntary basis.
She has spent almost all of the last four years in various psychiatric units in Ireland and England.
In response to a query over the case, the HSE released a brief statement in which it said it involved difficult and complex circumstances which were still subject to oversight by the courts.
Patients who require specialised treatment not available in this country can be referred to mental health services abroad where clinically indicated. Patients being treated abroad often have a complex and broad range of conditions, the statement said.
The case itself was before the courts on numerous occasions. Last March, the High Court directed an arrangement should be put in place for her return to Ireland by June 12th last.
The HSE subsequently brought further proceedings arguing her circumstances had changed since the March order.
Those circumstances included a view of some doctors that she could not be kept safe in the Irish services and should remain in the UK unit, where high levels of security could be put in place.
Earlier this week, however, lawyers for the HSE, the woman, her parents and her court-appointed guardian all agreed she had the necessary legal capacity to make decisions regarding her treatment and should be returned to Ireland.
The case has focused attention on the practice of sending vulnerable young people with specialised needs abroad for care and treatment.
Latest available figures show Irish authorities spent about 3.5 million in 2013 on facilities outside this jurisdiction for 10 vulnerable young people due to a lack of services here.
Childrens rights campaigners have argued over many years that these services should be available in Ireland.
The HSE has pledged to develop services to ensure no Irish citizen should need to be sent overseas for a care placement, and the number being placed abroad has been falling over recent years.
But latest figures indicate there is still a lack of specialised treatment programmes for some children with emotional problems or challenging behaviour.
Health authorities have previously pointed out that children placed abroad represent a tiny proportion of more than 6,000 young people in the care or health system.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:21:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heritage group hopes Irish investors buy Harry Clarke works</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/heritage-group-hopes-irish-investors-buy-harry-clarke-works-1.2279522</Link>
        <Description>Chairman says stained glass windows an integral part of State’s history   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Heritage group hopes Irish investors buy Harry Clarke works
Chairman says stained glass windows an integral part of States history
A national heritage group has appealed for Irish investors to purchase a collection of stained glass church windows created at the studio of Dublin artist Harry Clarke. Image: Fonsie Mealy Auctioneers.
Finnian Curran
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 20:21
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 20:21
A national heritage group has appealed for Irish investors to purchase a collection of stained glass church windows created at the studio of Dublin artist Harry Clarke .
Damian Cassidy , chairman of the National Conservation and Heritage Group, said the windows should be considered a national treasure and all efforts must be taken to keep them in Ireland .
We would regard these beautiful pieces of artwork as national treasures and we are appealing for any Irish investor who may be interested to bid for them, he said.
Mr Cassidy said it was imperative the windows are kept in Ireland as they were an integral part of the States history and heritage.
The collection - estimated to be worth up to 25,000 - was created at the Harry Clarke studio. The illustrator and stained glass artist died in 1931.
He created 160 windows during his career including The Eve of St Agnes - which is now in the Hugh Lane Gallery - and six windows for Bewleys caf on Grafton Street.
The windows being auctioned were made for churches in Ireland, Wales and New Zealand but were never installed. They were inherited by the artists family and are to be broken up and sold individually.
Among the collection are two windows depicting St Francis Xavier which were commissioned for an unknown church in Co Kilkenny but were never collected.
A three-panelled piece measuring about 8ft by 2ft has a pre-auction estimate of 7,000-9,000 while an image entitled Saint Francis Xavier preaching in the Orient has an estimate of 2,500-3,000.
One piece from the collection, depicting St Francis Loyola, has already been sold to Carlow College, where it is installed in its library.
The windows will go on public view at Fonsie Mealy Auctioneers saleroom in Castlecomer, Co Kilkenny, from Sunday, July 19th.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:14:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NI Minister for Sport  Carál Ní Chuilín criticised over resignations</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/ni-minister-for-sport-car%C3%A1l-n%C3%AD-chuil%C3%ADn-criticised-over-resignations-1.2279517</Link>
        <Description>Minister insists evaluation of leadership would  restore public confidence in Sport NI   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
NI Minister for Sport  Carl N Chuiln criticised over resignations
Minister insists evaluation of leadership would  restore public confidence in Sport NI
Northern Irelands Minister for Sport Carl N Chuiln said: Rather than hiding from challenges or denying that the challenges exist, I am dealing with the challenges, she said. Its called leadership. File photograph: Steven McCaffery/PA Wire
Topics:
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 20:14
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 20:14
Northern Irelands Minister for Sport has said her department is not dysfunctional and that she is still mystified by the resignation of nine Sport NI board members earlier this week.
During an appearance before the Stormont Culture, Arts and Leisure scrutiny committee, Carl N Chuiln faced significant criticism and had to bat away calls for her to resign.
Rather than hiding from challenges or denying that the challenges exist, I am dealing with the challenges, she said. Its called leadership.
The Minister on Thursday appointed an interim executive leadership team, made up of senior civil servants, to conduct a confidential and independent employee survey, a cultural audit and an evaluation of the leadership at Sport NI - a departmental arms length body.
Whistle-blowing allegations
She said the action followed a series of whistle-blowing allegations over leadership at Sport NI regarding a culture of fear, sexism and gender bias, harassment and bullying, and also regarding application of the HR processes within the organisation.
Ms N Chuiln strongly defended her intervention, telling MLAs that doing nothing was not an option.
To do nothing for people in distress was not an option for me, she said.
The DUPs William Humphrey asked Ms N Chuiln if the department was dysfunctional under her leadership.
The Minister replied: Absolutely not.
We have a situation where the chief executive of National Museums Northern Ireland has stepped aside in another arms length body of your department, Mr Humphrey said.
You have the whistle-blowing in Sport NI. You have the difficulties within the department around the inquiries around Casement Park and now you have nine members of the Sport NI board who have resigned - we dont know the position of the two that are on holiday.
Mr Humphrey also raised concerns that the appointment of civil servants to Sport NIs board had made the arms length body an integral part of her department.
You have failed
MLA Basil McCrea, of the NI21 party, claimed the Ministers position was untenable.
I think that you have failed. Completely and utterly, he said.
I think your department has failed. All of those people that you are now saying there are serious problems with - you, your department, your senior officials, have failed those people because you had a review in 2013 where you said there were problems and you were going to fix them. You said in 2014 you were going to fix them and you are back to the same thing again.
You should consider your position. You are not doing your job.
Rejecting the attacks on her leadership, Ms N Chuiln accused some MLAs of playing to the cameras.
She insisted the new mechanisms would restore public confidence in Sport NI and help staff members through a challenging period.
PA
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:44:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Couple who occupied  council offices moved up housing list </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/high-court/couple-who-occupied-council-offices-moved-up-housing-list-1.2279485</Link>
        <Description>Council says it does not know when it can house couple  as there are 8,500  people on list   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Couple who occupied  council offices moved up housing list
Council says it does not know when it can house couple  as there are 8,500  people on list
South Dublin County Council  told Mr Justice Paul Gilligan it cannot say when it will be able to house Alan Murphy and his partner Kelly Gilsenan (both above), as there are 8,500 people on its housing list. Photograph: Courts Collins
Aodhan O'Faolain
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 19:46
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 19:44
A homeless couple who camped out at the offices of South Dublin County Council in protest about their accommodation situation have been moved up the local authoritys housing list, the High Court has heard.
The council told Mr Justice Paul Gilligan it cannot say when it will be able to house Alan Murphy and his partner Kelly Gilsenan , as there are 8,500 people on its housing list.
The council had obtained an injunction against the couple after they, along with several supporters, refused to leave the councils offices in Tallaght.
They remained there for two days until the court granted the order directing them to leave the premises. The couple later gave an undertaking to the court to comply with the terms of the order.
Priority raised
When the matter came to court on Thursday, Carol OFarrell BL, for the council, said the couples priority on the housing list had been raised as it was now accepted they formed a family. Mr Murphy has a six-year-old child who suffers from asthma.
Counsel said it was not known when they would get housing as there are 8,500 people on the housing list.
While the couple had been co-operating with the council, it was concerned they were not doing enough to help themselves by seeking private accommodation for which they would be entitled to a housing assistance payment, counsel said.
The couple told the court the most recent temporary accommodation they were provided with was filthy with damp walls, damp ceiling and blood on the sheets. They asked the court to strike out the injunction but the judge refused.
Undertakings renewed
They both renewed their undertakings to abide by the terms of the injunction.
The judge also suggested they contact an individual, whose name was provided by the council, who could help provide them with private accommodation.
The only other option they had was to wait in hotels and hostels until the council provided them with housing, he said.
There were many thousands of others also waiting to be housed, he added.
Adjourning the case to the end of the month, the judge said he hoped those individuals in court who were advising Mr Murphy and Ms Gilsenan would continue to help them.
The injunction was granted late last month after the court was told the couple refused an offer of temporary emergency accommodation from the local authority because it was not suitable for their needs.
The couple said they ended up sleeping in a tent after they became homeless after they had to leave the private accommodation they had been renting when that property was sold.
They said they were unable to obtain other accommodation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:29:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bacteria in sea prompts ‘do not swim’ warning in Salthill</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/bacteria-in-sea-prompts-do-not-swim-warning-in-salthill-1.2279472</Link>
        <Description>Investigations into cause of contamination being carried out  by Galway County Council   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Bacteria in sea prompts do not swim warning in Salthill
Investigations into cause of contamination being carried out  by Galway County Council
The promenade at Salthill in Galway. Galway City Council has advised against sea swimming in Salthill until further notice. Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times.
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 19:36
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 19:29
Galway City Council has advised against sea swimming in Salthill until further notice, after high levels of a bacteria were detected in the water.
The elevated levels of intestinal enterococci, which can cause gastro-intestinal illness, were detected at the Blackrock and Ladies beaches in Salthill in samples taken on Monday. Full results became available on Thursday, it said.
The city council said the cause was unknown and investigations were continuing.
Dog bites, deer droppings and public health protection
Galway has been the only Irish city to enjoy blue flag beach status in recent years, mainly due to its population size and the impact of the Mutton Island sewage treatment plant.
The local authority said it posted do not swim notices at both beaches on Thursday afternoon following advice from the HSE.
Testing for intestinal enterococci is one of two new microbiological parameters which have been monitored by local authorities since 2011 on advice from the Environmental Protection Agency .
The city council said that results of re-sampling would be available on Saturday. It said samples taken from Grattan Road beach and Silver Strand nearby were well within guidelines for safe swimming.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:21:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trial shown footage of protesters at Shell compound</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/circuit-court/trial-shown-footage-of-protesters-at-shell-compound-1.2279469</Link>
        <Description>Footage  appeared to show some protesters and security officers involved in scuffles   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Trial shown footage of protesters at Shell compound
Footage  appeared to show some protesters and security officers involved in scuffles
The jury in the trial of two Shell protesters were shown video footage of the protest where up to 70 protesters entered a Shell compound in north Mayo
Anton McNulty
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 19:23
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 19:21
The jury in the trial of two Shell protesters were shown video footage of the protest where up to 70 protesters entered a Shell compound in north Mayo .
The video footage was captured by CCTV at the compound and by security officers policing the site when the protesters entered the Shell compound at Aughoose , Pollathomas in Co Mayo on June 23rd, 2013.
Gerry Bourke of Aughoose, Pollathomas Co Mayo and Liam Heffernan of Kilnagear, Belcarra, Castlebar , Co Mayo are on trial in Castlebar Circuit Criminal Court both charged with violent disorder and criminal damage as a result of the protest.
Corrib gas project protesters on trial for criminal damage charge
They have both pleaded not guilty.
The protest took place at approximately 1pm on Sunday, June 23rd, 2013 and the CCTV footage showed the protesters arriving at the main gate of the compound, where a play was taking place.
The protesters then moved to the Lenamore side of the compound near the seashore where the video footage showed the protesters removing the heras fencing and entering the site. The video footage also appeared to show the protesters and security officers scuffling with each other.
As well as the charge of violent disorder, Mr Bourke is accused of causing damage to heras fencing and Mr Heffernan is accused of causing damage to wooden railings in the compound.
The third day of the trial before Judge Petria McDonnell also heard evidence from Ionat Ghita, a former security officer who worked for the Senaca security group which was also known as IRMS. Mr Ghita told the court he was responsible for downloading the CCTV footage of the protest and giving it to the garda.
When questioned by Mr Brendan Nix , SC for Mr Bourke, he said he knew Tipperary man Michael Dwyer and Hungarian national Tibor Rvsz who both worked as security for IRMS on the Corrib gas project in 2008, and were killed by Bolivian police in April 2009.
When asked if the killings were discussed by the security staff working on the Corrib project, he replied, Not at all, nobody spoke about it. He added all he knew about the killings was from what was in the newspapers.
A Romanian national, Mr Ghita said he had no military experience and no longer worked with the Senaca Group .
He also said he had no knowledge of any of the security workers on the Corrib gas project wearing badges with Operation Solitaire Shield and Operation Glengad Beach on their uniform.
The trial continues.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Plight of the bumblebee: climate change puts insect at risk</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/science/plight-of-the-bumblebee-climate-change-puts-insect-at-risk-1.2279122</Link>
        <Description>Researchers say  bees  dying  out as they fail to migrate north to escape rising temperatures    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Plight of the bumblebee: climate change puts insect at risk
Researchers say  bees  dying  out as they fail to migrate north to escape rising temperatures
Bumblebees in Europe and North America may be heading for a wipeout as a result of climate change. They are not migrating northwards to keep in temperate conditions. Photograph: Nick Ansell/PA Wire
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 19:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 19:00
Bumblebees in Europe and North America may be heading for a wipeout as a result of climate change . They are not migrating northwards to keep themselves in temperate conditions and are dying out in the overheated south.
Canadian and US researchers tracking them say the insects, vital for pollinating our food crops, have already lost 300km from the southern fringe of the range in which the can live. And things can only get worse for them as average temperatures rise.
Irelands bees are also at risk, with habitat loss the big threat, said Dr Una FitzPatrick, an ecologist at the National Biodiversity Data Centre .
Surprising alliance: Naomi Klein praises  Pope Francis
About a third of all bee species are threatened with extinction here, she said. The insects are loosing the battle against habitat loss caused by humans.
We know they are in decline and why they are in decline and how to fix it. We need to provide them with habitat and food. They are looking for the same things we are, a home and a way to feed the family, she said.
The bees and other pollinator insects are essential as food crops and wild plants often cant pollinate themselves. It is about the services they are providing, it is worth 53 million a year in services to agriculture, Dr FitzPatrick said.
The very real threat to bumblebees over wide swaths of the northern hemisphere is apparent in the study led by Jeremy Kerr from the University of Ottawa and colleagues. The results are published in the journal Science.
Historical data
They used historical data covering 110 years up to 2010 collected in Europe and North America looking at 67 bumblebee species. Their database holds about 423,000 observations.
They also took into account non-climate factors such as land use and pesticide application. They found the bees did not advance northward as temperatures rose over the period by about 2.5 degrees. This was true for both continents.
But because the bees are not moving away from areas that have become too warm for them, their total range is now shrinking and by a measurable amount.
Warming has shrunk their southern range limits by about 300km. So the band the bees can successfully occupy is getting narrower all the time, the reports authors say.
The researchers do not know why the bumblebees have failed to shift their ranges north, but their behaviour increases their vulnerability to climate change, the authors say.
In Ireland the bumblebees are on the move, but in a westerly direction, Dr FitzPatrick said.
There are 20 different bumblebee species in Ireland. Their range change is to move west due to loss of habitat in the east and centre of the country, she said.
The Burren is far and away most important habitat for them at the moment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kenny says Greece must make ‘realisable’ proposals</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/kenny-says-greece-must-make-realisable-proposals-1.2279432</Link>
        <Description>Taoiseach denies EU has shown more ‘solidarity’ to creditors than Greek people   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Kenny says Greece must make realisable proposals
Taoiseach denies EU has shown more solidarity to creditors than Greek people
An Taoiseach Enda Kenny spoke about the Greek situation during a  visit to the Irish pavilion at Expo Milano.  Photograph: Stephen Collins/Collins Photos
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 18:44
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 18:43
Taoiseach Enda Kenny has denied that the European Union has shown more solidarity to Greeces creditors than to the countrys people.
Asked about an observation that just 10 per cent of the 294 billion loaned to Greece in the last five years went into the Greek economy, whilst the remaining 90 per cent went to paying off creditors, the Taoiseach said: That suggests that the payment of the money was not followed by the necessary reforms to make it work.
In Ireland we were able to buy out the 18 billion of IMF loans inside a four-year period . . . so the opportunity to restructure and reform is there for every country including Greece.
Tsipras under pressure at home as Athens races to finalise proposals
Mr Kenny said the Greeks were in a very difficult position and that it was important the proposition Athens made to the EU for a new programme made economic sense and was achievable.
If the euro zone is to support and encourage Greece to continue being a member then it [the Greek proposal] . . . has to be realisable and achievable, he said.
Greece is currently facing a very stark choice  the country is bust, the banks are bust, they have neither liquidity nor solvency and if you dont have those, then you dont have credit and you are blocked out of the markets.
Mr Kenny said the choice for Greece was between going down the road of introducing their own currency or availing of the opportunity to reform and restructure and have an achievable set of goals.
That would mean that monies would be available to them through the ESM and the emergency liquidity funds, that solvency and liquidity would be put back into the banks and that credit would be restored.
Expo Milano
The Taoiseach was speaking in Milan during a visit to the Irish pavilion at the Expo Milano exhibition, prior to a meeting on Saturday with his Italian opposite number, prime minister Matteo Renzi .
Asked how he saw events evolving over the next few days, the Taoiseach confessed that he did not know.
It is hard to speculate what the actual outcome [of Sundays European council meeting] will be. I would hope that the situation is now so dire in Greece, and such a stark choice has be faced there, that the proposition that has to come will make economic sense and will be realisable in terms of its reform.
At the moment, Greek banks have neither solvency nor liquidity and that situation is having a terrible impact on ordinary people throughout the country. So, I would like to see that ended, and ended by negotiation.
As for Expo itself, Mr Kenny was full of praise for the Irish pavilion, arguing that its 6 million overall cost was money well spent.
Expo represents a brilliant opportunity for Ireland to promote what it does best, namely food, hospitality and tourism. Over the next few months, 1.25 million people are expected to visit the Irish pavilion . . . I would say that it was a good decision by the government to participate in Expo Milano . . .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:31:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heuston Station  services  delayed over freight train  fault</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/heuston-station-services-delayed-over-freight-train-fault-1.2279426</Link>
        <Description>Irish Rail says refunds will be issued as services  disrupted  for up to an hour     </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Heuston Station  services  delayed over freight train  fault
Irish Rail says refunds will be issued as services  disrupted  for up to an hour
Train services operating to and from Heuston Station were subject to serious delays on Thursday evening when a freight train developed mechanical faults in Kildare. File photograph: Nick Bradshaw
Finnian Curran
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 18:33
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 18:31
Train services operating to and from Heuston Station were subject to serious delays on Thursday evening when a freight train developed mechanical faults in Kildare.
In the latest update issued shortly before 6pm, Irish Rail said the freight train was in the process of being removed from the section of tracks.
All train services in and out of Heuston were delayed for up to an hour due to the fault.
Update: significant delays continuing to services to/from Heuston. Freight train at Kildare expected to be cleared within 20 minutes.
 Iarnrd ireann (@IrishRail) July 9, 2015
@IrishRail How do a whole cohort of non Twitter users, older generation, find out updates about train delays? No announcement in 45 mins!
 Oliver Skehan (@oliskehan) July 9, 2015
@IrishRail please get it together. Train broken down on Waterford line for 2 hours. No communication with your customers is bad for business
 Una Herlihy (@UnaHerlihy) July 9, 2015
Irish Rail has apologised to affected customers and tweeted that refunds will be issued.
Customers took to Twitter to complain about a lack of communication between the company and commuters.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:00:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Burglary complaint leads gardaí to cannabis plant </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/district-court/burglary-complaint-leads-garda%C3%AD-to-cannabis-plant-1.2279384</Link>
        <Description>Man in court after gardaí responding to his call over burglary  discover  smell of cannabis   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Burglary complaint leads garda to cannabis plant
Man in court after garda responding to his call over burglary  discover  smell of cannabis
Christoph Bardges of Cappamore, Kells, Co Kerry, went home on January 15th, 2014 to find there had been forced entry. He called  garda but  when they arrived they got an odour of cannabis, Cahersiveen District Court heard. File photograph: Gareth Fuller/PA Wire
Anne Lucey in Cahersiveen
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 18:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 18:00
A 30-year-old man who called garda after his apartment was burgled ended up in court himself after garda who arrived initially found a strong smell of cannabis.
Christoph Bardges of Cappamore, Kells , Co Kerry, had returned to his then residence at Gortaforia, Kells, at about 11pm on January 15th, 2014 to find there had been forced entry and disturbance of his rented accommodation.
He called the Cahersiveen garda to inform them of the unlawful entry.
However, when garda arrived they got an odour of cannabis, Cahersiveen District Court was told on Thursday.
Mr Bardges was co-operative with garda and showed them a cannabis plant growing upstairs, Insp John Brennan outlined.
The plant was valued at 800.
Guilty plea
Mr Bardges pleaded guilty on Thursday to possession and cultivation of cannabis on the date of January 16th. He had no previous convictions.
Padraig OConnell said his client, originally from Leipzig, suffered from depression .
He was growing the plant for his own use, he had told him, as he found the price of 30 for two grammes a rip-off, the solicitor said.
He purchased the seed. He is no longer growing it, Mr OConnell told the judge, who asked where his client got the plant.
Mr Bardges was questioned by Judge James OConnor as to whether he was still using cannabis and he said he was, but only at weekends, and was buying it. During the week he tried to occupy himself with woodwork.
He is the unfortunate victim. He is the one who was burgled and he is now before the court, Mr OConnell pleaded.
Judge James OConnor agreed to adjourn the matter for a report from the Probation Service next October.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:49:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dangerous driving charge for speeding to save relationship</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/district-court/dangerous-driving-charge-for-speeding-to-save-relationship-1.2279369</Link>
        <Description>Judge hears that ‘Mills and Boon’ romance had no storybook ending   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Dangerous driving charge for speeding to save relationship
Judge hears that Mills and Boon romance had no storybook ending
A 21-year-old south Kerry man who sped from his bed in the early hours  after it  came to light his girlfriend might be with another man, has ended up before the court on a charge of dangerous driving
Anne Lucey in Cahersiveen
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 17:49
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 17:49
A 21-year-old south Kerry man who sped from his bed in the early hours of the Feast of the Epiphany, after it suddenly came to light his girlfriend might be with another man, has ended up before the court on a charge of dangerous driving.
And the relationship with the girlfriend had no Mills and Boon storybook ending, Cahersiveen District Court was told.
Conor Daly of Spunkane, Waterville was at home in bed in the early hours of January 6th, 2013 when he was alerted to the fact his girlfriend was leaving a disco with another man, Cahersiveen District Court was told
At 3am and at high speed at Gurranebane, Cahersiveen he overtook the car of the other young man, and slammed on the brakes , Inspector John Brennan outlined.
Paul ODonoghue, his solicitor, said: He was in bed at home as he had work the next morning and he got a phonecall saying Dalys girlfriend is leaving the disco with another man! the solicitor said.
He decided needed to confront them. She was in the car with the other gentleman. He went ahead so he could stop the car and speak with the lady. He was quite upset, the solicitor continued.
There was no collision, no accident, Mr ODonoghue added.
At this point, Judge James OConnor asked where was the evidence of dangerous driving  the charge was way out of proportion he told the State.
However before finalising the matter the judge asked the young mans solicitor: No one wants half a story! What happened with the girl? the judge enquired.
Judge OConnor was told that it was no storybook ending.
It was not like a Mills and Boon novel. He got out of the car. There were words  robust and frank, Mr ODonoghue said.
Unfortunately, the relationship ended there and then, on the spot, Mr ODonoghue added.
His client was now working in the UK and hoping to go to New Zealand , the solicitor added.
The State agreed to withdraw the charge of dangerous driving, reducing it with the lesser charge of driving without reasonable consideration, and the matter has been adjourned for mention to November 12th by which time Mr Daly is to make a 1,000 contribution to the court poor box, at which point he may avoid any conviction.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:39:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Company law being examined over Clerys closure, Dáil told </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/company-law-being-examined-over-clerys-closure-d%C3%A1il-told-1.2279360</Link>
        <Description>Tánaiste says workers have to be looked after first after  criticism from SF’s Peadar Toibin    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Company law being examined over Clerys closure, Dil told
Tnaiste says workers have to be looked after first after  criticism from SFs Peadar Toibin
Sinn Fin TD Peadar Toibin alleged duplicity was at the heart of the Clerys debacle. All the [workers] have received from the Labour Party so far is a two-faced response, he added. File photograph: Alan Betson/The Irish Times
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 17:43
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 17:39
The Government was undertaking a very detailed examination of company law following the closure of the Clerys store in Dublin, Tnaiste Joan Burton said.
First of all, we have to look after the workers, she added.
Ms Burton said Minister of State Ged Nash had produced an important and significant report setting out in clinical detail the sequence of the history of events that happened.
Clerys worker: I assumed  laws would stop a firm  closing like this
It also set out how and where company law operated in Ireland at the moment, she added.
She said she had met a number of the Clerys workers, many of whom were there for 40 years and more. Workers should get those redundancy and insolvency entitlements, which were their right in law, as soon as possible.
The Tnaiste was replying to Sinn Fin TD Peadar Toibin , who said duplicity was at the heart of the Clerys debacle.
Almost a month had passed since staff and concession holders were turfed out on to the street by liquidators.
All they have received from the Labour Party so far is a two-faced response, he added.
Tactical insolvency
He said while Mr Nashs report provided a textbook analysis of a tactical insolvency delivered with merciless precision, astoundingly the Minister of State had said there was nothing to see there.
If the State is on the hook for millions of euro with regard to the redundancies of workers who have been treated in a despicable manner, how in Gods name can anybody accept there are no deficiencies in the legislative framework in this State? Mr Toibin asked.
The truth is that the legislation in this State, under the stewardship of the Government, incentivises ruthless employers to go down the route of separating out companies so that they can use tactical insolvency to insulate themselves from their responsibilities to this State and to their workers.
Lack of experience alleged
Ms Burton replied that if Mr Toibin was suggesting legislation should be used in some way to up-end the entitlement of workers, she would suggest he was advocating such a tactic out of a lack of experience of dealing with issues that arose in the Clerys case.
Mr Toibin replied: Nobody on the planet has made that suggestion.
Ms Burton accused Mr Toibin of throwing a lot of stuff around like snuff at a wake.
Mr Toibin said multiple companies in this country had separated out their firms in an effort to insulate their investments from the responsibilities they had to their staff.
The fact is that both the State and the workers are getting stuffed over and over again, he added.
We have complete inertia from the Labour Party with regard to its response.
It was clear, he said, there was a flaw in the existing framework.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:34:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Father in ‘house of horrors’ case to appeal abuse conviction</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/father-in-house-of-horrors-case-to-appeal-abuse-conviction-1.2279348</Link>
        <Description>Roscommon man (57) received 14-year sentence for sexual assault of son in 2010   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Father in house of horrors case to appeal abuse conviction
Roscommon man (57) received 14-year sentence for sexual assault of son in 2010
The Court of Criminal Appeal is to hear an appeal by a man against his conviction for sexual abuse of his son over a three-year period, when the boy was between 12 and 15 years old. File photograph: Frank Miller/The Irish Times
Brian McDonald
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 17:34
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 17:34
The father from the Roscommon house of horrors case will on Friday begin an appeal against his conviction and 14-year sentence.
The appeal by the 57-year-old, who was convicted in 2010 for the systematic sexual abuse of his eldest son over a three-year period, is listed for hearing before the Court of Criminal Appeal.
The court will hear a full appeal against conviction and severity of sentence.
The father had pleaded not guilty to 47 counts of the rape and sexual assault of his son, when the boy was aged between 12 and 15 years old.
Despite being found guilty by a jury, he has continued to claim that he is innocent.
Passing sentence on March 8th, 2010, Mr Justice Barry White jailed him for 14 years, but suspended the final 18 months of the sentence.
The mans wife was jailed in January 2009 for the maximum term of seven years for incest, other sexual abuse, neglect and wilful ill-treatment of her six children at the family home in Co Roscommon, dubbed the house of horrors.
She had pleaded guilty to 10 charges including forcing her 13-year-old son to have sex with her.
She was freed in April of last year after serving five years at the Dchas womens prison in Dublin. She had a quarter of her sentence reduced for good behaviour.
The couple cannot be identified to protect the identity of their victims.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:29:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jury in Dublin shooting trial asks judge to define provocation</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/criminal-court/jury-in-dublin-shooting-trial-asks-judge-to-define-provocation-1.2279331</Link>
        <Description>David Cully (24) admits firing at his uncle  but pleads not guilty to murdering him in 2013   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Jury in Dublin shooting trial asks judge to define provocation
David Cully (24) admits firing at his uncle  but pleads not guilty to murdering him in 2013
The jury in a Dublin shooting trial has requested the legal definition of provocation. File photograph: Alan Betson/The Irish Times
Topics:
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 17:29
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 17:29
The jury in the trial of a Dublin man who shot his uncle dead but denies murdering him has asked the judge to give the legal definition of provocation again.
David Cully (24), of Kilshane Road, Finglas West, has pleaded not guilty to murdering Edward OConnor (41), but guilty to his manslaughter at Ballycoolin Road, Finglas West on December 15th, 2013.
Mr OConnor died of two gunshot wounds to his back.
Mr Cully claims he shot Mr OConnor in the heat of the moment after the deceased commented about somebody who had made an allegation of sexual abuse against him.
The allegation had been investigated, but the Director of Public Prosecutions had decided not to prosecute Mr Cully, the court heard.
The Central Criminal Court trial heard that both men had attended an organised straightener fight between two other men on the day of the killing and that Mr Cully shot his uncle in the back afterwards.
Mr Cully told garda that his uncle had made a comment that had caused him to lose control.
Provocation
Yesterday, Mr Justice Carroll Moran told the jury that a charge of murder could be reduced to manslaughter if there was provocation.
The jury had spent about five hours considering its verdict and returned just before 4pm, when the foreman asked the judge to give the legal definition of provocation again.
The foreman said that, given the nature of the case, the jury was giving considerable regard to the defence and to understanding all aspects of it.
He said the jury also wanted to see part of a Garda interview with the accused.
The seven women and five men have retired for the evening and the jury will resume its deliberations after the judge deals with the request tomorrow morning.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:49:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boxer John Joe Nevin charged with violent disorder</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/district-court/boxer-john-joe-nevin-charged-with-violent-disorder-1.2279288</Link>
        <Description>Olympic silver medallist to face charges arising from pub fracas last April   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Boxer John Joe Nevin charged with violent disorder
Olympic silver medallist to face charges arising from pub fracas last April
John Joe Nevin arriving at Mullingar District Court on Thursday. Photograph: James Flynn/APX
Brian McDonald
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 18:35
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 16:49
Olympic silver medallist John Joe Nevin is facing a trial by judge and jury after he was charged yesterday with the offence of violent disorder.
Nevin (26) appeared before Mullingar District Court on Thursday to answer two lesser charges arising from a fracas outside a public house in the town in April.
Four other members of his extended family were also in court on similar charges arising from the same incident.
Boxer John Joe Nevin barred from every pub in Co Westmeath
John Joe Nevin of St Anthonys Cottages, Mullingar had initially been charged with the public order offences of being drunk in a public place and with threatening and abusive behaviour at Dominic St , Mullingar on April 6th.
It had previously been flagged to the court that further charges in respect of the incident outside the Stillery Bar in Dominic Street may arise. The court heard that the incident involved up to 25 people fighting outside the pub in a late-night brawl.
John Joe Nevin has since been on bail in respect of the charges and one of the bail conditions is a ban on entering any licensed premises, including supermarket off-licences, in Co Westmeath until the case is heard.
He also has to observe a curfew from 11pm to 8am, but alterations have been made to the curfew by Judge Hughes, including the temporary lifting of it to allow John Joe Nevin train abroad.
In court yesterday Inspector Jarlath Folan told Judge Seamus Hughes that there was an additional charge against John Joe Nevin. This new charge would replace the two existing public order charges which were being withdrawn.
Sergeant Damien Connaughton gave evidence of arresting John Joe Nevin yesterday morning and charging him with committing violent disorder on the occasion of the fracas. He had made no reply to the charge.
Sgt Connaughton gave evidence of separately arresting Joseph Nevin (20) of Grange Meadows and Christopher Nevin (22) of Grange Park, both in Mullingar, on Wednesday morning and charging them both with the same violent disorder offence.
There was no reply from either of the accused to the charge and it would now replace the existing public order charges which were being withdrawn.
Inspector Folan said that the Director of Public Prosecutions had directed that the cases be tried on indictment. They are due to be heard in due course before Mullingar Circuit Court.
All three were remanded on continuing bail conditions to appear again at Mullingar District Court in October for preparation of the book of evidence.
A fourth accused, David Nevin (24), The Moorings, Ballymahon Road, Mullingar, is also before the court on charges arising from the incident, but was unable to attend due to illness. His case was adjourned to next week.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:30:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pensioner awarded €58k after car was hit by Garda</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/circuit-court/pensioner-awarded-58k-after-car-was-hit-by-garda-1.2279234</Link>
        <Description>Man will  undergo hip surgery after incident when gardaí were chasing third party   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Pensioner awarded 58k after car was hit by Garda
Man will  undergo hip surgery after incident when garda were chasing third party
Brendan Tierney (83) of Church View, St Margarets Village, Dublin, pictured leaving the Four Courts on Thursday. Photograph: Courts Collins
Saurya Cherfi
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 16:30
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 16:30
An 83-year-old pensioner, who will have to undergo a hip replacement operation as a result of his car being hit by a Garda vehicle, was on Thursday awarded almost 60,000 damages in the Circuit Civil Court.
Circuit Court President Mr Justice Raymond Groarke said he was satisfied Brendan Tierney , who had an underlying degenerative condition in his hip, had led an extremely active life before the October 2013 accident.
The judge heard that Mr Tierney and his wife Christine, also in her 80s, had enjoyed a Mediterranean Cruise just the month before their Fiat Panda was hit by a car driven by Garda Michael ORourke in Blessington , Co Wicklow .
Barrister Timothy Sheehan , counsel for Mr Tierney, said several members of the Garda had been chasing a car driven by Michael Cash , of Hazelhill Terrace, Tallaght, Dublin, who had allegedly failed to stop at a check point.
Judge Groarke was told the Tierneys, of Church view, St Margarets, Co Dublin, had been on their way to their daughters for a Sunday lunch and the accident had happened when Garda ORourke had made a U-turn.
Mr Sheehan, who appeared with OReilly Doherty solicitors, said liability had been admitted in the case which had become an assessment of damages.
The judge heard that since the accident, Mr Tierney was not able to climb up ladders and do some gardening, and he now would not drive more than about five miles from his home.
Mr Shehan said the accident had exacerbated a degenerative condition, which may have never troubled Mr Tierney but has left him where he may now need a hip replacement.
The court heard Mr Tierney had been on a waiting list to undergo the operation publicly but he may now have it done by next November privately. He sued the Motor Insurers Bureau of Ireland; the Minister for Finance and also Michael Cash, for negligence and breach of duty.
Judge Groarke said there was no question Mr Tierneys life had been disrupted since the accident. He said he was satisfied the surgery he was going to undergo had been partly caused by the accident, and would award him half of its cost in that regard.
The judge awarded Mr Tierney 45,000 damages for pain and suffering, and 13,023 damages for fees and expenses, including future expenses, a total of 58,023.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
