<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Latimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece offers to implement pension and tax reforms for 3-year bailout</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-bailout-debt-20150708-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Greece asked its European partners for a new three-year bailout Wednesday as the clock ticked down on a weekend deadline for an agreement to keep the nearly bankrupt nation in the Eurozone.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>26
The Greek request submitted by letter Wednesday did not specify how much Athens was hoping to receive in what would be its third international bailout in five years. The first two totaled nearly $265 billion at current exchange rates; the second of them expired last week, leaving the Greek government dangerously short of funds.
A study released last week by the International Monetary Fund estimated that Athens would need at least $55 billion and major relief on its massive public-debt load to keep going over the next three years. The report was seized on by Tsipras government. It has argued that debt relief is necessary but to little avail with other Eurozone nations, which hold a significant portion of that debt.
Wednesdays letter to the European Stability Mechanism repeated Athens desire to discuss the possibility of action on Greeces debt, which equals 180% of the countrys entire economic output. But some European officials, particularly in Germany, remain adamantly opposed, raising questions of whether a compromise can be reached by the weekend.
On Wednesday morning, Tsipras appeared before the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France, to defend his governments handling of the worst crisis to face the Eurozone and possibly the European Union.
He said the Greek economy, which has contracted by a staggering 25% since 2009, had essentially become a guinea pig for destructive austerity policies. Tsipras insisted that the crisis was not Greeces alone but one that confronted Europe as a whole.
But some Parliament members blamed him for pushing Greece to the brink of exit from the euro, known colloquially as a Grexit, and accused him of undermining confidence in Europe.
We are in fact sleepwalking towards a Grexit, the former Belgian Prime Minister Guy Verhofstadt, now a member of the European Parliament, thundered in an extraordinary statement. It is not you and it is not we who shall pay the bill. Its going to be the ordinary Greek citizens who are going to pay the bill of a Grexit.
With trust between Tsipras government and other European countries at an all-time low, Athens has few friends it can turn to as it tries to stave off financial disaster. Its biggest backer is turning out to be France, whose top officials have emphasized the importance of keeping Greece within the Eurozone for the greater sake of European unity.
The destiny of Europe is at stake, French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said Wednesday.
In a sign of growing American unease with the possibility that Greek might collapse into chaos, leaving Europes southeastern flank exposed, the Obama administration made one of its most forceful statements yet in the Greek debt crisis.
U.S. Treasury Secretary Jacob J. Lew said it was time for European and Greek leaders to reach a deal or face potentially devastating consequences. He noted that the two sides were within a couple of billion dollars of closing a deal in previous negotiations but were now risking hundreds of billions of dollars in economic damage through their unwillingness to yield.
I think its a mistake for the European economy, the global economy to take the risks that are involved with an uncontrolled crisis in Greece, Lew said during a forum at the Brookings Institution think tank in Washington. The risk of an accident goes up dramatically when you create more of these kind of life-and-death deadlines. Once youre measuring it in days, its time to get the deal done.
Tsiantar is a special correspondent. Times staff writer Jim Puzzanghera in Washington contributed to this report.
Follow @HenryHChu on Twitter for news out of Europe
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis' visit a respite for embattled Ecuadorean president</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pope-francis-visit-ecuador-20150708-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  While probably not his intention, Pope Francis handed embattled Ecuadorean President Rafael Correa a much-needed political respite - a de-facto if temporary truce with the legions of opponents who had been staging daily protests against the government.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis' visit a respite for embattled Ecuadorean president
Pope in Ecuador
Martin Bernetti / AFP/Getty Images
Pope Francis with Ecuadorean President Rafael Correa at the airport in Quito before his departure for Bolivia on July 8.
Pope Francis with Ecuadorean President Rafael Correa at the airport in Quito before his departure for Bolivia on July 8.
(Martin Bernetti / AFP/Getty Images)
Pope Francis
While probably not his intention, Pope Francis handed embattled Ecuadorean President Rafael Correa a much-needed political respite  a de-facto if temporary truce with the legions of opponents who had been staging daily protests against the government.
Many of those foes accused the leftist Correa of politicizing the pope's three-day stay in Ecuador, which ended Wednesday with the pontiff's departure to Bolivia.
To be sure, the charismatic Correa was beaming as he greeted Francis on the tarmac in Quito upon his arrival Sunday.
And what was supposed to be a brief courtesy visit by the pope to the president at his Carondelet palace on Monday ran much longer than expected when Correa escorted Francis down a winding reception line, TV cameras in tow.
The Ecuadorean people are Catholic and noble. But this is also a people that fights for its rights. - Susana Gonzalez, a City Council member in Guayaquil
And Correa again accompanied the pope to his departure flight.
The pope had not even left Ecuadorean airspace, however, when the opposition announced it would resume the demonstrations.
With all due respect for the pope, his visit does not solve the countrys problems, because the abuses continue, Clever Jimenez, of the indigenous Pachakutik party, told The Times.
The president speaks of dialogue, but we cannot believe him.
8
Correas foes criticize him for what they say are his efforts to stifle the independent press and destroy or co-opt most of Ecuador's democratic institutions. His government has also been accused of rampant corruption. The most recent blow was an effort by Correa to restructure inheritance and capital-gains taxes to redistribute wealth.
He, in turn, claims his critics are trying to overthrow the government in order to preserve longtime, rapacious economic interests. His supporters point to his accomplishments in building up the countrys transportation system and expanding spending on health and education.
Much of the opposition to Correa, like Jimenezs party, espouses the same leftist ideology as the president. Indigenous groups accuse him of being in league with profit-churning mining companies that are destroying their land. They plan a national strike for early August.
The political heat on Correa has been so intense that the Ecuadorean army last week found it necessary to deny rumors of a military coup  always a sign that trouble may be brewing. His poll ratings, while still quite high, are at their lowest point in his more than eight years of governing.
While Correa apparently hoped to use Francis as an endorsement (and his associates claimed as much), and the opposition wanted Francis to advocate on its behalf, the pope was subtle in any scolding that can be gleaned from his words.
His admonishments seemed aimed at all sides of the political disputes here.
Dialogue is needed and is fundamental for arriving at the truth, the pope said in his final and most overtly political speech in Quito.
In a participatory democracy, each social group, indigenous peoples, Afro-Ecuadoreans, women, civic associations and those engaged in public service, are all indispensable participants in this dialogue.
0
Susana Gonzalez, a City Council member in Guayaquil, Ecuadors largest city and a center of much of the opposition to Correa, said that despite the countrys deep Catholicism and admiration for the pope, the presidents critics arent going to abandon their struggle based on Francis visit.
The Ecuadorean people are Catholic and noble, she said in an interview. But this is also a people that fights for its rights.
Whether or not Correa scored political points, his supporters sought to portray the popes visit in those terms.
Pamela Falconi, a congresswoman from his Alianza Pais political movement, said the pope had defined the important points for the country, such as family, solidarity and respect, which should govern any future talks with the opposition.
We want to dialogue, but there are radical sectors of the opposition that seek to agitate the streets instead of generating proposals, she said.
Ecuadors Confederation of Indigenous Nationalities, one of the civil-society groups chosen to meet with the pope on Tuesday and a staunch opponent of Correa, wrote the pontiff asking for his help in protecting their mother earth.
It is not clear whether they got through to him, but in a speech that day he said: We cannot keep turning our back on our reality, on our brothers, on our mother, the Earth.
Advocacy for the poor and sharp criticism of Western consumerism and greedy multinational corporations have characterized the Jesuit popes speeches since he assumed St. Peters Chair in 2013. That tone may have encouraged Correa and other leftists to assume he was in their camp.
But the Argentine-born pontiff who served as a prominent cleric in Buenos Aires under that countrys military dictatorships, also has no taste for authoritarian regimes and clashed until recently with Argentinas pro-left President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner.
Francis will face a similar political minefield with Bolivia's President Evo Morales who, in addition to leftist politics, emphasizes an indigenous nativism that is also sometimes anti-clerical.
Special correspondent Viteri reported from Quito and Times staff writer Wilkinson from Mexico City.
For more news from the pope's trip, follow @TracyKWilkinson on Twitter
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>24 suspected Islamic State militants sentenced to death for Tikrit massacre</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-iraq-islamic-state-20150708-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  An Iraqi court on Wednesday sentenced to death 24 suspected Islamic State members accused of taking part in the slaughter of hundreds of military recruits from a former U.S. base known as Camp Speicher last summer.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>24 suspected Islamic State militants sentenced to death for Tikrit massacre
Islamic State massacre
Karim Kadim / Associated Press
An Iraqi father holds a poster of his slain son during the July 8 session of a trial of suspected Islamic State members accused of taking part in the killings of 1,700 government soldiers in Tikrit in June 2014.
An Iraqi father holds a poster of his slain son during the July 8 session of a trial of suspected Islamic State members accused of taking part in the killings of 1,700 government soldiers in Tikrit in June 2014.
(Karim Kadim / Associated Press)
Iraqi officials announced Monday the discovery of several mass graves near the city of Tikrit, state news media reported. ( Nabih Bulos )
Islamic State later released graphic images and video showing the terrified captives, most of them Shiite Muslims, being led to shallow trenches and shot. Others were executed near the Tigris River, their bodies tossed into the water.
Islamic State claimed to have killed 1,700 soldiers -- a figure that many Iraqi officials consider credible -- in what would be its bloodiest massacre to date. Hundreds of bodies were exhumed from mass graves after the militants were driven out of Tikrit in April.
The 24 men sentenced to death by hanging denied taking part in the killings, telling the judge during a hasty trial at Baghdads central criminal court Wednesday that they had been tortured into confessing, according to news reports.
Thank Bush, thank Cheney, for they let all the ISIS animals out of the Iraqi zoos.
Brain Police
1
Four other defendants were acquitted for lack of evidence. They were among more than 600 suspects in the case, most of whom remain at large.
Family members of some of the victims attended the trial, holding pictures of their slain loved ones. Several stormed the courtroom and started throwing shoes and water bottles at the defendants, who were inside a cage, the Associated Press reported.
Some of the family members told the judge that they had received calls from their relatives on the day that Tikrit fell, telling them that Sunni tribal chiefs had arrived at Speichers gates to say the soldiers could safely leave and head home, AP reported.
Instead, the soldiers were rounded up and killed.
News of the massacre galvanized Shiite militias to join the fight against Islamic State last year, raising the specter of sectarian war.
The militias formed the backbone of the governments successful campaign to retake Tikrit. Some are accused of taking part in revenge killings and looting in the Sunni-dominated hometown of former Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein.
Special correspondent Amro Hassan contributed to this report.
For more international news, follow @alexzavis
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will Pope Francis chew coca? (It's a thing in Bolivia)</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pope-francis-ecuador-20150708-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Pope Francis took his Latin American pilgrimage to the heavily indigenous Andean nation of Bolivia, where his challenge will be to reconcile ethnic communities with traditional Catholicism.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>0
The theme being pronounced by the first pope from the Americas on a three-country tour of his native continent has been the need to include the excluded, be they poor, elderly or indigenous. He also has advocated dialogue that includes all voices in a region torn by divisive politics.
Before departing Quito, Francis visited a home for the elderly run by nuns from the order established by Mother Teresa of Calcutta. He greeted, kissed and blessed scores of elderly, many infirm or in wheelchairs. Then he went to the sanctuary of the Virgin del Quinche, patron saint of Ecuador, where he tossed out a speech and spoke off the cuff.
In Bolivia, where Aymara Indians are expected to participate in many of the papal ceremonies, the pope will preach on behalf of a Catholicism that embraces indigenous cultures, despite centuries of history in which Spanish and Catholic colonizers subjugated, abused and even slaughtered native peoples. Despite that, Bolivia is a very Catholic country.
Sometimes it needs work to learn to respect each other  but it is easy to coexist and enrich one another mutually, Father Eugenio Scarpellini, bishop of El Alto, told the CNN Spanish-language service as he awaited the popes arrival.
The popes message, he said, will be that Catholicism "does not come to destroy a culture but to plant seeds of the gospel and the values of solidarity and fraternity.
The pope is expected to spend only about four hours in La Paz before traveling to the Bolivian lowland city of Santa Cruz. After Bolivia, he travels to Paraguay, completing a tour of some of South Americas smallest and poorest nations.
For more news from the pope's trip, follow @TracyKWilkinson on Twitter
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What China's bursting stock bubble means for the U.S. economy</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-asia-stocks-fall-20150708-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  China is a long way from Greece and the high-profile debt troubles of the Eurozone, but its stocks have been taking a far worse beating in recent days.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>What China's bursting stock bubble means for the U.S. economy
Explaining China's sinking stocks
China is a long way from Greece and the high-profile debt troubles of the Eurozone, but its stocks have been taking a far worse beating in recent days. But these problems aren't a surprise to some people.
China is a long way from Greece and the high-profile debt troubles of the Eurozone, but its stocks have been taking a far worse beating in recent days. But these problems aren't a surprise to some people.
Brookings Institution
China is a long way from Greece and the high-profile debt troubles of the Eurozone, but its stocks have been taking a far worse beating in recent days.
On Wednesday, the growing investor panic over Chinese stocks shook confidence in Beijing's ability to manage its slowing economy and threatened to cause problems for overseas markets, including America's.
Despite increasingly desperate measures by the Chinese government to halt the slide, shares listed on China's main stock exchange in Shanghai fell nearly 6% Wednesday, piling on losses that have plunged the market by about a third since mid-June.
China's surging stocks fell in recent months
Sign up for our California Inc. business newsletter
Thats incredible, said John Lonski, chief capital markets economist for Moodys Analytics. Thats scary.
Most Chinese stocks remain well above year-ago levels thanks to a raging bull market that began in November 2014 and was egged on by Beijing. China's Shanghai stock market is still up 72% over the July 2014, despite the recent drops.
But the sudden nose dive has sparked concerns about growth in the world's second-largest economy and has started to spill into other markets.
8
Stocks in Hong Kong fell even more Wednesday while markets slid also in Japan, South Korea, Australia and other economies with close links to China. The gloom spread to copper and other global commodity markets, which are hugely dependent on China's economy.
U.S. stocks also opened sharply lower Wednesday, despite rising hopes that Greece might be able to avert a disastrous exit from the Eurozone.
The Chinese selloff has caught world markets by surprise as they focused on the slowly unfolding drama in Greece. But Lonski said the China bear market is potentially far more consequential by dint of Chinas size and the potential contagion effects on the global economy and trade.
If China hits the skids, I think the U.S. will suffer, the equity markets will suffer, he said.
Treasury Secretary Jacob J. Lew on Wednesday downplayed concerns that the turmoil in Chinas stock markets would pose an immediate threat to the U.S. economy.
Chinas markets are still pretty much separated from world markets, Lew said during a forum at the Brookings Institution think tank in Washington. Theyre obviously moving towards being more integrated, but right now theyre not so I dont think youre going to see the direct linkage there.
@grossbeak Especially if they are connected to or a relative of "party" officials.
gaseousclay13
30
Some analysts have likened China's boom-to-bust market to the dot-com bubble in the U.S., when furious, irrational buying eventually led to a Nasdaq burst in 2000. But what makes China's story unusual is just how rapidly prices soared and then fell, as well as the Chinese government's not-so-invisible hand in the matter.
Leaders in Beijing have made public their desire to let markets play a bigger role in the Chinese economy, which is still dominated by state-owned enterprises and banks.
"Official publications were telling investors to get involved and buy stocks," said Tim Condon, an economist at ING Group in Singapore. "There's official complicity in boosting the market."
Millions of ordinary Chinese jumped into the action, many of them borrowing funds to buy stocks. In recent months, government officials have sought to tamp down such leveraged purchases, and since June 12, when the Shanghai stock index reached 5178, the market has swooned, closing at 3506 on Wednesday.
The persistent fall is especially worrisome, analysts said, because it comes despite efforts by Chinas central bank, the Peoples Bank of China, to stem the stock slide through extraordinary measures, including declaring a halt to initial public offerings, and relaxing terms for margin borrowing. Both efforts have failed so far, and backfired by spooking foreign investors.
Condon thinks Beijing can stop the rout with back-stopping measures by the Chinese central bank, but other analysts wondered whether the latest episode in China's evolving economy could set back financial and market reforms that many in the U.S. and other advanced economies have been calling on Beijing to continue.
Lew raised the concern Wednesday, questioning whether the market meltdown could delay efforts by the Chinese government to make the nations economy more market-oriented.
If the reaction is to put the brakes on reforms it will slow that process, Lew said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear negotiators wrangle over U.N. arms embargo</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-iran-nuclear-talks-20150708-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Obama administration officials who face the tough task of selling their nuclear deal with Iran to Americans are looking at a new challenge: how to avoid perceptions that the nearly-complete agreement will uncork a flood of arms to Tehran and militant allies such as Hezbollah.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear negotiators wrangle over U.N. arms embargo
Iran nuclear talks
Georg Hochmuth / European Pressphoto Agency
Police officers patrol in front of the Palais Coburg in Vienna, where talks between Iran, the United States, France, Britain, Germany, Russia and China continued on July 8.
Police officers patrol in front of the Palais Coburg in Vienna, where talks between Iran, the United States, France, Britain, Germany, Russia and China continued on July 8.
(Georg Hochmuth / European Pressphoto Agency)
Iran Nuclear Talks
Obama administration officials who face the tough task of selling their nuclear deal with Iran to Americans are looking at a new challenge: how to avoid perceptions that the nearly-complete agreement will uncork a flood of arms to Tehran and militant allies such as Hezbollah.
The issue emerged this week after Iranian officials at nuclear negotiations in Vienna insisted that the United Nations Security Council should drop its bans on sales of conventional arms and missiles to Iran as part of the nuclear deal the country is negotiating with the U.S. and five other world powers.
Six leading world powers and Iran acknowledged that they would miss a midnight Tuesday deadline for wrapping up a comprehensive nuclear deal, forcing them to extend talks for the fifth time in the last year. ( Paul Richter )
U.S. officials say they dont want more weapons flooding into a region in turmoil. They insist that the U.N. resolution that puts the emerging nuclear deal in place must include restrictions on arms sales.
However, hints suggest that some U.S. officials would prefer to find a compromise than let the dispute sink the nuclear deal, which now appears within reach. Officials on Tuesday missed a self-imposed deadline to complete the deal, and now hope to wrap up on Friday.
Diplomats seem split on immediate prospects for an agreement. Some predicted that a pact could still be completed by 6 a.m. Friday Vienna time, in time for the administration to meet a congressional deadline set for midnight EDT Thursday.
8
But others say big political issues and smaller technical ones must be resolved before the 80-page agreement and its annexes can be completed. A senior U.S. official said optimism about an immediate end of talks was not grounded in reality.
The United States and five other powers -- France, Britain, Germany, Russia and China -- have been negotiating with Iran for almost two years on a deal that would lift economic sanctions on Iran if it accepts restrictions intended to prevent it from obtaining a nuclear bomb.
Iranian officials believe that the arms embargoes should never have been included in U.N. sanctions on Iran in connection with its disputed nuclear activities. They want all the U.N. sanctions lifted, in part to show their public that the country is no longer an international pariah.
Russia and China also would like the weapons embargoes lifted because they want to sell arms to Iran. Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov this week described the embargoes as the most important issue left to be negotiated.
The two sides may be groping toward a compromise, but it may be a tough one to reach.
cComments
-- "A senior administration official seemed to hint at U.S. flexibility this week. Speaking to reporters on condition of anonymity . . bla bla bla" -- Really - no ****! As observers - by the dozens - have observed all along, the Obama administration wants a deal. Winning on what is...
forparity
3
Ali Vaez, an Iran specialist at the International Crisis Group, a nonprofit non-governmental organization, said lifting the U.N. arms embargoes amid sectarian-tainted turmoil in the region could not only exacerbate concerns among the Arab states and Israel, but even turn into a poison pill that could sink the agreement.
He said he saw no perfect middle-ground solution.
One route that would meet Iranian goals but apparently not the Americans would make the U.N. restrictions voluntary. Another approach, which might not satisfy Iran, would delay a lifting of the embargoes until some later, arbitrary milestone is reached, Vaez said.
A senior administration official seemed to hint at U.S. flexibility this week. Speaking to reporters on condition of anonymity to discuss internal assessments, the official said the administration would insist on continued restrictions on arms sales, but declined to say if they would be as comprehensive as those now in place.
Analysts say another approach would be to drop the U.N. sanctions but use bilateral American sanctions to try to maintain an arms sales ban.
Diplomats have cited several other major issues still in dispute at the talks: the pace and structure of sanctions relief, the future of Irans nuclear research and development, monitoring of its nuclear activities, and unresolved questions about its suspected past nuclear weapons research.
Other questions also appear unanswered.
Iranian officials, for example, say they want a means of recourse in case the six world powers dont live up to their end of the bargain. If Iran is seen to be violating its obligations, there will be a snapback of sanctions; Iran wants some mechanism in return to give it leverage, officials say.
Reza Marashi of the National Iranian American Council said one Iranian worry is that the White House will use administrative authority to temporarily lift U.S. sanctions on Iran but that Congress wont follow through to permanently remove sanctions that were enacted into law.
Congress has a long history of not removing sanctions, such as those imposed on Russia, and many U.S. lawmakers oppose the Iran deal and might vote against sanctions repeal.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghan, Taliban officials end peace talks, agree to meet again</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-peace-talks-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Less than 24 hours after they were announced, direct talks between the Afghan government and the Taliban concluded Wednesday with both parties agreeing to meet again after the holy month of Ramadan, according to officials in the host nation, Pakistan.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan, Taliban officials end peace talks, agree to meet again
Afghan forces
Rahmat Gul / Associated Press
Afghan security forces inspect the site of a suicide attack in Kabul, Afghanistan, on July 7. Pakistan's Foreign Ministry says peace talks between Afghan officials and Taliban representatives have ended for now.
Afghan security forces inspect the site of a suicide attack in Kabul, Afghanistan, on July 7. Pakistan's Foreign Ministry says peace talks between Afghan officials and Taliban representatives have ended for now.
(Rahmat Gul / Associated Press)
8
The participants agreed to continue talks to create an environment conducive for [the] peace and reconciliation process, read a statement from the Pakistani Foreign Ministry. The next meeting will be held at a mutually convenient date after Ramadan, which ends next week.
With his weapon in one hand, Ibrahim answered his cellphone with the other. He was hoping the call would bring news of reinforcements for his Afghan Local Police post, which was under siege from hundreds of Taliban insurgents. ( Ali M. Latifi )
The meeting in Murree, on the outskirts of the Pakistani capital of Islamabad, was billed as the first in which Afghan officials and Taliban insurgent leaders sat across from one another and raised hope of a diplomatic resolution to more than a decade of conflict.
But the meeting Tuesday appeared to end almost as quickly as it was announced .
The killing will never stop in the Middle East...talk is just a waste of time.
R.L. Schaefer
1
Representatives from the United States and China also attended the talks as observers, Afghan and Pakistani officials said. The Taliban are reportedly seeking an easing of terrorism-related sanctions imposed by the United States as part of an eventual settlement with the Afghan government.
Soon after Afghan President Ashraf Ghanis office disclosed the meeting Tuesday, some Taliban members denied that they supported talks with the government, which they have long described as a Western puppet.
The comments underscored divisions within the insurgent organization that raise questions about whether a truce, if reached, will end the violence that killed or injured more than 10,000 Afghan civilians in 2014, according to United Nations figures.
The Islamic Emirate of Afghanistan, as the Taliban calls itself, issued a statement Wednesday saying that its political office has the authority to start or stop negotiations whenever and wherever necessary.
But Taliban representatives at the meeting said they had the mandate of the insurgent groups Pakistan-based leadership. The groups delegation was headed by Mullah Abbas, a close aide of Mullah Mohammed Omar, the Talibans reclusive leader.
The Afghan delegation was led by Hekmat Khalil Karzai, the deputy foreign minister. Haji Din Mohammad, an advisor to Ghani, and Mohammad Natiqi, a member of the governments High Peace Council, long tasked with outreach to the Taliban, also attended.
The Pakistani Foreign Ministry said both sides agreed to approach the process with sincerity and to make efforts to bring lasting peace not just in Afghanistan but also in the region. The next meeting was expected to be held in the coming weeks, possibly in Qatar, where the Taliban opened a diplomatic mission in 2013.
Sahi is a special correspondent. Staff writer Bengali reported from Mumbai, India.
Follow @SBengali on Twitter for news out of Afghanistan and Pakistan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why other bailed-out euro countries may back a third rescue for Greece</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-eurozone-greece-bailed-out-countries-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Having swallowed the bitter medicine of their own austerity-driven bailout programs, the people of Ireland, Spain, Portugal and Cyprus might be expected to insist that Greece live up to obligations taken on in exchange for the $270 billion it has already received.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>2
Spain's ruling conservatives, who secured access to European rescue loans of up to $110 billion for its troubled banks three years ago, have also advised Athens that fundamental reform is unavoidable if the country wants to escape the slow strangulation of crushing debt.
"We're inclined to help Greece but Greece must follow Europe's rules," Spanish Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy told the Telecinco news program Tuesday, noting that Spain is now reaping the benefits of having taken the hard steps of government cutbacks and privatization. The Spanish economy has posted growth in each of the last seven quarters, although the unemployment rate has remained stubbornly high at 23.8%.
Spanish Finance Minister Luis de Guindos said during the Eurozone gathering in Brussels that Greece "has the right to ask for a third rescue package." The Greek economy is so indebted that without more immediate support it has no opportunity to generate growth and eventually reduce the debt burden. He faulted the troika for too much emphasis on austerity but said, "It isinevitable that Greece make reforms because there have been nations that havedone them and they are emerging from the crisis."
Portugal is another example. Lisbon needed a 78-billion-euro ($86 billion) rescue in May 2011 when borrowing from credit markets became unaffordable. The country exited its bailout program last year after enduring three years of painful budget cuts and tax increases.
Portuguese officials have said little about the Greek default except to distance themselves from the Balkan country's plight.
"Portuguese have made a lot of effort to beat bankruptcy and do not deserve to be associated with the Greek situation," Deputy Prime Minister Paulo Portas said in apparent response to concern expressed among Eurozone analysts that Athens' default might give rise to the moral hazard of other borrowers deciding to shirk their debts.
Cyprus, where banks were hit by the 2012 writedown of Greece's debt that came with its second bailout, secured a 10-billion-euro rescue package in March 2013. The loans to Cyprus were granted in concert with a raid on bank deposits that imposed a one-time levy of 9.9% on accounts with 100,000 euros or more and 6.75% on the rest.
Cypriot President Nicos Anastasiades was the most unequivocal of bailed-out Eurozone leaders in backing Athens' expected call for significant reduction of its debt to create some breathing space for income- and job-producing growth projects.
"What is needed, in my view at this stage, is to consider the unsustainability of the Greek debt," the right-of-center Anastasiades said.
Leftist parties in the Eurozone periphery applauded Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras's victory Sunday in persuading a majority of his country's voters to reject the troika's demands for more austerity before talks on a third bailout can begin.
But those political forces, though on the rise in Spain and Portugal, are unlikely to make major gains on the governing conservatives in the next elections unless the Greek rebellion pays off. If Greece's far-left Syriza government fails to win an easing of repayment terms with its spurning of creditors, economic chaos is expected -- hardly an outcome that would be embraced by austerity-weary voters.
Follow @cjwilliamslat for the latest international news 24/7
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In wartime Syria, bus depot is a bridge between two worlds</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-c1-syria-aleppo-bus-stop-20150708-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The men arrive at the depot sucking on their cigarettes, no longer fearful that smoking in the wrong place will earn them a rendezvous with the whip, or the executioner.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>1
Many commuters are state employees trapped behind militant lines. Even though they can no longer work, they continue to receive their salaries, which requires a trip to the government side to pick up monthly checks.
The militants exact a tax or tithe on their salaries, as they do on all property, including cars, houses and farmed produce, residents say.
All arrivals from opposition territory are subject to searches and security screening.
Likewise, the rebels posted at opposition checkpoints conduct their own checks and impose harsh travel restrictions: Fighting-age men are generally banned from leaving insurgent territory without an airtight excuse, such as serious illness. A woman can travel only if accompanied by an adult male. And those given permission to travel must leave family members behind as collateral  hostages, that is.
No cigarettes are allowed in Islamic State territory. Those found trying to smuggle in smokes may face a dozen lashes or worse.
"I try to bring in some cigarettes in my underwear," says Abu Ahmed, a bus driver who frequently ferries passengers to Islamic State territory, including Raqqah, the Islamic State bastion about five hours away.
A resident of Raqqah, Abu Ahmed, 55, has three wives  two in Raqqah and one in Aleppo  and 13 children. He wears a traditional Arab tunic and sandals.
He agrees to speak in a bus station office so no one who travels to opposition territory will see him in the company of a foreign journalist. A stone-faced Syrian security officer in aviator glasses listens to every word. Other drivers and passengers are terrified by the notion of speaking to a Western reporter. Rebel informers are everywhere, someone says.
At first, Abu Ahmed is matter-of-fact about life in Raqqah and shuttling between two realities. He has a big family and needs the job. He gets a bonus equivalent to about $7 for each trip. It helps. He chain-smokes as he speaks.
Many of the Islamic State militants are foreigners, he says, mostly from other Arab nations: Saudi Arabia, Tunisia, the Persian Gulf states.
He, like others, has learned to fear the Hisbah, the Islamic State morals police, who prowl the streets of Raqqah and other militant territory, whips at the ready for offenders. Women who defy Islamic State strictures in Raqqah can end up in a Thursday slave market, he says. The bodies and heads of Islamic State enemies are frequently on display in the city center. Residents are warned to not move them.
On a more mundane level, he says, electricity is even scarcer than in Aleppo, sometimes on for as little as an hour a day.
Somehow, the conversation drifts to his son  actually, his late son, Ahmed.
The young man was serving in the Syrian army in Damascus, the father explains. At the time, Al Nusra Front was among the militant factions vying for control of Raqqah, before Islamic State consolidated its dominion. Al Nusra Front militants came to his door when they learned that he had a son fighting in the army.
Abu Ahmed says he was arrested and put in jail. He was strapped to a cross, he says, beaten and tortured. The militants began extracting his teeth.
He opens his mouth to bare a lower jaw absent of teeth. He begins to sob. Tears roll down his face. Everyone present is silent.
The militants, he says, forced his wife to call his son and implore him to come and help free his father. The mother pleaded with her son. He relented. He came to Raqqah, probably knowing that he was doomed. The father was released. Family members were soon informed they could come collect the son's body. He had been executed.
Abu Ahmed, a strapping, strong-willed man, can't stop sobbing.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU leaders give Greece a Friday deadline for an acceptable bailout plan</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-eurozone-meeting-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Greece has until the end of this week to come up with an acceptable proposal for a new government bailout, failing which its neighbors will be prepared to let Athens go broke and flunk out of the euro currency group, European leaders said Tuesday.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>EU leaders give Greece a Friday deadline for an acceptable bailout plan
Europe Greece bailout
Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos arrives for a meeting of Eurozone finance ministers Tuesday.
Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos arrives for a meeting of Eurozone finance ministers Tuesday.
(Francois Walschaerts / Associated Press)
Angela Merkel
Greece has until the end of this week to come up with an acceptable proposal for a new government bailout, failing which its neighbors will be prepared to let Athens go broke and flunk out of the euro currency group, European leaders said Tuesday.
The stark warning came after back-to-back meetings in Brussels of senior European officials, who offered a glimmer of hope that the debt-stricken Greek government might yet avoid a disastrous default but also expressed exasperation over its unpredictable negotiating strategy.
A credible Greek proposal of how it planned to cut costs and reform its economy in exchange for billions of dollars in emergency loans must be submitted no later than Friday morning, and leaders from all 28 nations of the European Union are to meet Sunday to decide if it is viable, officials said.
In 2010 and 2012, the Eurozones debt problems shook global stock markets and sparked fear of a financial contagion that might derail Americas fragile economic recovery. ( Don Lee )
We have only five days left to find the ultimate agreement, European Union President Donald Tusk declared. Until now, I have avoided talking about deadlines. But tonight I have to say loud and clear that the final deadline ends this week.
Time is running desperately short for Greece, whose government and financial system are both close to running out of cash. Without a funding deal in the next few days, Greek banks will collapse and Athens will default on payments due, triggering an economic earthquake in a nation whose economy is already in deep depression.
With no more euros to draw on, the government would be forced to print its own much-less valuable currency. Financial chaos would ensue, as would, potentially, unrest in the streets.
At their back-to-back summits Tuesday, Eurozone finance ministers and leaders had expected Athens to present a detailed new bailout agreement.
8
The meetings were the first between Athens and its European partners since talks broke down late last month over a surprise referendum called by Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras on the European bailout proposals then on the table. Relations between the two sides reached a low point.
But some participants at the summits were shocked when Greek officials, including the newly installed finance minister, Euclid Tsakalotos, put down no formal written offer at either meeting. Instead, officials held only oral discussions, which, though described by some as productive and useful, fell far short of the progress that European leaders had hoped to make toward a new solution to Greeces long-running debt crisis.
The leaders then issued their ultimatum: Athens is now expected to submit its written proposals within the next few days.
Tsipras, looking upbeat, said the proposals would contain credible reforms that are socially just and described Tuesdays discussions as taking place in a positive climate.
Broadly, Tsipras government is expected to agree to substantially the same package that was on the table before negotiations collapsed and that was voted on  and soundly rejected  by Greeks in Sundays referendum. Although it includes what a Greek official called certain improvements, the plan entails painful austerity cuts on top of the substantial reductions in public spending that Athens has implemented during the last five years.
How Tsipras, a magnetic left-wing leader who came to power in January pledging to end austerity, plans to sell this to his backbenchers and the Greek public is unclear. Since becoming prime minister, he has confounded observers with a governing style that critics describe as reckless and erratic.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, the chief of the Eurozones finance ministers, said a formal Greek bailout request needed to come in quickly so that it could be properly scrutinized and then, if it passed muster, deliberated on by European leaders.
Mathematics - aka the Fat Lady - is getting on the stage to sing the final song.
friedfish2718
56
We will see if we can formally start the negotiations. All this has to be done in a matter of days, Dijsselbloem said.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel said that, during the discussions in Brussels, Athens had still not shown itself ready to commit to the reforms and cuts that the Eurozone says are necessary for it to be granted a bailout package.
But Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi sounded a more optimistic note, saying he hoped for a happy ending to the Greek crisis at the emergency EU summit called for Sunday.
The comments by Merkel and Renzi were another indication of the rift that has opened up between Eurozone nations on reaching an agreement with Greece, which could further complicate the process.
Several Northern European countries, such as Germany and Austria, have vented their frustration with Greece and have expressed a desire to cut it loose if it continues to flout the rules, whereas some Southern European countries, including France and Italy, have appeared more willing to be flexible in finding a solution.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said his country would do its utmost to keep Greece within the Eurozone, describing an exit as a risk for global economic growth and a serious blow to European unity.
The Eurozone must stay coherent, reliable, Valls said in a radio interview. Europe is not just a currency. It is a conception of the world.
Tusk, the EU president, described the next few days as maybe the most critical moment in our history.
But Jean-Claude Juncker, the head of the European Commission, said it was now up to Athens whether it stayed in the Eurozone. He also revealed that European officials have already drawn up in detail a plan to deal with a Greek exit from the euro, or Grexit.
Im strongly against Grexit, but I cant prevent it if the Greek government is not doing what we expect the Greek government to do, Juncker said. Another contingency plan called for humanitarian aid to Greece in the event of a Greek bank failure and government default, he said, which would wreak havoc on residents lives.
Analysts say the possibility of default by Greece and the countrys subsequent exit from the Eurozone, the club of 19 nations that use the euro currency, is now higher than ever. Such an event would have an immediate disastrous effect on the Greek economy, which has shrunk by 25% since 2009.
The Greek government needs new rescue loans to pay public-sector salaries and pensions and to service its monumental debt later this month. If it fails to make a debt payment to the European Central Bank on July 20, Greece would almost certainly be declared in default and be forced to start issuing IOUs, and potentially a new currency.
Greek banks have been closed since June 29, and residents have been restricted to daily ATM withdrawals of about $66. Although the banks are supposed to reopen Thursday, most analysts doubt that it will happen.
Follow @HenryHChu on Twitter for news on the Greece debt talks
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:56:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crowd estimated at near 1 million hears Pope Francis extol unity in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pope-francis-in-ecuador-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Pope Francis, delivering his second massively attended sermon in his tour of South America, made an eloquent plea Tuesday for unity and inclusiveness on his native continent through what he portrayed as a more welcoming form of evangelization.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Crowd estimated at near 1 million hears Pope Francis extol unity in Ecuador
Pope Francis in Ecuador
Gregorio Borgia / Associated Press
Pope Francis walks with his pastoral staff to celebrate Mass at Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on Tuesday.
Pope Francis walks with his pastoral staff to celebrate Mass at Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on Tuesday.
(Gregorio Borgia / Associated Press)
Ecuador
Pope Francis, delivering his second massively attended sermon in his tour of South America, made an eloquent plea Tuesday for unity and inclusiveness on his native continent through what he portrayed as a more welcoming form of evangelization.
Speaking at this capitals Bicentennial Park, which commemorates the independence from Spain that most of Latin America won two centuries ago, the pope also linked that struggle for freedom with the call to follow God.
There was no shortage of conviction of strength in that cry for freedom, which arose a little more than 200 years ago, the pope said, speaking in Spanish.
Pope Francis in Ecuador
Vladimir Rodas / AFP/Getty Images
Faithful gather for an open-air Mass celebrated by Pope Francis at Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on Tuesday.
Faithful gather for an open-air Mass celebrated by Pope Francis at Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on Tuesday.
(Vladimir Rodas / AFP/Getty Images)
But history tells us that it only made headway once personal differences were set aside, together with the desire for power and the inability to appreciate other movements of liberation which were different yet not in opposition.
Francis message appeared aimed at disconnecting the often abusive evangelization of colonial-era Spanish Catholics from a broader embrace of the faith.
Evangelization does not consist of proselytizing, he said, departing from a prepared text to say that knowing God should be as simple as tapping on the door.
No one is excluded, he said, reiterating a common theme in his first trip as pope to Spanish-speaking Latin America. In 2013, he visited Portuguese-speaking Brazil.
On Wednesday he is to travel to Bolivia, then to Paraguay.
8
Tens of thousands of pilgrims, from all over Ecuador as well as neighboring countries, had been camping out at the park since the start of the week in anticipation of what is likely to be the popes largest event in this country.
Some estimates put the crowd at more than 800,000. Interior Minister Jose Serrano said via Twitter that as many as 900,000 people may have attended. They braved early-morning showers and chilly air.
Being near Pope Francis is like a miracle; any sacrifice is worth it, said Omar Eudoro Velasquez, a merchant who had traveled seven hours from Pasto, Colombia, with his wife and 16-year-old son.
The Mass was using 300,000 communion wafers, the governmental newspaper El Ciudadano reported, made by the nuns of the 17th century El Carmen Alto monastery, founded as the first site in Ecuador of the Order of Discalced Carmelites.
Being near Pope Francis is like a miracle; any sacrifice is worth it. - Omar Eudoro Velasquez, a merchant from Pasto, Colombia
In his homily, the pope also made a plea for unity, part of a concept known as patria grande, or vast fatherland. The pope has frequently called for unity as a way to overcome societys ills, reduce divisive and violent tension and include those who would otherwise be marginalized. The promotion of this concept on his native continent is of special importance to him, Vatican specialists say.
Like Jesus, the pope said, we too encounter daily a world torn apart by wars and violence. It would be facile to think that division and hatred only concern struggles between countries or groups in society.
Rather, they are a manifestation of that widespread individualism which divides us and sets us against one another.
Their only job was to give you a massage with a happy ending, but you were premature, so they all had the time free! LucifersHammer
Raul Gjijalva
3
Mankind must not respond with nonchalance, he said, or complain that the problems are too big. Instead, we must respond by taking up the cry of Jesus and accepting the grace and challenge of being builders of unity.
Our unity can hardly shine forth if spiritual worldliness makes us feud among ourselves in a futile quest for power, prestige, pleasure or economic security on the backs of the most poor, the most vulnerable, those who do not lose their dignity despite being beaten down every day.
The crowd applauded enthusiastically.
"The Mass was beautiful; I hope the pope's message will be put in practice," said Zoila Hernandez, 50, a professional driver. "We'll see how the country reacts. I hope the people calm down," she said, alluding to a long series of street demonstrations in recent weeks against the government of President Rafael Correa, which were suspended during the pope's visit.
"The pope's presence is an opportunity for the people to come together again, understand that we are brothers, reduce the distances among us that the politicians, especially the president, have widened," said Homero Cardenas, a 58-year-old mechanic. "The pope's message was spiritually enriching and reminds us we are all the children of the same father."
In later appearances Tuesday, the Argentine-born pontiff waded closer to contemporary domestic politics.
Meeting with civic, political and indigenous groups, Francis was expected to get an earful from opponents of the Correa government. In his speech after private meetings with members of the groups, he appeared to be telling both Correa and his opponents to work better at ending their acrimony and negotiating and sitting down to dialogue.
The pontiff initially sounded tired, but he frequently departed from his prepared text and seemed to become more animated as he went along.
Members of a family work together, and so it should be in a national society, he said.
Our relationships in society and political life ... in the broadest sense of the word ... are often based on confrontation and the attempt to eliminate our opponents," he said. If only we could view our political opponents or neighbors in the same way we view our children or our spouse, mother or father!
Special correspondent Jaramillo Viteri reported from Quito and Times staff writer Wilkinson from Mexico City
Follow @TracyKWilkinson on Twitter for news from Latin America
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece is not alone when it comes to sovereign defaults</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-debts-defaults-other-countries-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  When Athens missed a $1.7-billion payment to the International Monetary Fund on June 30, much was made about how Greece had become the first developed nation to default on an IMF loan.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece is not alone when it comes to sovereign defaults
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras
Michel Euler / Associated Press
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras after an emergency summit of eurozone leaders in Brussels on Tuesday.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras after an emergency summit of eurozone leaders in Brussels on Tuesday.
(Michel Euler / Associated Press)
In the end, Greek voters preferred ambiguity about their future to the certainty of more economic hardships. ( Patrick J. McDonnell )
Their research shows that through 2006, Greece has had five defaults and that it has spent more years of its history in default than not (50.6% to be exact) since its independence in 1829.
Whats also unusual about Greece is that most government defaults historically have involved private creditors, whereas the Greek debts today are concentrated in the hands of European and international agencies. The last major sovereign defaults on debt owed to official creditors were back in the 1930s after the Great Depression.
Does Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras look like a guy to whom you would lend even $20?
woof  woof
2
More recently, there were big defaults by Argentina and Russia, somewhat parallel to Greeces case in that, like Athens, those governments were cash-strapped and financed themselves by not paying their bills, says Reinhart. One lesson for Greece from those two cases, as well as the default by Panama in 1987, is that even if Athens and the Eurozone can reach agreement on a new bailout, things arent likely to settle down for Athens anytime soon.
The idea that this episode is going to come to a very quick close here  its possible, but certainly these other episodes do not suggest that, she said.
Heres a look at some sovereign defaults in recent decades:
Country: Russia
Causes: Fall in oil prices, sagging productivity
Results: International loans; devaluation of ruble
Country: Argentina
Causes: Large debts, collapsing economy
Results: International loans; converted dollars to pesos; restrictions on bank accounts for a year
Country: Panama
Causes: Political and economic pressures
Results: Freeze on deposits for nine weeks; restructuring of debts
Country: Indonesia
Causes: Weak banks, corporate leverage
Results: Restructuring of corporate and official debt
Country: Nigeria
Causes: Heavy borrowing, rising interest rates, inefficient trade
Results: International debt relief
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Changes urged at World Health Organization after bungled Ebola response</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-ebola-who-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The World Health Organization must undergo fundamental changes if it is to fulfill its function of protecting global health, according to an independent panel of experts that reviewed the agency's bungled response to the deadly Ebola outbreak.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Changes urged at World Health Organization after bungled Ebola response
Ebola outbreak
Dominique Faget / AFP/Getty Images
Healthcare workers in protective suits leave the high-risk area of a Doctors Without Borders Ebola treatment facility in Monrovia, Liberia, in August. A panel of experts says the outbreak exposed the World Health Organization's organizational failings.
Healthcare workers in protective suits leave the high-risk area of a Doctors Without Borders Ebola treatment facility in Monrovia, Liberia, in August. A panel of experts says the outbreak exposed the World Health Organization's organizational failings.
(Dominique Faget / AFP/Getty Images)
United Nations
The World Health Organization must undergo fundamental changes if it is to fulfill its function of protecting global health, according to an independent panel of experts that reviewed the agencys bungled response to the deadly Ebola outbreak.
The panel considers that WHO does not currently possess the capacity or organizational culture to deliver a full emergency public health response, it says in a scathing report released Tuesday.
The panel, headed by Barbara Stocking, a former head of the aid group Oxfam GB, urged the WHO to create a division to oversee preparations for the next major outbreak and coordinate the response.
Caption Ebola in Liberia
John Moore / Getty Images
Sanitized gloves and boots hang to dry as a burial team collects Ebola victims from a Ministry of Health treatment center for cremation on Oct. 2 in Monrovia, Liberia.
Sanitized gloves and boots hang to dry as a burial team collects Ebola victims from a Ministry of Health treatment center for cremation on Oct. 2 in Monrovia, Liberia. (John Moore / Getty Images)
Caption Ebola in Liberia
Pascal Guyot / AFP/Getty Images
Medical personnel at the Ebola treatment center at Island hospital in Monrovia, Liberia, disinfect people who had brought patients suspected of having the Ebola virus on Oct. 2.
Medical personnel at the Ebola treatment center at Island hospital in Monrovia, Liberia, disinfect people who had brought patients suspected of having the Ebola virus on Oct. 2. (Pascal Guyot / AFP/Getty Images)
See more galleries
But it did not endorse more radical solutions, such as creating a separate agency or putting another United Nations body in charge of health emergencies. Such agencies would in any case need to coordinate with the WHO, complicating the response, the review concluded.
The panel said it would be far more effective and efficient to revamp the WHO. This transformation must be carried out urgently, it said.
The WHO welcomed the panels findings. In a statement Tuesday, it said it was already moving forward on some of the recommendations, including the development of a global workforce that can be deployed in a health emergency and the establishment of a contingency fund to ensure that resources are available for the initial response. Others will be discussed at a meeting in August.
The WHO ordered the review in March after coming under intense criticism from aid groups such as Doctors Without Borders, which argued that the largest Ebola epidemic on record could have been averted had the agency more quickly sounded the alarm and mobilized outside help.
8
The WHO first reported the outbreak in March 2014 but did not declare a public health emergency of international concern until August. By then, the virus had spread to four West African countries, and casualties were beginning to arrive in the United States and Europe.
More than 11,000 people are now believed to have died of Ebola, most of them in Guinea, Liberia and Sierra Leone. Although the epidemic has slowed, new cases continue to be reported in these countries.
Dr. Margaret Chan, director general of the WHO, acknowledged in May that the world was ill-prepared to respond to an outbreak of the scale and complexity of Ebola. WHO was overwhelmed, as were all other responders, she said.
The panel did not single out individuals for blame but criticized the U.N. organizations bureaucratic culture.
WHO does not have a culture of rapid decision-making and tends to adopt a reactive, rather than a proactive, approach to emergencies. - From an independent panel's report on the World Health Organization
WHO does not have a culture of rapid decision-making and tends to adopt a reactive, rather than a proactive, approach to emergencies, the report said.
In the early stages of the outbreak, messages were sent by WHO staff members at headquarters and in the field about the seriousness of the crisis.
Either these did not reach senior leaders, or senior leaders did not recognize their significance, the report said. There seemed to be a hope that the crisis would be managed by good diplomacy rather than by scaling up emergency response.
As a result, aid groups in the affected countries were left to respond to a crisis for which they were not well equipped.
Gee, I guess we were right to be CAUTIOUS!
Hiram A
2
Stocking acknowledged at a news briefing Tuesday that an emergency declaration by the WHO carries serious political, economic and trade implications for the affected countries, which might resist such a move. The panel recommended the introduction of an intermediate-level alert that could mobilize the international community at an earlier stage in a crisis.
The report also highlights failings of member states, which it says did not fulfill their responsibilities under the WHOs international health regulations. The agencys nearly 200 members are supposed to conduct surveillance and collect data to detect public health threats at an early stage, but largely failed to do so in this outbreak.
Countries that have not developed the capacity to fulfill these functions need support from the WHO and other member states to do so, the report says.
In addition, nearly a quarter of the member states instituted travel bans and other measures that were not called for by the WHO. This not only impeded the delivery of medical supplies and personnel but also created a disincentive for countries to quickly report Ebola cases, as they were often penalized as a result, the report says.
Stocking said both incentives and penalties might be needed to encourage countries to fulfill their obligations.
Where member state behavior threatens the response to the crisis by, for example, making it impossible for health workers to reach affected countries, there should be a procedure to take this matter to the United Nations Security Council, the report says.
The panel welcomed the creation of a $100-million fund for health emergencies and urged member states to contribute. But it said it was disappointed that they had not agreed to increase core funding for the WHO.
Although critical of the WHOs organizational failings, the panel praised its efforts to develop a vaccine, treatment and diagnostic tools for neglected diseases such as Ebola.
Dr. Joanne Liu, the international president of Doctors Without Borders, welcomed the recommendations but said member states would need to step up and see that they were translated into action.
This is not the first time we come with a good plan and a good design for reforming the WHO. This happened after the swine flu [pandemic in 2009] and all the good plans stayed on paper, she told the Los Angels Times.
Meanwhile, there is still an Ebola epidemic to contain. "I think that its good to want toprepare for the next hypothetical epidemic," she said, "but we need to finish the job" at hand.
The panel recommended that an independent board be established to oversee the development of a new Center for Emergency Preparedness and Response and hold it accountable.
The world simply cannot afford another period of inaction until the next health crisis, the report said.
For more international news, follow @alexzavis on Twitter
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 00:05:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How does the Greek debt crisis impact the United States?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-us-impact-qa-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  In 2010 and 2012, the Eurozone's debt problems shook global stock markets and sparked fear of a financial contagion that might derail America's fragile economic recovery.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>How does the Greek debt crisis impact the United States?
Parthenon
A European Union flag waves near the Parthenon atop the Acropolis hill in Athens.
A European Union flag waves near the Parthenon atop the Acropolis hill in Athens.
(Aris Messinis / AFP/Getty Images)
In 2010 and 2012, the Eurozones debt problems shook global stock markets and sparked fear of a financial contagion that might derail Americas fragile economic recovery.
Both times the crisis eased, but not before swiping a little bit of confidence and economic growth.
Once again, a financial crisis in Europe has flared, and this time a Greek exit from the euro group looks very possible. Financial markets have fallen in recent days, and many are nervous about how this will unfold.
But most agree that the impact in the U.S. is likely to be small. Here are answers to some common questions about the crisis:
In the end, Greek voters preferred ambiguity about their future to the certainty of more economic hardships. ( Patrick J. McDonnell )
How are conditions today different from those three years ago?
Although global markets have taken a hit in recent days, there are no signs of widespread panic outside Greece. One key factor is that unlike a few years ago, investors and analysts arent as worried about a collapse in Greece spreading to larger Eurozone countries. Borrowing costs in Italy and Spain, two major economies that have also struggled with bloated debts, have risen some but havent surged as they did several years ago when they caused major financial and political turmoil.
The difference is that Greeces debt, held mostly by private creditors in 2010, has since been absorbed by government agencies and international organizations, including the European Central Bank. And the ECB has committed firepower to buy government bonds to hold down rates should there be a massive investor sell-off, something it hadnt done before. In autumn 2012, Eurozone countries also set up a crisis-resolution mechanism with a lending capacity of 500 billion euros as a firewall to guard against contagion to other euro member states.
What is the likely effect on the U.S. economy?
The U.S. has very little direct exposure to the Greek debt crisis. At the end of last year, U.S. banks had claims of about $12.7 billion on Greece, including its banks. American taxpayers have some limited exposure in that the U.S. is a shareholder of the International Monetary Fund, which is a creditor of Greece. But under the IMFs arrangement, it is expected to be paid back in full eventually.
@kafantaris2 For the want of maturity, Greece is lost... This has been some years in the making, but you must be a liberal who believes in responsibility only for the rich or White...
Wazoo2u2
13
The volume of American exports to Greece is a speck, totaling $772 million last year out of total U.S. merchandise exports to the world exceeding $1.6 trillion, or less than .05%. A prolonged Greek debt crisis, however, is likely to slow an already sluggish European economy, which in turn could crimp U.S. exports more significantly. A little more than a fifth of American exports are to Europe, and many U.S. companies with operations on that continent already have felt a pinch to their earnings from weaker sales and the strong dollar, a result partly of the European Central Banks pumping more money into the economy.
What can the U.S. do about the problems in Europe, and what leverage does the government have?
In a word, little.
For several years, the Obama administration has repeatedly urged the Eurozone to strengthen its institutional framework while taking an approach in Greece and with other troubled countries that calls for balancing growth measures with policies aimed at fiscal belt-tightening. But though they listen politely, European leaders have made clear that this is a problem to be dealt with in Brussels, not Washington.
How will the Greek debt crisis affect Federal Reserve policies on interest rates?
The Feds leader, Janet L. Yellen, raised some caution last month about the situation in Greece: To the extent that there are impacts on the euro-area economy or on global financial markets, there would undoubtedly be spillovers to the United States that would affect our outlook as well.
At the moment, however, the problems in Greece arent likely to weigh heavily on the central bank as it considers raising interest rates for the first time in nearly a decade. The Feds primary concern is the performance of the U.S. economy, and indicators of late have been mixed, suggesting that policymakers may want to wait a little longer and to feel more confident about the job market and inflation trends before raising rates.
What does the crisis mean for American consumers and investors?
In the short term, financial markets are likely to remain volatile. In recent days, U.S. stocks have fallen, although not as much as in Europe. Still, further declines could be expected to cut into consumer confidence and possibly spending.
At the same time, oil prices have retreated again, in part because of expectations that Europes trouble will slow demand a bit. Lower energy costs would, on net, be a positive for American consumers, although that may prove to be short-lived.
Follow me on Twitter at @dleelatimes
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 23:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Obama is sticking with his Islamic State strategy</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-obama-islamic-state-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  President Obama talks every day about defeating the Islamic State militants, but advisors say one option never surfaces for serious consideration - bringing the U.S. military in more directly to save the fledgling Iraqi security forces from their failures.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Why Obama is sticking with his Islamic State strategy
President Obama at Pentagon
Saul Loeb / AFP/Getty Images
President Obama said Monday atthe Pentagon that theU.S.-led coalition battling Islamic State militants is "intensifying" its campaign but offered few specifics beyond increased airstrikes in Syria.
President Obama said Monday atthe Pentagon that theU.S.-led coalition battling Islamic State militants is "intensifying" its campaign but offered few specifics beyond increased airstrikes in Syria.
(Saul Loeb / AFP/Getty Images)
Iraq Crisis (2014)
President Obama talks every day about defeating the Islamic State militants, but advisors say one option never surfaces for serious consideration  bringing the U.S. military in more directly to save the fledgling Iraqi security forces from their failures.
Obama doubled down on his approach this week in a meeting with top generals, who later stood with him at the Pentagon as he explained his conviction that a large-scale investment of U.S. troops in another fight in the Middle East is a bad idea. He insisted that his military leaders agreed.
In every one of the conversations that we've had, the strong consensus is that, in order for us to succeed long term in this fight against ISIL, we have to develop local security forces that can sustain progress, Obama said, using an acronym for the extremist group.
In 2012, President Obama made it plain in a letter to Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei that any attempt to close the strategic Strait of Hormuz would be met with American force. ( Paul Richter )
His position has plenty of challenges, particularly for a president trying to implement a long-term strategy on a short-term clock.
The timeline for the improvements Obama hopes to see  an Iraqi military that can take and hold ground, a resolution to the civil war in Syria, stability in either country  is not in his favor; they will probably come long after hes left office, if at all. Leading Republican critics are losing patience. They argue that Islamic State's gains in Iraq and Syria and its expanded presence in Libya and Egypt, plus its persuasive recruitment campaign, prove Obama's strategy isnt working.
And then there is what top Obama aides see as the biggest problem: Iraqs inability to address rampant sectarianism. The presidents national security apparatus is deeply concerned that too few Sunni Muslims are in positions of power, and that the Iraqi government relies too heavily on Shiite Muslim militias and Iranian advisors to fight Islamic State.
8
Yet advisors to the president say Obama is growing more resolute in his belief that slowly building up Iraqs capacity to defend its own territory, despite appearing to be messy and unsatisfying now, offers the only realistic way forward.
Although the alternative  more direct U.S. military involvement  could work in the short run, as the president has acknowledged, he frequently expresses the belief that the situation would quickly fall apart again as soon as American forces leave. He is unwilling to occupy Iraq indefinitely and believes the public feels the same, a conclusion that goes back to his promise as a candidate that hed be the president who ends wars, rather than starting them.
If we came in and did it for them, its not going to get at the root causes that allowed ISIL to have such dramatic momentum last summer, said one senior administration official, who requested anonymity in characterizing the presidents viewpoint as he recently expressed it in internal conversations. We could quell the uprising, but that will not suffice if there is, at its root, this political and social divisiveness within the country.
Thats the critical piece of the presidents approach, the official said.
Obamas view dates to the beginning of his administration. In his earliest White House statements about the war in Iraq, he emphasized the importance of Iraqis taking responsibility for their security.
In 2011, as the last American convoys were preparing to leave Iraq, aides noticed that Obama was inverting President George W. Bushs pledge that, as the Iraqis stood up, the U.S. would stand down. Obamas evolving view was that it would take the U.S. relinquishing responsibility before the Iraqis would govern.
cComments
@LJP-305 @R.L. Schaefer The execution of "Ways - training up Iraqi Security forces", while correct in principle, in practice is not working as well as the President hoped for, for the reasons I explain above. So I present a bolder strategy, in my comments above, which makes much...
Supreme Allied Condista
61
Over the next four years, each new failure of the Iraqi security forces, hindered by corruption in the government of former Prime Minister Nouri Maliki, was seen in the White House as a grim confirmation of Obamas assumption.
This was a belief that ran all the way back to his campaign in 2008, said Julianne Smith, a former advisor on the White House national security team. The question for him all along was, Will it be sustainable?
That remains an open question. In Sunni-populated areas such as Anbar province, citizens distrust their army and, in some cases, even view them as an occupying force.
To help ease the sectarian divide, the White House set up a training base last month in Anbar for outreach into Sunni tribal areas with the goal of drawing them into the fold. The U.S. has seen positive results over the last two weeks, with 1,300 Sunni tribal fighters enrolled in the traditionally Shiite militias.
Still, other problems persist. So far, the U.S.-led military training program in Iraq has only turned out about 9,000 Iraqi soldiers, far short of the 24,000 that the Pentagon envisioned training by this fall.
And Defense Secretary Ashton Carter told lawmakers Tuesday that the U.S. has trained just 60 Syrian opposition fighters to fight Islamic State in that country, far below its goal.
After four years, Mr. Secretary, that is not a very impressive number, Republican Sen. John McCain of Arizona, the Armed Services Committee chairman, told Carter.
The Obama administration announced in May that it hoped to train more than 5,000 Syrians a year at camps in Jordan and Turkey to form a so-called moderate opposition in Syria. The program has faced setbacks, though, including the difficulty of finding recruits free of extremist ties who want to fight Islamic State, rather than forces loyal to Syrian leader Bashar Assad.
Some Iraqi officials are worried about the U.S. strategy.
Obama recently agreed to send 450 additional U.S. military trainers and support personnel, on top of the 3,100 already in place, to help with the training mission. Yet many Iraqi officials, who wanted the U.S. to take on a more active role, were let down.
Mowaffak Rubaie, Iraq's former national security advisor and now a lawmaker, accused the White House of failing to adequately articulate its strategy against Islamic State and said it doesnt seem to be willing to commit to the fight.
He has called on the Obama administration to send U.S. troops to the front lines to direct coalition airstrikes, especially in densely populated areas where it can be difficult to tell friend from foe. But that seems unlikely, so Rubaie is turning his attention to a new U.S. president in 2017.
We hope the next U.S. administration will be more engaging and proactive, he said, describing a not-so-veiled frustration with Obama. At least we will know what the U.S. strategy is to sync with.
White House officials have come to expect regular attacks on Obamas viewpoint, especially when Islamic State takes more territory.
Republicans generally see those losses as proof that Obamas strategy is flawed. On the campaign trail, several GOP candidates blame Obamas failure to leave a residual force in Iraq. Notably, though, his critics, including McCain, have yet to offer an alternative long-term solution.
Speaking at the Pentagon this week, Obama made clear his growing comfort with the criticism.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 21:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>It's a bumpy ride for China's stock market investors</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-china-stock-market-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Having invested in China's stock market for more than a third of his life, Zhou Jinli had plenty of experience with the cycle of boom and bust. But a recent crash that wiped out two-thirds of Zhou's retirement funds told him he hadn't seen it all.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>It's a bumpy ride for China's stock market investors
China financial markets
AP
A stock investor slumps in front of a screen Monday displaying the Shanghai Composite Index at a brokerage house in Qingdao, in east China's Shandong province.
A stock investor slumps in front of a screen Monday displaying the Shanghai Composite Index at a brokerage house in Qingdao, in east China's Shandong province.
(AP)
NYSE
Having invested in Chinas stock market for more than a third of his life, Zhou Jinli had plenty of experience with the cycle of boom and bust. But a recent crash that wiped out two-thirds of Zhous retirement funds told him he hadnt seen it all.
This is the worst Ive ever seen, said Zhou, 63. I hope the government will get to the bottom of this.
China markets
Andy Wong / Associated Press
A man rubs his head while browsing his smartphone outside a brokerage house in Beijing on Tuesday.
A man rubs his head while browsing his smartphone outside a brokerage house in Beijing on Tuesday.
(Andy Wong / Associated Press)
Zhou, a retired foreign ministry official with a crown of snowy white hair, said he had put more than $32,000 of his savings into the market. On Tuesday, he was outside the China Securities Regulatory Commission, the equivalent of the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, to lend moral support to a trio of demonstrators. Like them, he believes the government should exercise more oversight to keep the stock market in check.
The Shanghai Stock Exchange Composite Index, mainland Chinas main stock index, reached the height of a vertiginous climb  a 63% gain in four months  in mid-June. Since then, it has been on a downward spiral, declining 20% so far and sending alarms through Chinas growing ranks of investors.
8
Since Chinas stock markets, except for one in Hong Kong, are largely closed to international investors (about 2% of Chinese shares are foreign owned), the contagion effect is expected to be minimal.
In early June, days before the decline began, the U.S.-based stock index MSCI decided not to include some of mainland Chinas stronger stocks in its Emerging Markets Index.
However, unlike in some other economies, Chinas shares are mostly in the hands of individual investors, and market woes reach a broad swath of the countrys best-educated and affluent people.
I do want to see my money back. - Adam Bai, a young investor
Theyre well-to-do and are extremely vocal, said Wang Tao, chief China economist at UBS Securities in Hong Kong. If theyre unhappy, the government may be concerned.
For many Chinese, the stock market is one of the few freely available investment channels. Foreign exchange is strictly controlled. In most cities, the government puts a limit on home purchases in an effort to curb soaring property prices.
0
The Shanghai Stock Exchange started trading in 1990, followed a year later by the Shenzhen Stock Exchange, which offers high-tech start-up stocks. Taken together, their combined capitalization would make them the worlds third largest market, behind the New York Stock Exchange and NASDAQ.
A recent survey by the state-run New China News Agency shows that more than 30% of college students own shares in the stock market.
Unlike Zhou, who started buying stocks in 1993, many of the stockholders are newcomers who jumped on the bandwagon in recent months.
In May, 12 million new stock market accounts were opened, bringing the total to 90 million in mainland China.
Adam Bai is one such newcomer. In late May, the graduate student in software engineering decided to plow $650 from the income he earned as an intern into three mutual funds, deeming them less risky than stocks. After some gains in his first two weeks, he doubled his capital. Now his investment is down 20% from its peak, tracking the market.
I do want to see my money back, said Bai. I believe in my government, and I still believe in the market.
Over the past week, government officers have pulled out all the stops to stabilize the market. They slashed the interest rate, curbed initial stock offerings and corralled major brokerages into pumping in more capital.
State media has been entreating everyone, from housewives to top executives, to buy shares. Meanwhile, rumors keep flying about market manipulation.
The crash points to the need to strengthen regulation and supervision and the lack of transparency, said Wang, the UBS economist.
Meanwhile, Zhou said he could nothing but wait out the worst bust in his life as an investor, buoyed only with faith that more effective government intervention would be coming. He warned that turmoil wont be confined to the stock indexes for long.
If the government doesnt do more about this situation, this could touch off a financial crisis and social instability, Zhou said.
Law is a special correspondent. Tommy Yang and Harvard Zhang of The Times' Beijing bureau contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 21:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghan envoys, Taliban in Pakistan for peace talks, officials say</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-afghanistan-taliban-peace-talks-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Representatives of the Afghan government and the Taliban were in Pakistan for their first face-to-face talks, Afghan officials said Tuesday, signaling the possible start of negotiations to end nearly 14 years of conflict.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan envoys, Taliban in Pakistan for peace talks, officials say
Afghanistan
Rahmat Gul / Associated Press
Afghan security forces inspect the site of a suicide attack that targeted a NATO convoy in Kabul on July 7, one of a series of recent attacks that came despite moves toward peace talks between the two sides.
Afghan security forces inspect the site of a suicide attack that targeted a NATO convoy in Kabul on July 7, one of a series of recent attacks that came despite moves toward peace talks between the two sides.
(Rahmat Gul / Associated Press)
8
President Ashraf Ghani said on his official Twitter account that members of the government's High Peace Council had traveled to Pakistan for the meeting. A Pakistani official confirmed that the talks would take place near Islamabad but did not offer details.
As soon as he sees the brightly colored storefronts of fruit sellers and general merchandisers on this small stretch of road, Gholam Karbalai knows he is safe. ( Ali M. Latifi )
The announcement marks a victory for Ghani, who has staked much of his young presidency on a high-stakes bid to engage Taliban insurgents and neighboring Pakistan in an elusive peace process.
It comes amid a wave of violence in Afghanistan, much of it blamed on the Taliban. The militants have mounted one of their fiercest offensives in recent months and inflicted heavy casualties on government forces as they attempt to take control of districts in northern and southern Afghanistan.
0
The impact of the talks on the violence was not immediately clear, but Pakistan's participation was seen as significant because the Taliban's leadership is based in that country and it has long been viewed in Afghanistan as an obstacle to peace.
Sources in Ghani's office described the meeting as crucial because it showed the Taliban were ready to negotiate directly with the government they have been battling since they were ousted from power by the 2001 U.S.-led invasion of Afghanistan.
The Taliban have sent intermediaries, including former insurgents, to meet with Afghan officials over the last year in secret talks in Qatar and China. However, the location, public acknowledgment and face-to-face contact would be firsts for these talks.
Taliban officials did not immediately confirm their participation, but they have disavowed past meetings. The group has long said it would not negotiate directly with a government it views as a U.S.-backed puppet, but behind the scenes some Taliban leaders are believed to be seeking a truce that grants them a role in Afghan public life and a softening of U.S. and Western sanctions against them.
U.S. and Chinese officials would be present at the meetings in Pakistan to serve as "monitors," said an official in Ghani's office, who could not be quoted by name due to the sensitivity of the talks. Ghani was due to meet Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif to discuss the peace initiative this week at a regional summit in Russia, the official said.
Special correspondent Latifi reported from Kabul and staff writer Bengali from Mumbai, India.
Follow @SBengali on Twitter for news out of Afghanistan and Pakistan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 17:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks extended again; Friday new deadline</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-iran-nuclear-talks-extended-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Six leading world powers and Iran acknowledged that they would miss a midnight Tuesday deadline for wrapping up a comprehensive nuclear deal, forcing them to extend talks for the fifth time in the last year.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks extended again; Friday new deadline
Iran talks
Carlos Barria / AFP/Getty Images
U.S. Secretary of State John F. Kerry and Undersecretary of State Wendy Sherman meet with foreign ministers at a hotel in Vienna on Tuesday to discuss Iran's nuclear program.
U.S. Secretary of State John F. Kerry and Undersecretary of State Wendy Sherman meet with foreign ministers at a hotel in Vienna on Tuesday to discuss Iran's nuclear program.
(Carlos Barria / AFP/Getty Images)
European Union
Six leading world powers and Iran acknowledged that they would miss a midnight Tuesday deadline for wrapping up a comprehensive nuclear deal, forcing them to extend talks for the fifth time in the last year.
Diplomats who last week emphasized the urgency of finishing work by the deadline said the important goal now was producing a sound deal. They set a new deadline of Friday, but acknowledged they were not certain when the work would be concluded.
As diplomats rush to reach an agreement to curb Iran's nuclear program, the U.S. military is stockpiling conventional bombs so powerful that strategists say they could cripple Tehran's most heavily fortified nuclear complexes, including one deep underground. ( W.J. Hennigan )
Were more concerned about a quality deal than we are about the clock, said Marie Harf, strategic communications advisor to Secretary of State John F. Kerry. Weve made substantial progress in all areas, but this work is highly technical and there are high stakes for all the countries involved.
We are taking these negotiations day to day, she said.
8
Missing the latest deadline means that the Obama administration may also fail to meet a congressional deadline of midnight Thursday for transmitting the deal and supporting documentation to lawmakers. If that deadline is broken, the period that Congress has given itself to review the deal will be extended to 60 days from 30 days.
The administration has been eager to meet that deadline, fearing an extension would allow time for critics to maneuver to undermine the agreement. But officials have said in recent days that missing the deadline would not be a serious setback.
Some of the foreign ministers who had arrived in the Austrian capital Sunday and Monday to try to resolve politically sensitive issues began to leave. Kerry, Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarifand European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said they would stay to continue work on the document and its voluminous technical annexes.
Iran and the six world powers -- the United States, France, Britain, Germany, Russia and China -- are seeking a deal that would ease sanctions on Iran if it agrees to restrictions aimed at preventing it from obtaining a nuclear bomb.
Diplomats have said since this round began June 26 that they had narrowed the remaining issues to three or four. Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said Tuesday that the remaining issues were now less than 10.
"The negotiations have always moved ahead and are now closer to completion than they have ever been." Makes you weep at how a reporter can be used.
mjfbauer
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Evangelicals take their fight with Satan to the streets of Sao Paulo</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-ff-brazil-street-preachers-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  It is 5 p.m., and the church bells in the center of the city begin to toll. Hundreds of commuters stream across the Praca da Se square, passing in front of the headquarters of the largest archdiocese in the nation with the most Catholics in the world.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Evangelicals take their fight with Satan to the streets of Sao Paulo
Brazilian street preacher
Vincent Bevins / For The Times
A street preacher spreads the word in Brazil in May.The evangelicals are foot soldiers on the front lines of a religious battle that their side seems to be winning.
A street preacher spreads the word in Brazil in May.The evangelicals are foot soldiers on the front lines of a religious battle that their side seems to be winning.
(Vincent Bevins / For The Times)
By Vincent Bevins
Pope Francis
It is 5 p.m., and the church bells in the center of the city begin to toll. Hundreds of commuters stream across the Praca da Se square, passing in front of the headquarters of the largest archdiocese in the nation with the most Catholics in the world.
But over the pealing sounds of the cathedral, many commuters are hearing a very different religious message.
"The world is dominated by sin! Only the Gospel can save you! Only evangelism can save you!" shouts a middle-aged man, gesticulating wildly and increasing volume as he utters each sentence. A rapt crowd of 30 or 40, mostly men, listens as the street preacher seeks to draw in additional passersby, warning them of danger to their souls.
I was born and raised Catholic like everyone else. But it's full of false doctrine and tradition which has nothing to do with the word. - Josemar Bento Mendes, Brazilian street preacher
"Satan is hidden everywhere! If you're with a religion, you're wrong! If you're Catholic, you're wrong! Put your hands together for Jesus!" The crowd obliges.
Nearby, homeless youths huddle together, passing a crack pipe back and forth. A young woman, apparently mentally ill, sits among the worshipers, playing with leaves and sticks on the ground.
Street preachers maintain a daily presence here and elsewhere around Brazil, calling upon believers to accept Jesus directly, rejecting the need for the Roman Catholic Church to serve as mediator.
Whereas some leaders behind Brazil's large evangelical churches have become famously wealthy and powerful, these men sweat on the street among Sao Paulo's downtrodden. They're foot soldiers on the front lines of a religious battle that their side seems to be winning.
8
When Josemar Bento Mendes was born, 50 years ago, more than 90% of Brazilians declared themselves Catholic. But by 2013, at the time that Pope Francis, the first pontiff from the Americas, visited, just 57% of Brazilians claimed allegiance to Rome. About 28% declared a commitment to some kind of evangelical Christian faith.
"I was born and raised Catholic like everyone else. But it's full of false doctrine and tradition which has nothing to do with the word," says Bento Mendes, who is preaching in the harsh cold of a wintry June day. "I come here because everyone in the city comes through the plaza. It's ground zero. It's a river with many fish, and many people suffering."
Mendes and others preach that the Bible is God's authoritative word, which should be spread evangelically, and that the Catholic Church is not necessary to interpret it.
Most of the fish in the river move along quickly, heading into the crowded metro station. But those loitering in the square tend to respect the seriousness of the gathering. After one young man, visibly high, spends a few minutes giggling, his perceived insolence is quickly singled out.
A tough-looking man in a hoodie and gold chains threatens him, instructing, "Respect the word of God!" The youth is soon clapping and praying along with the rest.
Preachers change off every hour or so and switch up styles. But they all rely on their intensity and passion, which could not contrast more sharply with the inside of the Catholic cathedral.
There, a priest's sermon is scarcely audible over the PA as he calmly explains the meaning of the church calendar. The audience for his Mass is barely larger than the circle formed around the preachers outside. Their slight presence in the pews is dwarfed by the ornate and grand structure built to hold thousands.
Superstitious nut jobs down south? The world is thick with these morons.
docrasta69
3
The format of the lessons outside is also looser, with the preachers reading select passages from the Bible, then expounding on their meaning. They may seem to be closer to adhering to Jesus' message of embracing the poor and sick, but these teachings  and indeed the Gospels themselves  are almost never the main point. Over the course of days and various preachers, a few dominant themes emerge: the imminent apocalypse, the influence of Satan and the evils of homosexuality.
"There are men sleeping with other men! We should see shame in your faces! You are worse than a dog or a pig. I have never seen a pig lie down with another pig," says one. Some in the crowd just listen intently, while others cry out spontaneously, or raise their eyes to the sky and tremble.
The preacher now turns his wrath on Edir Macedo, the media mogul billionaire leader of the evangelical Universal Church of the Kingdom of God, for airing sexually charged shows on his Record TV network. Bento Mendes and preacher Waldo Silvio Santos belong to the competing Assembly of God congregation. "Woe to you who pays his tithes to men who put naked women on TV to make millions. False prophets love money."
The evangelical movement has been criticized for profiting off Brazil's most destitute and sometimes offering a version of Christianity that they consider fundamentalist and reactionary, rejecting much of modern society. Within the complicated rules of Brazil's brutal class system, however, many middle-class liberals have also felt uncomfortable criticizing any movement that is largely working class.
But in the last few months, evangelical figures have risen to top positions of political power, causing liberals to panic. Eduardo Cunha, an evangelical who serves as president of the lower house of Congress, is considered a dangerous, cynical schemer by progressives, and he has said he will bar any vote on liberalizing abortion, which is illegal here.
After evangelical congressmen staged a protest against Sao Paulo's recent Gay Pride Parade, the major Folha de S.Paulo newspaper printed a scathing indictment: "A growing spirit of fundamentalism is manifesting itself ... and Congress seems committed to reflect this trend, intensify it, and use it to demagogic ends."
But the halls of the capitol in Brasilia are very far away from Praca da Se. As a Catholic priest and a Franciscan friar walk slowly, Bento Mendes has no time for focus on matters of politics.
"It is a thousand times better to trust in God than to trust in princes," he booms. "And I tell you this: Christ's return is coming sooner than we imagine. If it doesn't, I'll stop preaching. I'll rip up my Bible, if terrible things don't rain down upon us soon."
Bevins is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Airstrikes hit two markets in Yemen; more than 100 people killed</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-yemen-market-explosion-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  More than 100 people were killed in airstrikes that hit two markets in Yemen on Monday, according to witnesses and officials, as a Saudi Arabian-led coalition continued aerial attacks against Houthi rebels for a fourth month.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>The second strike happened about 11 p.m. at a market in the area of Joub, north of Sana, and killed more than 60 people, according to the Houthi-run Defense Ministry.
Khalid Mahlah of Sana wondered when the world would call for an end to the airstrikes.
It is a shame on all the international [community] that they have given in and remain silent, Mahlah said in an interview.
More than 3,000 people, half of them civilians, have been killed and 14,000 more wounded since airstrikes began March 25, according to the United Nations, as the conflict has deepened into an alarming humanitarian crisis in the Arab worlds poorest country.
More than 1 million Yemenis have fled their homes, and 13 million have poor access to food, according to the United Nations. The organization has called the conflict a humanitarian catastrophe and is seeking a cease-fire until at least the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan in mid-July.
The Shiite Muslim rebels took over Sana in September, and the stated goal of the Saudi-led coalitions airstrikes has been to restore to power exiled President Abdu Rabu Mansour Hadi.
Previous air bombardments have struck Houthi positions and weapons caches but also residential areas and historic sites. The coalition has not acknowledged the killing of civilians and has accused the Houthis of using civilians as human shields.
Airstrikes on Monday also hit other parts of Yemen, including an area of Aden where seven people were killed, officials said. One strike hit a Houthi political office in a heavily populated area of Sana, injuring several people.
Special correspondent al-Alayaa reported from Sana, and staff writer Pearce from Los Angeles.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece seeks a bailout proposal that Eurozone nations could stomach</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-resignation-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Greece raced to come up with bailout proposals palatable to its international lenders Monday before its banks run out of money and the country slides closer to a chaotic default and exit from the Eurozone.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece seeks a bailout proposal that Eurozone nations could stomach
Yanis Varoufakis
Angelos Christofilopoulos / Associated Press
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis speaks Sunday in Athens after the results of the bailout referendum.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis speaks Sunday in Athens after the results of the bailout referendum.
(Angelos Christofilopoulos / Associated Press)
International Monetary Fund
Greece raced to come up with bailout proposals palatable to its international lenders Monday before its banks run out of money and the country slides closer to a chaotic default and exit from the Eurozone.
At the same time, officials in various European capitals huddled in their own emergency meetings to forge a common response amid signs of rifts between, and within, countries over how hard a line to take with Athens.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras is expected to offer new proposals for funding his cash-starved government to the leaders of the other 18 nations that use the euro currency during a summit Tuesday evening in Brussels. Convincing the Eurozone leaders that there is a basis for an agreement is key to Greeces short- and long-term economic survival.
Greek voters' resounding rejection of international creditors demands may have strengthened the hand of their prime minister, Alexis Tsipras, who rose to power promising to halt painful austerity measures imposed in the bailout. But what options are open to the Greek leader when he meets with... ( Don Lee )
If they agree that a deal is possible, then the European Central Bank is likely to maintain the special lifeline it has extended to Greeces ailing banks to keep them functioning.
But if differences between Athens and its lenders appear irreconcilable, the European Central Bank could conclude that Greeces banks are insolvent and cut its emergency aid, and Greek banks would collapse within days, if not hours. Trade would seize up, residents would lose access to their savings and Greeces ability to continue using the euro would fall into serious doubt.
Under major pressure to reach an understanding with his Eurozone counterparts, Tsipras secured support from nearly all of Greeces political parties for his new offer, a show of unity meant to demonstrate his sincerity in negotiating in good faith on behalf of all Greeks. Trust between Tsipras and his European partners is at rock bottom since the previous round of talks broke down and Greek voters, in a referendum Sunday, heeded his call to reject creditor bailout proposals that were heavy on austerity.
8
On Monday, the European Central Bank avoided inflicting immediate catastrophe on Greece.
But as happened last week, the European Central Bank declined to increase the amount of emergency funds available, meaning that the banks cash supplies are continuing to dwindle. The European bank also upped the value of assets that the banks must provide as collateral to keep receiving aid, putting the banks in an even more precarious position.
The European bank has pumped $98 billion into the Greek financial system in recent months to prevent it from running out of money as depositors scrambled to withdraw their euros while they still could, for moving into accounts abroad or hiding under their mattresses. Greece's banks are reportedly down to their last $555 million  or about $50 per person in this country of 11 million.
Athens announced Monday that its weeklong closure of the banks and its cap on the amount customers can withdraw each day  about $66  would be extended through Wednesday. Officials had previously pledged to reopen the banks Tuesday.
Long lines at ATMs under the hot Aegean sun have been a common sight since capital controls were imposed. But Greeks have mostly taken the situation in stride, and some seem unfazed by the possibility of even worse restrictions if Greeces financial predicament worsens.
There is no fear in our hearts. We dont worship at ATMs, said Katerina Bakaliani, a 35-year-old film director. If I dont have enough to eat, I will pick an apple from a tree.
In Paris, the Eurozones two most important leaders, French President Francois Hollande and German Chancellor Angela Merkel, met to discuss the Greek crisis and to try to damp speculation of a split in attitude toward Greece between Northern and Southern European countries.
@sittingherethinking - Question. In your mind, are Germany, Holland, Denmark and Sweden "socialist" countries?
Thinkandverify91
92
Officials from Germany, Finland and the Netherlands spoke harshly of Athens on Monday, saying that the referendum result had set back relations with the Eurozone and that any bailout deal would now be harder to negotiate, not easier.
A German Finance Ministry spokesman poured cold water on the idea of any discussion of relief of Greeces colossal public debt, something that Greek negotiators insist must be on the table. A report by the International Monetary Fund released last week said that Athens needed loans of $55 billion and massive debt relief to survive through 2018.
Other European officials have been more conciliatory, including the French finance minister, Michel Sapin, who said discussions of Greeces debt were not taboo. Spanish and Italian officials also urged a fair settlement with Greece as soon as possible and expressed their desire to see Athens remain a member of the Eurozone.
There were reports that Hollande had encouraged Tsipras to get the backing of other Greek political parties for his new bailout offer, which would make it easier for France to broker a deal.
Speaking to reporters with Merkel, the French leader said it was incumbent upon Europe to resolve the crisis over one of its own.
Within this Europe, there is room for solidarity, Hollande said.
The door for talks remains open. Time is of the essence, and we hope that this week we will get these proposals, said Merkel, who spoke with Tsipras by phone Monday.
It was unclear what concessions either Greece or its lenders would be willing to make to break their previous impasse and clinch a deal. In fact, with the referendum result backing him, Tsipras might feel emboldened to press for an even greater reduction of austerity measures, whereas some creditor countries might feel inclined to dig in their heels.
The last offer we made was quite a generous one, Merkel said.
Tsipras plan is likely to involve tapping a bailout fund known as the European Stability Mechanism, which was set up after the euro debt crisis erupted in 2009, first in Greece and then in nations such as Ireland and Portugal.
Although Tsipras came to power in January pledging to end austerity, further spending cuts will probably be unavoidable in any deal. That will require the Greek leader to persuade members of his own left-wing Syriza party to stay on his side.
He chaired a six-hour meeting with leaders of the other political parties Monday to thrash out proposals that would garner their support.
Despite rejecting more Europe-ordered austerity in Sundays referendum, in a 61% to 39% vote, the vast majority of Greeks want their country to remain in the Eurozone. Tsipras insists that it will do so, and officials have let slip no indication of contingency plans to introduce a parallel currency or reprint drachmas in the event of a bank system failure or a default by Athens on its debts. Such talk would undoubtedly spook the markets.
Merkel, too, must worry about politics at home.
Any new bailout deal for Greece would need the Bundestags approval. Her grip on power is tight in Germany, Greeces biggest lender, but many of her backbenchers have openly expressed anger with Athens over its perceived irresponsibility and unwillingness to play by the rules.
To improve his chances of getting a deal, Tsipras named a new finance minister Monday, Euclid Tsakalotos, after the surprise resignation of the colorful but controversial Yanis Varoufakis.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks philosophical about uncertain future after rejecting bailout deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-react-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  In the end, Greek voters preferred ambiguity about their future to the certainty of more economic hardships.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Greeks philosophical about uncertain future after rejecting bailout deal
Yanis Varoufakis
Petros Karadjias / Associated Press
Outgoing Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis is surrounded as he tries to leave on his motorcycle after resigning in Athens. Greece and its membership in the Eurozone face an uncertain future after voters rejected a bailout plan that would have led to drastic austerity measures.
Outgoing Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis is surrounded as he tries to leave on his motorcycle after resigning in Athens. Greece and its membership in the Eurozone face an uncertain future after voters rejected a bailout plan that would have led to drastic austerity measures. (Petros Karadjias / Associated Press)
European Union
In the end, Greek voters preferred ambiguity about their future to the certainty of more economic hardships.
"We don't know what's going to happen now: Maybe it will be worse for a while, but maybe it will get better eventually," said Alexandra Tsalafouta, who, along with her husband and infant son, was among the multitudes strolling Monday along the picturesque harbor-front promenade of this northern port city. "But if we had voted 'yes,' for sure things would have been worse."
A lot of people felt it was all propaganda. It had the opposite effect, making a lot of people vote "no." - George Giorgos, Internet cafe employee
It was a sentiment often heard a day after Greeks overwhelmingly rejected an international bailout plan that would have imposed drastic new austerity measures on a nation where residents are plainly fed up with what many view as cutbacks imposed by a shadowy economic elite. More than 60% voted "no" to the rescue package, a landslide by any measure.
"I don't know who's behind it all: the Germans, the Russians, the Americans  who knows?" asked one pensioner seated with other elderly Greeks on a bench in Aristotle Square, where a bronze bust of the philosopher ponders the tranquil scene. "Someone is doing this to us."
Still, she said she was in the minority that voted "yes" in Sunday's referendum.
"For stability," explained the woman, who gave only her first name, Eugenia, for privacy reasons.
"We are worried; Greece needs stability," she said, as her bench mates nodded in agreement. "The banks? What is going to happen to them?"
8
It was a theme  vote "yes" for stability  that was often heard from "yes" proponents, especially in the media. But the campaign may have backfired: Many seemed to view the intensive pro-"yes" effort as a scare tactic meant to convince Greeks that voting "no" could have catastrophic consequences, especially for pensioners.
Closed banks and long lines at ATMs in recent days fanned the fears. Yet Greeks ultimately didn't buy the doomsday scenario.
"A lot of people felt it was all propaganda," said George Giorgos, 19, an Internet cafe employee studying computer science in Thessaloniki, Greece's second-largest city and home to a large student population. "It had the opposite effect, making a lot of people vote 'no.'"
He, like others, stressed that Greeks were determined to remain part of the European Union, a bond that many view as historic, cultural and unbreakable. Many seemed confident that a deal more favorable to Greeks will emerge from talks between European leaders, keeping Greece from defaulting on its debt and exiting the Eurozone.
"Of course we will stay with Europe," said Michael Michalis, 18, a physics student.
cComments
Greece is like the dysfunctional cousin that the family must support to keep off skid row. EU faces another problem though. Once Greece gets away with draining EU money, there are a couple additional countries that are waiting to follow whatever escape mechanism Greece negotiates. That's...
Future View
18
People in the city talked about a collective fatigue with years of dwindling incomes, vanishing job opportunities and a loss of a sense of security. Many who cast "no" votes Sunday did so as a collective rebuff of forced pauperization, a national declaration that enough is enough. They lamented the pejorative image of Greeks as people who don't want to work.
"We all work hard and want something better for our children," said Tsalafouta, glancing at her 18-month-old son, Gabriel, in the arms of her husband, Evangelous Siomas, whose pest-control business has endured cutbacks. "Everyone is working longer hours and earning less."
On a practical level, many business owners feared that new austerity measures and higher taxes would have been the death knell for already struggling enterprises.
"A 'yes' vote would have killed tourism here," said a hotel owner on the island of Lesbos, a popular vacation spot for European visitors. "Tourism is the best thing Greece has going for it now. Why make it harder for us?"
Among "no" voters, there was a distinct sense that Greece had finally fought back against the banks and oligarchs  and especially against Germany, the economic colossus of the European Union.
"I'm not frightened of Germany's junta," said Anthi Papadopoulou, 73, a pensioner with four grandchildren who was among the jubilant "no" backers celebrating into the early hours of Monday in Athens' Syntagma Square, in front of the Parliament building. "Right now we have a junta without tanks. It is economic war."
Despite the prevalent uncertainty about what will happen next, she said she was not frightened, even if she were to lose her pension of nearly $555 per month.
"Many are not afraid  we will survive," Papadopoulou proclaimed. "We'll live on lentils if we need to.... They can take my pension.... My pride, they will never take."
Others were more somber than exultant as European officials frantically tried to negotiate a solution to the crisis.
"Of course I'm still afraid and biting my nails expecting what's going to happen over the next five days," said Giorgos Kavasakalis, 38, an architect who voted "yes" in the referendum.
"Time is not on our side right now," added Kavasakalis, who has been considering immigrating to the United States. " We really have to hurry. Greece doesn't have time. Something has to happen, and it has to happen real fast."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After the Greek referendum: What will Merkel do?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-merkel-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  German Chancellor Angela Merkel has long said she wants to see Greece remain in the Eurozone, but "not at any price." And the Sunday vote by Greeks to reject their creditors' formula for repayment of $270 billion in bailout loans sent that price skyrocketing in both political and economic terms.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>62
However, in light of the decision by the Greek citizens, the conditions to start negotiations on a new aid program are not met yet, Seibert said, adding that Berlin would wait and see what the Greek government makes of it.
Seibert said the German government was stressing the principle that solidarity is inseparable from [a country's] own efforts, implying that the attempt by Athens to get a significant write-down on its debts was not in the offing.
Those in the Eurozone who support holding Greece to its previous commitments exuded frustration and showed signs of losing patience after the referendum.
Now [German Chancellor Angela] Merkel and the others must organize a Grexit, with all the cushions and upheavals that will result as a consequence. - Alexander Graf Lambsdorff of Germany's Free Democratic Party
Though Merkel may be reluctant to see the integrity of the Eurozone breached, her conservative colleagues in the grand coalition that governs Germany are of the view that the Greek no vote may well be a prelude to the country's exit from the Eurozone  a Grexit, as it has become known.
The referendum was a clear signal that Athens refuses to be beholden to its creditors, said Markus Ferber, who oversees euro policy for the Christian Social Union, the Bavarian sister party to Merkel's Christian Democratic Union.
The country and the government have knocked away the helping hand of their Eurozone colleagues, Ferber said. The only chance for Greece now is to leave the euro.
The Economist Intelligence Unit, an independent forecasting and advisory service of the Economist Group, put the chances of a Greek exit from the Eurozone at 60%.
Opposition political forces in Germany also signaled readiness to interpret the referendum result as a rejection of what is required to stay in the Eurozone, even if many Greeks voted no because their leaders suggested it would compel the creditors to offer a substantial debt write-off and more lenient plan for repaying the rest.
Now Merkel and the others [of the European creditors] must organize a Grexit, with all the cushions and upheavals that will result as a consequence, said Alexander Graf Lambsdorff of the Free Democratic Party, one of the German politicians willing to take no for an answer even if that wasnt what many Greeks meant.
Special correspondent Hassan reported from Berlin and Los Angeles Times staff writer Williams from Los Angeles.
Follow @cjwilliamslat on Twitter for the latest international news 24/7.
Copyright  2015, Los Angeles Times
UPDATE
5:25 p.m.: This article has been updated with developments from German Chancellor Angela Merkel's meeting with French President Francois Hollande.
It was first published at 11:20 a.m.
Related Content
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis' Mass in Ecuador focuses on family, draws multitudes</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pope-francis-family-ecuador-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Hundreds of thousands of cheering people welcomed Pope Francis to Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday for the first Mass on the Argentine-born pontiff's landmark pilgrimage to Spanish-speaking Latin America.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis' Mass in Ecuador focuses on family, draws multitudes
Pope Francis in Ecuador
Vincenzo Pinto / AFP/Getty Images
Pope Francis arrives to celebrate an open-air Mass at Parque Samanes in Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday.
Pope Francis arrives to celebrate an open-air Mass at Parque Samanes in Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday.
(Vincenzo Pinto / AFP/Getty Images)
Pope Francis
Hundreds of thousands of cheering people welcomed Pope Francis to Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday for the first Mass on the Argentine-born pontiffs landmark pilgrimage to Spanish-speaking Latin America.
Enthusiastic crowds thronged Francis as he walked from the airplane that took him from the Ecuadorean capital, Quito, to the coastal city of Guayaquil. Many tried to shake his hand and took selfies with the widely admired pope. Still more lined the route that the popemobile took to the site of the Mass.
Caption Pope Francis in Ecuador
VLADIMIR RODAS / AFP/Getty Images
Pope Francis waves from the popemobile while heading to the Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador. Pope Francis celebrates his second open air mass in as many days in Ecuador the capital city roiled for the past month by anti-government protests.
Pope Francis waves from the popemobile while heading to the Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador. Pope Francis celebrates his second open air mass in as many days in Ecuador the capital city roiled for the past month by anti-government protests.
(VLADIMIR RODAS / AFP/Getty Images)
Caption Pope Francis in Ecuador
RODRIGO BUENDIA / AFP/Getty Images
Hundreds of faithful gather before the start of an open-air mass by Pope Francis at the Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador.
Hundreds of faithful gather before the start of an open-air mass by Pope Francis at the Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador.
(RODRIGO BUENDIA / AFP/Getty Images)
See more galleries
Preliminary estimates of attendance at the Mass, in Guayaquils sprawling Parque Samanes, topped half a million. The pope dedicated the service to the traditional family, the promotion of which he believes can stave off many of societys ills, especially in impoverished Latin America.
The family, he said, speaking in his native Spanish, is the nearest hospital ... the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly.
The family constitutes the best social capital, he continued. It cannot be replaced by other institutions. It needs to be helped and strengthened, lest we lose our proper sense of the services that society as a whole provides.
8
Those services should not be regarded as charity but as part of the social debt owed the institution of family, he said to sustained applause.
Illness, unemployment and other difficult situations can rob families of their warmth and sense of solidarity, he warned.
As expected, the pope departed from his prepared text on several occasions. At one point, as he spoke of how all members of a family are to be valued, he paused to recall an anecdote involving his mother. He said she was asked once which of her five children she loved the most. She responded that the five were like the five fingers on her hand; hurting any one of them would hurt her equally.
The family constitutes the best 'social capital.' It cannot be replaced by other institutions. It needs to be helped and strengthened.... - Pope Francis
The pope is on an eight-day visit to his native continent, deliberately choosing three of its poorest and most marginalized countries to drive home his belief in preaching from the periphery, or among the most disadvantaged. After Ecuador, he will travel to Bolivia and then Paraguay. In addition to meeting with clergy and national officials he will made a point of spending time at so-called places of pain  including a childrens hospital and a notorious prison.
The is Francis second trip to South America since becoming pope. His first, in 2013, was limited to Portuguese-speaking Brazil for World Youth Day.
cComments
Long-haired preachers come out every night To tell you what's wrong and what's right But when asked about something to eat They will answer in voices so sweet You will eat bye and bye, In that glorious land above the sky. Work and pray, live on hay, You'll get pie in the sky when...
LouAZ
2
Earlier Monday and shortly after his arrival in Guayaquil, the pope stopped to pray at the Divine Mercy shrine, where he blessed sick faithful and then chatted with the staff members who care for them. In his typical joviality, he said to the staff: I will bless you, and I wont charge.
Leaders of the Roman Catholic Church credit Francis popularity with stanching an exodus from the faith and attracting people back to the fold. It is too soon, however, to bear that out with numbers.
The countries the pope is visiting are among the most Catholic in South America.
Francis was scheduled to meet later Monday with Ecuadors leftist president, Rafael Correa, who also greeted the pontiff on the tarmac at his arrival in Quito on Sunday.
People began gathering at the Quito cathedral Monday afternoon to hear the pope speak that night.
It is a blessing that the pope has come, a signal of joy, said Angel Tapia, a 44-year-old IT engineer. I think the pope came because he wanted to, not because the president invited him. But political tension will return once the pope is gone.
Though most of the popes public comments at the Mass in Guayaquil were heavily religious and Bible-based, many in Ecuador hope he will stake out a more political position.
The visit of the pope comes at a critical moment for the country, because the division between those who support the government and those who criticize it is at its highest point, said architect Diego Moreano, 35, among those on the streets attempting to get a glimpse of the pope. The pope can serve as a point of balance, of social stability and peace. Lets hope his message lowers tensions.
Fabiola Cruz, a 50-year-old homemaker, said she hoped the pope could revive the spirituality of the people of Ecuador. Unfortunately we live in a moment of little reflection in our country.
Special correspondent Jaramillo Viteri reported from Quito and Times staff writer Wilkinson from Mexico City.
Follow @TracyKWilkinson on Twitter for more news from Latin America

Copyright  2015, Los Angeles Times
UPDATE
4:45 p.m.: This article has been updated to include the gathering at Quito cathedral before the popes Monday night address.
It was first published at 12:12 p.m.
Related Content
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama says anti-Islamic State strategy unchanged even as airstrikes increase</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-obama-islamic-state-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  President Obama acknowledged Monday that the Islamic State terrorists have been "particularly effective" at recruiting volunteers to fight in Iraq and Syria but pledged to stay on track with his current strategy even though it "will not be quick" in bringing about the group's defeat.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>37
But senior administration officials said Monday that the president is committed to his current strategy and that he was not going to the Pentagon to discuss possible changes in it.
There is no situationon the ground that has prompted this, White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest said Monday. The White House is mindful of the many risks in Iraq and Syria, Earnest said, adding that the fact is, our national security professionals are always vigilant.
As Obama prepared to visit the Pentagon on Monday, the White House complained publicly that Senate Republicans are dragging their feet in confirming his nominee to target terrorist funding in a sanctions drive at the Treasury Department.
In his daily briefing, Earnest called for the quick confirmation of of his pick, Adam Szubin, so that he begin efforts to cut off funding for Islamic State and its allies.
Obama described Szubins post as a vital position to our counter-terrorism efforts, adding that, if Congress wants to help, lawmakers will confirm him immediately.
As he spoke, Obama was joined onstage by commanders involved in the ISIL discussion, including Defense Secretary Ashton Carter, Joint Chiefs Chairman Gen. Martin Dempsey and Gen. Lloyd J. Austin III, head of U.S. Central Command, which oversees military operations in the Middle East.
The air war and the train-and-assist missions have been effective, Obama said.
We have taken out thousands of fighting positions, tanks, vehicles, bomb factories and training camps. We've eliminated thousands of fighters, including senior ISIL commanders, Obama said. And over the past year we've seen that, when we have an effective partner on the ground, ISIL can be pushed back, he added, ticking off Islamic State defeats across Iraq.
Obama, who was flanked by decorated generals, said it would take more than just military might to win the fight against Islamic State.
There's a cause, a coalition that's united countries across the globe, some 60 nations including Arab partners, Obama said. Our comprehensive strategy against ISIL is harnessing all elements of American power across our government -- military, intelligence, diplomatic, economic development and, perhaps most importantly, the power of our values.
For more White House coverage, follow @cparsons
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
