<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nbcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:56:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge Locks Up Three Kids for Refusing Lunch With Dad</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fd0be0/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cjudge0Eorders0Esiblings0Ejuvenile0Ecenter0Erefusing0Esee0Edad0En389456/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Three Michigan siblings were sent to a juvenile detention center after they refused a judge's order to have a meal with their father.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 5:56 pm ET
Michigan Judge Orders Siblings to Juvenile Center for Refusing to Have Lunch With Father
by Jacquellena Carrero
advertisement
They say you can indict a ham sandwich, but one judge put three kids behind bars for refusing to eat lunch.
The Michigan siblings were sent to a juvenile detention center after they refused a judge's order to have a meal with their father.
Judge Lisa Gorcyca ordered the three siblings  ages 9, 10 and 15  to a juvenile facility on June 24th for failing to maintain a "healthy relationship" with their father. The judge held the kids in contempt of court after they refused to have lunch with or talk to their dad Omer Tsimhoni in the Oakland County Family Court cafeteria.
According to court records, the children's parents Maya Eibschitz-Tsimhoni and Omer Tsimhoni have been involved in a lengthy custody dispute since December 2009
The siblings were removed from their mother's custody after the June 24th court hearing.
advertisement
According to a court transcript of the hearing obtained by NBC News, Judge Gorcyca told the siblings they should have lunch with their father but the kids refused.
"I'll tell you this, you two don't have a nice lunch with your dad and make this up to your dad you're going to come back here at 1:30 and I'm going to have the deputies take you to Children's Village [a juvenile lock up with over 100 offenders]," the judge said.
Gorcyca berated the siblings when they responded saying they did not want to go to lunch with their father, even questioning the IQ of one of the children.
"I've never seen anything like this," she said. "Your dad is a good man who loves you. You have been brainwashed. You are brainwashed. This is not normal behavior."
One of the siblings told the judge earlier in the conversation that he did not want to apologize to his father because he alleged he became violent with his mother.
advertisement
Oakland County Judge Lisa Gorcyca Oakland County
"I do not apologize for  for not talking to him because I have a reason for that and that's because he's violent and he  I saw him hit my mom and I'm not going to talk to him," one of the three siblings told the judge.
Gorcyca's office said that the judge would not comment on the ongoing Tsimhoni case.
Maya Eibschitz-Tsimhoni's attorney Lisa Stern wouldn't comment due to the sensitive nature of the case.
Ronn Torossia, a family friend of Omer Tsimhoni and his spokesperson, claimed "Ms. Eibschitz continues to endanger the children rather than serve their best interests."
advertisement
"Ms. Eibschitz continually alienates the children from their father, and has ignored countless court hearings and rulings. Mr. Tsimhoni has great respect for the court and the legal system. He is a loving, caring father who desires a healthy relationship with his children," Torossia said in a statement.
The three kids were ordered to Children's Village detention center in Pontiac, Michigan. Judge Gorcyca said the siblings would be kept separate while in the facility, according to the court transcript.
"You're not even going to be with your brother," she said to the 15 year old. "You won't be in the same cell. I'll put in there, 'stay away from your brother.'"
When contacted on Thursday, Children's Village would not release any information on the children's case. The website for the center describes the facility as "a safe, structured environment for youth that includes secure detention, residential treatment and shelter care services."
Larry Dubin, a law professor at the University of Detroit Mercy School of Law, says that while he has not been involved with the case he has been following it closely. He called Judge Gorcyca's actions unusual.
advertisement
"Usually you would see any contempt citations go against the spouse that is charged with the alienation of the other spouse," Dubin explained. "I can't say its never happened, but I think its unusual to exercise a contempt order with the children."
Karen Weiner, a neighbor of Maya Eibschitz-Tsimhoni, said she was appalled by the judge's actions and had always found the kids to be well cared for by their mother.
"These are nice sweet kids, and it seems like she should consider the circumstances and finding out what these kids are scared about," Weiner said.
Jacquellena Carrero
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:52:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FDA Strengthens Heart Safety Warnings on Painkillers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fd0be1/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Cheart0Ehealth0Cfda0Estrengthens0Eheart0Esafety0Ewarnings0Epainkillers0En389516/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The FDA is strengthening its warnings about painkillers like ibuprofen, saying they do raise the risk of heart attack or stroke.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 5:52 pm ET
FDA Strengthens Heart Safety Warnings on Painkillers
by Maggie Fox
Painkillers such as ibuprofen raise the risk of heart attack and stroke, the FDA says. NBC News
Share
advertisement
The Food and Drug Administration is strengthening its warnings about painkillers like ibuprofen, saying they do raise the risk of heart attack or stroke.
People should think carefully about taking these drugs, both over-the-counter versions and prescription pills, the FDA says. It's asking manufacturers to change the labels.
"They used to say they might cause risk of heart attack or stroke. Now we are saying they do cause increased risk of heart attack and stroke," FDA spokesman Eric Pahon told NBC News.
The warning covers drugs called nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs or NSAIDS for short. They include ibuprofen, sold under brand names like Advil or Motrin; naproxen (Aleve), as well as prescription arthritis drugs known as COX-2 inhibitors, such as Celebrex. Tylenol, known generically as acetaminophen, is not an NSAID.
Cough and cold remedies can also contain NSAIDs as an ingredient.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_06_tco_aspirin_140505" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
"FDA is strengthening an existing warning in prescription drug labels and over-the-counter (OTC) Drug Facts labels to indicate that nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) can increase the chance of a heart attack or stroke, either of which can lead to death," the agency said in a statement.
"Those serious side effects can occur as early as the first few weeks of using an NSAID, and the risk might rise the longer people take NSAIDs. (Although aspirin is also an NSAID, this revised warning doesn't apply to aspirin.)"
Last year, FDA said it was reviewing the safety of these drugs.
Some of the studies they looked at showed a clear pattern: people who took NSAIDS were more likely to have heart attacks or strokes .
"There is no period of use shown to be without risk," said Dr. Judy Racoosin, deputy director of FDA's Division of Anesthesia, Analgesia and Addiction Products.
"In the coming months, the FDA will request that manufacturers update the existing cardiovascular risk information in Drug Facts labels for over-the-counter (OTC) non-aspirin NSAIDs. Consumers and health care professionals should remain alert for the development of heart- and stroke-related symptoms throughout the time a consumer takes any NSAID," FDA said.
This doesn't mean people should just stop taking NSAIDS, FDA said.
"Take the lowest effective dose for the shortest amount of time possible," said FDA's Dr. Karen Mahoney.
The American Heart Association advises people to try acetaminophen (Tylenol) first.
"If you have heart disease or high blood pressure, consult a health care provider before using an NSAID," FDA added.
"Take the lowest effective dose for the shortest amount of time possible."
advertisement
"Balance the benefits of NSAIDs with the possible risks and weigh your options. If you take low-dose aspirin for protection against heart attack and stroke, you should know that some NSAIDs, including ibuprofen and naproxen, can interfere with that protective effect."
And the agency gives advice on what symptoms to look for.
"Stop taking NSAIDs and seek medical help if you experience symptoms that might signal heart problems or stroke, such as chest pain, trouble breathing, sudden weakness in one part or side of the body, or sudden slurred speech."
In 2013 Americans bought more than 275 million boxes of over-the-counter NSAIDs, racking up $1.7 billion in sales, according to retail tracker IRI.
Maggie Fox
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:43:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How a Broken Leg Ended Bogus Cancer Nightmare</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fd3b77/sc/32/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Ccancer0Cmonica0En389321/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Monica Flagg says she hopes Dr. Farid Fata gets a life sentence after he diagnosed and treated her for cancer she did not have.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_drfata3_150709" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A disgraced cancer doctor who admits he gave patients unnecessary treatments to make millions will find out Friday morning whether he spends the rest of his life in prison.
Anything less than that will be a disappointment to Monica Flagg  who says she was given a bogus diagnosis and expensive treatments by Dr. Farid Fata before relief came, in a strange twist, in the form of a broken leg.
"When I saw Fata walk in the door, I cried," Flagg, 53, said of coming face-to-face with the oncologist in Detroit Federal Court for this week's pre-sentencing hearing. "[It] was just horrible to see him again."
advertisement
In 2012, Flagg's primary care doctor noticed an abnormality in her blood work and referred her for a followup with Fata, who had built an empire of upscale cancer clinics in Detroit suburbs in less than a decade.
Fata told her she had multiple myeloma and, according to prosecutors, lied about her medical tests to make it appear that she needed aggressive treatment.
She had three bone biopsies and was bombarded with immune boosters before being given one round of a chemotherapy drug, Velcade, in July 2013, court papers say.
"The day was horrible. It was a lot of stress," she said of that first treatment.
She came home from the clinic, went upstairs to unpack a suitcase, and tripped and fell.
"I heard both my bones crack. I knew that my leg had been broken in half. I screamed for help," Flagg told NBC News.
The painful injury turned out to be a blessing in disguise.
Flagg was taken to Crittenton Hospital Medical Center in Rochester Hills, Michigan, where Fata  who prosecutors say was notorious for treating all his patients personally and keeping other medical professionals away  normally would have overseen her care.
But Fata was away from Michigan and his sprawling mansion, on a rare vacation to his native Lebanon. The doctor on duty was one of his underlings, Soe Maunglay, who told NBC News he was already harboring suspicions about his boss' unconventional treatments.
"He told me, 'You don't have cancer. You are 51 years old. You're healthy. Don't ever go back to Dr. Fata. Find a new doctor.'"
advertisement
At Crittenton, a pre-operative bone marrow biopsy did not show any indication of cancer, according to the prosecution memo. And after Maunglay reviewed Flagg's file, he asked her a series of questions that made alarm bells go off in her head.
"This doctor was in my hospital room today and even though he didn't say it, I don't think he thinks I have cancer," Flagg told her husband, Steve, at the time.
Two days later, her hunch was confirmed.
"He came in, asked the lady who was visiting me to leave and he told me, 'You don't have cancer. You are 51 years old. You're healthy. Don't ever go back to Dr. Fata. Find a new doctor,'" Flagg recalled.
"I was overcome with joy," she added. "It was one of the happiest days of my life."
advertisement
Her lawyer, Brian McKeen, said the broken leg and Maunglay's intervention saved Flagg from months or even years of more needless treatments.
"Had she not broken her leg, God only knows what would have happened," McKeen said. "But Monica might very well not have been with us any longer because people can get very sick from these toxic levels of chemotherapy that he was using and was going to be using."
A month after Maunglay's warning to Flagg, Fata was arrested by the FBI  and his former patient learned that she was far from alone.
Dr. Farid Fata of Oakland County, Mich. The Oakland Press / ZUMAPRESS.com
In court papers, prosecutors say Fata victimized more than 500 patients  telling some they had cancer when they did not, giving too much or improper treatment to others who did have cancer, and continuing to give chemotherapy to terminal patients who didn't need it any longer.
Some two dozen of them took the stand in court this week to testify about how Fata had stolen their health, money and trust.
Prosecutors want the judge to give him 175 years in prison  an effective life sentence  painting his businesses as a "criminal enterprise" in which patients were used as cash cows.
Fata's lawyers argued in court on Thursday that the feds had based their sentencing recommendation on the millions that the doctor billed the government, not the lower amount that Medicare actually paid out, which would justify a more lenient sentence.
Defense attorneys have declined to comment outside court on the prosecution's allegations.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:41:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Baby Doe': Authorities Struggle to ID Little Girl</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fb9a70/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cmillions0Efollow0Esearch0Egirl0Efound0Edead0Emassachusetts0Ebeach0En389311/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The girl, whom authorities believe was about 4 years old and refer to as "Baby Doe," was discovered on June 25.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 5:41 pm ET
'Baby Doe' Discovery on Deer Island in Boston Harbor Mystifies Authorities
by Emmanuelle Saliba and Jon Schuppe
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nc_tipspourin_150706" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
As authorities work to identify a young girl whose body was found on a Massachusetts beach last month, millions of people are immersed in the mystery on social media.
The girl, whom authorities believe was about 4 years old and refer to as "Baby Doe," was discovered on June 25 on the island's rocky western shore by a woman walking a dog on Deer Island in Boston Harbor, officials said. Her body had been stuffed into a trash bag and was in the early stages of decomposition.
An autopsy has been completed but a cause of death has not been determined, authorities said.
advertisement
The Massachusetts State Police, with help from the National Center for Missing &amp; Exploited Children, posted to Facebook a computer-generated image of what she may have looked like alive.
That image has been viewed close to 50 million times and has been shared more than 600,000 times, state police spokesman Dustin Fitch told NBC News on Thursday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:37:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>S.C. Governor Signs Bill Removing Confederate Flag</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fcdb03/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cconfederate0Eflag0Efuror0Cgov0Ehaley0Esign0Ebill0Eremoving0Econfederate0Eflag0En389231/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley signed into law a bill that removes the Confederate battle flag from the capitol.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 5:37 pm ET
South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley Signs Bill Removing Confederate Flag
by Jon Schuppe
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_sc_haley_confederate_flag__150709" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
They're taking it down.
South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley on Thursday signed into law a measure to remove the contentious Confederate battle flag from the state Capitol, the culmination of a years-long movement that was reignited by the murders of nine members of a historically black church in Charleston.
Before adding her signature to the legislation, Haley spoke of the black victims, who were killed by a white man after they welcomed him into a June 17 prayer meeting at Emanuel African Methodist Church.
advertisement
Their act of love and faith, Haley said, set into motion a chain of events that led to the flag's removal less than a month later.
"May we never forget the actions that those people took to get us to this point today," the governor said.
Haley noted that when the confessed killer, 21-year-old Dylann Roof, was caught, relatives of the victims said in court that they forgave him. That act of forgiveness, Haley said, sparked a wave of compassion around the country that motivated people to change things.
In the days after the shootings, photos emerged of Roof posing with the Confederate flag, a Civil War relic that is also seen as an emblem of racism. That sparked a nationwide debate about the flag's place in American culture. Many businesses stopped making and selling the flag and its images, and public officials discussed removing the flag from public grounds.
That included South Carolina, which first flew the Confederate flag at Capitol in Columbia in 1962 as a response to the civil rights movement.
The state legislature, which lost state Sen. Clementa Pickney, Emanuel's top pastor, in the shooting, responded by voting overwhelmingly this week to take the flag down .
The shootings forced a change in Haley, too. The Republican governor had previously opposed calls to lower the flag, and had voiced support of a 2000 compromise in which the flag was moved from atop the Capitol dome to a nearby flag pole. But she shifted her view amid the furor that followed the shootings.
She signed her name to the legislation with several pens, nine of which will go the families of the victims.
U.S. Sen. Lindsey Graham of South Carolina praised the flag's removal. "After the horrific tragedy in Charleston, our state could have gone down one of two paths, division or reconciliation," Graham said in a statement. "I am thankful we chose the path of reconciliation."
Charleston Mayor Joseph Riley Jr. said the flag had been an insult to many people, and its removal would help heal those wounds. "Our state's response to a horrific act of racial hatred has been a clear and decisive act of graceful unity, respect and healing for all of our citizens," he said.
The flag will be removed at 10 a.m. ET Friday.
Jon Schuppe
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:24:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OPM: 21.5 Million Affected By Background Check Breach</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fcb2eb/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Ctech0Csecurity0Copm0Ehack0Esecurity0Ebreach0En389476/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>OPM announced on Thursday that sensitive information including Social Security numbers for 21.5 million people was among the data lost.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_dc_opm_breech_150623" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
The investigation into the hacks concluded that the second breach, which targeted background investigation records kept by OPM, included Social Security numbers, information on family members and other contacts, as well as health and criminal records. The data haul also included an estimated 1.1 million fingerprint records.
In total, hackers are thought to have netted records on 19.7 million people who applied for background check investigations with the federal government, and another 1.8 million people including spouses who did not apply for a background check but whose information was included in the forms. Anyone who applied for a background check from 2000 on is likely to have had their information compromised in the breach, OPM said on Thursday.
"I truly understand the impact this has had on our current and former federal employees, our military personnel, and our contractors," OPM Director Katherine Archuleta told reporters Thursday on a conference call.
Among the forms used in federal background checks is the Standard Form 86, an 127-page document that delves into intimate questions about prior brushes with the law, drug use, psychiatric health, and info on friends and family members. It requires the applicant to put his or her Social Security number on nearly every page of the document.
Read More: OPM, Reeling from Federal Data Hacks, Will Hire Cybersecurity Advisor
China was named as "the leading suspect" in the breach last month by Director of National Intelligence James Clapper.
Asked on the call whether China was behind the hacks, Michael Daniel, special assistant to the president and cybersecurity coordinator, responded, "At this point, the investigation into the attribution of this event is still ongoing and we are exploring all the different options that we have."
He added: "Just because we're not doing public attribution does not mean we're not taking steps to deal with the matter."
Officials did confirm on the call that both attacks were the work of "the same actor" who gained access to the OPM system with a contractor's username and password.
advertisement
The breaches have been the subject of numerous hearings on Capitol Hill since they first came to light, with Archuleta facing tough questions from lawmakers who have called for her dismissal and that of OPM CIO Donna Seymour.
"Since at least 2007, OPM leadership has been on notice about the vulnerabilities to its network and cybersecurity policies and practices," House Oversight Committee Chairman Jason Chaffetz (R-UT) said in a statement on Thursday. "Director Archuleta and Ms. Seymour consciously ignored the warnings and failed to correct these weaknesses. Their negligence has now put the personal and sensitive information of 21.5 million Americans into the hands of our adversaries."
On Thursday, Archuleta told reporters that she would not be stepping down.
"I am committed to the work that I am doing at OPM," Archuleta said. "I have trust in the staff that is there, including Donna Seymour."
In the aftermath of the breaches, OPM suspended the use of its Electronic Questionnaires for Investigations Processing system (e-QIP), taking it offline for a month or more to make security upgrades. Anyone undergoing a background check for secret clearances in the meantime will have to do so using an older, less hackable technology: paper forms.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:49:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>600 U.S. Churches Call for an End to the 'War on Drugs'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fd07a3/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0C60A0A0Eu0Es0Echurches0Ecall0Eend0Ewar0Edrugs0En389511/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The New England Conference of The United Methodist Church voted for an end to the drug war, citing its disproportionate impact on minorities.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 4:49 pm ET
600 U.S. Churches Call for an End to the 'War on Drugs'
by Jon Schuppe
advertisement
A group of more than 600 churches has joined a small but growing movement within the religious community to call for and end to the war on drugs through legalization.
The New England Conference of The United Methodist Church, representing more than 600 congregations, voted last month to support efforts to address the nation's drug abuse problem through "means other than prohibition."
The resolution was passed during an annual conference in which supporters argued that the war on drugs had unintentionally left countless dead, overwhelmed courts and prisons, wasted taxpayer money and destroyed innumerable families  most of them black and Latino.
"To people of color, the 'War on Drugs' has arguably been the single most devastating, dysfunctional social policy since slavery," the resolution says.
The move put the conference on the leading edge of outspoken religious groups who are questioning the impact of the decades-old war on drugs. The Unitarian Universal Association has come out against it, and in Illinois, a marijuana decriminalization bill is being pushed by Clergy for a New Drug Policy , a coalition that includes Protestant pastors and Jewish rabbis.
advertisement
The motivation behind this stance, the religious leaders say, is the drug war's disproportionate impact on minorities.
"It's a justice issue," said Eric Dupee, the pastor of Crawford Memorial United Methodist Church in Winchester, Mass., which wrote the resolution passed by The New England Conference on June 18. "Basically what I wanted to do is put forth the idea that our drug war is creating more harm, more problems than it's solving, and I wanted people to be aware of that."
Dupee said he hoped the resolution would be taken up at the church's global conference next year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:00:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>You're Still Not Eating Enough Vegetables</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fcb2f5/sc/26/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Cdiet0Efitness0Cyoure0Estill0Enot0Eeating0Eenough0Evegetables0En389466/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Americans are not getting even close to eating enough fruits and vegetables daily, a new government report finds.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 4:00 pm ET
You're Still Not Eating Enough Vegetables
by Maggie Fox
Why doesn't this make your mouth water? A new survey finds Americans are passing over fruits and veggies. Akira Kaede / Getty Images stock
Share
advertisement
Americans are not getting close to eating enough fruits and vegetables daily, a new government report finds.
Guidelines are clear -- people should get a cup and a half to two cups of fruit every day and two to three cups of vegetables. But three-quarters of Americans do not manage to get that much fruit and 87 percent fail to eat enough vegetables.
"Everyone would be healthier eating more vegetables," said Marion Nestle, professor of nutrition, food studies, and public health at New York University, who wasn't involved in the survey.
Latetia Moore of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and Frances Thompson of the National Cancer Institute went through data from a large national survey to calculate just how close Americans come to meeting national recommendations.
"These results indicate that fewer than 18 percent of adults in each state consumed the recommended amount of fruit and fewer than 14 percent consumed the recommended amount of vegetables," they write in the CDC's weekly report on disease and death.
advertisement
"Fewer than 18 percent of adults in each state consumed the recommended amount of fruit."
People who eat just five servings of fruits and vegetables a day lower their risk of cancer, heart disease, stroke, diabetes and other conditions.
One study found that people who ate seven or more servings of fruits and vegetables were 42 percent less likely to die from any cause over the next eight years compared to those who ate less than one serving a day.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_health_diet_130529" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
But Americans just don't eat their veggies.
On average, Americans eat only one serving of fruit a day  equivalent to a small glass of orange juice or an apple  Moore and Thompson found. Consumption ranges from just under one serving a day on average in Arkansas to 1.3 servings in California.
People do barely any better on vegetables, getting 1.4 servings a day in Louisiana, Mississippi and North Dakota on the low end and just under two servings a day in California and Oregon, the highest-scoring states.
"Overall, 13.1 percent of respondents met fruit intake recommendations, ranging from 7.5 percent in Tennessee to 17.7 percent in California, and 8.9 percent met vegetable recommendations, ranging from 5.5 percent in Mississippi to 13 percent in California," they wrote.
"Substantial new efforts are needed to build consumer demand for fruits and vegetables through competitive pricing, placement, and promotion in child care, schools, grocery stores, communities, and worksites."
advertisement
The best place to start is with kids, who are setting up their habits for a lifetime. Some school districts are trying to make vegetables more appealing to kids .
"If the government were serious about getting people to eat more fruits and vegetables, it could do for vegetable growers what it does for corn and soybean farmers. You can subsidize."
The researchers have other advice, also. "For example, work sites can make it easier for employees to make healthy food choices and create social norms that support healthy eating by creating policies to ensure that fruits and vegetables are provided at work-site gatherings, including meetings, conferences, and other events," they suggest.
It's not easy to eat vegetables, Nestle notes. "People perceive vegetables as being difficult to manage," she said. "Start with expensive. There's a lot of waste. They have to be peeled. They have to be washed. They have to be cut. They aren't as filling as junkier foods. The barriers are real."
Politics doesn't help, Nestle adds. There aren't powerful lobby groups for fruit and vegetable growers like there are for beef, soy, corn and dairy.
"If the government were serious about getting people to eat more fruits and vegetables, it could do for vegetable growers what it does for corn and soybean farmers. You can subsidize," she said.
Maggie Fox
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:21:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Women's Soccer Team's Ticker-Tape Parade a Rarity</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fc3396/sc/42/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Csports0Cwomens0Esoccer0Estars0Ewill0Ebe0Efirst0Ewomen0Efeted0Eticker0Etape0En389316/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>They will be the first women honored in a ticker-tape parade in three decades.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_or_soccer_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
When the U.S. Women's National Soccer Team rolls down the "Canyon of Heroes" on Friday morning, they will be the first women feted in a ticker-tape parade in three decades.
Not since Mary Lou Retton, Cheryl Miller and their fellow 1984 Olympic medal winners were celebrated after the Los Angeles Summer Games has a woman been given the ticker-tape treatment.
That 1984 moment included both male and female athletes. Other parades in the 1960s  when the honor was more common  included the queens and empresses of Iran, Afghanistan and Thailand alongside their royal spouses.
advertisement
The last time a woman was the lone honoree of a ticker-tape parade was March 1960, when figure-skating champion Carol Heiss Jenkins  a native of Queens  earned the distinction.
Ticker-tape parades generally have been reserved for New York-based championship teams because of the great expense  The New York Times reported the estimated cost to the city is $1.5 million  and the traffic jams they tend to cause. The New York Giants were the last to be so honored after their 2012 Super Bowl victory.
The New York Giants motorcade of floats make their way during the team's NFL football Super Bowl parade in New York, Tuesday, Feb. 7, 2012. The Giants returned from their Super Bowl win to a celebration the likes that only New York can throw: a ticker-tape parade in the Canyon of Heroes on Broadway, where the city has honored stars for almost a century. Mark Lennihan / AP
And while women have rarely been granted the honor, the first ticker-tape parade in U.S. history was held for a female  well, sort of.
Here's the backstory: In the fall of 1886, an impromptu celebration broke out on the streets of the city as part of the dedication of the Statue of Liberty, according to the Mayor's Office.
advertisement
The New York Times reported that "the air was white with curling streamers," as revelers marched from Madison Square to the southern tip of Manhattan.
Those curling streamers were, of course, cut-up ticker tape  a one-inch wide-ribbon of paper that stock quotes were recorded on by a "ticker" machine  thrown out of office windows high above Broadway. Hence, ticker-tape parades were born.
The most recent ticker-tape parade, honoring the New York Giants' Super Bowl win in 2012, resulted in a little more than 34 tons of refuse scattered on the city's streets, according to the sanitation department. None of that paper actually came from tickers, however. The machines became obsolete in the 1960s.
Not since Mary Lou Retton, Cheryl Miller and their fellow 1984 Olympic medal winners were celebrated after the Los Angeles Summer Games has a woman been given the ticker-tape treatment.
Patrick Garrity
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:19:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sisters Found After Vanishing in Wyoming Wilderness</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fb4cbf/sc/10/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Candrews0Esharer0Esisters0Efound0Eafter0Evanishing0Ewyoming0Ewilderness0En389381/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The sisters, originally from Milwaukee County, Wisconsin, left for their extended camping trip in Grand Teton National Park on June 28.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Three sisters who disappeared while backpacking in the Wyoming backcountry were found alive Thursday  cold and hungry but healthy, search and rescue officials said.
The young women  Megan, Erin, and Kelsi Andrews-Sharer  have since been reunited with their father after a helicopter spotted them in a remote part of the Bridger-Teton National Forest just after 10 a.m. local time.
"We're so pleased with the outcome of this search and the safety of the missing hikers and all the rescue personnel," Teton County Sheriff Jim Whalen said in a statement.
Sisters Kelsi, 16, Megan, 25, and Erin Andrews-Sharer, 22, with their father after their rescue in Grand Teton National Park. Sarah Durant
The sisters, originally from Milwaukee County, Wisconsin, left for their extended camping trip in Grand Teton National Park on June 28 and were supposed to return home Tuesday, the Teton County Sheriff's Office said.
advertisement
The women's car was discovered Wednesday, about 15 miles south of the resort town of Jackson. Their disappearance prompted a search by ground crews, including sniffer dogs, and by helicopter on Wednesday.
The effort got a fortuitous break when a guide noted seeing a person in a white rain jacket in an area with no trails on Wednesday. On Thursday morning, realizing a search was in progress, he phoned in a tip to the sheriff's office.
Officials said the guide's accurate description of the location proved critical  and a search team redirected a helicopter to the coordinates provided. The sisters were found within 20 minutes.
The sheriff's office credited the trio for staying together, using their tent and having the proper clothing to weather through their ordeal.
Authorities earlier said the sisters were experienced backpackers and believed they "may have simply made a wrong turn."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:11:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI Chief: Several ISIS-Inspired July 4 Attacks Foiled</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fc23d6/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cisis0Eterror0Cseveral0Eisis0Einspired0Ejuly0E40Eattacks0Efoiled0Efbi0Edirector0Ejames0En389441/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>James Comey said that would-be terrorists inspired by ISIS still present several challenges to the FBI, including that they can be "unreliable"</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Some of the dozen arrests made by federal agents in the last four weeks helped to thwart potential terror attacks during the Fourth of July holiday, FBI Director James Comey said Thursday.
"I do believe our work disrupted efforts to kill people, likely in connection with July 4," Comey told reporters at FBI headquarters in Washington.
Comey's comments are a public confirmation made by other law enforcement that several people were arrested in the past month over concerns that they might have been inspired by ISIS to carry out attacks either during the holiday or during the Muslim holy period of Ramadan.
A New York Police Officer watches crowds before the annual Fourth of July 2015 Nathan's Famous Hot Dog Eating Contest in Brooklyn, New York July 4, 2015. ANDREW KELLY / Reuters
Comey added that those inspired by ISIS don't make elaborate plans and often act on the spur of the moment.
advertisement
"It's actually hard to figure out when they're trying to kill somebody," Comey said. "And you cannot say, 'Well, we've got to do it on the Fourth.' Because you know you have people who are motivated to kill people, and they are unreliable in terms of when they're going to act."
Related: Worries of ISIS-Inspired Attacks Cloud July 4 Holiday Weekend
The FBI has arrested around a dozen people in the past four weeks, Comey said.
"We made the arrests to thwart what we thought they were up to," he added. "Some of them were focused on the Fourth of July, and that's as specific as I can get."
He declined to say how many of those arrested were planning to carry out attacks or to describe the nature of what they were planning.
advertisement
Some of those arrested, he said, had been using end-to-end encryption programs to communicate with ISIS. He warned Congress on Wednesday that it's becoming much harder for the FBI to track potential ISIS followers because of the growth in encryption technology.
Pete Williams
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:57:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Confederate Flag Is Coming Down, But...</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fd07a0/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cfeature0C10A10Cvideo0Cthe0Econfederate0Eflag0Eis0Ecoming0Edown0Ebut0E481234499974/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Black people in South Carolina still face real, systemic discrimination.</Description>
        <MainBody>Five facts can go a long way.
Sponsored By
The Confederate Flag Is Coming Down, But...

Black people in South Carolina still face real, systemic discrimination.
Previous
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:19:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bumblebees Being Bumped Off by Climate Change</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fc23e9/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cscience0Cenvironment0Cbumblebees0Eare0Ebeing0Ebumped0Eclimate0Echange0Escientists0Esay0En3890A41/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists say wild bumblebee species are being squeezed into extinction by climate change — so much so that some will need help to find safe havens.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 2:19 pm ET
Bumblebees Are Being Bumped Off by Climate Change, Scientists Say
by Alan Boyle
This buff-tailed bumblebee is visiting catmint flowers, sipping nectar and moving pollen from one plant to another. Rapid climate change is linked to widespread losses in this vital group of pollinators. Jeremy T. Kerr / Univ. of Ottawa
Share
advertisement
Scientists say wild bumblebee species are being squeezed into extinction by climate change in North America and Europe  so much so that some of them might need help from us humans to find safe havens.
Their conclusion, published in this week's issue of the journal Science , is based on an analysis of more than 423,000 archived observations of 67 bee species, going back to 1901.
The scientists expected to find that the species have moved northward in response to rising temperatures, as other species ranging from flowers to foxes have done.
That's not what they found. Yes, the bumblebee species dwindled or disappeared in warmer southern climes, retreating an average of about 190 miles (300 kilometers). And in mountainous regions the bees moved up to higher elevations  about 1,000 feet (300 meters) higher, on average. But they didn't move into cooler, higher-latitude regions.
For some reason, bumblebees are being caught in a "climate vise," said University of Ottawa biologist Jeremy Kerr, the lead author of the Science study.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_bees_150709" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Kerr and his colleagues tried to account for other factors that have been cited as bad for bees, ranging from neonicotinoids and other pesticides to changes in land use  but they said those factors don't explain the losses in the range of the species.
The scientists emphasized that the scenario for wild bumblebees is different from the problems faced by European honeybees.
advertisement
The concern about honeybees focuses on colony collapse disorder, which has been linked to a host of factors including pathogens, pesticides and diversity loss. But the concern about bumblebees is just as serious, said study co-author Leif Richardson, a bee researcher from the University of Vermont.
Richardson pointed out that bumblebees play a key role in pollinating crops ranging from apples and blueberries to soybeans. "If we see declines in the diversity or abundance of bumblebees, we should expect to see lower crop yields, higher food costs, and perhaps lower food diversity," he told NBC News.
Why bumblebees are bummed
The researchers suggested that bumblebees aren't as capable of coping with warmer temperatures as, say, butterflies, because bumblebees evolved in temperate regions of the world rather than tropical regions.
"You imagine a car that starts running out of coolant and starts blowing steam out the front of the hood. That's kind of like an analogy for what bumblebee species do when it gets too hot," Kerr told reporters.
Related: Extreme Bumblebees Can Scale Mount Everest
So why aren't bumblebee species pushing farther northward into Canada, or showing up in more northerly regions of Europe? The reasons for that aren't fully clear: It may be that the plants on which the bumblebee species feed are lacking, Or it may be that the bee colonies have to be of a certain size to take root in new regions. Kerr noted that bumblebee species with larger colony sizes seemed to handle moving into new areas better.
About a third to a quarter of the bumblebee species are in decline, but some species "seem to be expanding their range," said York University's Sheila Colla, another co-author of the study. These include the common Eastern bumblebee in the United States  as well as the buff-tailed bumblebee in Europe, which Kerr called the "dandelion of the bumblebee world."
What is to be done?
The researchers said regular folks could help out the bumblebees by planting bee-friendly crops in their gardens and backyards  native wildflowers, bee balm and milkweed, for example, or even raspberries . Another way to boost the bees is to participate in BumbleBeeWatch.org , a citizen science project that keeps track of bee sightings in North America.
advertisement
The study touches on the strategy of "assisted migration"  that is, transporting bumblebee colonies to cooler refuges. Kerr said conservation groups and government agencies will have to have a "thoughtful and quick conversation" about when and how to use such a strategy.
"We're playing with fire, and we are now going to begin paying some of those consequences," Kerr said. "If we're interested in conserving species like bumblebees for the future, it is possible that we will need to intervene in a significant and extensive way to help them adapt."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:11:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trump's Troubles Cast Shadow on GOP's Senate Hopes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fc18fd/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpolitics0C20A160Eelection0Ctrumps0Etroubles0Ecast0Eshadow0Egops0Esenate0Ehopes0En38930A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Trump's outsized profile could cause real damage to the party's chances of defending a fragile majority in the Senate</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 2:11 pm ET
Trump's Troubles Cast a Shadow on GOP's Senate Hopes
by Alex Jaffe
Potential Republican 2016 presidential candidate Donald Trump listens as he is introduced at the Tuscan Kitchen in Salem, New Hampshire, United States April 27, 2015. REUTERS/Lisa Hornak LISA HORNAK / Reuters
Share
advertisement
For Colorado Republican Senate candidate Greg Lopez, Donald Trump's comments about Mexicans are personal.
Before Lopez was mayor of Parker, Colo., and before he served as director of the Small Business Administration there, he migrated back and forth over the U.S.-Mexico border with his family. At the age of just five years old, Lopez would come to the States to pick onions, tomatoes and cotton, "what Mexican-Americans did" in the 1950's and 60's.
Lopez said he's not offended by Trump's suggestion that Mexico is sending "rapists" and "killers" to the United States. Trump, he says, is just "uninformed."
"What I see is there's an individual out there that has an uninformed opinion and he's verbalizing it without really acknowledging the totality of the situation," he told NBC in an interview.
But for Lopez, the personal is also political. He's running in a GOP primary in a state where Latino voters make up an estimated 14 percent of the electorate, and he says his bilingualism and unique personal story are key assets in his campaign. That may explain why, though Lopez said Trump's comments didn't offend him, he was quick to distance himself from the real-estate mogul.
advertisement
"With my network and reputation here in Colorado, and people understanding what I stand for, I know they're not going to connect me to Trump," he said. "My network will be able to clearly articulate what I represent -- which is not close to what Donald Trump represents."
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_orig_trumpfull_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
That's because what Donald Trump has come to represent over the past few weeks is not just his typical bombast and bluster but what some critics have decried as blatant racism. And there's growing concern among Republicans that Trump's outsized profile could cause real damage, not only to the GOP's 2016 hopes, but to the party's chances of defending a fragile majority in the Senate as well.
"There's a lot of concern that Trump's very overheated and unsolicitous rhetoric is really a gift for Democrats," said one Republican strategist advising a Senate candidate in a key battleground state, who was granted anonymity to speak frankly on the issue. "And it obscures, as Marco Rubio says, a lot of the real problems surrounding the immigration debate."
advertisement
Democrats need to net only four or five seats to take back the upper chamber, depending on which party wins the White House, and they're eyeing Latino-heavy states like Florida and Illinois as prime pickup opportunities. They also see Latino voters as potentially creating a firewall of support for their candidates in two of the GOP's few opportunities to play offense: Nevada and Colorado. Latino voters make up anywhere from nearly 10 percent in Illinois, to 17 percent, in Florida, of the state's eligible voters, and could prove decisive in a tough race.
"I certainly think that a Republican presidential candidate -- who is going to be in the debates -- making hateful and racist comments about large groups of voters is not going to do any favors for [Nevada Republican Senate candidate] Joe Heck or [Illinois Sen.] Mark Kirk or whoever the nominee is for the clown show in Florida on the GOP side," said Justin Barasky, spokesman for the Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee.
The National Republican Senatorial Committee didn't respond to a request for comment. And Trump disagrees, doubling down on his comments in a Tuesday interview with NBC in which he insisted both that "the country of Mexico is killing us" and "I will win the Latino vote."
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_fh_trump_tur_latino_vote_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
But polling has shown rhetoric like Trump's does have a lasting effect, and could impact the party as a whole. A survey conducted during the 2013 immigration reform effort in the Senate tested a handful of statements made by senators opposed to the deal and found they negatively impacted the perception of their party among Latino voters, not just the senators themselves.
"The brand and the image of the party as a whole suffers when these sorts of comments come out," said Matt Barreto, co-founder of the polling firm Latino Decisions, which conducted the survey.
Barreto also said that the comments were likely to bleed downballot into races where the Latino vote is "going to be critical."
"The rate of turnout [among Latinos] often fluctuates and is very responsive to the political environment. If this immigration issue, the Trump issue, which has frankly also been suggested by other Republicans -- that will serve to really create a lot of anger and frustration in the Latino community," he said.
He likened it to the record-breaking Latino turnout during the last presidential race, when surveys showed Latino voters were driven to the polls both in favor of President Obama's pro-immigrant moves and what they saw as GOP nominee Mitt Romney's anti-immigrant rhetoric. The same could be true this cycle, Barreto said, if rhetoric like Trump's continues to dominate the debate and the party.
advertisement
But as Romney was in 2012, the GOP remains conflicted on the immigration issue, caught between warring impulses to appease its base and broaden its appeal.
On Wednesday, RNC chairman Reince Preibus asked Trump in a telephone conversation to "tone it down," NBC News , the Washington Post and other news outlets reported - although Trump disputes part of that account.
Other Republicans have been quick to publicly distance themselves from Trump's rhetoric. Nevada Sen. Dean Heller dismissed the comments as "absolutely wrong" and said he gave Trump's donations to his campaign to charity.
Rep. Joe Heck, the Republican hoping to take retiring Sen. Harry Reid's seat and join Heller in the Senate, had similar criticism for the businessman.
"That's Donald Trump's opinion, and certainly he said it only in a way that only he can, which is to promote himself and generate controversy," Heck said. "You can't stereotype an entire ethnicity, and that's what he attempted to do."
But others have been more reticent. Illinois Sen. Mark Kirk didn't respond to a request for comment on the issue; nor did Rep. Ron DeSantis, a Republican running for Florida Senate who has also received contributions from Trump.
Arizona Sen. John McCain is running for reelection in a state where Pew estimates 20 percent of the eligible voters are Latino. Asked about whether Trump's comments were appropriate or not, he cited the "close relationship" his home state has with Mexico, but didn't outright criticize Trump.
"I think that anybody in America is free to make the statements that they make, but I can tell you that people in my state, because of our knowledge and background and history would certainly not feel that way," McCain said.
Republicans are hopeful that the controversy will die down long before voters begin to tune in to the Senate races. But in the meantime, it's up to the candidates to avoid getting tangled in an unnecessary controversy and risk alienating either conservatives or Latino voters.
That delicate dance was on display Wednesday when Todd Wilcox, a Florida businessman who launched his campaign for Senate just that day, weighed in on the comments in an interview with NBC. He said that he didn't "necessarily agree with [Trump's] generalization" that most immigrants are unsavory.
"I don't know where he gets his facts from," he said.
But he added: "I kind of applaud him for talking about it. I don't necessarily agree with the approach, but it's certainly something we should be talking about."
Wilcox also said, unless Trump's comments "were much much more inflammatory, I wouldn't turn his money away if he were to donate to my campaign," citing the $5 million he expected to need to spend on TV ads alone to be competitive.
And unlike some others in his party, Wilcox doesn't "necessarily think we have to attack the guy for his tone."
"I don't want to discourage anybody for getting up and speaking their mind," Wilcox said.
Alex Jaffe
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:15:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>George W. Bush Was Paid $100K to Speak at Vets Event</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f9c803/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpolitics0Cpolitics0Enews0Cformer0Epresident0Egeorge0Ew0Ebush0Epaid0E10A0Ak0Espeak0Eveterans0Egroup0En389181/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>But the Helping a Hero charity says Bush was a big draw: The nonprofit netted almost $2.5 million that year — the next year was less than half that.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 5:15 pm ET
Former President George W. Bush Was Paid $100K to Speak to Veterans Group
by Erik Ortiz
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_mor_speaking_150709" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Former President George W. Bush was paid $100,000 to attend a veterans charity gala in Houston in 2012, NBC News has confirmed.
And the year before, former first lady Laura Bush received $50,000 for her remarks at a gala event for the same group, Helping a Hero . The nonprofit helps to outfit homes for veterans wounded during the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.
advertisement
Robert Clark, chairman of the Helping a Hero board, said in a statement that the former president's appearance actually helped to raise "significant funds" for the charity. The year that Bush spoke the charity netted almost $2.5 million; the next year was less than half that amount.
"His presence was appreciated by the veterans and supporters of the organization," Clark said.
A spokesman for the former president did not immediately return a phone call and email from NBC News.
The office of former President Bill Clinton said he has never received a speaking fee for addressing a veterans group. The office of former President Jimmy Carter said he has never taken money to speak to a veterans group.
Erik Ortiz
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:04:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NYSE Says Software Problem Led to Trading Outage</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fc95d8/sc/24/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Ctech0Cinternet0Cnyse0Esays0Eproblem0Enew0Esoftware0Eled0Etrading0Eoutage0En389396/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The NYSE that the halt on the exchange was due to a technical problem that stemmed from new software that was rolled out the previous evening.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 1:04 pm ET
NYSE Says Problem with New Software Led to Trading Outage
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_shorttake_stocks_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
The New York Stock Exchange said its nearly four-hour trading halt on Wednesday resulted from a technical problem that stemmed from new software rolled out the previous evening.
The NYSE said on Thursday that the glitch caused communication problems between one of its trading units and NYSE customers as they began connecting to the exchange at 7 a.m. EDT on Wednesday morning.
NYSE said it attempted to fix the problem before the market opened, but customers were still reporting "unusual system behavior" midmorning, and it decided to halt trading.
Read More: New York Stock Exchange Reopens After Tech Glitch
The exchange said it then began canceling all open orders and reaching out to its customers as it worked to solve the problem.
Trading in NYSE-listed stocks continued uninterrupted on other exchanges. The NYSE came back online shortly after 3 p.m., once the technical issues had been resolved.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:24:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NASA Picks Four Astronauts for Commercial Spaceflights</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fc23ea/sc/32/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cscience0Cspace0Cnasa0Epicks0Efour0Eastronauts0Etrain0Ecommercial0Eu0Es0Espaceflights0En389366/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>NASA has selected a quartet of space shuttle veterans who could ride Boeing's CST-100 capsule or SpaceX's Dragon capsule into orbit as early as 2017.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 12:24 pm ET
NASA Picks Four Astronauts to Train for Commercial U.S. Spaceflights
by Alan Boyle
NASA plans to use commercial space vehicles to transport astronauts to and from the International Space Station. NASA file
Share
NASA has named the first four astronauts to train for commercial spaceflights  a quartet of space shuttle veterans who could ride Boeing's CST-100 capsule or SpaceX's Dragon capsule to the International Space Station as early as 2017.
The four include:
Robert Behnken, an Air Force colonel who performed spacewalks during flights of the shuttle Endeavour in 2008 and 2010.
Eric Boe, an Air Force colonel who flew into space on Endeavour in 2008 and on Discovery's last spaceflight in 2011.
Doug Hurley, who first went into space on Endeavour in 2009 and was on the shuttle Atlantis' crew for the final mission of the space station program in 2011. He's a retired Marine colonel.
Sunita Williams, a Navy captain who did months-long tours of duty on the space station in 2006-2007 and 2012. Williams holds the record for cumulative spacewalk time by a woman astronaut (50 hours and 40 minutes).
All four of the astronauts are test pilots, each with thousands of hours of flying experience.
"These distinguished, veteran astronauts are blazing a new trail, a trail that will one day land them in the history books, and Americans on the surface of Mars," NASA Administrator Charles Bolden said Thursday in a statement .
advertisement
The four NASA astronauts named to train for commercial spaceflights include, clockwise from top left, Robert Behnken, Eric Boe, Sunita Williams and Doug Hurley. NASA file
NASA is providing billions of dollars to SpaceX and the Boeing Co. to develop the Dragon and the CST-100 to carry crew. The plan calls for a series of uncrewed test flights, leading up to a demonstration flight to the space station with at least one NASA astronaut aboard. Just last month, NASA put in the first order for flights with Boeing, and it's expected that a similar order eventually will be placed with SpaceX.
The current schedule calls for crewed flights to begin in 2017, but NASA says that's dependent on funding. The space agency says it needs $1.2 billion next year to stay on track. A Senate panel trimmed that figure back to $900 million last month.
In the meantime, NASA is paying the Russians $76 million a seat for trips to the station and back aboard Soyuz capsules. In comparison, the average cost of a seat on a U.S.-built spaceship will be $58 million, Bolden said. "What's more, each mission will carry four crew members instead of three, along with 100 kilograms of materials to support the important science and research we conduct on the ISS," he said.
Bolden has repeatedly suggested that reduced funding levels from Congress will delay the start of commercial spaceflights to the station and extend NASA's dependence on the Russians.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:39:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Country Legend Willie Nelson Scores Big Music Prize</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fb3cc1/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpop0Eculture0Cmusic0Cwillie0Enelson0Eadds0Egershwin0Eprize0Estoried0Ecountry0Emusic0Ecareer0En38930A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Nelson was named on Thursday as the 2015 recipient of the Gershwin Prize for Popular Song</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 11:39 am ET
Willie Nelson Adds Gershwin Prize to Storied Country Music Career
by Reuters
advertisement
Country singer Willie Nelson was named on Thursday as the 2015 recipient of the Gershwin Prize for Popular Song, joining the likes of Paul McCartney, Billy Joel and Carole King in one of the highest U.S. music honors.
The Library of Congress said Nelson, whose career spans six decades, would be given the prize, which recognizes lifetime achievement, at a ceremony in Washington, D.C., in November.
Librarian of Congress James Billington described Nelson in a statement as a "musical explorer" who has "helped make country music one of the most universally beloved forms of American artistic expression."
Singer Willie Nelson performs at the 2012 CMT Music Awards in Nashville, Tennessee. HARRISON MCCLARY / Reuters
Nelson, 82, said he was honored to be chosen for the award, which was established in 2007 and named for composers George and Ira Gershwin.
advertisement
"I appreciate it greatly," Nelson said.
Texas-born Nelson has recorded more than 60 albums, written songs such as "Crazy," and appeared in more than 30 movies and TV shows.
His most recent album, a collaboration with Merle Haggard called "Django and Jimmie," made its debut at No. 1 on the Billboard Country Album chart in June.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:18:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israeli Singer Jailed for Hacking Madonna's Computer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fb3ccd/sc/32/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Ctech0Csecurity0Cisraeli0Ejailed0Ehacking0Emadonnas0Ecomputer0En389291/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 11:18 am ET
Israeli Jailed for Hacking Madonna's Computer
by Reuters
advertisement
A former contestant in Israel's version of "American Idol" was jailed for 14 months on Thursday for hacking the computers of singers including Madonna, who had complained about unfinished tracks from her latest album being leaked online.
Under a plea bargain, Adi Lederman confessed to computer trespassing and infringement of privacy and property rights, Tel Aviv Magistrate's Court said, citing Madonna as one of his victims without specifying that he was behind the song leak.
Lederman was also fined 15,000 shekels ($4,000).
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_jones_madonna_141229" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
"The ease with which crimes such as this can be committed by those who have skills in the field, such as the accused, require an appropriate punitive response that has a deterrent and uncompromising message," the court said in a statement.
Lederman, 39, was arrested in January after an investigation assisted by the FBI. Police said he was suspected of selling songs he had stolen through hacking.
advertisement
In December, unfinished tracks were leaked before the release of Madonna's "Rebel Heart" album. Madonna has said the crime was an "invasion into my life -- creatively, professionally and personally (that) remains a deeply devastating and hurtful experience".
Lederman previously made a brief appearance on "A Star Is Born," Israel's version of "American Idol", before being voted off. The court statement on Thursday said he had medical problems that had mitigated his sentence.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:13:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Restaurants Have an Extra Year to Put Calories on Menus</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47fb3cca/sc/26/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Chealth0Enews0Cfda0Egives0Erestaurants0Eextra0Eyear0Elabel0Emenus0En389281/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Restaurants will get an extra year, until 2016, to add calorie counts to their menus</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 9 2015, 11:13 am ET
FDA Gives Restaurants an Extra Year to Put Calories on Menus
by Maggie Fox
advertisement
Restaurants will get an extra year to add calorie counts to their menus. The Food and Drug Administration says they'll have until December 2016 to list clear calorie information where customers can easily see it.
The new rules have been extremely controversial. Not only will chain restaurants have to list calories , but so will movie theaters that sell popcorn and even establishments with salad bars.
The FDA hopes people will see just how many calories they're about to take in, make wiser choices, and that fast-food chains and other retailers will revise their offerings to meet a new consumer demand for more healthful foods.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_trend_menus_130719" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
But the lobbying has been heavy and constant  and the FDA says it has heard the complaints.
"The FDA agrees additional time is necessary for the agency to provide further clarifying guidance to help facilitate efficient compliance across all covered businesses and for covered establishments to come into compliance with the final rule," the agency said in a statement.
"The FDA is extending the compliance date for the menu labeling rule to December 1, 2016 , for those covered by the rule."
The agency will release detailed guidance in August. "There will be an opportunity for comment on the draft guidance and the FDA will review any comments received as quickly as possible," it said.
Only chains with 20 or more stores are covered, but "big box" stores that serve food  such as Target and Costco  will be included.
Pizza restaurants can list calories by the slice but have to say how many slices in a pizza. They can also list a range of calories to take into account different toppings that customers will ask for.
Maggie Fox
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
