<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nbcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Collision With F-16 Is 2nd Tragedy for Family in a Week</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f54ee9/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cplane0Ecollision0Emarks0E2nd0Efatal0Etragedy0Efamily0Eweek0En388996/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A collision between a small plane and an F-16 fighter jet that killed a father and son was the second fatal tragedy to strike their family in just four days.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_costello_plane_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
James Johnson and his wife, Beverly, were found dead in their home in a neighborhood of manicured houses with large yards surrounded by farm fields just outside St. Joseph, Missouri.
The couple's home is at the end of a dead-end road and protected by a steel gate. The front of the large acreage had a "no trespassing" sign as well as a sign with a phone number to call to enter the property.
Kelley Steele, who lived near the two, said the couple and the grandson kept to themselves and did not socialize with neighbors.
"We're a very close-knit neighborhood, but they just weren't receptive," Steele said.
advertisement
Stallworth told The News-Press in St. Joseph that the Johnsons met while working at naval shipyards in South Carolina. She said the couple adopted their grandson after they retired and returned to Missouri. She said Beverly home-schooled her grandson.
In South Carolina, authorities found Michael Johnson's body in the Cooper River in a sparsely populated area. He was 68. Recovery teams are still searching the same area for his son, who was 30.
On Wednesday, National Transportation Safety Board investigator Dennis Diaz told reporters that his first goal is to document the two crash sites, which are about 10 miles apart. He also said the F-16 pilot, who ejected safely, will be interviewed. But that may not happen for several days.
State police set up a roadblock to the area where a US Air Force F-16 fighter aircraft collided with a small Cessna 150 private aircraft in Moncks Corner, South Carolina. RICHARD ELLIS / EPA
Investigators will look at flight data recorders and interview witnesses, though that is expected to take months, Diaz said.
advertisement
He would not comment on the direction, speed or altitude at which either aircraft was traveling.
The jet's pilot, Maj. Aaron Johnson from the 55th Fighter Squadron, was taken to Joint Base Charleston's medical clinic for observation, officials from Shaw Air Force Base in Sumter said in a news release.
The jet crashed into woods around the privately owned Lewisfield Plantation, an estate dating to 1750.
At the time of the collision, Maj. Johnson was flying solo, practicing instrument approaches to a military base and was communicating with Charleston air traffic controllers, according to Col. Stephen Jost, commander of the 20th Fighter Squadron at Shaw Air Force Base.
Jost said he thought it was overcast at the time of the collision, but he was not aware of any weather-related problems.
It was not clear if a flight plan had been filed, but Berkeley County officials say the civilian pilot had indicated he was traveling to Myrtle Beach.
The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:53:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Tennessee Law Allows People to Save Pets From Hot Cars</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f54ef6/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cpets0Eare0Epeople0Etoo0Enew0Etenn0Elaw0Esaves0Epets0Ehot0En388946/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The law gives immunity to good Samaritans for any damages caused while trying to rescue an animal from a sweltering vehicle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 7:53 pm ET
New Tennessee Law Allows People to Save Pets From Hot Cars
by Kathryn Robinson
advertisement
A new Tennessee law now allows people to break into hot cars if an animal is trapped inside  without fear of punishment.
The law, which went into effect on July 1st, extends the states' good Samaritan law from including just kids, to pets too.
It protects individuals from civil liability for any damages caused while trying to rescue a child or an animal in danger.
advertisement
Yorkshire Terrier dogs Bobby, Billy, Benni and Zorro look out of the window of a car in Ravensburg, southern Germany, on April 10, 2015. FELIX KAESTLE / AFP - Getty Images file
The ASPCA said they strongly support giving law enforcement and good Samaritans the ability to intervene and protect animals suffering in hot cars.
"It takes only minutes for a pet to face death  on a 78-degree day, the temperature inside a parked car can reach 160 degrees, even with the windows cracked," Chloe Waterman, senior manager of State Legislative Strategy for the ASPCA.
KC Theisen, Director of Pet Care Issues at The Humane Society of the United States, said this happens because a pets response is not the same as a humans.
"If you leave a dog, as soon as they begin to feel that they are overheating they get anxious and panicked," Theisen told NBC News. "That causes their heart rate and body temperature to spike, putting them in more danger."
advertisement
Tennessee joins only 16 other states with statutes in place protecting animals in hot cars, according Michigan State University's Animal Law Center.
"Although many states do not have a law that specifically addresses leaving pets in hot cars, this act can constitute a violation of the cruelty code depending on the circumstances," Waterman said.
Kathryn Robinson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:50:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Well, Wookiee Here - It's the Official 'Star Wars' App</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f54ef7/sc/15/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Ctech0Cmobile0Cwell0Ewookiee0Ehere0Eits0Eofficial0Estar0Ewars0Eapp0En3890A0A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>"Star Wars" fans will be happy to hear that there is now an official app that brings news, sound clips, and trivia to your Android or iOS smartphone.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Disney
"Star Wars" fans will be happy to hear that there is now an official app that brings news, sound clips and trivia to your Android or iOS smartphone. The app from Lucasfilm and Disney Interactive has notifications for trailers and movie releases, a lightsaber training game, sound banks, access to the franchise's various social media accounts  and believe it or not, a special "Star Wars"-themed selfie mode.
Related: Rebels Seek Death Star Plans in 'Star Wars' Movie 'Rogue One'
Pick a light side or dark side theme (depending on how you identify) or a blue droid color scheme if you don't want to take sides. There's even a five-day weather forecast made to look like it's for Tatooine or another of the famous "Star Wars" planets.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:36:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>12-Year-Old Murder Suspect Puts Spotlight On Gangs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f51c88/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Carrest0E120Eyear0Eold0Emurder0Esuspect0Eputs0Espotlight0Emidwestern0Egang0En388836/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Nearly a dozen gangs are blamed for most of the gun violence in Omaha, where one of the latest murder cases involves a 12-year-old suspect.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Neighborhoods wrapped in crime tape have become a sobering sight in Omaha, Nebraska, where a fatal shooting allegedly carried out by a 12-year-old boy is the latest case being linked to gangs.
While violent gun crime dipped over the past decade in this Midwestern city of more than 430,000, the latest statistics show a resurgence of gun assault incidents this year. It's alarming enough for Omaha officials this week to pledge a stronger and more effective response to the scourge of gang activity.
The most troublesome months of January, May and June saw 41 gun assaults this year, up from 35 during the same three months of last year, according to Omaha police data.
"What you're seeing is today's victim becomes tomorrow's suspect," Omaha Police Chief Todd Schmaderer told NBC affiliate WOWT . "These outbreaks are simply gang and gun violence and retaliation. You will never arrest yourself out of this situation."
The number of gun assault incidents from January-June 2007 to 2015 in Omaha, Nebraska, provided by Omaha police. Omaha360
advertisement
Nearly a dozen gangs are blamed for most of the gun violence. The first half of the year was capped with the June 29 shooting of a 31-year-old man in north Omaha during an alleged drug deal.
The youngest of the gunmen  a baby-faced 12-year-old named Jarrell Milton  managed to flee 400 miles north to Minneapolis before he was caught Tuesday night, officials said.
Jarrell is being extradited back to Omaha to face a first-degree murder charge. His two alleged accomplices  17-year-old brother Jamar Milton and 15-year-old Shuntayvious Primes-Willis  have already been charged as adults.
Investigators told WOWT that all three suspects were carrying guns and are believed to have gang affiliations.
Jarrell's mother, Iyannia Moss, was convicted for felony assault when Jarrell was a toddler, WOWT reported. And according to court documents, the boys' father, 37-year-old Javaris Milton, is serving a 30-year prison sentence in Minnesota for a 2010 murder, WOWT reported .
Related: How One Woman in Chicago is Combating Gun Violence
Other high-profile shootings this year in the city also have gang ties.
In January, eight people were shot at a house party, three of them fatally in the name of gang retribution, police said. Then, in May, Omaha police veteran Kerrie Orozco was killed in a gun battle with a convicted felon and known gang member who was on the run for another shooting.
While the recent spike is hard to explain, Omaha street gangs continue to have a stranglehold on impressionable youth, said Bruce Ferrell, a former gang unit officer in the city.
Omaha police investigate the fatal May 20 shooting of veteran officer Kerrie Orozco. NBC News
advertisement
Ferrell said the problem remains a generational one: Gang members raising their children into the lifestyle.
"I started in the gang unit in 1988, and there are guys back then who are now grandfathers who taught their sons  who are now teaching their sons to be a gang member," said Ferrell, chairman of the Midwest Gang Investigators Association, which offers gang activity training to police departments.
He said there's also a shift in younger kids joining gangs because social media offers opportunities for them to connect through Facebook and YouTube.
"It has allowed them to learn about how to become a good gang member," Ferrell said. "These channels can be used as a way to harass rival gangs or to intimidate people online."
In addition, gangs are using the allure of hip hop stardom to draw recruits. Slickly produced music videos uploaded online show members counting money, cooking drugs and flashing firearms.
"These kids see it and think they can be an aspiring musician, too," Ferrell said.
"We can't lose focus, one shooting or homicide is one too many."
But Omaha has managed to see a significant decrease in gun assaults over the past decade, according to city police stats. After a high of 95 incidents during the first six months of 2007, the first six months of 2015 totaled 59.
The drop is being credited to the growth of community policing. City officials said they will continue targeting problem neighborhoods with more police.
Willie Barney, the president of the Empowerment Network , an Omaha group working to better the city, said various community and faith-based organizations, residents and businesses are also doing their part. They have banded together to provide employment, educational programs and recreational activities as alternatives to the streets, Barney said.
The groups also do outreach, providing mentors and coaching to youth. But Barney acknowledged that there are more children in Omaha who can use help than there are available opportunities.
The community groups made an effort this week to canvass the same neighborhood where the fatal shooting involving the 12-year-old suspect took place.
"We can't lose focus," Barney said, "one shooting or homicide is one too many."
Erik Ortiz
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:26:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miserably Hilarious Letters From Sleepaway Camp</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f4aa80/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnightly0Enews0Cvideo0Cmiserably0Ehilarious0Eletters0Efrom0Esleepaway0Ecamp0E480A492611991/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Camp can be a trying time for kids, but the lost art of letter-writing lets them tell their parents just how much fun they are - or aren't - having.</Description>
        <MainBody>Miserably Hilarious Letters From Sleepaway Camp

Camp can be a trying time for kids, but the lost art of letter-writing lets them tell their parents just how much fun they are - or aren't - having.
Previous
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:20:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Widow of Waco Shootout Biker Sues Restaurant</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f58c87/sc/26/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Ccrime0Ecourts0Cwidow0Ewaco0Eshootout0Ebiker0Esues0Erestaurant0En38890A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The widow of a man killed in a shootout between cops and bikers has filed suit against the parent company of the restaurant where it all started.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 7:20 pm ET
Widow of Waco Shootout Biker Sues Twin Peaks Restaurant for Negligence
by Erin Calabrese
advertisement
The widow of a biker killed in a shootout between cops and members of two motorcycle clubs in a Texas restaurant's parking lot has filed a negligence lawsuit against the chain's parent company.
Mary Rodriguez, whose husband Jesus Delgado Rodriguez died after he was shot multiple times during the May 17 incident, claims that Waco's Twin Peaks restaurant was negligent in allowing a biker meeting to take place because they disregarded law enforcement warnings that tensions were rising between the clubs, the Associated Press reported.
Just after the shooting, Rodriguez' son, Vincent Ramirez, told NBC News that his father was "in the wrong place at the wrong time." Rodriguez, a veteran of the Vietnam War, was regularly invited to charity runs, Ramirez said.
"He's been invited to a lot of runs  all the charity runs." adding that his dad even did 'Crime Stopper' runs. "He never carried any kind of weapons. He didn't even wear colors or anything like that. He used to carry a small pocket knife but he was told he couldn't bring it into a convention once - so, he stopped carrying, even that," Ramirez said.
Rodriguez' widow, Mary, told the AP her husband's death was, "something that shouldn't have happened," adding that the police should've done something to stop the rumble between Bandidos and Cossacks motorcycle club members from happening in the first place.
advertisement
Authorities investigate a shooting in the parking lot of the Twin Peaks restaurant Sunday, May 17, 2015, in Waco, Texas. Authorities say that the shootout victims were members of rival biker gangs that had gathered for a meeting. Jerry Larson / AP
Rodriguez, a grandfather to 19, was one of nine people  all bikers  killed in the shooting. Another 18 bikers were hurt, and more than 170 were arrested in the melee. Only four of the 177 people held on $1 million dollar bonds for engaging in organized crime, remain in custody  most of the others have been released on reduced bonds or have not been indicted.
Erin Calabrese
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:00:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wildly Successful Birth Control Initiative Scrambles for Cash</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f52161/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Csexual0Ehealth0Cneeded0E50Emillion0Efund0Esuccessful0Ebirth0Econtrol0Eprogram0En388926/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A program that cut abortions by 42 percent among teens is scrabbling for cash after a big grant ran out and the state legislature refused to fund it.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nc_teenbirths0909_500kmsnbc_130909" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Medical experts from the American Academy of Pediatrics to the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists recommend intrauterine devices (IUDs) and implantable birth control drugs as the most effective methods, as well as safe . But research shows only 7 percent of teenagers use these methods, called long-acting reversible contraception.
Instead, they prefer unreliable methods such as condoms and birth control pills.
The program provided free birth control to needy, high-risk young women. It educated doctors, nurses and other caregivers about how to use and administer these methods. "It's much easier for them to hand out condoms and write prescriptions for birth control pills," Wolk said.
"It takes time to insert an IUD or a long-acting contraceptive like Norplant."
advertisement
The program was a success by any measure. It provided more than 30,000 IUDs or implants at low or no cost to low-income women at 68 family planning clinics.
"Teen birth rates in our state have declined more rapidly than in any other state or the nation as a whole," the state said in a statement. "The decline in births among young women served by these agencies accounted for three-quarters of the overall decline in the Colorado teen birth rate."
This saved money.
"The birth rate for Medicaid-eligible women ages 15 to 24 dropped sharply from 2010 to 2012, resulting in an estimated $49 million to $111 million avoided expenses in Medicaid birth-related costs alone."
The foundation extended the funding for a couple of years, Wolk said, but the point of the grants was to start up pilot projects that could serve as demonstrations to encourage state and federal funding.
advertisement
So the state asked the legislature to pay for it, but the Republican-led body voted against it. Some lawmakers argued that IUDs are tantamount to abortion, Wolk said. ACOG and other groups say this is untrue but it remains a widely held belief.
Republican state senator Sen. Kevin Lundberg says IUDs can cause abortions.
"Protecting life is a very big issue," Lundberg said in discussing the funding issue last January. "In my mind, that's what government is all about, and to protect the life of the most vulnerable and most innocent seems to be the most important."
"Teen birth rates in our state have declined more rapidly than in any other state or the nation as a whole."
The second barrier: the Affordable Care Act's requirement that insurers provide birth control for free.
Some lawmakers felt if taxpayers were paying for birth control once, through Medicaid, that they shouldn't have to pay again to fund this program. "They took a clinical and social program and made it political," Wolk said.
"We tried to explain that  there are still a lot of gaps," Wolk said. "Those include provider training." Studies show many doctors still don't understand how well IUDs work, for instance.
"And there are still a fair number of women who lack insurance or don't want their insurance involved," Wolk added. For instance, teens on their parents' health insurance plans may not want their parents notified. "The critics will imagine the 12-year-old girl," said Wolk, a practicing pediatrician. "But they forget you can be a dependent on your parents' coverage up to age 26."
People who lack any insurance, even Medicaid, are among those most likely to have an unwanted pregnancy, statistics show.
Plus, the implants and devices are pricey, costing $800 to $900 a pop. Many insurers willnot pay for them and the law only requires that they pay for some form of birth control, not every form.
Maggie Fox
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:44:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Donald Trump: 'I Will Win the Latino Vote'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f24cef/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpolitics0C20A160Eelection0Cdonald0Etrump0Ei0Ewill0Ewin0Elatino0Evote0En388696/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Presidential candidate Donald Trump tells NBC that "I will create jobs and the Latinos will have jobs that they don't have right now and I will win that vote."</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_fh_trump_tur_mexico_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Trump dismissed the idea that his business has been hurt by companies backing away from him as a result of his controversial comments. Macy's, Serta, NBC Universal and Univision have announced that they've severed business ties with him.
advertisement
"This is too important. Yeah, I'm losing some contracts. Who cares?" he said. "They're weak and they want to be politically correct. Some of them have already apologized to me and said they made a mistake."
Trump was also asked about a Washington Post report that quoted undocumented immigrants working on his hotel project in Washington, D.C.
"We have a very strong system," he replied, saying that the newspaper did not reference any of the workers by name. "I have a contractor that is one of the biggest in the nation, they're doing it. So far, they're doing a very good job. We have a very strong verification system."
In a statement, Trump's campaign said:
Trump International Hotel, Washington DC has hired Lend Lease, a globally recognized construction management firm, to oversee construction at the Old Post Office and requires all contractors performing work at the project to follow all applicable federal, state and local laws. Our contractors are required to have prospective employees produce documentation that establishes identity and employment eligibility in compliance with immigration law. Lend Lease and the Trump Organization have worked on many large development projects together and have always used best in class practices above and beyond what is required by law."
Trump's controversial remarks about Mexican immigrants came during his unscripted announcement speech last month.
"When Mexico sends its people, they're not sending the best," he said during the speech. "They're not sending you, they're sending people that have lots of problems and they're bringing those problems. They're bringing drugs, they're bringing crime. They're rapists and some, I assume, are good people, but I speak to border guards and they're telling us what we're getting."
NBC Universal announced on June 29 that it was cutting ties with Trump as a result of the comments.
"At NBC, respect and dignity for all people are cornerstones of our values," NBC's statement read. "Due to the recent derogatory statements by Donald Trump regarding immigrants, NBCUniversal is ending its business relationship with Mr. Trump."
NBC News is owned by NBC Universal.
Katy Tur
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:41:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York Stock Exchange Reopens After Tech Glitch</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f38166/sc/21/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cbusiness0Cmarkets0Cnew0Eyork0Estock0Eexchange0Ereopens0Eafter0Etech0Eglitch0En388711/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Trading on the New York Stock Exchange was set to resume at midafternoon Wednesday after being halted by a technical issue.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 6:41 pm ET
New York Stock Exchange Reopens After Tech Glitch
by Jacob Pramuk and Mike Brunker
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_sgo-nyse_computer_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Trading on the New York Stock Exchange resumed at mid-afternoon Wednesday after being halted for more than three-and-a-half hours by a technical issue.
Officials provided few details on the problem that they said caused the suspension of trading from 11:32 a.m. until about 3:10 p.m. ET. Earlier, the NYSE took to Twitter to assure the public that the shutdown was not caused by a cyberattack, a message that was echoed by the Obama administration.
"It's not a good day. I don't' feel good for our customers who are having to deal with the fallout," NYSE President Thomas Farley told CNBC after trading resumed.
He indicated the problem was likely related to an earlier problem that had been deemed fixed.
Just after 8 a.m. ET on Wednesday morning, the NYSE put out an alert about "a reported issue with a gateway connection" affecting certain symbols. It issued a notice at 10:37 a.m. ET that the problem was resolved.
"We opened the market as usual. All the NYSE-listed stocks opened without incident. Around mid-morning, we started to see some concerns about the way trading was occurring. Customers weren't getting all of the messages back that you otherwise expect," Farley said.
advertisement
Two U.S. officials told NBC News there was no indication the NYSE shutdown was related to the computer issue that temporarily grounded all United Airlines flights on Wednesday morning . They also said there was no indication of a cyberattack.
Separately White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest said, "There is no indication that there are malicious actors involved."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:29:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore Mayor Fires Police Commissioner as Crime Spikes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f4405d/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cbaltimore0Eunrest0Cbaltimore0Emayor0Efires0Epolice0Ecommissioner0Eamid0Espike0Ehomicide0Erate0En388841/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake has fired Police Commissioner Anthony Batts.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 6:29 pm ET
Baltimore Mayor Fires Police Commissioner As Murders Rise
by Jon Schuppe
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_balt_interimchief_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake replaced the city's police commissioner on Wednesday, saying the city needed to be more focused on suppressing a spike in violence in the months since the death of a man in police custody.
Rawlings-Blake said the police department under Commissioner Anthony Batts had become too preoccupied with internal politics and not enough with stemming a surge in shootings and killings.
"This was not an easy decision, but it is one that is in the best interest of Baltimore," the mayor said in a late afternoon news conference. "The people of Baltimore deserve better. The brave men and women of our department who put their lives on the line to make our cities deserve better."
advertisement
Baltimore, historically one of America's most violent cities, has stumbled particularly hard, ending the first six months of the year with a 48 percent increase in homicides over the same period in 2014. That trend continued into July, with 10 killings in one week, including the shooting of three people Tuesday near the city's University of Maryland campus.
Baltimore Police Commissioner Anthony Batts, who was replaced Wednesday. Andrew Burton / Getty Images file
Of the 154 murders so far this year, more than half occurred since the April 19 death of Freddie Gray , who succumbed to injuries suffered while riding in the back of a police transport van. His death triggered looting and rioting and resulted in charges against six police officers .
To many, the timing of that backlash and the spike in murders is not coincidental.
Since Gray's death, the relationship between police and the city's high-crime communities has suffered, making it harder for cops to patrol streets and investigate cases, officials say. Arrests have plummeted, sparking accusations of a deliberate police slowdown.
advertisement
At the same time, officials have blamed some of the violence on the looting of pharmacies and methadone clinics, which may have put a glut of opiates on the black market, triggering drug feuds.
Local crime experts told NBC News that the initial spike in killings likely fueled waves of retaliatory violence, further pushing the murder rate up.
"Gun violence has a cyclical aspect to it. It can operate like a contagion: one shooting leads to another, then leads to another, then leads to another," said Daniel Webster, director of the Johns Hopkins Center for Gun Policy and Research. "So while there may have been a small number of events that occurred initially, they got many more people out there looking for revenge."
"It was almost the perfect storm of circumstance," former Deputy Baltimore Police Commissioner John Skinner said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:03:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mom Sues YMCA for Excluding Son With Down Syndrome</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f3d3de/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cohio0Emom0Esues0Eymca0Eexcluding0Eson0Edown0Esyndrome0En388796/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Ironically, the 6-year-old has been featured "as a poster child" for YMCA programs with the tag lines 'Providing Opportunities for Everyone,'" the suit says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 6:03 pm ET
Ohio Mom Sues YMCA For Excluding Son With Down Syndrome
by Elizabeth Chuck
Steven Heffron, 6, and his mother, Denise Watts, play in Smale Riverfront Park in downtown Cincinnati. Watts has filed a federal lawsuit alleging discrimination, saying an Ohio YMCA excluded her son from summer camp because he has Down syndrome and treated him hypocritically after using him in promotions extolling opportunities for everyone. John Minchillo / AP
Share
advertisement
It's a battle for integration, but race is not the issue.
An Ohio mother is suing a YMCA she says won't accept her son into its general summer program, only offering the boy with Down syndrome a spot in its camp for kids with disabilities.
In addition to refusing to make reasonable accommodations for 6-year-old Steven Heffron, the Great Miami Valley YMCA uses him "as a poster child for its programs with the tag lines 'Providing Opportunities for Everyone,'" the federal lawsuit, which includes photos of YMCA promotional material featuring Steven, says.
His mother, Denise Watts, of Middletown, Ohio, said she's been asking for months for the YMCA to allow Steven into the camp.
"Each time they just said no, that it wasn't safe, the environment wasn't safe," she told NBC News. "It's more like he's a liability, but that's not my fault."
advertisement
Steven Heffron, 6, wasn't allowed to go to the YMCA camp his mom wanted him to go to. Courtesy of Denise Watts
Steven, who Watts said is often described by people as "the most charismatic kid they've ever met," just finished kindergarten at a local public school. He hoped to go to the YMCA camp because his classmates were going there.
Watts wanted him to have the experience of going to a mainstream summer camp. According to civil rights attorney Richard Ganulin, who represents Watts, "Steven shuts down when he's segregated with just children with disabilities."
"Some people with disabilities are very, very medically fragile and very disabled, and Steven doesn't respond well when he's segregated with just individuals with disabilities," Ganulin, who is based in Cincinnati, told NBC News.
The suit accuses the YMCA in Butler County of violating the federal Americans with Disabilities Act and the federal Rehabilitation Act. Watts said she suggested they accommodate him by adding another counselor to the group of campers that Steven is with. She said she also proposed only sending Steven for half-days as a compromise.
advertisement
"The child has a right to be in an integrated program. They can offer what are called segregated programs, which is just children with disabilities, but he has the right to be in an integrated program for children without disabilities."
"I'm not asking for anything that's off the walls," she said. "But they're saying it would change the continuity of the program."
NBC News was not able to reach lawyers for the YMCA. YMCA Attorney Michael Hawkins told the Associated Press he is still gathering the facts of case, and said youth development has been a focus for the organization for decades. He added that the YMCA will do everything possible to support children's needs.
Ganulin said that, in addition to the camp, the YMCA also won't allow Steven to attend a before-school program, and will only let him attend an after-school program for 15 minutes a day.
"The YMCA or any other program that is subject to these laws has to make reasonable modifications to accommodate Steven's needs to allow him to have equal access," he said. "There are behavioral experts who assess situations like this and they provide recommendations for how to accommodate the needs of someone with a disability. We asked the YMCA to do that here, but it refused."
advertisement
The YMCA's response, he said, was that it didn't have sufficient staffing or training to make sure Steven was safe in its general summer program, but said it welcomed him at its camp for special needs.
That is a violation of the Americans with Disabilities Act, according to Kevin Truitt, an attorney with non-profit Disability Rights Ohio.
"The child has a right to be in an integrated program. They can offer what are called segregated programs, which is just children with disabilities, but he has the right to be in an integrated program for children without disabilities," Truitt told NBC News. "They have to accommodate his needs to ensure he has the same access to this program as any other child."
With the YMCA not budging, Watts will send Steven to the camp for special needs so he doesn't spend the summer cooped up in their apartment. The lawsuit seeks for accommodations to be made for Steven at all of the YMCA's programs, plus unspecified damages.
Watts worked part-time at the YMCA until March of this year, and says she was fired for expressing her frustrations about the lack of support there for Steven.
"Denise is a single mom," Ganulin said. "Basically her life is dedicated to Steven's welfare."
Elizabeth Chuck
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:57:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Selleck Accused of Stealing Water, but Cops Come Up Dry</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f4c400/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ccalifornia0Edrought0Cno0Ecrime0Efound0Eafter0Esuit0Eaccuses0Etom0Eselleck0Estealing0Ewater0En388866/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>While a lawsuit accuses Tom Selleck of swiped precious water, California law enforcement officials told NBC News no crime has been committed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 5:57 pm ET
Lawsuit Accuses Tom Selleck of Stealing Water, but Cops Come Up Dry
by M. Alex Johnson and Andrew Blankstein
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_mal_tom_selleck_water_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
TV cop Tom Selleck may or may not have improperly swiped precious water by the magnum, but he didn't commit a crime, real California cops told NBC News on Wednesday.
Selleck, the 70-year-old star of "Blue Bloods" and formerly of "Magnum, P.I.," and his wife, Jillie, were sued this week by the Calleguas Municipal Water District in Ventura County for allegedly sending a water tender  like the giant tanker trucks used to supply fire engines  to siphon off tankloads of water from a public hydrant at a construction site at least 12 times over the last two years.
The water district said in its suit that it hired a real private investigator who several times observed the same water tender leave the 61-acre ranch the fictional P.I. owns in the ritzy Hidden Valley area of Ventura County, which is in a different water district and was assessed last year at more than $10 million (and was once owned by Dean Martin).
advertisement
The suit says a commercial water tanker drained tankfuls of water from a public hydrant in Ventura County, California, and ferried it to Tom Selleck's $10 million ranch, which is in a different water district, at least 12 times over the last two years. Michael Ochs Archives / Getty Images
The suit says the water district sent cease-and-desist letters to Selleck after its investigator spotted the truck at the hydrant eight times the week of Sept. 29, 2013.
But the truck showed up again in December of that year, and was tracked as it proceeded to Selleck's property, according to the suit.
Then, on four straight days just last March, the same truck again drained tankloads of water from the construction site and delivered it to the Selleck ranch, the suit says.
The suit seeks an order forcing Selleck to stop using the district's water, plus reimbursement for the $21,685.55 it paid the investigator, with damages and other costs.
advertisement
But the suit is a civil action, not a criminal case. Ventura County sheriff's Capt. John Riley meanwhile told NBC News that the sheriff's office did investigate allegations of criminal water theft, but "we are unable to establish a crime was committed."
The Ventura County district attorney's office also confirmed that no case has been referred to it for prosecution.
Selleck hasn't responded to requests for comment, and it's unknown whether he has anything to do with the water truck, which is registered under a commercial license.
Eric Bergh, the water district's manager of resources, said the suit wasn't meant to be an example of "drought shaming," a peculiarly California activity in which people suspected of hogging water are publicly called out.
"Our policies have been on the books for decades," Bergh said. "We just want any such activity to stop  that is the bottom line for us. It's really about doing the right thing and preserving our water supply for our users."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:01:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charleston Families Call for Gun Policy Reform</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f44062/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ccharleston0Echurch0Eshooting0Ccharleston0Efamilies0Elawmakers0Ecall0Egun0Epolicy0Ereform0En388881/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Family members of people who were killed by gun violence stood next to top Democrats as part of a call for stricter gun control measures on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 5:01 pm ET
Charleston Families, Lawmakers Call for Gun Policy Reform
by Alex Moe
advertisement
Family members of several people who were killed by gun violence in America  including the recent shooting at a South Carolina church  clutched photos of loved ones as they stood next to top Democrats as part of a call for stricter gun control measures on Wednesday.
Andre Duncan, who lost his aunt, Myra Thompson, in the Charleston shooting last month said he believes the tragedy "made Charleston much stronger than it ever was".
Thompson was killed June 17 along with eight other parishioners at Emanuel AME Church when a gunman opened fire during a bible study session.
Duncan added he "will not rest until our legislators do what is right by expanding Brady background checks."
House Democratic Leader Nancy Pelosi, D-Calif., fellow California Democrat Rep. Mike Thompson and South Carolina Democratic Rep. Jim Clyburn joined the Brady Campaign to Prevent Gun Violence in calling on Congress to pass tougher gun laws.
advertisement
Rep. Clyburn  who said he only just returned to Washington D.C. last night following the Charleston shooting  had strong words as lawmakers in his home state debated the symbolism of the Confederate flag .
"It's an important symbol, it is a very strong symbol but the fact still remains that though this young man worshiped that symbol, hye carried out his dastardly act with a gun," Clyburn said.
Pelosi, who also commented on the killing of Kathryn Steinle in San Francisco last week by a gun, said it was essential for Congress to take a vote on the Brady background check bill. The bill, H.R. 1217, would amend the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act.t
"What we need is for this entire Congress to say 'we are Charleston' but we cannot allow people to say it unless it is accompanied with 'we are Charleston and we will give you a vote on a Brady background check bill'," Pelosi said.
advertisement
President Barack Obama has previously expressed frustration over the stymied status of federal gun control reform and called for stricter controls and congressional action after similar tragedies in such places as Aurora, Colorado, and Newtown, Connecticut.
"Every country has violent, hateful or mentally unstable people. What's different is not every country is awash with easily accessible guns," the president told a gathering last month at the U.S. Conference of Mayors in San Francisco. "So I refuse to act as if this is the new normal or to pretend that it's simply sufficient to grieve, and that any mention of doing something to stop it is somehow politicizing the problem."
However, legislative action has fallen short.
Policy experts say that despite the president's pointed remarks about gun violence in the wake of the Charleston church shooting, it is unlikely that Washington will revisit the issue.
"I don't expect we will see new federal laws passed in the near future despite broad public support for gun safety laws," Daniel Webster, director of the Johns Hopkins Center for Gun Policy and Research told NBC.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:42:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore Mayor Fires Police Commissioner</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f419ec/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbaltimore0Emayor0Efires0Epolice0Ecommissioner0Eamid0Espike0Ehomicide0Erate0En388841/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake has fired Police Commissioner Anthony Batts.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 6:29 pm ET
Baltimore Mayor Fires Police Commissioner As Murders Rise
by Jon Schuppe
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_balt_interimchief_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake replaced the city's police commissioner on Wednesday, saying the city needed to be more focused on suppressing a spike in violence in the months since the death of a man in police custody.
Rawlings-Blake said the police department under Commissioner Anthony Batts had become too preoccupied with internal politics and not enough with stemming a surge in shootings and killings.
"This was not an easy decision, but it is one that is in the best interest of Baltimore," the mayor said in a late afternoon news conference. "The people of Baltimore deserve better. The brave men and women of our department who put their lives on the line to make our cities deserve better."
advertisement
Baltimore, historically one of America's most violent cities, has stumbled particularly hard, ending the first six months of the year with a 48 percent increase in homicides over the same period in 2014. That trend continued into July, with 10 killings in one week, including the shooting of three people Tuesday near the city's University of Maryland campus.
Baltimore Police Commissioner Anthony Batts, who was replaced Wednesday. Andrew Burton / Getty Images file
Of the 154 murders so far this year, more than half occurred since the April 19 death of Freddie Gray , who succumbed to injuries suffered while riding in the back of a police transport van. His death triggered looting and rioting and resulted in charges against six police officers .
To many, the timing of that backlash and the spike in murders is not coincidental.
Since Gray's death, the relationship between police and the city's high-crime communities has suffered, making it harder for cops to patrol streets and investigate cases, officials say. Arrests have plummeted, sparking accusations of a deliberate police slowdown.
advertisement
At the same time, officials have blamed some of the violence on the looting of pharmacies and methadone clinics, which may have put a glut of opiates on the black market, triggering drug feuds.
Local crime experts told NBC News that the initial spike in killings likely fueled waves of retaliatory violence, further pushing the murder rate up.
"Gun violence has a cyclical aspect to it. It can operate like a contagion: one shooting leads to another, then leads to another, then leads to another," said Daniel Webster, director of the Johns Hopkins Center for Gun Policy and Research. "So while there may have been a small number of events that occurred initially, they got many more people out there looking for revenge."
"It was almost the perfect storm of circumstance," former Deputy Baltimore Police Commissioner John Skinner said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:28:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Is Uptick in Shark Attacks Biting Into Carolinas' Tourism?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f419f4/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cbusiness0Ctravel0Cshark0Eattacks0Earent0Ebiting0Etourism0Ecarolinas0Ebusiness0Eowners0Esay0En38880A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Shark attacks in North and South Carolina are not preventing people from vacationing on the states' beaches, local business owners say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 3:28 pm ET
Shark Attacks Aren't Biting Into Tourism, Carolinas' Business Owners Say
by Ali Montag
advertisement
CORRECTION: There were 23 total shark attacks reported in Australia in 2014. That fact was misstated in an earlier version of this article.
Shark attacks in North and South Carolina are not preventing people from vacationing on the states' beaches, local business owners say  though tourists may be thinking twice about diving into the water.
It's only July, but the Carolinas have already seen 12 shark attacks in 2015, compared with a normal average of four to six for the region in an entire year. To put that in further perspective, the entire country of Australia, which gets wide media attention for shark attacks, saw a total of 23 attacks in 2014.
But none of that is keeping families away from places like the Outer Banks, Hilton Head or Myrtle Beach.
No one has canceled their summer reservations at Outer Banks Blue, a vacation home rental company in North Carolina, said owner Tim Cafferty. He's actually seen a spike in business.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_alexander_shark_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
"Over the last two weeks we've seen more last-minute rentals than we have in the last five years," Cafferty said. "It's really been ironic. I think people understand it's an isolated event, and that the chances are infinitesimally small."
advertisement
"I believe we've seen a better economic situation here, quite frankly, that people are doing other things besides going to the beach," he said. He's seen increased tourist attendance at the Wright Brothers National Memorial , para-sailing on the more enclosed "Soundside" waters, and ropes courses.
The Island Resort and Inn, a hotel off the beach in Oak Island, N.C., where two of the attacks have occurred, already has customers rebooking vacations for next year, said office manager Rose Dauphinais.
"I've been coming here since 1976, and this was the first shark attack I've ever heard of," she said, but added that "no one has canceled their trips."
That said, the attacks are serious  and unusual  said George Burgess, director of the Florida Program for Shark Research at the University of Florida.
"It's an all-time high for a yearly total. It's an unprecedented situation," he said. "This is just a slap in the face that we need to be more careful entering the sea."
advertisement
Even with this year's unusually high number of attacks in the Carolinas, in context, there are more pressing dangers at the beach than sharks, Burgess said. The world saw only three known shark-attack fatalities in 2014. The last fatal shark attack in South Carolina was in 1852.
Burgess added that the number shark attacks is directly related to the number of people in the water.
"It's sort of a back-handed compliment to the chambers of commerce who are bringing that many people into the waters," he said. "The next step is development of beach safety personnel and services to reduce the risk of shark attacks on their beaches that are now drawing so many people."
Tourism brought $21.3 billion to North Carolina in 2014, said Wit Tuttell, executive director of Visit North Carolina. Six and a half million people spent their time visiting North Carolina beaches in 2014, according to a survey from the organization.
This year's tourism season has yet to take a hit from the shark attacks, said Lee Nettles, executive director of the Outer Banks Visitors' Bureau. Nettles said his office has seen an increased number of concerned calls from visitors, but that people aren't canceling their trips.
How summer vacation can hit your Christmas budget
"Clearly something extraordinary is going on, but the three shark encounters we've had in the Outer Banks are relative to the 5 million visitors annually," he said. "Three shark bites is three too many, but it's still a relatively safe environment."
At the Ocean Boulevard Bistro and Martini Bar in Kitty Hawk, N.C., owner Donny King said he saw an uptick in business at his restaurant during the Fourth of July weekend. He's personally taking precautions, but he's not staying out of the water.
"I'm a surfer myself. My nephew is in town with us working at the restaurant, and we go surfing as much as we can," he said. "We just make sure we're in a busy area and staying near life guards."
Ali Montag
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:42:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>S.C. House Begins Debate Over Confederate Flag</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f2e824/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cconfederate0Eflag0Efuror0Cs0Ec0Ehouse0Eopens0Edebate0Eover0Econfederate0Eflag0En388756/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The South Carolina House started deliberating a proposal that could remove the banner from the Capitol grounds, as soon as the end of the week.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 7:01 pm ET
South Carolina House Opens Debate Over Confederate Flag
by The Associated Press
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_shorttake_allen_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
COLUMBIA, S.C.  The South Carolina House opened debate over the future of the Confederate flag Wednesday, deliberating a proposal that could remove the banner from the Capitol grounds, possibly before the end of the week.
Lawmakers are under pressure to act after the state Senate passed its own measure, which is supported by Gov. Nikki Haley. If approved, it would consign the flag to the state's Confederate Relic Room.
But some House Republicans planned to offer amendments to the Senate bill that would preserve some kind of symbol in front of the Statehouse to honor their Southern ancestors.
advertisement
One of them, Rep. Mike Pitts, said to banish all flags from the site would be akin to erasing history, including that of his family members in Laurens County and the mountains of North Carolina and Virginia.
On the House floor, Pitts talked about a black colleague, Rep. Lonnie Hosey, and how they bonded over the shared memories of military service.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_ral_confederate_flag_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
"I'm willing to move that flag at some point if it causes a twinge in the hearts of my friends," Pitts said. "But I'll ask for something in return."
advertisement
Pitts said his favorite amendment proposes flying the flag of the 1st South Carolina Volunteers regiment, a blue banner similar to the state flag with its Palmetto tree and crescent moon but with a wreath around the tree. Similar art is etched on a wall inside the Statehouse, Pitts said.
Pitts did not share all his amendments Tuesday, but The Associated Press was able to obtain copies of the more than two dozen proposals.
The House is expected to debate a measure Wednesday that would remove the flag from the Capitol grounds. John Bazemore / AP
One would put the flag issue to a popular vote. Another would allow the rebel banner to fly only on Confederate Memorial Day in May, and a third would replace the Confederate battle flag with a different banner.
Other amendments appear more like parodies than serious alternatives to the Senate bill: One would fly the U.S. flag upside-down above the Statehouse dome. Another would remove all of the monuments at the Statehouse, regardless of whether they honor Confederates.
If House members back the Senate bill, Gov. Nikki Haley could quickly sign it into law, potentially bringing the flag down within days.
Any change to the Senate bill is unacceptable to the 46 Democrats in the 124-member House  a critical number because some Democrats will have to support any bill to take down the flag to reach the two-thirds threshold required by law, Minority Leader Todd Rutherford said.
Rutherford said any flag that goes up beside the monument to Confederate soldiers "will be the new vestige of racism."
If the House amends the Senate bill, the Senate will have to agree with the changes or lawmakers will have to reconcile their differences in a conference committee, possibly delaying action for weeks. Several senators said the lopsided 36-3 final vote on the flag shows they do not want their bill to change.
"As strong as the support was, it would be absolutely foolish" to attempt to amend the Senate bill, Republican Sen. Larry Martin said.
advertisement
If the two sides cannot reach an agreement, or the House rejects the Senate bill, the flag debate would probably be dead for this year.
After the flag was pulled off the Statehouse dome 15 years ago, it was called a settled issue. The banner was instead moved to a monument honoring Confederate soldiers elsewhere on the Capitol grounds.
But the flag debate regained urgency last month after state Sen. Clementa Pinckney and eight other black people were fatally shot at a historic African-American church in Charleston. A white gunman who police said was motivated by racial hatred is charged in the attack.
The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:19:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York Stock Exchange to Reopen After Major Glitch</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f24994/sc/21/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cbusiness0Cmarkets0Cnew0Eyork0Estock0Eexchange0Ehalts0Etrading0Eall0Esymbols0En388711/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Trading on the New York Stock Exchange was set to resume at midafternoon Wednesday after being halted by a technical issue.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 6:41 pm ET
New York Stock Exchange Reopens After Tech Glitch
by Jacob Pramuk and Mike Brunker
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_sgo-nyse_computer_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Trading on the New York Stock Exchange resumed at mid-afternoon Wednesday after being halted for more than three-and-a-half hours by a technical issue.
Officials provided few details on the problem that they said caused the suspension of trading from 11:32 a.m. until about 3:10 p.m. ET. Earlier, the NYSE took to Twitter to assure the public that the shutdown was not caused by a cyberattack, a message that was echoed by the Obama administration.
"It's not a good day. I don't' feel good for our customers who are having to deal with the fallout," NYSE President Thomas Farley told CNBC after trading resumed.
He indicated the problem was likely related to an earlier problem that had been deemed fixed.
Just after 8 a.m. ET on Wednesday morning, the NYSE put out an alert about "a reported issue with a gateway connection" affecting certain symbols. It issued a notice at 10:37 a.m. ET that the problem was resolved.
"We opened the market as usual. All the NYSE-listed stocks opened without incident. Around mid-morning, we started to see some concerns about the way trading was occurring. Customers weren't getting all of the messages back that you otherwise expect," Farley said.
advertisement
Two U.S. officials told NBC News there was no indication the NYSE shutdown was related to the computer issue that temporarily grounded all United Airlines flights on Wednesday morning . They also said there was no indication of a cyberattack.
Separately White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest said, "There is no indication that there are malicious actors involved."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:14:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hot Water: Tom Selleck Accused of Swiping H2O</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f317e3/sc/14/l/0L0Snbclosangeles0N0Cnews0Clocal0CTom0ESelleck0EAccused0ESwiping0EWater0E3124424810Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Actor Tom Selleck has been accused of stealing public water for use on his spacious Hidden Hills ranch.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tom Selleck Accused of Swiping Water
Link
Close
Embed this video
&lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="UTF-8" src="http://www.nbclosangeles.com/portableplayer/?cmsID=312386371&amp;videoID=XlQcS8Vip4kQ&amp;origin=nbclosangeles.com&amp;sec=news&amp;subsec=local&amp;width=600&amp;height=360"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
More videos (1 of 9)
 
The Calleguas Municipal Water District claims its private investigator found actor Tom Selleck swiping public water for private use. Robert Kovacik reports for the NBC4 News at 11 p.m. on Tuesday, July 7, 2015. (Published Tuesday, Jul 7, 2015)
Updated at 12:21 PM PDT on Wednesday, Jul 8, 2015
Actor Tom Selleck has been accused of stealing public water for use on his spacious ranch in Hidden Hills, California.
A truck registered to the "Magnum, P.I."actor was allegedly caught pumping water from a public hydrant in Thousand Oaks then transporting it back to his home, according to a lawsuit filed by the Calleguas Municipal Water District. The agency hired a private detective, who claims to have observed the actor's vehicle being filled with water.
But the Ventura County Sheriff's Department told NBC News the agency investigated the allegations and could find no criminal wrongdoing. A sheriff's department official did not provide details about the investigation, but said the agency looked into the accusations.
"We are unable to establish a crime was committed," said Capt. John Riley.
Top Celeb Pics: Foo Fighters
The case remains a civil matter being handled by the local water district. The Ventura County District Attorney's office confirmed to NBC News that no case had been referred to them for criminal prosecution.
It is claimed Selleck was sent numerous cease and desist orders. The district claims the 70-year-old's truck was pumping public water and taking it to his property a few months ago, according to the lawsuit.
Watch Father and Daughter's Intense Beatboxing Battle
The district claims that between September 2013 and March, the vehicle was seen taking water from a public hydrant back to Selleck's property. The district claims the truck was seen taking water to Selleck's property at least 12 times.
The water district is suing Selleck in the amount of $21,685.55, the cost of the private investigator it hired, and also asking Selleck to stop taking its public water, according to court documents.
Dramatic Photos of California's Drought
Selleck, the actor's wife Jillie and 50 other people, who are listed as John Does, are named as defendants in the lawsuit.
Selleck was contacted regarding the claims, but has yet to make any comment.
NBC News' Andrew Blankstein contibuted to this report.
Published at 6:01 AM PDT on Jul 8, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:58:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man, Adult Son Aboard Cessna That Collided With F-16</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f2f661/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbody0Epassenger0Eaboard0Ecessna0Ecollided0Ef0E160Erecovered0En388731/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The two victims aboard the Cessna C150 were identified as pilot Joseph Johnson, 30, and his father, Michael Johnson, 68.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_f16_crash_animation_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A man and his adult son were aboard a small private plane that was wrecked Tuesday after it collided midair with an F-16 fighter jet over South Carolina, officials said.
Officials have recovered the body of Michael Johnson, the 68-year-old passenger, Berkeley County Rescue Squad Chief Bill Salisbury said at a news conference Wednesday. Authorities are still searching for the body of his son, Joseph Johnson, the 30-year-old pilot of the Cessna 150.
The elder Johnson's body was found in a river near the crash site in the rural town of Moncks Corner, Salisbury said.
Related: Two Killed After Cessna Collides With F-16: NTSB
He told reporters that dive teams, helicopters and drones were scouring that same vicinity, about 30 miles north of Charleston, where the elder Johnson was found.
"Any case where you involve water recovery of debris is always very difficult," Dennis Diaz, a National Transportation Safety Board air safety investigator, said at a news conference.
North Charleston police assist in a water search in a residential area where an Air Force F-16 fighter aircraft collided with a small Cessna 150 private aircraft in Moncks Corner, South Carolina, on July 7, 2015. RICHARD ELLIS / EPA
The Johnsons had left the Berkeley County Airport in Moncks Corner shortly before 11 a.m. ET Tuesday, officials said. The men were headed for Myrtle Beach for the day.
advertisement
The pilot of the fighter jet  Maj. Aaron Johnson, of the 55th Fighter Squadron at Shaw Air Force Base  managed to eject from the aircraft and parachute safely in a plantation. He was taken to Joint Base Charleston for observation.
Johnson was flying solo, practicing instrument approaches to a military base and was communicating with Charleston air traffic controllers at the time, military officials said.
Debris from the collision was scattered on land and water, including a nearby rice field. Parts of the Cessna were spread out about 2,000 feet in length, Diaz said. There were no reports of injuries on the ground, and only one report of damage to property.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:49:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Startup Plans to Sell First 3D-Printed Cars Next Year</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47f3376d/sc/23/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cbusiness0Cautos0Cstartup0Eplans0Estart0Eselling0Efirst0E3d0Eprinted0Ecars0Enext0Eyear0En388766/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Arizona startup Local Motors plans to get into the automotive industry next year when it launches what it promises will be the world's first 3D-printed car.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Forget making vases, bracelets and other trinkets. Startup Local Motors plans to get into the automotive industry next year when it launches what it promises will be the world's first 3D printed car.
The Arizona-based company plans to build two versions of the ReLoad Redacted vehicle using a design that was submitted as part of a contest by Kevin Lo, an engineer living in Vancouver, Wash. Set to debut during the first quarter of 2016, it will be a low-speed battery-car, or so-called neighborhood electric vehicle, priced between $18,000 and $30,000. A full speed vehicle is set to follow, the company said.
"At Local Motors, we are hell-bent on revolutionizing manufacturing," said John B. Rogers, Jr., CEO and co-founder of Local Motors. "Car manufacturers have been stamping parts the same way for more than 100 years. We now have the technology to make the process and products better and faster by linking the online to the offline through DDM (Direct Digital Manufacturing). This process will create better and safer products, and we are doing exactly that."
Reload Redacted by Local Motors Local Motors
In 3D printing, a laser is used to form various materials, from epoxy resins to powdered titanium, into solid objects, one pixel at a time. The process is relatively slow compared to conventional manufacturing but has the advantage of allowing near endless customization.
advertisement
Local Motors publicly demonstrated its concept at the Detroit Auto Show in January, printing out an entire body on the floor of the Cobo Hall convention center. That prototype, dubbed the Strati, had barely 50 individual parts, beyond the electric powertrain.
Plans for mini-factories
Where a traditional automobile is put together, piece by piece, on an assembly line that can be miles long, snaking through a plant that might cost as much as $1 billion to erect and tool up, Local Motors plans to set up a series of compact facilities a fraction of the size and cost.
"Micro-factories are a great counterpoint because they employ an economy of scope by taking advantage of low-cost tooling and co-creation, resulting in the ability to get products to market faster and in less time while using less capital to find a winning concept," co-founder Rogers explained at the time.
Local Motors has been working with the Oak Ridge National Laboratory on 3D printing, which is also referred to as stereo lithography. And it claims to have tapped into a vast, worldwide network of pioneers, some professional, some amateurs, to work out the kinks in 3D printing. That includes contest winner Lo, who works for Hewlett-Packard on advanced printer systems.
advertisement
Among the judges in the contest was comedian and car fanatic Jay Leno, the former host of NBC's "Tonight Show," who said, "You need something that makes you go 'what's that?'"
While the technology is less expensive and complex than operating an assembly line it also is a lot slower. It currently takes days to print out a car's body. So, were Local Motors ever to envision going large-scale, it might need hundreds or even thousands of 3D printers. However, research is ongoing and some proponents claim they are working on techniques that could increase printer speeds by as much as 500-fold.
The two initial Local Motors models, the ReLoad Swim and Sport will be followed later next year by a 3D printed vehicle homologated - or designed to conform - to meet federal safety standards, the company states.
Meanwhile, it has launched a program it calls LOCO University Vehicles, short for Local Motors Co-Created University Vehicles. Three colleges have already signed up to participate, the University of Michigan, Arizona State University and the University of Nevada at Las Vegas. Several projects will focus on developing an autonomous vehicle.
"Think Uber, but with low-speed, autonomous cars," said Ed Olson, an associate professor of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science at University of Michigan, who leads the project there. "The goal of this program is for us to begin to understanding the challenges of a transportation-on-demand system built around autonomous cars."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
