<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:45:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Despite pressure, Trump 'not going away'</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Despite-pressure-Trump-not-going-away-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Despite being asked to tone down his rhetoric, Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump says he's not going away.</Description>
        <MainBody>Despite pressure, Trump 'not going away'
2015-07-09 23:45
Donald Trump (AP)
Hispanic leaders say GOP must condemn Trump
Washington - Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump says he's not going away.
A day after the Republican National Committee chair asked the reality television star to tone down his rhetoric, Trump's campaign insisted he would not back off his portrayal of Mexican immigrants as criminals.
At the same time, he vowed to file paperwork next week ensuring he would qualify for next month's Republican presidential debate on national television.
"Mr Trump said this is an issue the American people care about, and I'm going to continue to talk about it," Trump campaign manager Corey Lewandowski said on Thursday, recounting a Wednesday conversation between Trump and RNC chair Reince Priebus.
Republican leaders worry that the outspoken businessman is hurting the party's standing with minority voters - particularly the nation's surging Hispanic population - months before voting begins in the 2016 presidential contest.
Trump described Mexican immigrants as "rapists" and "criminals" in his campaign announcement speech last month that prompted various concerned business interests to cut ties with him.
Leading Republicans were slow to condemn his remarks in recent weeks as many hoped their inattention would help him fade from the headlines. It did not.
"Priebus said, 'I'd appreciate it if you could tone down your rhetoric about illegal immigrants coming across border and killing Americans,'" Lewandowski recounted. "Mr Trump said, 'I'm going to continue to talk about illegal immigrants coming across the border.'"
Meanwhile, Lewandowski said Trump would file his personal financial disclosure next week that shows a net worth of $11bn. Such a disclosure is necessary for Republican candidates wishing to participate in the first debate on August 6, according to guidelines released by organisers on Thursday.
"It's very clear that Trump is going to be on the debate stage," Lewandowski said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:30:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | EU ministers disagree on 40 000 refugees</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/EU-ministers-disagree-on-40-000-refugees-20150709</Link>
        <Description>EU ministers have failed to reach agreement on relocating 40 000 refugees who landed in Greece and Italy.</Description>
        <MainBody>EU ministers disagree on 40 000 refugees
2015-07-09 23:30
EU to use drones, subs against migrants
Brussels - European Union ministers failed Thursday to agree on relocating 40 000 of the refugees making risky boat trips from North Africa to Italy and Greece and will try again later this month to broker a deal on how many people each country will accept.
"The debate we've had today has been difficult. It's a very sensitive issue," said Luxembourg Foreign Minister Jean Asselborn, whose country hosted Thursday's ministerial meeting. He said ministers will meet again July 20 to try to reach an agreement.
The stalemate came a day after the UN refugee agency announced that data from Greece, Italy, Malta and Spain showed 137 000 people arriving in those countries between January and June, 83% more than the same time last year. The United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees said 1 867 people died making the crossing, up from 588 a year earlier.
Asselborn said ministers did manage to agree how to distribute 20 000 refugees currently being housed outside Europe, but getting countries to commit to divide up the 40 000 making their way to Greece and Italy over the next two years was a step too far.
"We're not very far from the target but some countries need time to negotiate, time to adjust and that is why today we preferred to defer it to July 20," he said.
The inability to reach an agreement again exposes deep divisions within the EU over how to deal with the huge influx of migrants fleeing conflicts in Syria, Iraq and Africa.
When the EU decided in June to share among members the 40 000 refugees, European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker called it "a very modest effort."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:32:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | FDA peeves calorie-counters</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/FDA-peeves-calorie-counters-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Diners in the United States will have to wait until the end of 2016 to find calorie labels on all chain restaurant menus.</Description>
        <MainBody>Apps aim to help people get fit
Washington - Diners in the United States will have to wait until the end of 2016 to find calorie labels on all chain restaurant menus.
The Food and Drug Administration, a government public health agency, said on Thursday that restaurants and other establishments will now have until December 1 2016, to comply with federal menu labelling rules - one year beyond the original deadline.
FDA said it is extending the deadline after restaurants and other retailers said they needed more time to put the rules in place. The agency said those businesses are in the process of training workers, installing menus and menu boards and developing software and technology for more efficient and specific calorie label displays.
The rules will require restaurants and other establishments that sell prepared foods and have 20 or more locations to post the calorie content of food "clearly and conspicuously" on their menus, menu boards and displays. That includes prepared foods at grocery and convenience stores and in movie theatres, bakeries, coffee shops, pizza delivery stores and amusement parks.
The menus and displays will tell diners that a 2 000-calorie diet is used as the basis for daily nutrition, noting that individual calorie needs may vary. Additional nutritional information beyond calories, including sodium, fat and sugar must be available upon request.
The Obama administration has said menu labelling is just one way to combat obesity, since Americans eat and drink about one-third of their calories away from home.
Congresswoman Rosa DeLauro, a long time menu labelling advocate, criticised the FDA's further delay. She said restaurants and retailers have had enough time.
"Industry is doing everything they can to stonewall implementation of this important public health tool," she said. "We need to make sure consumers have nutrition information available to them when making purchasing decisions."
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:32:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Israel will 'engage' with ICC on war crimes probe</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Israel-will-engage-with-ICC-on-war-crimes-probe-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Israel will "engage" with the International Criminal Court probing alleged war crimes, but only to question the tribunal's right to investigate Palestinian complaints, an official says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Israel will 'engage' with ICC on war crimes probe
2015-07-09 22:32
International Criminal Court in the Hague ( Shutterstock )
'War crimes' likely by both sides in 2014 Gaza war
Jerusalem - Israel will "engage" with the International Criminal Court probing alleged war crimes, but only to question the tribunal's right to investigate Palestinian complaints, an official said on Thursday.
"We've decided to engage with the ICC, the engagement will be limited solely to the question of authority" to deal with Palestine, the official told AFP on condition of anonymity.
The Palestinian Authority last month submitted a first dossier of evidence to the ICC, following a decision by the court's chief prosecutor Fatou Bensouda to launch a preliminary probe.
The probe, ordered in January, was set up to establish whether there was enough evidence for a full-blown war crimes investigation into last year's conflict in the Gaza Strip between Israel and the Palestinian Islamist movement Hamas.
Israel, which has not signed up to the ICC, had rejected Bensouda's "absurd decision" with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu saying the ICC was ignoring "international law and agreements, under which the Palestinians don't have a state".
Netanyahu also noted that Israel's actions were subject to the review of its own legal system.
The Palestinian appeal to the ICC is part of an increased focus on diplomatic manoeuvring following mounting frustration with the lack of progress in creating their own independent state.
A June UN report said both Israel and Palestinian militants may have committed war crimes during the 2014 Gaza conflict.
Bensouda has warned that both sides in the Gaza war could face war crimes charges.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:11:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UN announces humanitarian truce in Yemen</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UN-announces-humanitarian-truce-in-Yemen-20150709</Link>
        <Description>A humanitarian truce is set to go into force in Yemen to allow urgently needed aid to reach civilians in the war-torn country facing the threat of famine, the United Nations says.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN announces humanitarian truce in Yemen
2015-07-09 21:11
(AP)
Ban calls for 2-week ceasefire in Yemen talks
New York - A humanitarian truce will go into force in Yemen on Friday to allow urgently needed aid to reach civilians in the war-torn country facing the threat of famine, the United Nations said.
The pause in fighting will go into effect at 23:59 local time (20:59 GMT) on Friday until the end of Ramadan on July 17.
The announcement came eight days after the United Nations declared Yemen a level-3 humanitarian emergency, the highest on its scale, with nearly half of the country's regions facing a food crisis.
"It is imperative and urgent that humanitarian aid can reach all vulnerable people of Yemen unimpeded and through an unconditional humanitarian pause," UN spokesperson Stephane Dujarric said Thursday.
UN Secretary General Ban Ki-moon has received assurances from the Shi'ite Huthi rebels and other parties that "the pause will be fully respected and that there will be no violations from any combatants under their control", he added.
More than 21.1 million people - over 80% of Yemen's population - are in need of aid, with 13 million facing food shortages.
Access to water has become difficult for 9.4 million people, according to the UN.
Ban had repeatedly called for a humanitarian ceasefire to allow badly needed aid to be delivered to civilians suffering from the air war and the rebel offensives.
Yemen slid deeper into turmoil when a Saudi-led coalition launched air strikes in late March to stop an advance by the Iran-backed Huthi rebels who drove the president into exile.
Saudi Arabia and its Gulf allies are demanding that the Huthis pull back from territory seized in their offensive and that President Abedrabbo Mansour Hadi be restored to power.
Read more on:  un | yemen | aid
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:49:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UK advises British tourists to leave Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UK-advises-British-tourists-to-leave-Tunisia-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Britain has advised its nationals in Tunisia to leave, saying local authorities could not provide "adequate protection" and warning a further terror attack is highly likely.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK advises British tourists to leave Tunisia
2015-07-09 19:49
Pallbearers carry the coffin of Adrian Evans, who was killed in the Tunisia attack. (Joe Giddens, AP)
Over 1 000 detained in Tunisia terror clampdown
London - Britain on Thursday advised its nationals in Tunisia to leave, warning local authorities could not provide "adequate protection" after last month's beach massacre that left 30 Britons dead.
"Although we have had good co-operation from the Tunisian government, including putting in place additional security measures, the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably, reinforcing our view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely," the Foreign Office said.
"On balance, we do not believe the mitigation measures in place provide adequate protection for British tourists in Tunisia at the present time and we have therefore changed our travel advice accordingly."
The Foreign Office had previously advised against travel to certain hotspots, including near the borders with Algeria and Libya, but now urged Britons to keep away from the whole of the country unless they had essential business.
"The FCO advise against all but essential travel to the rest of Tunisia. If you're in Tunisia and you don't have an essential need to remain you should leave by commercial means," the ministry said in online travel advice.
It said that tour operators would be arranging additional flights to bring tourists home from Britain.
The warning comes almost a fortnight after a Tunisian student went on a rampage at a popular beach resort, killing 38 foreign tourists, including 30 Britons. It was Britain's worst terror attack since the 2005 London bombings.
Tunisian President Beji Caid Essebsi on Saturday decreed a state of emergency in the north African country for 30 days, and Prime Minister Habib Essid said on Wednesday that the government feared more attacks.
"We would not have felt obliged to decree the state of emergency if we were not convinced that our country was facing numerous terrorist plans to destabilise the country," he told parliament.
Tunisia stepped up security around tourist sites in the wake of the June 26 shootings, the second attack on tourists there in three months. Both were claimed by the Islamic State group.
The Foreign Office said: "The Tunisian authorities have increased their security measures but have also acknowledged the limitations in their ability to counter the current terrorist threat."
About 20 000 British tourists were on package holidays in Tunisia at the time of the attack, according to ABTA, the country's largest travel association.
Thousands chose to return home after the shooting.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:13:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Iran nuke talks set to bust another deadline</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Iran-nuke-talks-set-to-bust-another-deadline-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Negotiations over Iran's nuclear programme appear set to burst through yet another deadline amid persistent uncertainty and vague pronouncements from participants.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuke talks set to bust another deadline
2015-07-09 19:13
Iran's President Hassan Rouhani (AFP) (AFP)
Iran talks may fail - German source
Vienna - Negotiations over Iran's nuclear programme appeared set to burst through yet another deadline on Thursday amid persistent uncertainty and vague pronouncements from participants.
US Secretary of State John Kerry was due to deliver a statement on the status of the talks, but there was no indication he would announce either success or failure.
After a day of mixed public comments and contradictory reports, diplomats suggested that a breakthrough was not imminent and that the talks would bleed into at least Friday. That would break a midnight Thursday deadline in Washington for the Obama administration to submit an agreement to Congress if it wants to avoid an extended legislative review.
The diplomats spoke on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the ongoing negotiations. If the administration misses the Thursday target, the congressional review period will double from 30 to 60 days, possibly delaying the sanctions relief that the US would have to give to Iran under the terms of an agreement.
The current round of talks has already been extended twice since it started on June 27, as has an interim nuclear accord with Iran that these negotiations are meant to finalise. The interim deal was due to expire on June 30, then July 7 and then Friday. It would have to be renewed a third time if the talks go beyond Friday.
As the talks entered a 13th day in Vienna on Thursday with a flurry of closed-door meetings at the 19th-century palace hosting the negotiations, Iran's President Hassan Rouhani said his nation was preparing for a "post-sanctions" era, suggesting that a deal may be in sight to curb the Iranian nuclear programme in exchange for the lifting of economic sanctions. His foreign minister, meanwhile, opined on Twitter that "with mutual respect, anything [is] possible".
Kerry said in a tweet that he and the others were "continuing to discuss difficult issues" and "working diligently to see if agreement possible".
Earlier, Kerry spoke by phone with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, who is in Russia and voiced optimism, saying he was prepared to return to Vienna.
"On the basis of the principles of gradualism and reciprocity, we have come close to a final agreement, it is within the bounds of the attainable," Lavrov said.
US President Barack Obama has said the United States would walk away from the negotiating table rather than sign a bad deal.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:05:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Hungry Labrador has unusual taste buds</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Hungry-Labrador-has-unusual-taste-buds-20150709</Link>
        <Description>A US vet doing exploratory surgery on a Labrador because it wasn't responding to medicine, has got the surprise of his life.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hungry Labrador has unusual taste buds
2015-07-09 19:05
Tjokkie the discarded dog gets new home
Mare - This hungry US Labrador has some unusual taste buds.
A Pennsylvania veterinarian retrieved 62 hair bands, eight pairs of underwear and a bandage from the dog's stomach during exploratory surgery.
The head technician at Good Shepherd's Veterinary Hospital told a local TV station that the black Lab named Tiki wasn't responding to medicine for vomiting, diarrhoea and a loss of appetite, and X-rays showed a mass in its stomach.
Last week's surgery lasted two hours, and the vet and his technician were shocked at the items that were pulled out.
The dog's owner, Sara Weiss, says Tiki once swallowed a plastic foam dart, but that passed through the dog's system naturally.
Read more on:  us | animals
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:07:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Spain sends aircraft to combat forest fires</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Spain-sends-aircraft-to-combat-forest-fires-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Spain has sent 16 planes and helicopters to combat forest fires aggravated by soaring temperatures.</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain sends aircraft to combat forest fires
2015-07-09 18:07
(Saeed Khan, AFP)
1000s evacuate as wildfires burn in Canada
Madrid - The government has sent 16 water planes and helicopters to help fight five forest fires in different parts of Spain as summer temperatures soar.
The Environment Ministry said on Thursday it sent five planes to combat a blaze near the southern towns of Gualchos and Lujar. Some 500 people have been evacuated from the towns since the fire started on Wednesday.
Planes and helicopters were also sent to help extinguish a fire that has destroyed 2 000 ha of land around the south-central town of Quesada since Sunday.
Firefighters were also trying to extinguish fires that have razed around 1 000 ha in the provinces of southwestern Huelva, northern Huesca and eastern Castellon.
Spain has been in a heat wave for nearly two weeks, with temperatures reaching 40C.
Read more on:  spain | fires
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:07:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Jet Airways plane diverts to Muscat</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Jet-Airways-plane-diverts-to-Muscat-20150709</Link>
        <Description>A Jet Airways flight from Mumbai to Dubai has made an emergency landing in Muscat after a bomb threat.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jet Airways plane diverts to Muscat
2015-07-09 18:07
SAA and Indian airline sign code share
New Delhi - A Jet Airways flight from Mumbai to Dubai made an emergency landing in Muscat on Thursday after a bomb threat, an official said, in the second such incident in two days.
All 54 passengers and seven crew members were evacuated once the plane landed safely in an isolated area at Muscat's international airport, a senior Jet Airways spokesperson told AFP.
"There was a bomb threat on the flight. It was a serious threat prompting the pilot to land at the closest airport," said Manish Kalghatgi.
"All guests and crew disembarked without any incident and were taken to the airport terminal," Kalghatgi said, adding the Omani security agencies were carrying out a search of the aircraft, baggage and cargo.
Jet Airways is one of India's biggest airlines with a fleet of 116 aircraft.
On Tuesday, a Turkish Airlines flight from Bangkok to Istanbul made an emergency landing in New Delhi after a bomb threat was scrawled in lipstick on a bathroom mirror.
It was the third such bomb threat to affect Turkish Airlines this year alone.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:07:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Ku Klux Klan fight to clean highway</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Ku-Klux-Klan-fight-to-clean-highway-20150709</Link>
        <Description>A US court is set to hear arguments over the state of Georgia's refusal to let a Ku Klux Klan group participate in a highway clean-up programme.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ku Klux Klan fight to clean highway
2015-07-09 17:07
The Ku Klux Klan parade through the streets of Tulsa, Oklahoma. (AP Photo)
KKK fights for rights to clean up US road
Atlanta - A US court is set to hear arguments over the state of Georgia's refusal to let a Ku Klux Klan group participate in a highway clean-up programme.
The Georgia KKK group's application for a volunteer road cleaning programme was denied in 2012. The American Civil Liberties Union Foundation sued on the group's behalf, saying its right to free speech was violated.
In November, a judge ruled in the organisation's favor, saying that the state gave the KKK scrutiny not applied to other groups.
The state has appealed and wants the ruling reversed. The Georgia Court of Appeals will take up the case on Thursday.
In denying the application, the state said promoting an organisation with a history of inciting unrest could hurt the state.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:07:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UK child sex abuse stuns judge</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UK-child-sex-abuse-stuns-judge-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Opening a public inquiry the judge says the scale of child sexual abuse has stunned Britain.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK child sex abuse stuns judge
2015-07-09 17:07
Justice Lowell Goddard opened a public inquiry into decades of abuse vowing that "no one, no matter how apparently powerful, will be allowed to obstruct our inquiries." (Home Office/PA via AP)
UK classifies child sex abuse as a national threat
London - Britain has been stunned by revelations about child sexual abuse, a judge said on Thursday, warning that the true scale of the crime may be worse than an official estimate that one in 20 children has been a victim.
Justice Lowell Goddard opened a wide-ranging public inquiry into decades of abuse in Britain's schools, hospitals and other institutions, vowing that "no one, no matter how apparently powerful, will be allowed to obstruct our inquiries."
A dam of official silence around child abuse in Britain began to break after the 2011 death of entertainer Jimmy Savile, when dozens came forward to say he had abused them over decades. Subsequent revelations have implicated everyone from taxi drivers to entertainers, clergy and senior politicians. There have also been claims that police failed to investigate allegations of abuse for decades.
Earlier this year Goddard, a judge from New Zealand, was appointed to investigate how public agencies - including government bodies, police, hospitals, churches and the BBC - handled child-abuse allegations.
Goddard said estimates suggest one child in every 20 in the United Kingdom has been sexually abused but "the true picture may be even worse."
"The sexual abuse of children over successive generations has left permanent scars, not only on the victims, but on society," she said.
The inquiry plans to release its final report in 2020 but Goddard said there will be annual updates starting next year. Victims will be able to testify anonymously and former civil servants will be granted immunity from prosecution under the Official Secrets Act if they disclose official wrongdoing.
While the inquiry doesn't have the power to find people guilty of crimes, Goddard said it will not hesitate to name abusers.
"No one will be immune from scrutiny by virtue of their position," she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:34:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Gaza holding Israelis</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Gaza-holding-Ethiopian-Arab-Israelis-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Two Israeli citizens are being held by Hamas in the Gaza Strip, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gaza holding Israelis
2015-07-09 16:13
A crow sits on a barbwire fence on the Mediterranean sea beach front near Kibbutz Zikim, on the Israel-Gaza border, near where Israeli Avraham Mangisto 'independently' crossed the border fence into the Gaza Strip. (Ariel Schalit, AP)
Hamas alleges mass arrests
Jerusalem - Two Israeli citizens are being held by Hamas in the Gaza Strip, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Thursday, a situation that could lead to demands for a prisoner exchange between Israel and the Islamist militant group.
Hamas, which has been in control of the small coastal territory since 2007 and fought three wars with Israel since then, declined to comment.
"We are working for the return of the two Israelis who crossed the border into Gaza," Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said, confirming information that has been restricted by the Israeli military censor since last September.
"We hold Hamas responsible for their safety."
Israel's defence ministry identified one of those held as Avraham Mengisto, 26, an Israeli of Ethiopian origin. The other is an Israeli Arab who was not named.
The ministry said it believed Mengisto, a resident of Ashkelon, a city close to the Gaza border, had crossed into the coastal territory on foot on September 7 2014. It gave no details on how or when the Israeli Arab had entered the territory.
Mengisto's brother, Ilan, said Avraham was unwell and needed help. In an emotional plea outside the family's apartment in Ashkelon, he called on Hamas to consider his brother's medical state and "release him immediately".
"This is a distressing humanitarian case because my brother is not well," he said. "I ask the Israeli government to bring him home safely and call on the international community to intervene and to bring its influence to bear for his release."
Israel has in the past engaged in prisoner swaps with Hamas, most notably in 2011, when Gilad Shalit, a soldier abducted by militants in a cross-border raid in 2006, was released in exchange for 1 000 Palestinians held in Israeli jails.
No tactical value
Israeli President Reuven Rivlin said the Mengisto family had feared for Avraham's safety before he crossed into Gaza, and that he should not be considered an asset - a reference to his possible use in a prisoner swap.
"Without discussing [medical] details, his family was very worried about him before he left," Rivlin told reporters. "He cannot be considered to hold tactical or strategic value in the struggle between us and Hamas or any other foes."
Gaza is fenced in by Israel to the north and east and by Egypt to the south. To the west it faces the Mediterranean. In some places the fence between Israel and Gaza is only a few metres high, while it is also possible to swim around into Gaza, although the Israeli military closely monitors such activity.
Israeli Defence Minister Moshe Yaalon said this week that Israel was seeking the return of the remains of two soldiers killed during last year's war between Israel and Hamas in Gaza, a separate situation to the missing citizens.
In the 50-day war that ended last August, more than 2 100 Palestinians were killed, most of them civilians. Israel put the number of its dead at 67 soldiers and six civilians.
Israeli air strikes and shelling hammered the densely populated Gaza Strip, causing widespread destruction of homes and schools. Hamas and other militant groups launched thousands of rockets and mortar bombs from Gaza into Israel.
Read more on:  hamas | gaza | israel
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:13:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Bull gets his man</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Bull-gets-his-man-20150709</Link>
        <Description>A burglary suspect in the US running away from deputies has found himself between a bull and barbed wire.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bull gets his man
2015-07-09 16:13
California cops beat horse thief
Arab - Police say a burglary suspect in the state of Alabama was taken into custody after being chased by a bull through a cow pasture.
Sheriff Scott Walls told a local TV station that 26-year-old Brad Lynn Hemby was being sought in connection with a burglary on Wednesday morning.
Walls says Hemby tried fleeing deputies by running through a cow pasture and a bull roaming the land joined the chase. Walls says Hemby eventually fell onto a barbed wire fence and surrendered.
Walls says stolen property was recovered from Hemby's truck and the man is charged with burglary, theft and attempting to elude.
Read more on:  us | animals
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:20:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Top Tibetan monk faces India money-laundering charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Top-Tibetan-monk-faces-India-money-laundering-charges-20150709</Link>
        <Description>A top Tibetan monk who is seen as a potential successor to the Dalai Lama is to be prosecuted for money-laundering after an Indian court overturned a decision to drop charges, police say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Top Tibetan monk faces India money-laundering charges
2015-07-09 15:20
China accuses Dalai Lama of inciting self-immolations
New Delhi - A top Tibetan monk who is seen as a potential successor to the Dalai Lama is to be prosecuted for money-laundering after an Indian court overturned a decision to drop charges, police said on Thursday.
At a hearing on Wednesday at the Himachal Pradesh High Court, a judge issued an order for authorities to open criminal proceedings against Karmapa Urgyen Trinley over the recovery of around $1m in foreign currency during a raid on his Buddhist monastery four years ago.
Although criminal conspiracy charges were filed in the aftermath of the raid, a district court had dismissed the case in 2012 in a verdict that was later appealed and the subject of Wednesday's hearing.
"The impugned order of May 21, 2012, passed by the judicial magistrate of Una is quashed and dismissed," Judge Sureshwar Thakur said in his judgement, a copy which has been obtained by AFP.
Local police chief Anupam Sharma confirmed that the first step in bringing a prosecution had begun.
"We have already filed a chargesheet in the court against him," Sharma told AFP, meaning that police have filed an outline of the evidence against the accused with the court.
His holiness the Karmapa Urgyen Trinley Dorje pic.twitter.com/FxQxUpMDLf
 The silent mind (@TheSilentBuddha) May 7, 2013
The case dates back to a raid in January 2011 on a monastery in the Himalayan town of Dharamshala in which investigators say stacks of bank notes from 26 different currencies were recovered, including more than $100 000 worth of Chinese yuan.
The raid came after two people were pulled over by police in a car containing large amounts of cash. During interrogations, the pair said the money was meant for a land deal involving a trust headed by Trinley.
The 30-year-old Trinley has denied any wrongdoing, saying the bank notes found in the monastery were donations from devotees which had accumulated over the years and that he had no involvement in the land deal.
The monk is revered by followers as the 17th incarnation of the head of the Karma Kagyu lineage, one of the four major schools of Tibetan Buddhism.
He fled Tibet at the turn of the century at the age of 14, reaching India after an eight-day journey by foot and horseback over the Himalayas.
Since fleeing, he has mainly lived at the Gyuto Monastery in Dharamshala, the northern Indian hill station that is the seat of the Tibetan government in exile.
Trinley is recognised by both China and the Dalai Lama as the reincarnation of the Karmapa Lama, head of the Karma Kagyu lineage, one of Tibetan Buddhism's four major schools.
He is seen as as having the highest profile of a cast of young lamas who could succeed the Dalai Lama who has just turned 80.
His appearances with the Dalai Lama have fuelled speculation he is being groomed as the Nobel peace laureate's spiritual successor.
His spokesman Kunzang Chungyalpa said Trinley has great faith in India's judicial system.
"He strongly believes truth will prevail at the end," he told AFP.
Read more on:  india | tibet
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:25:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | India's top court orders investigation into job scam, deaths</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Indias-top-court-orders-investigation-into-job-scam-deaths-20150709</Link>
        <Description>India's top court has ordered a federal investigation into a multimillion-dollar college admission and government job recruitment scandal said to be linked to dozens of mysterious deaths.</Description>
        <MainBody>India's top court orders investigation into job scam, deaths
2015-07-09 14:25
(Shutterstock)
India school head beaten to death by angry mob
New Delhi - India's top court Thursday ordered a federal investigation into a multimillion-dollar college admission and government job recruitment scandal in central India said to be linked to dozens of mysterious deaths.
The Supreme Court ordered the Central Bureau of Investigation, India's FBI, to investigate the alleged irregularities in job recruitment and college admissions as well as the deaths of nearly 50 people associated with the scam.
Police have arrested hundreds of officials for allegedly rigging eligibility tests for admission to medical colleges and recruitment for jobs in the police force, schools and banking sector in Madhya Pradesh state.
'Vyapam scandal'
Opposition Congress party leaders had been demanding a federal inquiry into the scandal as dozens of people, either witnesses or accused participants in the scam, have died over the last five years in inexplicable circumstances. Congress leaders have alleged that some top state bureaucrats and politicians accepted millions of dollars in bribes to facilitate the admissions.
The scandal has come to be known in India as the "Vyapam scandal," after the Hindi language acronym for the state-run employment agency in Madhya Pradesh. For the past couple of weeks, India media have given wide coverage to the sudden deaths of a number of people connected to the scam.
The scandal hit the front pages of newspapers once again last weekend after the death of an investigative journalist who had gone to Madhya Pradesh to speak with witnesses.
The following day, the body of a medical college dean was found in a New Delhi hotel. The official headed a medical college in Madhya Pradesh that was involved in the admissions scandal.
The scam dates to 2007, but investigations began only in 2013 after details emerged that many unqualified and undeserving candidates had been admitted into medical and engineering colleges.
Read more on:  india | fraud
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:25:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Myanmar joins chemical weapons organisation</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Myanmar-joins-chemical-weapons-organisation-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Myanmar has ratified the chemical weapons convention and will become the 192st member of the Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons, the body says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Myanmar joins chemical weapons organisation
2015-07-09 14:25
File: AP
Iraqi army retakes chemical weapons site from ISIS
Amsterdam - Myanmar has ratified the chemical weapons convention and will become the 191st member of the Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons, the body said on Thursday, another step in a rapid period of reform for the Asian country.
Myanmar's membership takes effect within 30 day, leaving just Angola, Egypt, Israel, North Korea and South Sudan as countries not to have joined.
"Myanmar is committed to fulfilling its obligations under the convention and looks forward to co-operating with other states parties to bring about a world completely free of chemical weapons," Myanmar's Foreign Minister Wunna Maung Lwin said in a statement.
Myanmar has undergone major changes since shifting to a quasi-civilian system in 2011, although it is now seeing tensions between rival forces vying for power.
The OPCW won the Nobel Peace prize in 2013 for its work in the wake of efforts to rid Syria of its chemical weapons stockpile.
Read more on:  myanmar
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:25:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Israeli held in Gaza is not in good health - brother</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Israeli-held-in-Gaza-is-not-in-good-health-brother-20150709</Link>
        <Description>A brother of an Israeli citizen held in the Gaza Strip is calling on the international community to exert pressure to lead to his release.</Description>
        <MainBody>Israeli held in Gaza is not in good health - brother
2015-07-09 13:25
A crow sits on a barbwire fence on the Mediterranean sea beach front near Kibbutz Zikim, on the Israel-Gaza border, near where Israeli Avraham Mangisto 'independently' crossed the border fence into the Gaza Strip. (Ariel Schalit, AP)
Netanyahu loses parliament vote for first time
Jerusalem - A brother of an Israeli citizen held in the Gaza Strip is calling on the international community to exert pressure to lead to his release.
Ilan Mangisto said at a news conference on Thursday that his brother Avraham Mangisto is not in the best of health. He called the situation "a difficult humanitarian matter".
Ilan Mangisto did not elaborate on the health issue, but Israeli Channel 2 TV cited the family as saying that Avraham Mangisto was depressed following the death of his brother.
Authorities say Avraham Mangisto walked through a breach in the border fence between Israel and Gaza last September and is believed to be held by the militant group Hamas, which rules the territory.
Israeli defense officials say an Arab-Israeli citizen being held in the Gaza Strip is a Bedouin man from Israel's Negev desert.
Officials refused to say how long he has been held in Gaza or how he got there. They also would not say which group had him in custody.
Bedouin make up a small group within Israel's Arab minority, numbering about 180 000.
Israeli authorities said Thursday that two of its citizens are being held in the Gaza Strip. The other is an Israeli Ethiopian man who crossed into the Palestinian territory last September and is believed held by the Hamas militant group which rules Gaza.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:25:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Bill Clinton to lead US delegation to Srebrenica</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Bill-Clinton-to-lead-US-delegation-to-Srebrenica-20150709</Link>
        <Description>Former US president Bill Clinton will visit Srebrenica for a commemoration, marking the 20th anniversary of the mass murder of 8 000 Muslim men and boys by Bosnian Serb forces.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bill Clinton to lead US delegation to Srebrenica
2015-07-09 13:25
(File, AFP) (AFP)
Bill Clinton hopes to keep working, whatever Hillary does
Washington - Former US president Bill Clinton will visit Srebrenica for a commemoration on Saturday marking the 20th anniversary of the mass murder of 8 000 Muslim men and boys by Bosnian Serb forces.
Clinton, US president from 1993 to 2001, will head a US presidential delegation, the White House said in a statement on Wednesday.
Earlier, Russia vetoed a draft UN resolution that would have recognised the Srebrenica massacre as genocide, saying it unfairly singled out Bosnian Serbs for war crimes.
Bosnian Serb forces led by Ratko Mladic overran the UN-protected safe haven of Srebrenica on 11 July, 1995 in what was to become one of the darkest chapters of the 1992-95 Bosnian war.
Mladic's troops brushed aside the lightly armed Dutch UN peacekeepers and loaded thousands of Muslim men and boys onto trucks before executing them in a nearby forest and burying them in mass graves.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
