<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="NEWS">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK girl charged in Anzac terror plot</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/national/crime/british-teenager-charged-in-anzac-day-terror-plot/story-fns0kb1g-1227436250569?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>A SECOND British teen has been charged for her role in an alleged Islamic State-inspired terrorist plot to attack an Anzac Day event in Melbourne.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Stopped alleged attack ... Police removing items from a house after a raid in Melbourne. Picture: Alex Coppel Source: News Corp Australia
A 16-YEAR-OLD girl has been charged with two terror offences in northern England in a case linked to a 15-year-old boy accused of inciting a man to commit a terror attack at an Anzac event in Melbourne.
The teenage girl, who cannot be named for legal reasons, was charged by counterterrorism police after a warrant was executed at a house in Manchester on April 3.
She is accused of two offences under the UKs Terrorism Act 2000 and will appear before Westminster Magistrates Court in London on July 22.
Police were led to the girl after investigating a teenage boy from Blackburn in Lancashire, who was held on April 2 in connection with a terrorist plot in Australia, after examination of a number of electronic devices.
British counterterrorism officers said they had uncovered communications between the UK and Australia representing a credible terrorist threat.
Police in Melbourne arrested five suspects in what they said was an operation to foil an Islamic State-inspired plot to attack an Anzac Day event.
The girl from Manchester has been charged with collecting or making a record of information likely to be useful to a person committing or preparing for an act of terrorism or possessing a document or record containing information of that kind.
The 15-year-old boy from Blackburn has appeared at the Old Bailey in London charged with inciting a terror attack in Melbourne.
His four-week trial is scheduled to begin on August 17 in Manchester.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mystery illness paralysing children</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/search-is-on-for-the-cause-of-an-outbreak-of-paralysis-among-children-in-the-united-states/story-fnet08ui-1227433582607?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>A NEW disease starting as a cold but ending as paralysis is afflicting young people in the US. Does polio have a twin? Or is a new debilitating virus to blame?</Description>
        <MainBody>Researchers at Purdue University have found a new polio-like virus that is causing paralysis in kids in the US. Courtesy: YouTube/Purdue University
News Corp Australia
08 Jul 2015
Technology
Every parents nightmare ... A new virus in the United States afflicts children with what appears to be the common cold  but can turn into paralysis. Source: Thinkstock Source: ThinkStock
A MYSTERIOUS new disease is afflicting children in the United States. It starts as a cold  but ends as weakness and paralysis. Does polio have a twin? Or are several new, potentially debilitating, viruses on the loose?
In the past 12 months, more than 118 children across 34 US states have been reported with a condition called acute flaccid myelitis.
Its a condition that seems to start out as a respiratory infection like a serous bout of the common cold.
In these cases the muscle pain doesnt go away. Then they lose their strength in their arms and legs.
While such symptoms are enough to panic any parent, disease experts say the cause does not appear to be particularly infectious.
But the number of cases seeking hospitalisation in the US has raised eyebrows.
Early suspicions have fallen on the viruses which belong to the family we know as the common cold, the rhinoviruses.
Why Do Viruses Kill? 51:48
From Swine Flu to SARS, Rabies to HIV, the number of dangerous viruses is increasing at an alarming rate so find out the truth about nature's greatest terror weapon.
Oovvuu
18 Jun 2015
TV/Science TV/Health TV/Documentary
The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) have named enterovirus D68 (EV-D68) as the chief suspect.
But new figures show only 20 per cent of the known cases in the US tested positive for D68  and it isnt certain if this virus is linked to the paralysis anyway.
But it is a big family of viruses, says infectious disease expert Associate Professor Sanjaya Senanayake of the Australian National University . Within that family you can get a virus that is more serious, and every so often we see large numbers of people being infected with a nasty virus which can do anything from not even making you sick through to the other extreme where they get brain type infections and can even effect the nerves and cause paralysis.
D68  a little active virus first diagnosed in California more than 50 years ago  may soon be let off the hook.
A new study of one paralysis sufferer has narrowed down another contender.
Horrors of polio ... patients were treated in iron lungs, isolated from their families because of fears of infection. Source: Supplied
PATIENT ZERO
Dr Ronald Turner of the University of Virginia has published a report on an otherwise healthy six-year-old girl who, her family thought, had simply caught the common cold.
Last year she developed a fever. But that and other cold symptoms cleared up as usual.
But her aching limbs remained.
Her shoulders began to droop.
After two weeks, she began having difficulty using her right hand.
According to the study to be published in the October 2015 edition of the journal Emerging Infectious Diseases , she was taken to the University of Virginia Childrens Hospital.
She did not have the D68 virus.
After proving unresponsive to treatments, she tested positive for a new virus  C105.
Its a recently discovered virus belonging to the same lineage as polio.
It is the first recorded case in the United States of a virus only identified within the past five years.
Eight months later, the paralysis victim has reportedly almost fully recovered her strength.
EMERGENT STRAIN
Enterovirus C105 is something new. It was first detected in patients from Peru and the Republic of Congo in 2010. The Congo case also suffered paralysis.
Its now thought to be circulating worldwide.
Dr Turner says his six-year-old patient may simply be the first known case in the US because the C105 virus is particularly hard to detect.
Dr Senanayake says its ties to polio makes guilt by association understandable.
What makes the polio virus different  and deadly  is that it is highly contagious. A century ago, polio paralysed hundreds of thousands of children every year. But it infected many more.
This is one group of infections were always aware of and keeping an eye on as enteroviruses are always circulating, Dr Senanayake says. Viral meningitis  the inflammation of the brain and spinal cord  is most commonly caused by an enterovirus.
Race against time ... scientists are attempting to track down the cause of the worrying outbreak. Source: Getty Images
But there is still a considerable body of research needed before C105 can be identified as the disease behind the new paralysis outbreak.
Magnetic resonance imaging of the six-year-old girl showed abnormal hyperintensity in her spinal column. But tests of her spinal fluid have so far not detected the presence of C105 there.
The potential remains for it to be a third, as yet unidentified, virus that just happens to be co-infecting victims at the same time as C105 and D68.
Or it could be linked to all of them.
Sometimes our immune system can be a bit overactive and cause problems, Dr Senanayake says. With these recent cases of paralysis in these children, theyve never found a virus in the spinal fluid. So one thought has been could it be that the virus has caused an infection elsewhere in the body and the immune system has got excited about that and ended up causing some damage to the nerves.
In this outbreak, the cause  whatever it may be  is not showing any signs of becoming a pandemic.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>This man just sent his dad to jail for life</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/north-america/son-finally-gets-justice-for-his-mum-after-his-dad-is-sentenced-to-15-years-jail-for-her-murder/story-fnh81jut-1227436087320?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>HE knew his mother hadn&amp;#8217;t committed suicide, as police originally ruled. So he spent four years and his entire inheritance to put her killer behind bars.</Description>
        <MainBody>Paediatrician John Wall was convicted of killing his cancer researcher ex-wife amid a bitter custody dispute and sentenced to 15 years-to-life in prison by a Salt Lake City court. Courtesy FOX Thirteen News
News Corp Australia
10 Jul 2015
News
Convicted ... John Brickman Wall, a Salt Lake City pediatrician, has been sentenced to at least 15 years jail for the murder of his ex-wife. Picture: AP Photo/Rick Bowmer Source: AP
THE eldest son of a Utah doctor smiled as he shook hands and hugged friends and family after his father was sentenced to 15 years to life in the killing of his ex-wife and escorted out of court in handcuffs.
The sentencing of John Brickman Wall closed another chapter in a long, painful journey of 21-year-old Pelle Wall, who was instrumental in pushing police to investigate his father even after the 2011 death of his mother, university cancer researcher Uta von Schwedler, was initially ruled a suicide.
Elated ... Pelle Wall was instrumental in pushing police to investigate his father even after the 2011 death of his mother was ruled a suicide. Picture: AP Photo/Rick Bowmer Source: AP
Pelle Wall spoke during Wednesdays sentencing hearing, asking state Judge James Blanch to make sure his father, a Salt Lake City paediatrician, spent the rest of his life behind bars.
He said his fathers portrayal of himself as the victim was despicable and has profoundly compounded the grief he and his three siblings are feeling.
Hes convinced himself of an alternate reality, Pelle Wall said outside court in Salt Lake City. Its super disrespectful to true victims. I cant reconcile it.
Speaking out ... John Brickman Wall, right, looks on while his son Pelle Wall speaks during a hearing. Picture: AP Photo/Rick Bowmer Source: AP
John Wall, 51, spoke before the packed courtroom saying emphatically, I did not kill Uta.
He vowed to appeal the conviction.
He lamented that his four children have lost their mother and father, and said he hopes they know he loves them unconditionally.
I can no longer assist them and support them in achieving their hopes and dreams. Nor can I comfort them in their times of need, said Wall, wearing a blue prison jumpsuit. Im left with only my memories.
Pelle Wall, the only sibling in court, said he wasnt buying his fathers speech. He said, I dont know how he could have committed such a crime with any of his children in mind.
Tragic loss ... mother Uta von Schwedler was a university cancer researcher. Picture: Facebook/Uta von Schwedlers Memorial Page Source: Supplied
The sentencing came after Blanch denied motions from John Walls lawyer to overturn the conviction on evidentiary issues. Blanch said he took note of Wall claiming his innocence but said the jury had found a chilling and despicable crime.
A jury convicted Wall in March after hearing a largely circumstantial case in which prosecutors said he attacked von Schwedler with a knife, gave her the anti-anxiety drug Xanax and drowned her in her bathtub.
Defence attorneys countered that the theory was unbelievable, and it was more likely that von Schwedler killed herself.
On Wednesday, lawyer G. Fred Metos said prosecutors relied on a pyramid of inferences and multiple pieces of circumstantial evidence to make their case against Wall.
Pelle Wall is the eldest of John Brickman Walls four children. Picture: AP Photo/Rick Bowmer Source: AFP
John Brickman Wall was convicted of killing his cancer researcher ex-wife amid a bitter custody dispute. Picture: AP Photo/Rick Bowmer Source: AP
In the lead-up to sentencing, Wall, his siblings and parents sent Blanch letters defending his character.
Wall said people around him misinterpreted his confused state as guilt when he was actually dealing with grief and psychological trauma from police interrogation.
His sister, Wendy Wall, said the man depicted during the trial bears little resemblance to the brother she knows. She said he was a loving, doting father who wasnt violent.
She was in court along with other family but left without making comment.
Relief ... Pelle Wall hugs a supporter after leaving the courtroom following his fathers sentencing. Picture: AP Photo/Rick Bowmer Source: AP
Pelle Wall remembered his mother, who died at 49, as a highly respected researcher who was driven and self-confident but also colourful, playful and goofy. He said he and his siblings still find themselves leaning on the lessons she taught them and miss her dearly.
He said hes convinced of his fathers guilt because he knows him well, and observed his interactions with his mother during a messy divorce and custody battle.
He told CBS in May this year that his lengthy campaign to see his father tried has cost him emotionally and financially.
Its essentially my entire inheritance from my mother, he said.
Pelle Wall told reporters on Wednesday that hes seen and heard all the evidence against his father gathered by authorities.
It all comes together and it all points to the same thing, Pelle Wall said. That is that hes guilty.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>‘Jewel’ under world’s busiest city</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-ideas/old-city-hall-station-the-jewel-in-the-crown-buried-underneath-new-york-city/story-fnjpj945-1227436031416?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>IT WAS designed as a showpiece, dubbed a &amp;#8216;jewel&amp;#8217;. Now thousands pass this time capsule every day, completely clueless.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Hardly touched: The Old City Hall subway station. Picture: Metropolitan Transportation Authority / Patrick Cashin Source: Supplied
IT WAS designed to be the showpiece of New York Citys first subway system, dubbed the jewel in the crown, yet thousands of people walk above this beautiful time capsule every day, clueless about its existence.
New Yorks first ever train station, City Hall, is buried underneath the citys oldest government building, but since its closure in 1945, few have walked along the stations elegant platform or glanced their eyes upon its breathtaking design.
Opened on October 27, 1904, New York Citys debut route  dubbed the Manhattan Main Line  began at City Hall and travelled north to Grand Central Terminal, through Times Square and up to 145th Street.
At its peak, City Hall station was the flagship of the Interborough Rapid Transit Companys subway line. Picture: Metropolitan Transportation Authority / Patrick Cashin Source: Supplied
Fittingly, Mayor George B. McClellan christened the first train using a Tiffany silver controller. Now thats class.
The night took on a carnival atmosphere, like New Years Eve, writes Clifton Hood in his book, 722 Miles: The Building of the Subways and how they transformed New York.
New York's subway in 1949 3:32
What it was like to take a ride on New Yorks subway system in 1949. Courtesy MTA
News Corp Australia
10 Jul 2015
News
Many couples celebrated in style by putting on their best clothes, going out to dinner, and then taking their first subway ride together.
Some people spent the entire evening on the trains, going back and forth from 145th street to City Hall for hours. Revelling in the sheer novelty of the underground, these riders wanted to soak up its unfamiliar sights and sensations for as long as possible.
Financiers, city officials, and policemen ride New York City's first subway on October 27, 1904 at City Hall station. Seated toward the front of the ceremonial flat car were Alexander Orr, August Belmont II, John B. McDonald, and Mayor George B. McClellan. Picture: Corbis Source: Corbis
The original plans for City Hall Station. Source: Supplied
Architects George Lewis Heins and Christopher Grant LaFarge designed an extravagant reflection of the City Beautiful movement, a time when graceful, uplifting urban settings reflected the civility of a society, and, in turn, helped to strengthen the communitys moral and cultural environment, according to the New York Transit Museum.
Brass chandeliers adorn the tiled, arched, antique ceiling, while on sunny days, natural light floods the space through glass skylights. Oak furnishings and glazed plaques inscribed with City Hall rest barely untouched today.
So intricate is the detail, its light bulbs were designed with treads in the reverse direction to prevent theft.
The station owes its breathtaking design to architects George Lewis Heins and Christopher Grant LaFarge. Picture: Metropolitan Transportation Authority / Patrick Cashin Source: Supplied
The station, which operated from 1904 to 1945, is often referred to as "the jewel in the crown,". Picture: Metropolitan Transportation Authority / Marc Hermann Source: Supplied
Yet in the 1940s, as more subway stations were built, City Hall came to a grinding halt, failing to match the standards of newer stops that could hold more commuters and accommodate longer trains.
Passenger numbers dwindled, and with the bigger and better Brooklyn Bridge station close by, officials deemed City Hall a thorn in the subways side, and closed it to the public on December 31, 1945.
It was the end of form over function.
The station soon became obsolete and is no longer in service. Picture:  Metropolitan Transportation Authority / Marc Hermann Source: Supplied
These days, the station rests entombed underneath City Hall, and visitors have few opportunities to see the site for themselves. But there are ways .
If you have the money to spend, visitors can sign up to become a member of the New York City Transit Museum and purchase tickets for a Jewel in the Crown: Old City Hall Station members-only tour.
The Museum only offers around two tours a month, with tickets released seasonally. Thats approximately eight tours per season. The next round of tickets will go on sale in mid-August. Tour dates, times and the on-sale date are released in the e-newsletter .
But youve got to be quick. When tickets go on sale, the entire season generally sells out within an hour.
Tour tickets to the Old City Hall Station and other tours are available for purchase here .
The original architects of this space designed the Cathedral of St. John the Divine. Picture: Metropolitan Transportation Authority / Marc Hermann Source: Supplied
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mum trapped by dead boyfriend</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/europe/woman-lay-next-to-boyfriends-dead-body-for-three-days-in-crashed-car-before-police-arrived/story-fnh81p7g-1227436065629?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>A MOTHER critically injured in a car crash spent three days waiting with her boyfriend&amp;#8217;s dead body for help to arrive.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Heartbreaking ... mum-of-two Lamara Bell is fighting for her life after a car crash in Scotland. Picture: Facebook/Lamara Bell Source: Supplied
A 25-YEAR-OLD mother critically injured in a car crash in Scotland spent three days waiting with the dead body of her boyfriend for help to arrive.
Lamara Bells father accused police of ignoring his daughter after officers admitted they had received a report of the crash on Sunday but failed to act.
The couple and their car were found by a motorway near the town of Stirling on Wednesday.
Father-of-two John Yuill, 28, was pronounced dead at the scene while Bell is in a critical condition in hospital, police said.
John Yuill, 28, died at the crash scene. Picture: Facebook/John Yuill Source: Supplied
Lamara Bell, 25, is in a critical condition in hospital. Picture: Facebook/Lamara Bell Source: Supplied
Bells father Ossie Dinnefash wrote on Facebook: Lamara was in a field for three days after the accident. She was on her way home. Because of some nice guy that phoned it in and was ignored by the incident room the messages were never passed on. Now my daughter is laying on life support.
When rescued, Bell told firefighters she thought she had lain in the wreckage for just 30 minutes. She has two daughters.
Furious ... Tamara Bells dad Ossie Dinnefash shared a message on Facebook. Picture: Facebook/Ossie Dinnefash Source: Supplied
Yuills father Gordon told the Daily Record newspaper that his son could not have been saved but said the delay may have an impact on the health of his girlfriend.
His injuries were such that he died on impact. But I feel it may have made a difference for Lamara. My heart goes out to her family for that, he said.
Public appeal ... John Yuills dad Gordon Yuill put out an appeal on Facebook for the missing pair. Picture: Facebook/Gordon Yuill Source: Supplied
In the days before they were found, the young couple had been reported missing.
The Police Scotland force said it had launched an investigation into why it did not act on the original report.
It has come to light that a call was made to police late on Sunday morning regarding a car which was reported as being off the road, it said in a statement.
For reasons currently being investigated, that report was not followed up at the time.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kim Jong-un’s bloodiest move yet</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/asia/kim-jong-un-has-reportedly-executed-70-officials-since-becoming-leader/story-fnh81fz8-1227435984173?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>NORTH Korean leader Kim Jong-un is thought to have surpassed his father with his reign of terror in the latest move reported by South Korean authorities.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Kim Jong-un is thought to have surpassed his fathers record for the deadliest reign. Source: AFP
NORTH Korean leader Kim Jong-un has managed to smash his fathers record as the countrys most brutal dictator by executing more people in his first few years in the top job.
Thats according to South Korean authorities who say the North Korean leader has executed 70 officials since taking power in late 2011 in a reign of terror that far exceeds the bloodshed of his father.
During a forum in Seoul this week, South Korean Foreign Minister Yun Byung-se said Kim Jong-il, Kim Jong-uns father, had only executed about 10 officials during his first years in power.
An official from South Koreas National Intelligence Service, who refused to be named, confirmed the spy agency believed the younger Kim has ordered the deaths of around 70 officials but wouldnt reveal how it obtained the information.
North Korea, an authoritarian nation ruled by the Kim family since its founding in 1948, is secretive about its governments inner workings, and information collected by outsiders is often impossible to confirm.
Kim Jong-un looking serious. This must have been before he found out he beat his fathers record for the most executions during his first few years as leader. Source: AFP
High-level government purges have a long history in North Korea.
To strengthen his power, Kim Jong-uns grandfather, North Korea founder Kim Il-Sung, removed pro-Soviet and pro-Chinese factions within the senior leadership in the years after the 1950-53 Korean War.
The high-ranking victims included Pak Hon Yong, formerly the vice chairman of the ruling Workers Party of Korea and the countrys foreign minister, who was executed in 1955 after being accused of spying for the US.
Kim Jong-un has also removed key members of the old guard through a series of purges since taking over after the death of Kim Jong-il.
The most spectacular purge to date was the 2013 execution of his uncle, Jang Song Thaek, for alleged treason.
Jang was married to Kim Jong-ils sister and was once considered the second most powerful man in North Korea.
South Koreas spy agency claimed that in May, Kim ordered his then-defence chief Hyon Yong Chol executed with an anti-aircraft gun for complaining about the young ruler, talking back to him and sleeping during a meeting.
Experts say Kim Jong-un could be using fear to solidify his leadership, but those efforts could fail if he doesnt improve the countrys shattered economy.
Kim Jong-un's aunt dies after argument with the dictator 1:05
The aunt of North Korean tyrant Kim Jong-un suffered a fatal stroke during a heated phone call with the dictator, just days after he executed her husband, according to a highly placed defector.
news.com.au
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia blocks MH17 tribunal</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/russia-confirms-it-opposes-mh17-tribunal/story-fnizu68q-1227436115398?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>RUSSIA has promised to fight a UN resolution to establish a tribunal that would prosecute whoever shot down MH17 over Ukraine last year, killing 298 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>THERE are islands here that are more than a billion years old, and they are actually the tips of ancient mountains. Here, its like time stood still.
Travel Updates
Russia confirms it opposes MH17 tribunal
by:
Play video
The Russian investigative committee released the name of a man in Moscow on Wednesday who is allegedly a key witness to the MH17 crash in Donetsk. The name was announced by the official representative of the 'Investigative Committee of the Russian Federation' Vladimir Markin. Evgeni Agapov, a military mechanic in the Ukrainian Air Force, is reportedly under Russian state protection after he volunteered to cooperate on the plane crash that killed 298 people. According to Agapov, a Ukrainian Sukhoi Su-25 aircraft left its base for a mission and later returned without ammunition on July 17, 2014, the day the MH17 flight was brought down. The committee decided to release the name of the witness to give his account more credibility. On Tuesday the corporation Almaz Antei, the Russian maker of the Buk air defense missile system, stated that its own investigators have concluded the Malaysian Airlines flight 17 was downed by an old missile version which is not used in Russia any more, but is in service in Ukraine. Opponents of this theory accuse Russian militia fighters in Ukraine of deploying the missile - a claim Russia has always strongly denied.
Rightster
04 Jun 2015
News/World
Wreckage ... a man looks at the wreckage of passenger plane Malaysia Airlines flight MH17 on July 18, 2014 in Grabovka, Ukraine. Picture: Brendan Hoffman/Getty Images Source: Getty Images
RUSSIA says it will oppose a draft UN resolution circulated by Malaysia on establishing an international tribunal to prosecute those behind the downing of Flight MH17 over Ukraine.
Deputy UN Ambassador Petr Iliichev on Thursday confirmed Moscows opposition to the plan, saying: Its not a good time and its counterproductive.
Asked whether Russia would push against the proposal, Iliichev responded, Yes.
A day earlier, Malaysia had circulated the draft Security Council resolution.
It says a UN tribunal would guarantee an independent trial for those behind the downing of the Malaysia Airlines plane on July 17, 2014.
Wreckage ... a man looks at debris from an Malaysia Airlines plane crash in Grabovka, Ukraine in 2014. Picture: Brendan Hoffman/Getty Images Source: Getty Images
The text, obtained by AFP, calls for establishing the tribunal under Chapter Seven of the UN charter, which means that the courts efforts to prosecute those responsible could be enforced by sanctions.
Malaysia is working with Australia, Belgium, the Netherlands and Ukraine  all member countries of the Joint Investigation Team  on setting up the international tribunal.
All 298 passengers and crew on board the Malaysia Airlines flight  including 38 Australian citizens and residents  died when the plane was shot down over eastern Ukraine.
Suspicions immediately turned to pro-Russian separatists who may have used a surface-to-air missile supplied by Russia to down the plane.
Wreckage ... members of a local militia guard access to the wreckage of Malaysia Airlines flight MH17 on July 20, 2014 in Rassipnoye, Ukraine. Picture: Rob Stothard/Getty Images Source: Getty Images
Russia has denied the claim and suggested that a Ukrainian missile may have hit it.
Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte has said the international court is the best option for prosecution but that there is also a back-up plan should the Russians block the proposal.
Last month, Russian deputy foreign minister Gennadiy Gatilov described the proposal as not timely and counterproductive, saying the investigation should be completed before any further steps are taken.
A final report on the Dutch-led probe is expected in October.
Malaysia is working with Australia, Belgium, the Netherlands and Ukraine  all member countries of the Joint Investigation Team  on setting up the international tribunal.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Son gets dad jailed for mum’s murder</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/brekkie-wrap-son-finally-gets-justice-for-his-mum-after-his-dad-is-sentenced-to-15-years-jail-for-her-murder/story-fndir2ev-1227436194514?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>BREKKIE WRAP: A MAN has been jailed for 15 years for killing his ex-wife after his son spent four years and his inheritance to prove it was murder.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Victory ... Pelle Wall smiles after taking his seat in court during his fathers sentencing. Picture: AP Source: AP
THE eldest son of a Utah doctor smiled as he shook hands and hugged friends and family after his father was sentenced to 15 years to life in the killing of his ex-wife and escorted out of court in handcuffs.
The sentencing of John Brickman Wall closed another chapter in a long, painful journey of 21-year-old Pelle Wall, who was instrumental in pushing police to investigate his father even after the 2011 death of his mother, university cancer researcher Uta von Schwedler, was initially ruled a suicide.
Pelle Wall spoke during Wednesdays sentencing hearing, asking state Judge James Blanch to make sure his father, a Salt Lake City paediatrician, spent the rest of his life behind bars.
He said his fathers portrayal of himself as the victim was despicable and has profoundly compounded the grief he and his three siblings are feeling.
Hes convinced himself of an alternate reality, Pelle Wall said outside court in Salt Lake City. Its super disrespectful to true victims. I cant reconcile it.
A jury convicted Wall in March after hearing a largely circumstantial case in which prosecutors said he attacked von Schwedler with a knife, gave her the anti-anxiety drug Xanax and drowned her in her bathtub.
Defence attorneys countered that the theory was unbelievable, and it was more likely that von Schwedler killed herself.
He said hes convinced of his fathers guilt because he knows him well, and observed his interactions with his mother during a messy divorce and custody battle.
Reclining drama ... A passenger did not take kindly to a man in front of him who reclined his chair during a short flight. Picture: Supplied Source: News Limited
IN NATIONAL NEWS
 A PASSENGER reclined his seat on a short flight to Queensland. The man behind him didnt like it and took the situation into his own hands. Now hes paying the price.
 VIRGIN Australia has cancelled all flights from Australia to Denpasar on Friday as ash cloud hovering over Denpasar airport continues to wreak havoc.
 THE most powerful cold front to cross Australias southeast in years will hit this weekend with forecasters warning of freezing conditions.
 A GROUP of workers who claimed they were cheated out of a $16.7m Powerball win have made a secret deal with the man who was accused of taking their money.
 A TRANSGENDER woman allegedly bashed at a Sydney pub last month says she has been threatened by one of her alleged attackers outside court.
Tax and pension reform coming ... Greece made a request for aid from Europes bailout fund as it rushed to deliver details of its proposed economic reforms. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
IN WORLD NEWS
 DESPITE Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsiprass pledge to enact new reform measures many predict the nation will move to a Grexit by weeks end.
 MEANWHILE the International Monetary Fund has cut its global economic growth forecast for this year but it is the US and not Greece that is to blame.
 RUSSIA says it will oppose a draft UN resolution circulated by Malaysia on establishing an international tribunal to prosecute those behind the downing of Flight MH17 over Ukraine.
 A MOTHER critically injured in a car crash spent three days waiting with her boyfriends dead body for help to arrive.
 AFTER a man dressed up as Toy Storys Sheriff Woody was arrested for groping Australian tourists , others have opened up about life inside the costume.
Royal family ... (Back row L-R) Michael Middleton, Pippa Middleton, James Middleton, Carole Middleton, Prince Charles, Camilla, Duchess of Cornwall and the Duke of Edinburgh. (Front row L-R) Prince William, Prince George of Cambridge, Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, Princess Charlotte of Cambridge and Queen Elizabeth II. Picture: Mario Testino Source: Getty Images
IN SHOWBIZ NEWS
 THE first official pictures of Princess Charlottes christening , taken by Dianas favourite photographer Mario Testino, have been released.
 IT is the place where actors like Michelle Pfeiffer and George Clooney honed their craft and now it is coming to Australia .
 GONE Girl director David Fincher believes Ben Affleck is duplicitous and said if I was his wife I think I would be very suspicious.
Spot the winner ... US player Serena Williams (R) waves as she leaves the court with Russia's Maria Sharapova. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
IN SPORTS NEWS
 INCOMPARABLE Serena Williams is into her eighth Wimbledon final where she will meet newcomer Garbine Muguruza after beating Maria Sharapova.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World growth forecast cut for 2015</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/finance/imf-cuts-world-growth-forecast-for-2015/story-e6frfm1i-1227436091792?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>THE International Monetary Fund has cut its global economic growth forecast for this year but it is the US and not Greece that is to blame.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Forecast gloomy ... Managing Director of the International Monetary Fund Christine Lagarde says growth for 2015 has been cut. Picture: AP Source: AP
THE International Monetary Fund has cut its global economic growth forecast for this year with the risk of a further reduction before 2015 is out.
While this might not be too much of a surprise given the gyrations in world financial markets in recent weeks, the IMF downgrade was largely the result of an unexpected weak start to the year in the United States rather than events in Greece and China.
But in an update of its April World Economic Outlook, released on Thursday, the IMF does warn that risks to the outlook remain tilted to downside, including from increased market volatility and lower commodity prices.
It has cut its 2015 global growth forecast to 3.3 per cent from 3.5 per cent three months ago, but it has kept its 2016 prediction at 3.8 per cent.
While the update does not include a specific forecast for Australia, other advanced economies  where it would be grouped  has been trimmed to 2.7 per cent from 2.8 per cent for 2015.
For China, Australias number one trading partner, it has kept its growth forecasts of 6.8 per cent and 6.3 per cent for this year and next.
However, the Washington-based institution does note the difficulties facing China as it grapples with a rapidly declining share market.
On Europe, it believes the recovery remains on track, but unfolding developments in Greece are expected to take a heavier toll on activity there relative to earlier expectations,
Developments in Greece have, so far, not resulted in any significant contagion, it said.
In downgrading the US, the IMF said this was largely the result of one-off factors of a hard US winter and port closures, as well as a downsizing of business spending in the oil sector.
However, it says the underlying factors for an acceleration in consumption and investment in the worlds largest economy remain intact.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>‘Tourists will go for my private parts’</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/theyll-go-for-my-private-parts-times-squares-characters-reveal-life-inside-the-costume/story-fndir2ev-1227436020598?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>AFTER a man dressed up as Toy Story&amp;#8217;s Sheriff Woody was arrested for groping Australian tourists, others have opened up about life inside the costume.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
A new Sheriff Woody patrols Times Square after his predecessor was arrested for groping Australian tourists. Source: Supplied
A MAN dressed as the Toy Story character Woody has faced court after an incident with three Australian tourists in Times Square.
Jos Vasquez has been charged with three counts of attempted forcible touching and three counts of sex abuse for the alleged groping of the tourists, who had stopped to pose for pictures with him on Jan. 9, 2014, the New York Post reports.
Police Officer Shreegan Meade was working undercover in the area at the time and witnessed the incident. He testified in the court hearing on Monday in New York.
Officer Meade said The defendant, who was dressed as Woody, was with Buzz Lightyear and Minnie Mouse taking group photographs.
He testified he heard a woman scream He just grabbed my butt.
Then I observed a woman in front of the defendant jump up and scream. She hopped up and down in place while shaking her hands.
He heard her exclaim: He just grabbed my butt! I cant believe he did that! Im really upset!
After taking a complaint from the women, Officer Meade said he kept a close watch on Sheriff Woody, only to discover him rubbing his open palm on the buttocks area of two more female tourists who had posed with him separately.
Thats when the undercover officer arrested him.
Mr Vasquez has denied the allegations against him.
Jos Vasquez, dressed as Woody being detained. Picture: Byron Smith Source: Supplied
The characters count their tips after a successful selfie. Picture: Matt Young Source: Supplied
Mickey and Minnie pose for the camera. No tip necessary this time. Picture: Matt Young Source: Supplied
Yet the characters roaming the tourist hotspot today have their own side to tell.
One character wishing to remain anonymous said that without commenting on the case involving the Australians, its not always the characters at fault, arguing sometimes tourists dont behave.
Tourists, they grope me and do all kinds of things to me.
Im a very attractive character, if theyve had a few drinks, theyll even go for my private parts.
I dont say anything, I never go to the cops or anything like that.
The group, dressed as an array of well-known identities including Elmo, Minnie Mouse, Cookie Monster, The Incredible Hulk, Spider-Man and Thor, roam Times Square in the hope of scoring a selfie with a tourist. For a dollar, or five.
Some of people behind these costumes dont know how to read, dont know how to write.
I dont know what the facts are [about the court case], but in my experience, the characters here are a positive thing.
(Abuse of tourists) is not allowed by us if we see it. If someone is too huggy-huggy, we tell them, its not in your interest.
The new Sheriff Woody patrolling Times Square refused to give a comment to news.com.au.
Jos Vasquez, Woody, being detained. Picture: Byron Smith Source: Supplied
Yet prosecutor Jesse Matthews argued that Mr Vasquez, along with many of the other characters are harassing unsuspecting tourists.
People from all around the world come to Times Square every day, he said.
They do not come to be groped, rubbed or grabbed in the buttocks by a man wearing a costume.
In June, Hello Kitty and Minnie Mouse were arrested after fighting over a tip .
Cookie Monster, meanwhile, was caught shoving a toddler after its mother wouldnt supply a tip.
And Elmo was jailed for attempting to extort money from the Girl Scouts of America.
In one day, at least 60 characters can be found along the Times Square strip.
This is the latest in a long series of disturbing incidents that reinforce our belief that these costume characters must be licensed and regulated, Times Square Alliance president Tim Tompkins told CBS New York .
 youngma@news.com.au
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
