<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="npr">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Their Country In Turmoil, Some Greeks Now Lash Out At Each Other</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/07/09/421492928/their-country-in-turmoil-some-greeks-now-lash-out-at-each-other?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>As Greeks argue about how their troubled country should reform, the debate has often turned personal and nationalistic. Some people are even accusing each other of treason.</Description>
        <MainBody>Their Country In Turmoil, Some Greeks Now Lash Out At Each Other
July 09, 2015 4:58 PM ET
Joanna Kakissis
The economic crisis in Greece has divided the country. Here, a pro-euro demonstrator shouts slogans as he holds a European Union flag in front of the Greek Parliament during a rally in Athens on Thursday. Petros Karadjias/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Petros Karadjias/AP
The economic crisis in Greece has divided the country. Here, a pro-euro demonstrator shouts slogans as he holds a European Union flag in front of the Greek Parliament during a rally in Athens on Thursday.
Petros Karadjias/AP
Konstantinos Koutsantonis is 22, a university student who works as a delivery boy to make some extra cash. He considers himself a conservative. He voted "yes" for a bailout deal in last Sunday's referendum because he believes Greece can only reform its economy within the eurozone.
"Some days ago," he says, "when the crisis really exploded and everyone was talking about the referendum and the political news, I had to express my opinion."
He complained on Facebook that the referendum was a bad move because it could be perceived as anti-European.
Many criticized him  including a childhood friend, who called him a "Germanotsolias."
It's a terrible insult, Koutsantonis says, "something like a traitor  that you want to promote the German interests and not the Greek ones."
Clock Ticks As Europe Awaits Greek Proposal
It's the same term that was used for Nazi collaborators in the Second World War.
"As part of the counterinsurgency effort that the German occupiers launched in Greece in 1944, they created a body who fought on their side, a local militia, so to speak," explains Stathis Kalyvas , an Athens-born political scientist at Yale.
These militias often attacked fellow Greeks  Communist resistance fighters who fought against the Nazis during World War II.
In the bloody civil war that followed, from 1946 to 1949, Greece was further divided between left and right as the country's Communists fought the Western-backed, conservative government.
Greek novelist Thanassis Valtinos lived through that civil war as a child. "Greece was absolutely destroyed in that war," he says. "More people were killed and there was much more catastrophe than during the German occupation during World War II."
After the civil war, the government violently cracked down on leftists and Communists. Many were imprisoned and tortured. The Communist Party was outlawed.
Minutes after being sworn in as Greece's prime minister in January, Alexis Tsipras laid flowers at a memorial for 200 activists who were executed by Nazis in 1944.
Calls For Unity
Valtinos says Greeks should be united today  not reliving wartime divisions. He says people are trying to score political points by comparing austerity to the suffering Greeks endured during wartime.
"Back then, people were dropping dead of hunger in the streets. Children were walking skeletons," he says. "Yes, it's very hard today. But it's not a humanitarian crisis. They don't realize the humanitarian crisis is coming. It could be at our door."
Valtinos realizes that people are suffering now. He knows that many people are out of work. Some are eating at soup kitchens. Some are homeless. But he worries that Greeks will suffer much more if the country tumbles out of the eurozone and reverts to the drachma, its previous currency.
Kalyvas, the political scientist, also worries about how caustic the debate has become between the left and right in Greece, with each side questioning the other's patriotism. Syriza, the leftist party now running Greece, too often blames foreign powers for the country's problems, he says.
"It's a very 1960s, leftist view that Greece is not really an independent country but is a kind of colony," Kalyvas says. "A puppet in the hands of the Americans before, the Germans now  and who knows who tomorrow. So it's a very nationalist perception."
The subtext, he says, is really about the economic reforms demanded by international lenders, and whether Greeks can modernize their country alone  or whether they'll need help from the outside to do so.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:31:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece's Debt Crisis Exposes Its Hidden Financial Plumbing</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/09/421528567/greeces-debt-crisis-exposes-its-hidden-financial-plumbing?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Greece is on the verge of an economic nightmare scenario of the modern world. The financial plumbing in Greece is starting to shut down, and the Planet Money podcast finds out the widespread and weird effects.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece's Debt Crisis Exposes Its Hidden Financial Plumbing
July 09, 2015 4:31 PM ET
David Kestenbaum
Audio for this story from All Things Considered will be available at approximately 7:00 p.m. ET.
Greece is on the verge of an economic nightmare scenario of the modern world. The financial plumbing in Greece is starting to shut down, and the Planet Money podcast finds out the widespread and weird effects.

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:31:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Belgrade's Ruined Defense Ministry Serves As Reminder Of NATO Airstrikes</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/09/421528498/belgrades-ruined-defense-ministry-serves-as-reminder-of-nato-airstrikes?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>After national trauma, some countries build memorials, and others forget. Sixteen years after bombs struck, the defense ministry in Belgrade remains a ruin, serving as a daily reminder of the NATO war against Serbia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Belgrade's Ruined Defense Ministry Serves As Reminder Of NATO Airstrikes
July 09, 2015 4:31 PM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:31:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece's Forced Exit From The Eurozone Would Be 'Tumultuous' </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/09/421528456/greeces-forced-exit-from-the-eurozone-would-be-tumultuous?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>NPR's Robert Siegel talks with economists Jeffrey Sachs of Columbia University and Carmen Reinhart of Harvard's Kennedy School about Greece's debt crisis and the larger implications for the eurozone.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece's Forced Exit From The Eurozone Would Be 'Tumultuous'
July 09, 2015 4:31 PM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Puerto Rico Lobbies Congress For Help In Solving Debt Crisis</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/09/421528470/puerto-rico-lobbies-congress-for-help-in-solving-debt-crisis?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Puerto Rico's governor has stepped up efforts to convince Congress to help solve its debt crisis. The U.S. territory wants lawmakers to pass a bill that would extend bankruptcy protection.</Description>
        <MainBody>Puerto Rico Lobbies Congress For Help In Solving Debt Crisis
July 09, 2015 4:31 PM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry Says Iran Nuclear Talks 'Will Not Be Rushed'</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/09/421528463/kerry-says-iran-nuclear-talks-will-not-be-rushed?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Secretary of State John Kerry says there's progress in nuclear talks with Iran but no deal yet. He says the U.S. won't be rushed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kerry Says Iran Nuclear Talks 'Will Not Be Rushed'
July 09, 2015 4:31 PM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cyclists Can Ignore Some Traffic Lights, Paris Announces</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/09/421500592/cyclists-can-ignore-some-traffic-lights-paris-announces?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The city says that tests have shown "the passage of cyclists through red lights isn't accident-prone and avoids certain conflicts between cyclists and vehicles."</Description>
        <MainBody>Cyclists Can Ignore Some Traffic Lights, Paris Announces
July 09, 2015 4:04 PM ET
A man takes an early morning bicycle ride across a bridge near the Eiffel Tower in Paris. GONZALO FUENTES/Reuters /Landov hide caption
itoggle caption GONZALO FUENTES/Reuters /Landov
A man takes an early morning bicycle ride across a bridge near the Eiffel Tower in Paris.
GONZALO FUENTES/Reuters /Landov
Announcing a new policy for cyclists who ride in Paris, the city says it will allow people on bikes to ride through red lights or turn right at intersections that are marked by a special traffic sign.
Cyclists will have the most leeway at T-shaped intersections, where they can continue on without crossing other lanes of traffic. But in all cases, they'll have to yield to pedestrians and other vehicles who have the right of way.
The new policy follows several years of an experiment in which Paris allowed cyclists to pass through intersections more fluidly. The city says the test demonstrated that "the passage of cyclists through red lights isn't accident-prone and avoids certain conflicts between cyclists and vehicles that are stopped at lights"  notably those cases in which a bike is in a car's blind spot.
Parisian officials say the new policy will be rolled out between July and September, as special signs that resemble the yield signs commonly seen in the U.S. are added to intersections where cyclists will be allowed to go through the red light.
A diagram released by the city of Paris shows how cyclists will be able to pass through intersections during red lights. In some cases, they can turn right; in others, they can go straight through. City of Paris hide caption
itoggle caption City of Paris
Making the practice legal is also "a nice thing to do," according to the Treehugger website , which adds, "in so many cities the police lie in wait to hand out tickets to cyclists for infractions for rules that make sense for cars but not much for bikes."
The change is one of several Paris is making as it tries to lower traffic pollution in the city. Paris also announced Thursday it will provide hundreds of dollars in aid to any residents who want to give up an older car to buy a bike or take part in other transit plans.
As Cycling Weekly reports , "The French city is hoping to become a 'capital of cycling' by 2020, with desires to see 15 percent of all journeys made by bike."
But lest Paris' cyclists begin to see themselves as above the law, the Parisian policy announcement concludes by noting:
"Attention, cyclists are not a priority: they must show prudence and respect in all circumstances the priority accorded to other users, in particular pedestrians to whom they must always give way."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Botched Police Response May Have Kept Car Accident Victims Waiting Days</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/09/421478558/botched-police-response-may-have-kept-car-accident-victims-waiting-days?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>A 28-year-old man was dead and a 25-year-old woman was seriously injured when they were found by police in a car on the side of the road in Scotland.</Description>
        <MainBody>Botched Police Response May Have Kept Car Accident Victims Waiting Days
July 09, 2015 4:02 PM ET
Twitter
Police in Scotland are investigating how they missed responding to a car accident that left one person dead and another severely injured on the side of the road for as many as three days.
John Yuill, 28, and Lamara Bell, 25, were found on Wednesday morning local time off the M9 highway near the city of Stirling. Police reportedly received a call early Sunday about a car on the side of the road but did not follow up.
The BBC says that Yuill was dead and Bell was seriously injured when they were found by police. Family members told the BBC that Bell had broken bones and had kidney damage due to dehydration. They had been reported as missing after having had last been seen with friends early Sunday.
The BBC adds:
"The Police Investigations and Review Commissioner is to investigate, focusing on the call made to police on Sunday. A separate police investigation into the crash itself is ongoing.
"Scottish Justice Secretary Michael Matheson, who is also a local MSP for Falkirk, said he wanted 'early answers' about the tragedy, and said Police Scotland had assured him that all relevant information would be passed on to investigators
"Mid Scotland and Fife MSP Murdo Fraser said it was vital the 'truly shocking incident' was investigated in depth.
"He said: 'People lying unattended at the side of the road for days is something you'd be surprised to encounter in the third world.' "
The Telegraph reported that some politicians wondered whether a larger investigation is needed, to see if the incident was connected to a more widespread problem within Police Scotland.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>From Pygmy Hunting Songs To Taylor Swift, What Makes Music Universal</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/07/09/418587373/from-pygmy-hunting-songs-to-taylor-swift-what-makes-music-universal?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Can you hear what's similar about a Palestinian line dance and Swift's "Shake It Off?" Or </Description>
        <MainBody>From Pygmy Hunting Songs To Taylor Swift, What Makes Music Universal
July 09, 2015 3:45 PM ET
i
Even if you don't speak their language, you can likely communicate with these musicians through song and dance: Men from Papua New Guinea; Wiz Khalifa at the 2015 Billboard Music Awards; and Japanese dancers at the Daihanya Festival in Kagoshima City. Ness Kerton/AFP/Getty Images; Ethan Miller/AFP/Getty Images; iStockphoto hide caption
itoggle caption Ness Kerton/AFP/Getty Images; Ethan Miller/AFP/Getty Images; iStockphoto
Even if you don't speak their language, you can likely communicate with these musicians through song and dance: Men from Papua New Guinea; Wiz Khalifa at the 2015 Billboard Music Awards; and Japanese dancers at the Daihanya Festival in Kagoshima City.
Ness Kerton/AFP/Getty Images; Ethan Miller/AFP/Getty Images; iStockphoto
No matter where you travel around the world, people share a few qualities. They cherish love for families and friends. They unite around good cooking. And they make music you can shake your booty to.
"Music is the universal language of mankind," Henry Wadsworth Longfellow wrote in first major work, Outre-Mer.
Yet nearly 200 years later, scientists still don't have a good understanding of how that language works. What are the nouns? What are the verbs? Which components are universal?
&lt;iframe src="http://www.npr.org/player/embed/418587373/421169588" width="100%" height="290" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;
Palestinian Line Dance
Now a team of musicologists in England and Japan have started to fill in those blanks. They've identified 18 musical features that are common across all geographic regions. They reported their findings last week in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.
The chorus of Taylor Swift's "Shake It Off" is a good example of a recent pop song with an obvious descending melody. Each phrase, "Playas gonna play, play, play, play, play, play," starts high and descends to end with lower notes.
This collection of universal features connects "Do-Re-Mi" from The Sound Of Music to a Pygmy hunting dance and Taylor Swift's hit " Shake It Off " to Palestinian line dancing. But they also allow people from all corners of the globe to communicate  without words, says graduate student Patrick Savage , who led the study.
"Same with my daughter," he says. "Before she could talk, she wanted to bang on the drums, and we would sing together. She didn't know the words, but we were communicating through music," says Savage, who's working toward a Ph.D. in muscology at the Tokyo University of the Arts.
Previous studies have looked for universal features in music by comparing songs from Western cultures with those from one or two very isolated, non-Western cultures. "But our study is the first to look at a wide and diverse sample of different types of music," he says.
Savage and his colleagues obtained and analyzed 304 recordings from the Garland Encyclopedia of World Music. "It's the biggest, most diverse sample of world music out there," he says.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Criticizes Thailand's Deportation Of Uighurs To China</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/09/421497316/u-s-criticizes-thailands-deportation-of-uighurs-to-china?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The ruling junta in the Southeast Asian country ordered 100 ethnic Uighur Muslims to return to China, where Washington says they "could face harsh treatment and a lack of due process."</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. Criticizes Thailand's Deportation Of Uighurs To China
July 09, 2015 3:15 PM ET
A group of Uighur protesters demonstrate outside the Thai embassy in Ankara, Turkey, on Thursday to protest Thailand's deportation of 100 Uighur refugees back to China. Burhan Ozbilici/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Burhan Ozbilici/AP
A group of Uighur protesters demonstrate outside the Thai embassy in Ankara, Turkey, on Thursday to protest Thailand's deportation of 100 Uighur refugees back to China.
Burhan Ozbilici/AP
The U.S. has condemned a move by Thailand to deport more than 100 ethnic Uighur Muslims back to China amid fears that the refugees will be persecuted by Beijing authorities.
Michael Sullivan, reporting for NPR from Thailand, says the Uighurs fled China more than a year ago and were detained while Thai authorities tried to figure out what to do with them. About 170 were sent to Turkey last month, and the remainder were handed over to Chinese authorities today.
U.S. State Department spokesman John Kirby said the deportees "could face harsh treatment and a lack of due process" in China.
"This action runs counter to Thailand's international obligations as well as its long-standing practice of providing safe haven to vulnerable persons," Kirby said in a statement. "We remain deeply concerned about the protection of all asylum seekers and vulnerable migrants in Thailand, and we strongly urge the Government of Thailand, and other governments in countries where Uighurs have taken refuge, not to carry out further forced deportations of ethnic Uighurs."
Thailand's move comes as the country's ruling junta, which toppled an elected government in May 2014, moves closer to Beijing amid criticism from Washington of the military government's poor human rights record.
Thailand's deputy government spokesman, Maj. Gen. Werachon Sukondhapatipak, is quoted in The Bangkok Post as defending the move to deport the Uighurs, saying: "We have followed proper procedures."
The Post reports: "His [defense] of Thailand's actions followed angry scenes in Istanbul, Turkey, overnight, when a mob broke into the Thai consulate in Istanbul to protest against the decision to deport the Uighur refugees to China."
The Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees also condemned the deportation of the Uighurs, saying it was "shocked" by what it called "a flagrant violation of international law."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In Yemen, Agony Continues As Civilians 'Bear The Brunt'</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/07/09/421449659/in-yemen-agony-continues-as-civilians-bear-the-brunt?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>An Amnesty International researcher provides a rare glimpse of life in Yemen, which the U.N. says is in the grip of a "massive humanitarian crisis." Will a new ceasefire help bring relief?</Description>
        <MainBody>In Yemen, Agony Continues As Civilians 'Bear The Brunt'
July 09, 2015 2:22 PM ET
NPR Staff
A man and a boy walk at a site hit by a Saudi-led air strike in Yemen's capital Sanaa on July 3. More than a million civilians have been displaced in recent fighting. Khaled Abdullah/Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Khaled Abdullah/Reuters/Landov
A man and a boy walk at a site hit by a Saudi-led air strike in Yemen's capital Sanaa on July 3. More than a million civilians have been displaced in recent fighting.
Khaled Abdullah/Reuters/Landov
It's not easy to get news these days from Yemen, where more than 3,000 people have been killed in fighting since March. As fighting rages between several different groups and Saudi airstrikes and a coastal blockade continue, the United Nations has warned of a "massive humanitarian crisis" in the country.
Aid groups report that more than a million Yemenis have been forced to flee their homes, food and fuel prices are skyrocketing and there's a rising threat of diseases like dengue fever.
UNICEF reported late last month that at least 279 children have died so far in the conflict, and warns that millions are at risk of malnutrition, diarrhea and other illnesses.
Rasha Mohamed, a London-based researcher with Amnesty International, tells NPR's Kelly McEvers on All Things Considered about recent deaths she documented of children killed in an airstrike in Sanaa, Yemen's capital.
She's been observing increasingly dire conditions faced by residents there and in the northern city of Saada. Mohamed has shared some of her observations and photos on Twitter. Additional photos are on Amnesty International's website . "It's getting worse and worse," she tells McEvers. A new ceasefire is to go into effect Friday.
Interview Highlights
On the most pressing issues for Yemenis
They tell us that we don't have enough to eat, things don't get to them, there is no petrol, they can't get out of their areas at times, and if there [are] these things, they can't afford them. This is the biggest issue right now in Yemen. There might be things available in the markets, but people just can't afford them, so it's getting worse and worse.
[Food and fuel prices] quadrupled. Most of the time, a bag of flour has quadrupled, if not more. Same with fuel  a cylinder of gas, cooking gas, would have been around 1,200 Yemeni rials [$5.58], now it goes up to about 5,000 Yemeni rials [$23.24], which is, you know, very difficult for a family that's trying to cook for 20 members. So that's one of the main issues here.
On the situation in the capital
Sanaa has not been as hard-hit as other areas, I would say. In Sanaa, [attacks] tend to focus on military infrastructure, airports, military locations and camps. Every now and then, they focus on airstrikes on the leadership ... And that's when civilians get caught in the middle and they bear the brunt. So they might either miss their targets, or they might hit the actual house and shrapnel might kill civilians in the area. That's what we've observed so far in Sanaa.
On the second of July, bombardment was very heavy in Sanaa before we headed to Saada, and we headed straight away after the airstrikes ... And what had happened they had apparently intended to target a house next door to the house that was struck ...The airstrike missed the house and hit the house next door, where a caretaker and his family  nine children and his wife  live. They take care of the house. The person who owns the house doesn't live there anymore due to the situation. So the caretaker, actually ... had already lost his son, Sammie, who was the youngest, who was around five. And there were two children still under rubble when we arrived at 2 p.m. They couldn't dig them out until 1 a.m. the next day.
They didn't [survive], unfortunately. He lost three kids, and it just happened that the wife and the kids actually live in the countryside. They had just arrived to visit the father the day before. So it was quite tragic.
On the viability of a humanitarian "pause" in airstrikes
I think a pause to the fighting would be very much welcomed. However, I think what needs to happen is an end to this crisis. I mean ... prior to this, already 60 percent of the population [was] aid-dependent. Now it's 80 percent of the country aid-dependent. Plus dengue fever is spreading. People are internally displaced. Now it's up to 1 million people internally displaced. That doesn't include old people who were internally displaced from old conflicts in the country.
I think this humanitarian pause that's being suggested is just a really short-term solution. It's not really going to bring the results that people need. In fact, the last humanitarian pause was broken by armed groups in Aden and in Taiz. The fighting continued. Airstrikes might have, you know, stopped, but the armed groups, they're all fighting on six different groups in the country  and they don't stop during the humanitarian pause. So I don't think it's going to help in the long or short run.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry: 'We Will Not Rush' Deal On Iran's Nuclear Program</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/09/421462274/iran-deal-close-as-congressional-deadline-looms?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>If an agreement cannot be reached by midnight, Congress will double the time it takes to review any pact.</Description>
        <MainBody>Secretary of State John Kerry (right) walks using crutches Thursday at the garden of the hotel where the Iran nuclear talks are being held in Vienna. Carlos Barria/Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Carlos Barria/Reuters/Landov
Secretary of State John Kerry (right) walks using crutches Thursday at the garden of the hotel where the Iran nuclear talks are being held in Vienna.
Carlos Barria/Reuters/Landov
Update at 1:20 p.m. ET
Secretary of State John Kerry says the United States and its five negotiating partners working to hammer out a deal to curb Iran's nuclear program "will not rush and ... will not be rushed" into a deal.
He said that "despite all of the progress" made at the negotiating table, key issues remain unresolved.
"If in the end we are able to reach a deal, it has to be one that can stand the test of time," he said.
Kerry's statement appeared to narrow the chances that a final agreement can be reached before midnight, the deadline that would trigger Congress to take two months instead of one to review any pact. That would in turn delay the lifting of U.S. sanctions.
As NPR's Peter Kenyon explains from Vienna, "all sides here say the focus is on getting a good deal, not meeting a deadline. Even so, the prospect of a 60-day congressional review of a deal instead of 30 days is not pleasant for the White House. But in order for that to happen, a draft of the deal must reach Capitol Hill by tonight, and extremely difficult issues remain."
The Associated Press quotes Iran's President Hassan Rouhani as saying his nation "was preparing for a 'post-sanctions' era, suggesting that a deal may be in sight to curb the Iranian nuclear program in exchange for the lifting of economic sanctions. His foreign minister, meanwhile, opined on Twitter that 'with mutual respect, anything possible.' "
The original deadline for the talks was June 30, but that was later extended.
The meetings include the so-called P5+1 powers  Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States.
Russian President Vladimir Putin reportedly told Rouhani on Thursday that he hoped an agreement could be reached soon.
"Putin underlined the positive dynamic in the talks on Iran's nuclear program and expressed hope that the necessary compromise will be found in the near future," said Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov, according to Reuters.
The biggest obstacle remaining is the United Nations embargo on conventional weapons sales to Iran. The Western powers, with the exception of Russia, insist it must remain in place.
As Reuters notes:
"The U.N. weapons and missile sanctions were imposed with Russia's consent nearly a decade ago, but Moscow has become hostile to the idea of sanctions since the United States and European Union began sanctioning it for annexing Ukraine's Crimea peninsula last year. Moscow and Tehran are interested in finishing a deal on the sale to Iran of Russian anti-aircraft missiles.
"The Kremlin signed a decree in April lifting a self-imposed ban on the delivery of the S-300 missile system to Iran, though the missiles have yet to be delivered."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India's Top Court Orders Federal Investigation Into Exam Scam</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/09/421453926/indias-top-court-orders-federal-investigation-into-exam-scam?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The multimillion-dollar job-recruitment scam has been linked to more than 30 deaths. Hundreds of people have been arrested in connection with the Vyapam scandal.</Description>
        <MainBody>India's Top Court Orders Federal Investigation Into Exam Scam
July 09, 201510:23 AM ET
Twitter
India's Supreme Court has ordered a federal investigation into a multimillion-dollar job-recruitment scam and more than 30 deaths to which it has been linked.
The country's highest court ordered the Central Bureau of Investigation to take over the inquiry by police in central Madhya Pradesh state into what's known as the Vyapam scam. Here's the background to the scam from India's NDTV :
"The Vyapam scam is named for a state board that conducts qualifying tests for colleges and jobs as government teachers, doctors and policemen. [Hundreds of thousands] of candidates paid bribes to manipulate the exam process, including hiring proxies to take the test for them."
More than 2,500 people have been linked to the scandal, and 1,900 have been arrested. Since 2012 , at least 36 people linked to the inquiry have died under mysterious circumstances; among them investigators, those accused and witnesses.
The Associated Press adds:
"The court also directed the Madhya Pradesh government to respond to a petition demanding the removal of the state's federally appointed governor after questions were raised about his involvement in the scandal. Gov. Ram Naresh Yadav's son Shailesh Yadav died mysteriously in May after the younger man was alleged to have accepted bribes in the governor's house."
Members of the opposition Congress Party have long been demanding a CBI inquiry into the scam, accusing the state government of trying to influence the course of the investigation.
"Students who have been arrested in connection with the scam should be made witnesses for the state," Congress leader Digvijay Singh told reporters Thursday. "Isn't it strange that hundreds of students and their parents are in jail, while those who took the bribes are roaming free?"
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek Government Hands European Creditors New Bailout Proposals</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/09/421413739/greek-cabinet-meets-on-proposal-amid-signs-of-a-deal?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>News reports say the new proposal accepts the tough austerity measures demanded by Greece's European partners but also includes a debt write-off, which Germany has opposed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek Government Hands European Creditors New Bailout Proposals
July 09, 2015 8:37 AM ET
Twitter
(This post was last updated at 4:48 p.m. ET.)
Just before the end of the day Thursday in Athens, the Greek government handed its European creditors a new bailout proposal.
A spokesman for Eurogroup President Jeroen Dijsselbloem tweeted that Greece's creditors would now consider the proposal.
There has been no official word on the details of the proposal, but The Guardian reports that under the terms, Greece would accept the "severe austerity measures" its EU partners have insisted on in exchange for "a modest debt write-off."
Here's what would happen next:
The country's creditors  the European Bank, the European Central Bank and the International Monetary Fund  will meet Friday to discuss the proposals.
On Saturday, July 11, the proposal will be taken up by finance ministers from the eurozone.
Sunday, July 12, is the key day. Eurogroup leaders and all 28 members of the EU will meet in Brussels. That meeting could see Greece's plan approved and pave the way for a new bailout for Greece. Failure will likely see a Greek exit from the eurozone, a move that could have profound implications not only for Greece but for the rest of the region's economy.
Realistic proposal from Athens needs to be matched by realistic proposal from creditors on debt sustainability to create win-win situation
 Donald Tusk (@eucopresident) July 9, 2015
As we have previously reported , Greece has received commitments of $244 billion from various countries and organizations as part of two bailouts, in 2010 and 2012. (The Wall Street Journal has an excellent interactive that explains what Greece owes its creditors and when payments are due.)
Many experts believe that debt, which is 177 percent of the country's gross domestic product, is unsustainable for a country that has not recovered from the 2008 financial crisis. Indeed, U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew added his voice to calls for "Europe [to] ... restructure the debt in a way that is more sustainable." Christine Lagarde, the managing director of the IMF, one of Greece's toughest critics , echoed those calls .
Donald Tusk, the president of the European Council, added his voice Thursday:
But some European countries, especially Germany, have been reluctant.
Chancellor Angela Merkel, on a visit to Bosnia on Thursday, appeared to rule out a "haircut" on Europe's loans to Greece.
"I have said that a classic haircut is out of the question for me and that hasn't changed between yesterday and today," she said, according to Reuters.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. Says Syria Represents Worst Refugee Crisis In 25 Years</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/09/421413467/u-n-says-syria-represents-worst-refugee-crisis-in-25-years?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The high commissioner for refugees estimates that more than 4 million have fled since the start of the civil war four years ago. An additional 7.6 million are believed to be displaced inside Syria.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.N. Says Syria Represents Worst Refugee Crisis In 25 Years
July 09, 2015 8:37 AM ET
i
Refugees from Syria arrive in Presevo, near the border with Macedonia, in the south of Serbia, on Wednesday. The U.N. says more than 4 million have fled the civil war in Syria, making it the worst refugee crisis in a quarter century. Djordje Savic/EPA/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Djordje Savic/EPA/Landov
Refugees from Syria arrive in Presevo, near the border with Macedonia, in the south of Serbia, on Wednesday. The U.N. says more than 4 million have fled the civil war in Syria, making it the worst refugee crisis in a quarter century.
Djordje Savic/EPA/Landov
The U.N. estimates that more than 4 million Syrians have fled the country since the start of the civil war there four years ago, making it the worst refugee crisis in a quarter century.
The Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees says the total number of refugees that have left Syria could be more than 4.25 million by the end of the year. An additional 7.6 million people are internally displaced.
"This is the biggest refugee population from a single conflict in a generation," U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees Antnio Guterres says in a statement. "It is a population that deserves the support of the world but is instead living in dire conditions and sinking deeper into abject poverty."
As The Associated Press notes: "The new figure shows that the flow of refugees is accelerating only 10 months after the agency recorded more than 3 million Syrians fleeing their country."
About 45 percent of the refugees are living in Turkey and most of the rest are scattered in four other countries: Lebanon, Jordan, Iraq and Egypt.
"Worsening conditions are driving growing numbers towards Europe and further afield, but the overwhelming majority remain in the region," Guterres added. "We cannot afford to let them and the communities hosting them slide further into desperation."
Reuters writes:
"UNHCR's appeal for $5.5 billion to support the Syrian refugees in 2015 is only 24 percent funded. The U.N. World Food Programme has already cut rations for refugees because of a lack of cash.
"About 86 percent of the 630,000 in Jordan live below the poverty line of $3.2 per day, the UNHCR statement said, while more than half of the 1.173 million Syrians in Lebanon live in sub-standard shelters."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
