<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nwfdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:07:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida's congressional districts rejected as gerrymandered</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/florida-s-congressional-districts-rejected-as-gerrymandered-1.496512</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Florida's congressional districts rejected as gerrymandered
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By The Associated Press
Published: Thursday, July 9, 2015 at 05:07 PM.
TALLAHASSEE  The Florida Supreme Court ruled Thursday that the state's congressional maps don't meet the requirements of a voter-approved constitutional amendment that prohibits political lines from being drawn to favor incumbents or a political party. The court ordered the Legislature to try drawing the maps again.
The ruling means there could be an upheaval as incumbents seek re-election and candidates from both parties seek to fill open seats. Florida has 27 congressional districts and the ruling could affect 22 of them. The court ordered eight districts be redrawn, but in doing so, 14 districts that border might also have to be changed.
The court told the Legislature to act swiftly since qualifying for congressional races is approaching. Candidates must file their paperwork to get on the 2016 ballot during the first week in May.
The ruling chastised the Republican-led Legislature not only for working with political operatives to violate the constitution in order to benefit the GOP, but also for making important decisions behind closed doors and destroying documents and deleting emails when they knew the maps would be challenged in court.
"The Legislature itself proclaimed that it would conduct the most open and transparent redistricting process in the history of the state, and then made important decisions, affecting numerous districts in the enacted map, outside the purview of public scrutiny," the ruling said.
The court questioned whether the full extent of the political maneuver was exposed in the case.
"Since many of the e-mails were deleted or destroyed, we still may have only a partial picture of the behind-the-scenes political tactics," Justice Barbara Pariente wrote for the majority in the 5-2 opinion. Justices Charles Canady and Ricky Polston dissented.
The court recommended the Legislature make all its decision in public when it redraws the maps and to save all emails and documents related to the effort.
The Legislature will have to have the new maps ready by October, which will require a special session to approve them. House Speaker Steve Crisafulli and Senate President Andy Gardiner were reviewing the decision and neither planned to comment on it Thursday.
Florida has 17 Republican U.S. House members and 10 Democrats despite Democrats having an advantage in voter registration. Florida has 4.6 million Democrats and 4.2 million Republicans.
The ruling will affect districts held by Democratic Reps. Corrine Brown, Kathy Castor, Ted Deutch and Lois Frankel and Republican Reps. Mario Diaz-Balart, Carlos Curbelo, Ileana Ros-Lehtinen and David Jolly.
Brown, who's long, narrow, oddly-shaped district is often used as the most obvious case of a gerrymandered district, criticized the opinion. Her district is designed to contain a majority of African-Americans.
"Minority communities do not live in compact, cookie-cutter like neighborhoods, and excessive adherence to district 'compactness,' while ignoring the maintenance of minority access districts, fragments minority communities across the state," she said in a statement emailed by her office.
A coalition that included the League of Women Voters challenged the lines, saying Republicans who drew them up ignored the new constitutional requirements approved by voters in 2010. A lower court agreed that GOP leaders and operatives made a mockery of the amendment, but only ordered two central Florida districts be redrawn.
The Supreme Court said that wasn't good enough.
"This is a complete victory for the people of Florida who passed the Fair Districts Amendment. The court has made it abundantly clear that partisan gerrymandering will not be tolerated. We look forward to the legislature following the constitution and the directives of the court," said David King, a lawyer for the coalition.
House Speaker Steve Crisafulli and Senate President Andy Gardiner were reviewing the decision and neither planned to comment on it Thursday.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:49:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Friday marks the 10th anniversary of the area’s last hurricane</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/weather/friday-marks-the-10th-anniversary-of-the-area-s-last-hurricane-1.496504</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Friday marks the 10th anniversary of the areas last hurricane
Gulf front homes in Seagrove Beach in Walton County were damaged from Hurricane Dennis' storm surge.
File photo
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, July 9, 2015 at 04:49 PM.
On the net: Read the full reports from DEP and NSW on Hurricane Dennis at nwfdailynews.com.
Ten years ago today Northwest Florida residents didnt know it, probably didnt believe it, but they were closing a decade-long chapter in local hurricane history.
Early that morning, Hurricane Dennis was barreling toward the local beaches. Many had evacuated. Everyone had prepared.
DOCUMENT: DEP report on beach and dune erosion
Residents learned their lesson not 10 months before when Hurricane Ivan crippled the area. They hung shutters, bought water and bread and fought the still-fresh memories of 1995s Hurricane Opal.
When it was over, they breathed a collective sigh of relief. Damage was extensive, but Hurricane Dennis had, mercifully, passed over the area quickly and caused no serious injuries or deaths.
If it had come down on its own, it would have been a major, major problem, said Kevin Carvalho, the assistant fire chief for the Okaloosa Island Fire Department. At this point, it was all about perspective.
Eye of the storm
Initially, it looked like Dennis was going to slam into Okaloosa County as a Category 4 hurricane. Before it made landfall, it changed its path slightly and lost some power.
Hurricane Dennis hit Santa Rosa Island the afternoon of June 10 as a Category 3 storm with sustained winds just shy of 100 mph and gusts of 121 mph, according to the National Weather Service.
The tidal surge was 6-to-7 feet at the eye and 6-to-12 feet east of the storm.
Whatever made it through Ivan on the north side, Dennis got, recalled Buck Lee, who had just taken over as the director of the Santa Rosa Island Authority at the time.
When Lee crossed over the bridge to the island from Gulf Breeze immediately after the storm, he didnt make it far. Downed phone lines covered the roadways. Once they were cleared, he was relieved to see erosion wasnt as big of an issue as with Ivan. The biggest problem was flooding.
Lee couldnt drive through the Gulf Islands National Seashore to Navarre Beach, because the storm had washed it out, but the damage was most definitely there as well.
Two sections of the Navarre Fishing Pier were missing and 26 major structures were damaged beyond repair, according to a Florida Department of Environmental Protection report.
Much of Gulf Boulevard in Navarre Beach was either in pieces or covered by sand when homeowners were given the first glimpse.
Wind combined with the incomplete dune recovery from Ivan and Opal, set up Navarre Beach for most of its issues, according to Roger Blaylock, who oversees it.
(Dennis) wiped out all the repairs that were on-going, Blaylock said.
When he thinks back on the storm now, its hard to separate Dennis from Ivan, and hes grateful for it.
It was a stronger, more intense kind of storm, but moving quickly, and thank God, Blaylock said.
Had Dennis lingered like Ivan, the damage would have been devastating.
Like a hangover
Pockets of Okaloosa County were hit much harder than others. The Parish Point Subdivision in Florosa was overwhelmed with water, but Fort Walton Beach withstood most of the storm.
News was good out of the north and central parts of the county as well. Initial estimates put Eglin Air Force Base at $19.5 million worth of damages to structures and Hurlburt Field a little less than $10 million.
Okaloosa Island wasnt destroyed, but it wasnt untouched either.
When Carvalho came back over the Brooks Bridge after the storm had passed, U.S. Highway 98 was covered in water and part of it was gone  again.
Sand was piled up everywhere.
Its almost a bit of Armageddon, he recalled. Theres nobody on the roads; theres stuff scattered all over the medians.
While out assessing damage and checking in on people who had remained, it wasnt uncommon to see sand filling the first level of a condo and all the contents pushed out the back.
It was a lot to take for a community still healing from natures last hit.
It really felt like we were targeted that year, Carvalho said.
A little farther down the coast, much of the sand was washed away, and homes and condominiums on Holiday Isle and Crystal Beach got the worst of it, said Destin City Manager Greg Kisela.
Jetty East Condominium also took a biggest hit.
North of U.S. Highway 98 in Destin, it was wind, not water that caused most of the damage. Any home that didnt have to get a new roof after Ivan, did following Dennis, Kisela said.
But property damage wasnt what hit Destin the hardest. It was the storms timing  peak tourist season. When Ivan hit in the fall, there was time to clean up and rebuild before the next summer.
After Dennis, businesses in Destin were looking at losing 40 percent of their gross profit for the year.
It was like a hangover, Kisela said. Thats the problem with Dennis - the lingering economic impact.
Beaches washed out
Walton County was farthest removed from the eye, but that didnt save it from Hurricane Dennis.
Beaches were all but washed away in the storm.
At the time, officials said they believed every beachfront property in the county sustained some damage during the storm. Eleven were destroyed.
It was just like somebody had sheared off the dunes, said Cindy Meadows, the then newly elected county commissioner for the Santa Rosa Beach area. Some houses were just hanging over the dunes. It was pretty devastating.
The waves washed away the then new sand dunes and crashed onto Scenic Gulf Drive near the Majestic Sun condominiums. When the water cleared, about a foot of the road was missing.
Most of the public and private beach accesses were partially or completely gone.
Away from the coast, damage was much less significant. Mostly people were just dealing with downed trees and power outages, but repairs along the coast kept officials occupied for a long time, Meadows said.
We had meeting after meeting to figure out how people were going to restore their properties, she said. It was a long drawn out process.
Stronger than before
Today most of the dune systems have been restored, and area beaches renourished.
U.S. Highway 98 on Okaloosa Island was rebuilt, but this time with extra armor that should protect it when the next storm blows in.
Homes and businesses have mostly returned to normal, and save the 2010 Deepwater Horizon oil spill, tourism seasons have gone forward without interruption.
If theres a silver lining, its your buildings are built to a better standard, Kisela said.
The pilings are put in deeper and wood frames have been replaced by concrete.
No longer are the first floors of condos occupied by people  instead theyve switched most over to parking garages, said Carvalho, who serves as a building inspector now. That way, when the tidal surge comes through, refrigerators and beds arent pushed out the back.
Everyone is hopeful when the next storm comes along, it wont be as painful as those in the past.
To me, (Dennis) was the closing of hurricanes, in what, I hope, is my lifetime, Carvalho said. It was very wearing to us all.
Daily News archives, the Department of Environmental Protection and the National Weather Service contributed to this report.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:47:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mid-Bay Bridge tolls are changing</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/mid-bay-bridge-tolls-are-changing-1.496502</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mid-Bay Bridge tolls are changing
File photo
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Thursday, July 9, 2015 at 04:47 PM.
BLUEWATER BAY  Most of the details arent finalized, but one things for sure: On Oct. 1, the price of tolls on the Mid-Bay Bridge will be going up.
By refinancing our debt, we were able to reduce considerably the need for the originally scheduled toll increase, said Van Fuller, the executive director of the Mid-Bay Bridge Authority. Unfortunately, we werent able to lower it enough to completely eliminate an increase, but it will be much, much lower than it would have been if we hadnt refinanced.
The final decision on the amount and structure of future tolls will be decided at the authoritys meeting on Aug. 20. Prior to that meeting, the authority will host two public information meetings  one in Niceville and one in Destin  during the last week in July. Exact dates, times and locations of the meetings have not been finalized.
We will be presenting about eight different options that the authority will be considering, Fuller said. These options will include the discount for SunPass users. Were also looking at possible ways to provide a discount for commuters, but nothing is definite yet.
While the public will be invited to write their thoughts about the different options on comment cards, Fuller said there will not be an open mike for people to express their opinions.
We will gather the data from the cards and present it to the authority members at the August meeting, Fuller said.
The toll rate is currently $2 for cars with a SunPass and $3 without.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:29:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Students explore English in ESOL Summer Camp (PHOTOS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/students-explore-english-in-esol-summer-camp-photos-1.496490</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Students explore English in ESOL Summer Camp (PHOTOS)
Carmen Rosales (from left), 14, Yarel Galeas, 11, and Medardo Lobes, 11, hold on to Leo Diaz, 11, during a game of Simon Says on Thursday at Pryor Middle School during an English language learning course.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, July 9, 2015 at 04:29 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  The English language was brought to life this summer for a group of students in the Okaloosa County School District.
Between reading and math assignments, a group of 70 English language learners tested their fluency through hands-on activities as part of a summer program aimed at bridging educational gap between one school year and the next.
On the second-to-last day of the English for Speakers of Other Languages Summer Camp at Pryor Middle School, teacher Maureen Byrd had her students toss around a ball with a world map on it. They worked their way through places that start with each letter of the alphabet.
Think of the states, and the counties and the cities, Byrd said. Think of any word that starts with the letter D.
In Spanish? Stephano Durso, who is going into ninth grade, asked with a smile.
In English, Byrd replied with a laugh.
A little later the students played Simon Says with Byrd to put their new vocabulary words to practice. First they worked as a group. Then individually. One student even agreed to become Simon and issued the commands.
Zoila Ganuza, who oversees the ESOL program for the school district, watched the interactions closely. She recently stood before the Okaloosa County School Board and asked it to expand the program to two weeks for middle and high school students and one week for elementary-aged children.
Though the exact number fluctuates, the district has about 900 students whose native language is not English, she said. The majority speak Spanish and come from Central America.
The students were clearly comfortable with each other and the environment during Thursdays class.
Based on observations and feedback from the instructors, theyve seen significant growth, Ganuza said afterwards. Its a safer place (than the regular classroom) to say, I dont know. 
During the program, students worked on learning English, academics and explored American culture.
Ganuza is excited at the prospect of growing the voluntary program further next year. She had a waiting list this year.
Shed also like to add science and civic curricula into the mix.
But first shell need to tackle the data from this year and only then will she go before the School Board and ask for more.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:06:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Flyover opens to drivers next week</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/flyover-opens-to-drivers-next-week-1.496477</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Flyover opens to drivers next week
A new traffic pattern will begin on July 18. The entire project is expected to be completed by the end of September or early October.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Thursday, July 9, 2015 at 04:06 PM.
If weather cooperates, the new U.S. Highway 98 flyover at Hurlburt Field will be partially operational by July 18.
The Department of Transportation plans to shift westbound through traffic onto the new bridge.
Crews will be out the night of the 17th doing some striping and laying transition work, DOT spokesman Ian Satter said. All of this is based on weather conditions cooperating... Itll be in the morning hours.
Crews will return the night of July 27 to prep the eastbound lanes of the flyover bridge. Eastbound through-traffic will shift on the morning of July 28.
Were going to guide traffic, Satter said. People will be directed to go toward the flyover portion.
Hurlburt Field officials had released information earlier this week indicating the traffic shifts would happen July 15 and July 22, but DOT officials said the dates are now set for July 18 and 28.
The $13.9 million project is expected to ease traffic woes on that portion of U.S. Highway 98 where major delays are commonplace.
The two new eastbound left turn lanes at the main Hurlburt Field entrance will be longer and remove more vehicles from the overall traffic flow. FDOT officials also predict faster morning commute times for the nearly 50,000 motorists traveling through the intersection each day.
Many locals expressed excitement about the flyover Thursday on the Daily News Facebook page.
I hope it helps with the traffic and maybe, just maybe, less accidents, Laura Perry posted.
I can only dream of completion, posted Eriq Sterling. I drive to (and) from Miramar for work every day, and any time after 4 p.m. its gridlock, so this will at least cut 20 minutes off.
Some folks questioned whether the changes were drastic enough to make a real difference.
I hope it helps, but it doesnt look like the feeder lanes are long enough, said Jessica Lynne Kidwell. I envision gridlock still and a lot of wrecks. But, it will be nice to have a 20-minute drive home rather than an hour or longer.
The overall project wont be completed until late September or early October.
We still have a lot to do on Cody Avenue, Satter said. Its still an active construction zone. Crews are still going to be out there doing work, so we just want (motorists) to be cognizant of that.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:19:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suicidal woman jumps off bridge, survives</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/suicidal-woman-jumps-off-bridge-survives-1.496406</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Suicidal woman jumps off bridge, survives
File photo
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, July 9, 2015 at 11:19 AM.
A 34-year-old Niceville woman survived jumping off Brooks Bridge early Thursday morning.
After she was rescued, she told an Okaloosa County Sheriff's Office deputy she was suicidal and was probably trying to kill herself.
A motorist flagged down the deputy, who was returning from a call on Okaloosa Island just after 5 a.m.
She landed between two concrete barriers, the deputy said, but escaped apparent injury.
She was taken to Fort Walton Beach Medical Center, where she was admitted for her own protection, according to the OCSO incident report.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LAURIE ELLISON'S BLOG: 5 tips for thrift store shopping</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/laurie-ellison-s-blog-5-tips-for-thrift-store-shopping-1.496378</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>LAURIE ELLISON'S BLOG: 5 tips for thrift store shopping
By LAURIE ELLISON | Daily News blogger
Published: Thursday, July 9, 2015 at 10:16 AM.
Photo Galleries
Clothes
Love fashion but dont have the budget for the designer labels you crave? Our local thrift stores are treasure troves brimming with brand-name clothing just waiting to be discovered. Learn the skills to score the stylish deals! If youre a thrift store newbie, here are five tips for thrift store shopping that you should know.
Go with a plan.
Thrift stores can be overwhelming if you dont have any idea what youre looking for. Know what you need and stay focused among the sea of endless racks.
Shop often.
Shopping at the thrift is hit or miss. Dont get discouraged. If you dont find anything one week, try again the following week. Thrift stores are constantly getting in new stock. Make shopping at thrift stores part of your routine.
Connect via social media.
Be in the know. Many stores now announce their sales via their social media networks. For example, Goodwill always announces its sales on Facebook so followers dont miss out. Know your favorite stores sale days and prepare to save BIG.
Make a friend on the inside.
If youre looking for something, just ask. Some of the store associates roaming the sales floor handle the merchandise, so they might be able to point you in the right direction. They might even remember you when that item youve been looking for pops up unexpectedly.
Keep an open mind.
That hidden gem is there, but once you find it, it might not be perfect. For example, I recently found a Marc Jacobs sweater at our local Salvation Army. It was missing several buttons but I bought it anyway and replaced the buttons. If you can clean it, repurpose it or fix it  go for it.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:35:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>State Road 4 crash kills Pensacola man</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/state-road-4-crash-kills-pensacola-man-1.496368</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>State Road 4 crash kills Pensacola man
By From Staff Reports
Published: Thursday, July 9, 2015 at 09:35 AM.
A 19-year-old Pensacola man died following a two-vehicle crash at the intersection of State Road 4 and Munson Highway on Wednesday evening, according to a Florida Highway Patrol report.
The wreck occurred at 4:35 p.m.
Moses Michael Gabriel Sturges was driving a Ford station wagon south on Munson Highway, approaching SR 4. Raymond E. McDaniel, 60, of Jay, was driving a GMC Sierra pick-up truck east on SR 4 toward Munson Highway.
Sturges failed to stop at a posted stop sign at the intersection and drove into the path of the truck. The front of the truck collided with the right side of the station wagon, according to the FHP report.
McDaniel suffered serious injuries in the crash. Both men were taken to Sacred Heart Hospital, where Sturges died, the report said.
Both drivers were wearing seatbelts at the time of the accident. Alcohol was not a factor in the wreck, according to the report.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:20:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman arrested after accusing husband of hitting her</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/woman-arrested-after-accusing-husband-of-hitting-her-1.496333</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman arrested after accusing husband of hitting her
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 08:20 PM.
NICEVILLE - A 27-year-old Niceville woman called Niceville Police officers on June 20, only to end up arrested herself.
The woman called around 2:17 a.m. to report that her husband had struck her in the face, according to the arrest report. When officers arrived, the woman said her husband had shoved her down in the gravel, slapped her in the face and locked himself in the bedroom.
She had two small, red marks on her face, the report said. When asked why he would shove her, she had no answer other than he'd been drinking whiskey.
Officers spoke with her husband, who said they'd been at the neighbors sitting on the stairs and she'd starting talking about him, according to the report. He told her that if she wanted to talk about him, he'd tell her friends that she called them crazy behind their backs.
He said his wife stood up and kicked him in the face "as hard as she could," the report said. Her friends grabbed her and he walked back toward their residence.
He said she ran at him before he got in the door and he shoved her, at which point she fell in the gravel, according to the report. He said he then went inside and locked the door.
He had a "busted" lip, the report said.
The woman is charged with misdemeanor battery.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:19:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man charged with neglect of 86-year-old man</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-charged-with-neglect-of-86-year-old-man-1.496331</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man charged with neglect of 86-year-old man
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 08:19 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A 46-year-old Fort Walton Beach man is charged with neglecting an elderly man he was supposed to be taking care of.
Fort Walton Beach Police officers went to the 86-year-old man's home on June 20 after getting a report through an abuse hotline, according to the arrest report. Officers and Department of Children and Families employees found the man home alone.
Officers spoke with the man, who was bed-ridden, through an open window, the report said. He invited officers in, but was unable to get up and open the door.
Officers crawled through the open window, finding that the home was "cluttered and extremely hot, with no power or running water, according to the report. The man was positioned next to a bucket to use as a toilet and no food was found in the home.
The man was taken to Fort Walton Beach Medical Center for malnutrition and severe dehydration, eventually being admitted due to poor health, the report said. Officers contacted Ernest Jerome Goshay, who said he'd been the man's caregiver since 2012.
He said he didn't have access to the man's social security income and had stopped receiving the man's pension checks, according to the report. He said he hadn't contacted the man's power of attorney for money to pay the bills because he didn't feel the condition of the home was a problem.
He is charged with neglect of an elderly person.
He is scheduled to appear in court on July 21.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:17:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teens accused of attempted shoplifting</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/teens-accused-of-attempted-shoplifting-1.496330</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Teens accused of attempted shoplifting
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 08:17 PM.
NICEVILLE - Two teenage girls are charged with trying to take $94.73 in merchandise from Walmart, 1300 E. John Sims Pkwy., by concealing it in their purses.
A 17-year-old girl and an 18-year-old girl from Missouri went into Walmart around 3 p.m. on June 20, according to arrest reports. The two allegedly went to several areas of the store, concealing items in their purses.
They then checked out, each purchasing a soda, but neither trying to pay for the merchandise in their purses, reports said. The two were stopped and detained by asset protection.
Items taken included shorts, tops, a little pink football, socks, makeup, makeup brushes and jewelry, according to reports.
They are each charged with shoplifting.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:43:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Okaloosa agrees to local BP settlement</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/okaloosa-agrees-to-local-bp-settlement-1.496286</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Okaloosa agrees to local BP settlement
By KARI C. BARLOW and TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 04:43 PM.
Okaloosa County has agreed to settle its local claim against BP for $1.6 million more than it initially requested.
County Commissioners voted unanimously Tuesday evening to accept BPs proposed settlement of $3.6 million for economic damages incurred by the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill of 2010.
County Attorney Greg Stewart said much of the settlement was additional money BP agreed to part with as an incentive toward settlement.
They are attempting to resolve all of these (local) claims by July 15, Stewart said.
The countys original claim against the oil giant was for $1.9 million.
Okaloosa Countys local claim is part of about $1 billion in local government claims against BP. Last week, the oil giant agreed to pay $18.7 billion in damages for its role in the oil spill.
The overall settlement still must be approved by a federal judge.
Theres still a lot of figuring to be done, County Commission Chairman Nathan Boyles said. I think theres a lot of value in certainty, and we think were getting that, and thats a good thing.
Yet Boyles and other officials expressed frustration with the 15-year payout schedule set forth under the terms of the settlement for funds it will receive through the RESTORE Act.
Okaloosa stands to average $2.3 million a year.
Sal Nodjomian, whose Niceville-based Matrix Design Group is acting as Okaloosas RESTORE Act consultant, said that amount is a nice chunk of change but isnt that once-in-a-lifetime opportunity many counties had expected.
A lot of people believe this was done because of expediency, trying to get it to settlement, Nodjomian said.

MORE BP SETTLEMENT DETAILS:
Santa Rosa County Commissioners will meet at 1:30 p.m. Monday to discuss its proposed local BP settlement in executive session. County Administrator Hunter Walker said the board is expected to convene in open session afterward for a vote.Walton County settled its local BP claim in March 2014 for $7.5 million.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn. Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UDPATE: Navarre man killed in crash on Hurlburt</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/udpate-navarre-man-killed-in-crash-on-hurlburt-1.496284</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>UDPATE: Navarre man killed in crash on Hurlburt
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 04:40 PM.
HURLBURT FIELD  A 43-year-old Navarre man was killed in a crash on Hurlburt Field Tuesday afternoon.
This is the eighth serious crash in the area in the past seven days, with five of them involving motorcycles, four fatalities and three involving a driver 75 years old or older.
Around 4 p.m. Tuesday, 86-year-old Eva Carasso of Destin was driving a 2009 Lincoln Town Car south on an access road on Hurlburt Field, turning left onto Independence Road, according to a media release from Florida Highway Patrol.
Kenyon Nessel, 43, of Navarre, was riding a 1999 Harley Davidson motorcycle west on Independence Road. Carasso made a left turn in front of the motorcycle, causing Nessel to lay down the motorcycle in an attempt to avoid a collision, the release said.
The left front of the Town Car struck the front of the motorcycle.
Nessel was taken to Fort Walton Beach Medi-cal Center, but died.
Carasso was uninjured.
The series of crashes kicked off on July 2 around 2:55 p.m., when 85-year-old Roger Eugene Anderson failed to stop at a stop sign and instead stopped on the railroad tracks in front of an oncoming train in Mossy Head, FHP said.
Anderson survived the initial crash, but succumbed to his injuries two days later.
That same night, at 9:28 p.m., three pedestrians were hit while trying to change a tire.
Joe Mack Wilkins, 76, was driving a 1999 Buick Lasabre on State Road 85 when he came upon the disabled vehicle, which had hazard lights on, FHP said.
Four pedestrians were trying to change the tire, but three of them were standing over the fog line in the roadway. Those three were hit. One of the men, 40-year-old Moabi LeSole of Botswana, Africa, died at the scene, FHP said.
The other two, Kim Eric Alexander Agatep and Kamugisha Kataumba, were taken to North Okaloosa Medical Center for their injuries.

SAFETY TIPS: The Florida Highway Patrols website offers several safety tips, re-minding all drivers to watch out for pedestrians, bicyclists and motorcy-clists.
Tips for motorcyclists include wearing appropriate, easily seen gear, taking a motorcycle rider safety course and riding when alert to avoid being impaired by drowsiness.
Motorcyclists are re-quired to have a motorcycle endorsement on their license or a motorcycle-only license.
The Safe Mobility for Life Coalition, a program partially sponsored by the Florida Department of Transportation, notes that aging drivers, which they classify as over 65, can have difficulties with driv-ing situations like making left turns, driving at night, yielding to traffic and changing lanes.
According to the coalition, Florida has 2.98 million licensed drivers over the age of 65.
They recommend several mature driver safety courses, including classes through AAA and AARP.
The Florida Department of Motor Vehicles requires drivers over the age of 80 to renew their license every six years instead of every eight and to have a vision test with every renewal.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:53:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Disney removes Bill Cosby statue at Hollywood Studios</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/disney-removes-bill-cosby-statue-at-hollywood-studios-1.496253</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Disney removes Bill Cosby statue at Hollywood Studios
In this May 1 photo, a bust of actor and comedian Bill Cosby is on display at Hollywood Studios theme park in Walt Disney World officials removed the bust from the park late Tuesday. The removal of the statute came after court documents unsealed on Monday revealed that Cosby testified in 2005 that he'd obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with.
AP
By The Associated Press
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 03:53 PM.
LAKE BUENA VISTA  Walt Disney World officials say a bronze statue of Bill Cosby is being removed from the Hollywood Studios theme park.
Local news outlets report the statue was being removed after the park closed Tuesday night. Disney offered no other comment.
The removal of the statute at Disney's Academy of Television Arts and Sciences Hall of Fame Plaza came after court documents unsealed on Monday revealed that Cosby testified in 2005 that he'd obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with.
The 77-year-old Cosby hasn't commented on the documents, which were secret for a decade until Monday, after The Associated Press went to court to get them released. He has never been charged with a crime and has repeatedly denied sexual assault allegations.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Auditor General requested to investigate missing $600,000 (LETTERS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/auditor-general-requested-to-investigate-missing-600-000-letters-1.496229</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Auditor General requested to investigate missing $600,000 (LETTERS)
File photo
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 03:20 PM.
State Sen. Don Gaetz and Walton County Attorney Mark Davis have separately requested that the states Auditor General look over the books of the countys Planning Department.
The requests comes about six months into an investigation of the Planning Department by the First Judicial Circuits State Attorneys Office.
State Attorney Bill Eddins office initiated its investigation after receiving information about a 2005 incident in which planning officials failed to collect more than $600,000 in recreation fees from the developers of the Lakeside at Blue Mountain Beach subdivision.
LETTER: Walton County's request for an audit.
That initial inquiry has expanded to encompass activities occurring between 2000 and 2012, and has required the review of hundreds of documents, said Walton County Chief Assistant State Attorney Greg Anchors, who is heading the Planning Department investigation.
It has uncovered areas of concern, according to Eddins, who intends to convene a grand jury at the conclusion of the investigation to review the findings.
Davis request for Attorney General action went out Wednesday. Sent at the request of the county commission, it requests an operational audit of the Walton County Planning Department for the years 2000 through 2012.
Gaetz, R-Niceville, sent a letter dated June 29 to state Sen. Joe Abruzzo, the chairman of Floridas Joint Legislative Audit Committee.
He said he did so after receiving correspondence from Walton County Commissioner Cindy Meadows corroborating what hed already read about the State Attorneys investigation.
It seemed to me this issue was ripe for an outside, independent financial audit, Gaetz said.
Gaetz said he has received assurance from Senate President Andy Gardiner that his request for an audit would be approved. He said a work plan would have to be established before the audit could be approved and scheduled.
Anchors said Wednesday he anticipates the Auditor Generals focus could uncover items his office has not.
Looking at the money will go beyond what were doing in some areas, he said.
Abruzzos office did not return a phone call seeking comment.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:57:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teen commits suicide at local marina</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/teen-commits-suicide-at-local-marina-1.496121</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Teen commits suicide at local marina
File photo
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 10:57 AM.
Walton County deputies rushed to the marina at Baytowne Wharf early Wednesday to cordon off an area where a teenager apparently killed himself in a very public setting.
A 15- to16-year-old male has hung himself at the marina, Walton County Sheriffs Office spokeswoman Corey Dobridnia said at shortly before 9 a.m.
Crime scene investigators hoped to cordon off the area as quickly as possible.
The hanging site was visible from the road running past the marina, Dobridnia said.
We want people to stay away. To avoid that area, Dobridnia said. Were urging residents and visitors, especially if accompanied by children, to dont be nosy.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:45:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BILL CAMPBELL'S BLOG: Court-ordered restitution doesn't always work</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/bill-campbell-s-blog-court-ordered-restitution-doesn-t-always-work-1.496111</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>BILL CAMPBELL'S BLOG: Court-ordered restitution doesn't always work
By BILL CAMPBELL | Daily News blogger
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 10:45 AM.
The oft-quoted state Rep. Matt Gaetz made headlines when he pushed through a bill that would  hang on, granny  require public officials convicted of corruption to make restitution.
Anyone with an IQ over room temperature is forgiven for saying, Duh?
But it hasnt always worked, even when courts order said restitution.
Which brings us to David Selby. He was the attorney for the Okaloosa County School Board until 1990. Thats when it was discovered hed absconded with 21 bucks short of $200,000.
He was sentenced to three years in prison  for which he served 67 days  and ordered to repay the money over 15 years. Didnt happen.
Selby got the court-ordered $1,137 reduced to $200 a month. Do the math. You know how long it takes to repay $199,721 at $200 a month? It was kind of the judge to think Selby would live to be 130.
But were not quite done. After Selbys probation was over, POOF! No Selby.
I think he might be living in Alabama, said current School District Attorney Jeff McInnis, an honorable man. He said he was told we have no legal jurisdiction or resources to pursue Selby.
McInnis thinks we may have gotten thirty, maybe thirty-five thousand dollars back from Selby.
So, young Gaetz, congrats on your bill. Heres hoping it has more sticking power than what was extant in 1990.
And heres a question for your dad, who was on the School Board after Selby was jailed: Who the hell vetted Selby?
Dad wasnt there when Selby was hired or fired, but maybe he could ask around. Not that there was any love lost between them. Don Gaetz said, Frankly, as far as Im concerned, since the payback plan is sort of a bad joke, Id rather have him sit in jail.
Sadly, neither happened.
The senior Gaetz took exception to an earlier version of this blog, which indicated he was on the board when this all went down. He certainly was not, but methinks if he had been, none of this would have happened.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crash on Hurlburt kills Navarre man</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crash-on-hurlburt-kills-navarre-man-1.496107</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Crash on Hurlburt kills Navarre man
By From Staff Reports
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 10:27 AM.
HURLBURT FIELDAir Force security forces and the Florida Highway patrol are investigating a Tuesday afternoon vehicle accident that killed a Navarre man.
The accident occurred at 4 p.m. near the intersection of Independence Road and Terry Avenue, according to an FHP report.
A Lincoln Town Car driven by 86-year-old Eve Carasso of Destin was headed south on an access road toward Independence Road. Carasso made a left turn onto Independence Road into the path of a Harley-Davidson motorcycle driven by 43-year-old Kenyon Nessel.
According to the report, Nessel laid the motorcycle down in an attempt to avoid a collision, but the left front of the Lincoln struck the front of the motorcycle.
Nessel, a civilian employee at Hurlburt Field, was wearing a helmet and was taken to Fort Walton Beach Medical Center. Carassom, who was wearing a seatbelt, suffered no injuries.
No charges have been filed in the accident.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:31:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man sentenced to 8 years on drug charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-sentenced-to-8-years-on-drug-charges-1.496094</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man sentenced to 8 years on drug charges
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 09:31 PM.
MILTON - A 37-year-old Pensacola man was sentenced to eight years in prison Monday a Santa Rosa County jury found him guilty of drug charges.
David Gerald Fields was convicted of manufacturing a controlled substance and possession of a listed chemical, according to the State Attorneys Office.
Fields was arrested Nov. 17, 2014, after Santa Rosa County sheriff's deputies responded to a report of a methamphetamine lab in Milton.
Fields and three other people ran from the home but were caught.
Deputies found various chemicals used to making meth in the home.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:30:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two people injured in motorcycle crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/two-people-injured-in-motorcycle-crash-1.496093</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two people injured in motorcycle crash
Stock photography
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 09:30 PM.
MILTON - Two Pensacola residents were injured Monday night when the motorcycle they were riding collided with a car on Willard Norris Road.
Michael Edward Theodorovich Jr., 34, of Milton, was driving a Kia west about 8:35 p.m. when Gregory S. Ward, who driving 2006 Honday motorcycle ahead of him, made an abrupt U-turn, according to the Florida Highway Patrol.
Theodorovich didnt see the motorcycle approaching and turned in front of Ward. The motorcycle hit the left side of the Kia, the FHP said.
Ward and his passenger, 44-year-old Jill M. Ward of Pensacola, were taken to Sacred Heart Hospital in serious condition.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
