<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nwfdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:43:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Okaloosa agrees to local BP settlement</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/okaloosa-agrees-to-local-bp-settlement-1.496286</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Okaloosa agrees to local BP settlement
By KARI C. BARLOW and TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 04:43 PM.
Okaloosa County has agreed to settle its local claim against BP for $1.6 million more than it initially requested.
County Commissioners voted unanimously Tuesday evening to accept BPs proposed settlement of $3.6 million for economic damages incurred by the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill of 2010.
County Attorney Greg Stewart said much of the settlement was additional money BP agreed to part with as an incentive toward settlement.
They are attempting to resolve all of these (local) claims by July 15, Stewart said.
The countys original claim against the oil giant was for $1.9 million.
Okaloosa Countys local claim is part of about $1 billion in local government claims against BP. Last week, the oil giant agreed to pay $18.7 billion in damages for its role in the oil spill.
The overall settlement still must be approved by a federal judge.
Theres still a lot of figuring to be done, County Commission Chairman Nathan Boyles said. I think theres a lot of value in certainty, and we think were getting that, and thats a good thing.
Yet Boyles and other officials expressed frustration with the 15-year payout schedule set forth under the terms of the settlement for funds it will receive through the RESTORE Act.
Okaloosa stands to average $2.3 million a year.
Sal Nodjomian, whose Niceville-based Matrix Design Group is acting as Okaloosas RESTORE Act consultant, said that amount is a nice chunk of change but isnt that once-in-a-lifetime opportunity many counties had expected.
A lot of people believe this was done because of expediency, trying to get it to settlement, Nodjomian said.

MORE BP SETTLEMENT DETAILS:
Santa Rosa County Commissioners will meet at 1:30 p.m. Monday to discuss its proposed local BP settlement in executive session. County Administrator Hunter Walker said the board is expected to convene in open session afterward for a vote.Walton County settled its local BP claim in March 2014 for $7.5 million.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn. Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UDPATE: Navarre man killed in crash on Hurlburt</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/udpate-navarre-man-killed-in-crash-on-hurlburt-1.496284</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>UDPATE: Navarre man killed in crash on Hurlburt
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 04:40 PM.
HURLBURT FIELD  A 43-year-old Navarre man was killed in a crash on Hurlburt Field Tuesday afternoon.
This is the eighth serious crash in the area in the past seven days, with five of them involving motorcycles, four fatalities and three involving a driver 75 years old or older.
Around 4 p.m. Tuesday, 86-year-old Eva Carasso of Destin was driving a 2009 Lincoln Town Car south on an access road on Hurlburt Field, turning left onto Independence Road, according to a media release from Florida Highway Patrol.
Kenyon Nessel, 43, of Navarre, was riding a 1999 Harley Davidson motorcycle west on Independence Road. Carasso made a left turn in front of the motorcycle, causing Nessel to lay down the motorcycle in an attempt to avoid a collision, the release said.
The left front of the Town Car struck the front of the motorcycle.
Nessel was taken to Fort Walton Beach Medi-cal Center, but died.
Carasso was uninjured.
The series of crashes kicked off on July 2 around 2:55 p.m., when 85-year-old Roger Eugene Anderson failed to stop at a stop sign and instead stopped on the railroad tracks in front of an oncoming train in Mossy Head, FHP said.
Anderson survived the initial crash, but succumbed to his injuries two days later.
That same night, at 9:28 p.m., three pedestrians were hit while trying to change a tire.
Joe Mack Wilkins, 76, was driving a 1999 Buick Lasabre on State Road 85 when he came upon the disabled vehicle, which had hazard lights on, FHP said.
Four pedestrians were trying to change the tire, but three of them were standing over the fog line in the roadway. Those three were hit. One of the men, 40-year-old Moabi LeSole of Botswana, Africa, died at the scene, FHP said.
The other two, Kim Eric Alexander Agatep and Kamugisha Kataumba, were taken to North Okaloosa Medical Center for their injuries.

SAFETY TIPS: The Florida Highway Patrols website offers several safety tips, re-minding all drivers to watch out for pedestrians, bicyclists and motorcy-clists.
Tips for motorcyclists include wearing appropriate, easily seen gear, taking a motorcycle rider safety course and riding when alert to avoid being impaired by drowsiness.
Motorcyclists are re-quired to have a motorcycle endorsement on their license or a motorcycle-only license.
The Safe Mobility for Life Coalition, a program partially sponsored by the Florida Department of Transportation, notes that aging drivers, which they classify as over 65, can have difficulties with driv-ing situations like making left turns, driving at night, yielding to traffic and changing lanes.
According to the coalition, Florida has 2.98 million licensed drivers over the age of 65.
They recommend several mature driver safety courses, including classes through AAA and AARP.
The Florida Department of Motor Vehicles requires drivers over the age of 80 to renew their license every six years instead of every eight and to have a vision test with every renewal.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:53:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Disney removes Bill Cosby statue at Hollywood Studios</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/disney-removes-bill-cosby-statue-at-hollywood-studios-1.496253</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Disney removes Bill Cosby statue at Hollywood Studios
In this May 1 photo, a bust of actor and comedian Bill Cosby is on display at Hollywood Studios theme park in Walt Disney World officials removed the bust from the park late Tuesday. The removal of the statute came after court documents unsealed on Monday revealed that Cosby testified in 2005 that he'd obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with.
AP
By The Associated Press
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 03:53 PM.
LAKE BUENA VISTA  Walt Disney World officials say a bronze statue of Bill Cosby is being removed from the Hollywood Studios theme park.
Local news outlets report the statue was being removed after the park closed Tuesday night. Disney offered no other comment.
The removal of the statute at Disney's Academy of Television Arts and Sciences Hall of Fame Plaza came after court documents unsealed on Monday revealed that Cosby testified in 2005 that he'd obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with.
The 77-year-old Cosby hasn't commented on the documents, which were secret for a decade until Monday, after The Associated Press went to court to get them released. He has never been charged with a crime and has repeatedly denied sexual assault allegations.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Auditor General requested to investigate missing $600,000 (LETTERS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/auditor-general-requested-to-investigate-missing-600-000-letters-1.496229</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Auditor General requested to investigate missing $600,000 (LETTERS)
File photo
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 03:20 PM.
State Sen. Don Gaetz and Walton County Attorney Mark Davis have separately requested that the states Auditor General look over the books of the countys Planning Department.
The requests comes about six months into an investigation of the Planning Department by the First Judicial Circuits State Attorneys Office.
State Attorney Bill Eddins office initiated its investigation after receiving information about a 2005 incident in which planning officials failed to collect more than $600,000 in recreation fees from the developers of the Lakeside at Blue Mountain Beach subdivision.
LETTER: Walton County's request for an audit.
That initial inquiry has expanded to encompass activities occurring between 2000 and 2012, and has required the review of hundreds of documents, said Walton County Chief Assistant State Attorney Greg Anchors, who is heading the Planning Department investigation.
It has uncovered areas of concern, according to Eddins, who intends to convene a grand jury at the conclusion of the investigation to review the findings.
Davis request for Attorney General action went out Wednesday. Sent at the request of the county commission, it requests an operational audit of the Walton County Planning Department for the years 2000 through 2012.
Gaetz, R-Niceville, sent a letter dated June 29 to state Sen. Joe Abruzzo, the chairman of Floridas Joint Legislative Audit Committee.
He said he did so after receiving correspondence from Walton County Commissioner Cindy Meadows corroborating what hed already read about the State Attorneys investigation.
It seemed to me this issue was ripe for an outside, independent financial audit, Gaetz said.
Gaetz said he has received assurance from Senate President Andy Gardiner that his request for an audit would be approved. He said a work plan would have to be established before the audit could be approved and scheduled.
Anchors said Wednesday he anticipates the Auditor Generals focus could uncover items his office has not.
Looking at the money will go beyond what were doing in some areas, he said.
Abruzzos office did not return a phone call seeking comment.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:57:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teen commits suicide at local marina</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/teen-commits-suicide-at-local-marina-1.496121</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Teen commits suicide at local marina
File photo
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 10:57 AM.
Walton County deputies rushed to the marina at Baytowne Wharf early Wednesday to cordon off an area where a teenager apparently killed himself in a very public setting.
A 15- to16-year-old male has hung himself at the marina, Walton County Sheriffs Office spokeswoman Corey Dobridnia said at shortly before 9 a.m.
Crime scene investigators hoped to cordon off the area as quickly as possible.
The hanging site was visible from the road running past the marina, Dobridnia said.
We want people to stay away. To avoid that area, Dobridnia said. Were urging residents and visitors, especially if accompanied by children, to dont be nosy.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:45:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BILL CAMPBELL'S BLOG: Court-ordered restitution doesn't always work</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/bill-campbell-s-blog-court-ordered-restitution-doesn-t-always-work-1.496111</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>BILL CAMPBELL'S BLOG: Court-ordered restitution doesn't always work
By BILL CAMPBELL | Daily News blogger
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 10:45 AM.
The oft-quoted state Rep. Matt Gaetz made headlines when he pushed through a bill that would  hang on, granny  require public officials convicted of corruption to make restitution.
Anyone with an IQ over room temperature is forgiven for saying, Duh?
But it hasnt always worked, even when courts order said restitution.
Which brings us to David Selby. He was the attorney for the Okaloosa County School Board until 1990. Thats when it was discovered hed absconded with 21 bucks short of $200,000.
He was sentenced to three years in prison  for which he served 67 days  and ordered to repay the money over 15 years. Didnt happen.
Selby got the court-ordered $1,137 reduced to $200 a month. Do the math. You know how long it takes to repay $199,721 at $200 a month? It was kind of the judge to think Selby would live to be 130.
But were not quite done. After Selbys probation was over, POOF! No Selby.
I think he might be living in Alabama, said current School District Attorney Jeff McInnis, an honorable man. He said he was told we have no legal jurisdiction or resources to pursue Selby.
McInnis thinks we may have gotten thirty, maybe thirty-five thousand dollars back from Selby.
So, young Gaetz, congrats on your bill. Heres hoping it has more sticking power than what was extant in 1990.
And heres a question for your dad, who was on the School Board after Selby was jailed: Who the hell vetted Selby?
Dad wasnt there when Selby was hired or fired, but maybe he could ask around. Not that there was any love lost between them. Don Gaetz said, Frankly, as far as Im concerned, since the payback plan is sort of a bad joke, Id rather have him sit in jail.
Sadly, neither happened.
The senior Gaetz took exception to an earlier version of this blog, which indicated he was on the board when this all went down. He certainly was not, but methinks if he had been, none of this would have happened.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crash on Hurlburt kills Navarre man</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crash-on-hurlburt-kills-navarre-man-1.496107</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Crash on Hurlburt kills Navarre man
By From Staff Reports
Published: Wednesday, July 8, 2015 at 10:27 AM.
HURLBURT FIELDAir Force security forces and the Florida Highway patrol are investigating a Tuesday afternoon vehicle accident that killed a Navarre man.
The accident occurred at 4 p.m. near the intersection of Independence Road and Terry Avenue, according to an FHP report.
A Lincoln Town Car driven by 86-year-old Eve Carasso of Destin was headed south on an access road toward Independence Road. Carasso made a left turn onto Independence Road into the path of a Harley-Davidson motorcycle driven by 43-year-old Kenyon Nessel.
According to the report, Nessel laid the motorcycle down in an attempt to avoid a collision, but the left front of the Lincoln struck the front of the motorcycle.
Nessel, a civilian employee at Hurlburt Field, was wearing a helmet and was taken to Fort Walton Beach Medical Center. Carassom, who was wearing a seatbelt, suffered no injuries.
No charges have been filed in the accident.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:31:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man sentenced to 8 years on drug charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-sentenced-to-8-years-on-drug-charges-1.496094</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man sentenced to 8 years on drug charges
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 09:31 PM.
MILTON - A 37-year-old Pensacola man was sentenced to eight years in prison Monday a Santa Rosa County jury found him guilty of drug charges.
David Gerald Fields was convicted of manufacturing a controlled substance and possession of a listed chemical, according to the State Attorneys Office.
Fields was arrested Nov. 17, 2014, after Santa Rosa County sheriff's deputies responded to a report of a methamphetamine lab in Milton.
Fields and three other people ran from the home but were caught.
Deputies found various chemicals used to making meth in the home.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:30:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two people injured in motorcycle crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/two-people-injured-in-motorcycle-crash-1.496093</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two people injured in motorcycle crash
Stock photography
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 09:30 PM.
MILTON - Two Pensacola residents were injured Monday night when the motorcycle they were riding collided with a car on Willard Norris Road.
Michael Edward Theodorovich Jr., 34, of Milton, was driving a Kia west about 8:35 p.m. when Gregory S. Ward, who driving 2006 Honday motorcycle ahead of him, made an abrupt U-turn, according to the Florida Highway Patrol.
Theodorovich didnt see the motorcycle approaching and turned in front of Ward. The motorcycle hit the left side of the Kia, the FHP said.
Ward and his passenger, 44-year-old Jill M. Ward of Pensacola, were taken to Sacred Heart Hospital in serious condition.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:17:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man reports road rage incident</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-reports-road-rage-incident-1.496092</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man reports road rage incident
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 09:17 PM.
NICEVILLE - A man called Niceville Police officers around 3 p.m. on June 19 to report an act of road rage in the Walmart parking lot, 1300 E. John Sims Pkwy.
The man said a large male in a work uniform of some kind cut him off in traffic, according to the call log. He said the man then brandished a weapon out the window and made a "bang noise."
The man's vehicle was seen pulling into Publix after that, the log said. The caller described the vehicle as having dark tinted windows, but was unable to describe the gun.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:15:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of carrying gun at The Swamp</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-carrying-gun-at-the-swamp-1.496090</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of carrying gun at The Swamp
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 09:15 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A 33-year-old Fort Walton Beach man is accused of having a loaded firearm tucked in the back of his pants while at The Swamp.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's deputies were called to the bar around 12:30 a.m. on June 19 by the head of security, according to the arrest report. He had heard that a man inside the bar was carrying a concealed firearm and had seen a bulge under the man's shirt.
Deputies spoke to the man, identified as Marcus Santrez Kenney, and asked him to step outside to talk, the report said. When they walked toward the door, deputies could see a bulge at the small of his back.
Kenney was detained and officers found a gun loaded with eight rounds and tucked into Kenney's waistband, according to the report. He does not have a concealed carry permit.
He is charged with carrying a concealed firearm.
His is scheduled to appear in court on July 21.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:14:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man allegedly pulls gun during chase</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-allegedly-pulls-gun-during-chase-1.496088</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man allegedly pulls gun during chase
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 09:14 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A 33-year-old Fort Walton Beach man is facing multiple charges, including pulling a pistol on a police officer during a foot chase.
Fort Walton Beach Police officers tried to pull Dennis Alexander Toomer over at 8:10 p.m. on July 5 for illegal window tinting, according to the arrest report. When officers turned their lights on, Toomer allegedly fled.
After a short car chase, Toomer stopped the vehicle and fled on foot, the report said. Officers gave chase through backyards, and Toomer fell to the ground in a driveway.
He started reaching into his pant's pockets and when officer flipped him onto his back, was holding a pistol, "clutched in his hands pulled to his chest," according to the report. The officer tried to gain control of the pistol and was eventually able to wrestle it away from Toomer.
Officers found one gram of methamphetamine and 2.1 grams of crack cocaine in Toomer's pockets after he was arrested, the report said. An additional 105.1 grams of crack cocaine was found on the path where he'd fled, but he denied that they were his.
While at the hospital, Toomer claimed he'd never had a gun, then said he "had a gun to protect himself," according to the report. He also allegedly admitted to selling narcotics.
He is charged with aggravated assault with a deadly weapon without intent to kill, possession of a firearm by a convicted felon, possession of a controlled substance, resisting an officer with violence and resisting an officer without violence.
He is scheduled to appear in court on Aug. 18.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 00:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police officers accused of harassment rehired</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/police-officers-accused-of-harassment-rehired-1.496059</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Police officers accused of harassment rehired
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 05:17 PM.
Two DeFuniak Springs police officers fired June 3 for racial harassment are back on the department payroll.
At least for now.
Patrolman Rick Boblitt and Sgt. Anthony Kaiser were terminated following an internal investigation into allegations Boblitt routinely harassed a fellow officer of Asian descent for several years.
Kaiser was fired for failing to take any action to put an end to the harassment.
They have been reinstated and placed on paid administrative leave pending a hearing before City Manager Sara Bowers, according to DeFuniak Springs Mayor Bob Campbell.
They get an official appeal to tell their side of the story, Campbell said.
Following a hearing, Bowers will determine whether Police Chief Mark Weeks acted correctly when he fired Boblitt and Kaiser.
She has the authority to finalize the terminations or reinstate the officers.
Its not really a day in court, its a day in the city managers office, Campbell said.
The officers have just been reinstated and no hearing date has been established, Campbell said.
Witnesses told those investigating Boblitt and Kaiser that theyd heard Boblitt speaking to the victim in a mocking Asian accent, and calling him names like Kung Fu Panda, a report said.
Boblitt, a city police officer for 16 years, admitted to making some of the comments, but said they were made between two friends and were not intended to be malicious, the internal investigation report said.
Kaiser a supervisor with five years on the force, found nothing inappropriate in Boblitt's comments, the investigation found.
He told investigators he was present when Boblitt made some of the comments, but thought it was friendly banter between co-workers and never crossed the line to harassment, according to the report.
Weeks declined to comment directly on the case. He denied through an employee that Boblitt and Kaiser were back at work with the city and made reference through the employee to a grievance process.
Bowers said the hearing is being held at the request of Boblitt and Kaiser and will correct a procedural error made at the time of the firings.
She said the officers will receive pay dating back to the time they were fired.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 00:03:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Birds mysteriously abandon colony; experts baffled</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/birds-mysteriously-abandon-colony-experts-baffled-1.496055</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Birds mysteriously abandon colony; experts baffled
In this June 19 photo, a variety of birds gather in branches at Snake Key near Seahorse Key, off Floridas Gulf Coast. In May, Seahorse Key fell eerily quiet, as thousands of birds suddenly disappeared, and biologists are trying to find the reason why. U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service biologist Vic Doig said what was once the largest bird colony on the states Gulf Coast is now a dead zone.
AP
By The Associated Press
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 05:03 PM.
SEAHORSE KEY  The din created by thousands of nesting birds is usually the first thing you notice about Seahorse Key, a 150-acre mangrove-covered dune off Florida's Gulf Coast.
But in May, the key fell eerily quiet all at once.
Thousands of little blue herons, roseate spoonbills, snowy egrets, pelicans and other chattering birds were gone. Nests sat empty in trees; eggs broken and scattered on the muddy ground.
"It's a dead zone now," said Vic Doig, a U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service biologist. "This is where the largest bird colony on the Gulf Coast of Florida used to be."
For decades, Seahorse Key has been a protected way station for myriad bird species. It's part of the Cedar Keys National Wildlife Refuge, which was established in 1929 as a sanctuary for birds devastated by decades of hunting for their colorful plumage. Accessible only by boat, today it's a rare island off Florida not dominated by human activity and development.
When the birds come to nest, so too do biologists and naturalists who study the different colonies. But this year, the birds' exit has the state's avian biologists scrambling for answers.
"It's not uncommon for birds to abandon nests," said Peter Frederick, a University of Florida wildlife biologist who has studied Florida's birds for nearly 30 years. "But, in this case, what's puzzling is that all of the species did it all at once."
Doig said some of the Seahorse birds seem to have moved to a nearby island, but they're just a fraction of the tens of thousands of birds that would normally be nesting on the key right now.
To find answers, service biologists have been acting on the few clues they have.
First, they tested left-behind bird carcasses for disease or contaminants. Those tests came back negative.
Next, they researched possible new predators. Did raccoons swim over from another island? Perhaps some great horned owls flew out at night and started feasting?
Traps caught a few raccoons, which is common, but not enough to have created a wholesale abandonment. There were no telltale signs of owls.
Finally, Doig said, recent years have seen an increase in night flights over the area by surveillance planes and helicopters used to combat drug runners. Although the planes' noise could be disruptive, Doig admits it's a longshot.
The abandonment concerns biologists because it could have a ripple effect: Many bird species here return year after year to the same nesting sites. The disruption provokes anxiety that this important island refuge could somehow be lost.
"Any rookery that's persisted for decades as one of the largest colonies is incredibly important," said Janell Brush, an avian researcher with the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission. "It's quite a large colony. There had to be some intense event that would drive all these birds away."
Biologist also don't know how the disappearance will affect the island's other animals, some of which rely on the birds to survive. Cottonmouth snakes eat bird predators like rodents, and in turn the birds drop lots of fish and other nutrients from the trees to feed the snakes.
In the meantime, tour operators that once spent hours taking naturalists and bird watchers to the island are making other plans.
Mike O'Dell runs tours out of the little marina in nearby Cedar Key. He said on a Tuesday in May he led a group out to view thousands of birds crowding the shores of the key. On Wednesday, there was nothing.
"It's just that drastic," O'Dell said. "There were none. It's like a different world."

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 23:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Appeal likely in Destin YMCA decision</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/appeal-likely-in-destin-ymca-decision-1.496035</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Appeal likely in Destin YMCA decision
File photo
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 04:31 PM.
DESTIN  An appeal of a recent Circuit Court ruling will indefinitely delay any decision on the fate of the former home of the Destin YMCA.
Beach Community Bank has filed notice of its intent to appeal Circuit Court Judge William Stones June ruling that gave control of the former Destin Y property to the Mattie Kelly Arts Foundation.
Stone said the Y building, pool and grounds became Arts Foundation property when a bankruptcy trustee abandoned it in January.
The ruling would have left the Arts Foundation board free to decide between the Emerald Coast Wildlife Refuge and a group called Emerald Coast Fitness Foundation as its choice to be the buildings next tenant.
But Arts Foundation President Marcia Hull said the board will not move forward with a court appeal pending and she doesnt expect the First District Court of Appeal to rule in the case before fall.
We could not enter into a binding agreement with anyone due to the pending litigation, Hull said.
Hull said if the Appeals Court does rule in favor of the Arts Foundation, the foundation board will still have to obtain approval for its choice of tenant from the Mattie Kelly 908 Trust and Kelly family heirs.
Mattie Kellys will laid down strict guidelines for what was to be built on the 42 acres she gave the Mattie Kelly Arts Foundation and was highly restrictive of any purpose outside of a Destin Family YMCA, Hull said.
A marine mammal institute and senior citizen programming were two areas Kelly specified as possibly appropriate uses for the property, Hull said.
Were bound by the litigation, but our ultimate decision will be based on requirements of the deed, she said.
Also important in the foundation boards ultimate decision, Hull said, was that the next tenant provides a sustainable business plan.
The last thing we want to do is put a tenant in there where a year from now we find ourselves in the same boat were in now, she said.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 23:27:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Girl mouths 'Help me'; man charged with sexual assault</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/girl-mouths-help-me-man-charged-with-sexual-assault-1.496022</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Girl mouths 'Help me'; man charged with sexual assault
Fidel Mandujano Jr.
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 04:27 PM.
SEASIDE  A man has been charged with sexual assault after deputies on a foot patrol at Seaside noticed a girl sitting on his lap mouthing the words help me.
The deputies were on patrol around midnight on Friday when they decided to do one more lap around the area when they noticed Fidel Mandujano Jr., sitting with the victim in his lap near the pavilion, according to a media release from the Walton County Sheriffs Office.
The victim was mouthing the words help me and as deputies got closer, one of them heard her say, help me, he wont let me go, the release said.
Deputies ordered Mandujano, who had his arm wrapped around the girls waist, to let her go. She was released and appeared to be scared, shaking and teary eyed, according to the release.
The victim told authorities she got separated from friends and was walking on the beach heading home when Mandujano approached her and tried to kiss her.
She tried to leave, but he grabbed her by the waist and pulled her onto the bench on his lap. She tried again to explain that she needed to leave, but he said she needed to stay with him and fondled her, according to the release.
She said she tried to get up and leave, but he wouldnt let her until deputies walked up, the release said.
Mandujano is charged with sexual assault and false imprisonment.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 23:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>School Resource Officers gain national recognition</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/school-resource-officers-gain-national-recognition-1.496019</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>School Resource Officers gain national recognition
Special to the Daily News
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 04:22 PM.
Okaloosa County School Resource Officers were recognized Tuesday as having one of the top programs in the country.
The National Association of School Resource Officers named the Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office unit a model agency and said they exemplify the high levels of providing security, education, counseling and mentoring to students, according to a news release from Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office.
It was an extremely proud moment for our entire agency today at the NASRO Annual Conference in Orlando, said Sheriff Larry Ashley in the release.
VIDEO: About the SRO program.
These deputies are responsible for such a diverse but critical mission.
The SROs handle a variety of responsibilities, including monitoring gang activity, teaching the Teen Driver Safety Challenge and mentoring struggling youths.
Ashley said the SROs couldnt do their jobs without help from the parents, teachers, administrators and school district.
Their level of excellence is the reason they stand out, Ashley said. Sgt. Gary Venuti was named the states top SRO in 2012 and last year our deputies were awarded Floridas SRO Unit of the Year.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 20:42:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Escambia deputy prefiles to run for Santa Rosa County Sheriff</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/election-news/escambia-deputy-prefiles-to-run-for-santa-rosa-county-sheriff-1.495939</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Escambia deputy prefiles to run for Santa Rosa County Sheriff
Sgt. Ted Roy
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at 01:42 PM.
GULF BREEZE  Escambia County Sheriffs Office Sgt. Ted Roy has become the second person to pre-file to run in the 2016 race for Santa Rosa County Sheriff.
Roy, a Republican from Gulf Breeze, has worked for the Escambia County Sheriffs Office since 1995.
He joins Robert Johnson, a Republican from Navarre, who pre-filed earlier this year.
Roy said he is eager to apply his leadership abilities and team focus to Santa Rosa County.
I feel that there is no greater responsibility than being entrusted with protecting the people of Santa Rosa County, he said.
Prior to joining the Escambia County Sheriffs Office, Roy served eight years in the U.S. Air Force as a security police officer.
At the Escambia County Sheriffs Office, his experience has included the SWAT team, public information, community policing, bicycle patrol and investigations.
Roy holds a bachelors degree in resource management from Troy University.
Roy is active in the Pensacola Sports Association, Baptist Hospital Foundation, Florida SWAT Association and the local trauma intervention program. For the past seven years, he has served as the race director of the In Hot Pursuit 5k, which supports the Florida Sheriffs Youth Ranch. He also is a graduate of the Greater Pensacola Chamber Leadership Pensacola Class of 2012.
Roy and his wife, Lisa, have five children.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UPDATE: Plan to move Confederate memorial draws mixed responses</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crestview-confederate-flag-coming-down-1.495837</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>UPDATE: Plan to move Confederate memorial draws mixed responses
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 09:11 PM.
CRESTVIEW  A proposal to remove a memorial to William Uncle Bill Lundy and the Confederate battle flag that flies over it has not been universally praised.
Critics include former Okaloosa County NAACP President Sabu Williams and Greg Lundy, Uncle Bills great great grandson.
Crestview Mayor David Cadle announced Monday that Foy Lundy, another Lundy relative, had offered to allow the memorial and the Confederate flag to be moved to private property owned by the family. The memorial is currently located about a half mile from the Okaloosa County Courthouse in Crestview.
Following his discussion with Foy Lundy, Cadle called off a Tuesday public meeting to discuss removing the flag from the memorial.
He said details of the plan need to be fleshed out and the City Council must be brought into the conversation before anything can move forward.
Greg Lundys criticism of the plan primarily centered around the fact the meeting had been cancelled.
He said he wants to voice again his familys belief that the Confederate flag flying at the Lundy memorial is about heritage, and not hate.
The city of Crestview was going to give us one more chance to state our opinion, Greg Lundy said. I honestly believe we deserved our chance. Then, if the majority wanted it moved I would have been fine with it.
The issue of the Confederate flags removal has arisen several times over the years, most recently following a racially motivated killing of nine at a church in Charleston.
Williams has always been at the forefront of the push to remove the flag.
In a message from Korea, where he is working for the Air Force, Williams Tuesday applauded the Lundy familys offer to move the memorial, but called the citys role in the endeavor a travesty.
The biggest travesty in this whole story is the fact that the city of Crestviews leadership is shirking its responsibility and allowing the Lundy family to provide them with political cover rather than them having to make a decision, he said. Im sure the City Council is breathing a great sigh of relief, but they really should be ashamed of themselves.
Cadle said if the decision is made to remove the monument, city equipment will be used to haul it from the Crestview right of way it currently occupies to its new home.
While the Lundy family owns land close to the First Avenue/State Highway 95 intersection, Greg Lundy said hed like to see the memorial located in a more public setting.
One suggestion has been putting it at the Almarante cemetery where Bill Lundy, rumored to be the last surviving Confederate veteran, was laid to rest in 1957.
A location in Auburn, where the memorial could be seen from the road, has also been discussed, Lundy said.
The Lions Club of Crestview was responsible for establishing the memorial in 1958 at a location that later became home to a Florida Highway Patrol station. The memorial was later moved to make room for the FHP building.
Original coverage
CRESTVIEW -- The descendants of Bill Lundy may have come up with a proposal to allow the dignified removal of the Confederate Flag from near the Okaloosa County Courthouse.
Family members have agreed to remove a memorial to Lundy, believed to have been the second longest living Civil War veteran, to private land, according to a release issued Monday by Crestview Mayor David Cadle.
The memorial is not the property of the City of Crestview and the Lundy family can claim possession, Cadle said in his release.
Okaloosa Countys NAACP leadership has been calling for years for the Confederate flag to be removed from its present location at East First Avenue and State Road 85.
A petition was circulated again this year following the racially motivated massacre of nine African-American churchgoers in Charleston S.C.
Current local chapter President Ray Nelson said though the NAACP did not directly participate in negotiations between the city and Lundy family, the end result did not shock him.
It wasnt a big surprise, I was expecting to hear it, Nelson said.
Nelson said he had spoken to Cadle Monday afternoon. The mayor couldnt be reached for comment later in the day.
Nelson said, and the news release confirmed, that details of the memorial being moved are still being ironed out.
Nelson said he has proposed that the flag itself be removed immediately while moving the memorial structure is discussed.
The problem was not with the memorial, but with the flag itself, he said.
With a compromise reached, Cadle also announced that a special meeting of the Crestview City Council, scheduled for 5:30 p.m., Tuesday, would be called off.
According to the news release the Lundy memorial was on Okaloosa County land until a Highway Patrol office was erected and the city permitted the memorial to be moved to its current location.
Daily News records indicate the memorial was originally erected in 1958, one year after Lundys death.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 01:04:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/photos-car-accident-at-beal-and-crewilla-1.495819</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 06:04 PM.
A car accident at the intersection of Beal Parkway and Crewilla Drive tied up traffic Monday afternoon. Nobody was injured in the wreck.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
COMMENTS
PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
http://www.nwfdailynews.com July 6, 2015 18:4
A car accident at the intersection of Beal Parkway and Crewilla Drive tied up traffic Monday afternoon. Nobody was injured in the wreck.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
