<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:39:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Exclusive: Japan interested in joining NATO missile consortium</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/zsC6WzcUrmo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TOKYO (Reuters) - Japan is interested in joining a NATO missile building consortium that would give Tokyo its first taste of a multinational defense project, a move the U.S. Navy is encouraging because it could pave the way for Japan to lead similar partnerships in Asia, sources said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Exclusive: Japan interested in joining NATO missile consortium
TOKYO | By Tim Kelly and Nobuhiro Kubo
TOKYO Japan is interested in joining a NATO missile building consortium that would give Tokyo its first taste of a multinational defense project, a move the U.S. Navy is encouraging because it could pave the way for Japan to lead similar partnerships in Asia, sources said.
The 12-country NATO consortium oversees development and shares the costs of the SeaSparrow missile, an advanced ship-borne weapon designed to destroy anti-ship sea-skimming missiles and attack aircraft. The missile is made by U.S. weapons firms Raytheon (RTN.N) and General Dynamics (GD.N).
In May, Japanese naval officers traveled to a North Atlantic Treaty Organization meeting in The Hague to learn more about the consortium, Japan's navy and a U.S. source familiar with the trip told Reuters.
Two Japanese sources familiar with the initiative said discussions in Tokyo were at an early stage, although joining the consortium would dovetail with Prime Minister Shinzo Abe's more muscular security agenda, which included the lifting last year of a decades-old ban on arms exports.
The sources declined to be identified because they were not authorized to speak to the media.
The consortium, established in 1968 by four countries including the United States, is set to develop an upgraded version of the SeaSparrow in the coming years.
Having Japan on board would spread the project's costs, but Washington also sees a role for Japan in leading multinational military industrial partnerships in Asia at a time when China's military modernization and assertiveness is alarming many countries in the region, said the U.S. source.
Such partnerships, which are rare in Asia, would create a network of security ties beyond formal military alliances that mostly involve Washington and its various regional allies.
"We think this project will allow Japan to lay the groundwork for further defense export programs in the future," the U.S. source said. "We would welcome this kind of security cooperation activity by Japan in the region."
Asked to comment, a spokesman for the Japanese navy said in an email: "The U.S. Navy is keeping us informed about the SeaSparrow project. With the aim of improving the procurement efficiency of our ship-based surface to air missiles we are gathering information to make the necessary choice."
The U.S. Navy said it was not immediately able to comment. NATO declined to comment.
TOKYO ALREADY BEEFING UP ASIA TIES
Japan has one of the most advanced military industrial bases in the world, but companies such as Mitsubishi Heavy Industries (7011.T) have long made weapons only for the Self Defense Forces because of the arms export ban.
Since lifting those curbs, Abe has begun boosting security cooperation across Southeast Asia, where several countries with tight budgets are worried by China's creation of man-made islands in the disputed South China Sea.
In June, Abe agreed with Philippine President Benigno Aquino on an exchange of military technology and hardware. Abe in May also agreed to start talks on transfers of defense equipment and technology with Malaysia.
And Australia is considering Japan as the possible builder of its next generation submarines, something U.S. naval commanders have publicly encouraged because doing so would deepen ties between two of Washington's closest allies in Asia.
None of these initiatives, however, are multinational.
SOME CONCERNS IN TOKYO
Japan's navy already uses the SeaSparrow missile, which is assembled locally by Mitsubishi Electric (6503.T) under a co-production agreement with NATO and the U.S. manufacturers.
That would make the transition to a full consortium partner easier, said the U.S. source.
One of the Japanese sources said some concerns had been raised in Tokyo over diminished control over production by being a member, even though sharing of costs would be welcomed.
"The concern is what it would mean to security by having to rely on other nations," the Japanese source said, referring to the possibility supplies of munitions and equipment from other countries could be disrupted more easily than those made at home, especially during any conflict.
It could also become a political issue since Japanese firms that supply parts for the SeaSparrow missiles made in Japan could miss out if Tokyo joined a consortium where work was spread among participating nations.
The U.S. Navy's desire to see Japan in the consortium comes after a proposal for Mitsubishi Heavy to join Lockheed Martin Corp's (LMT.N) F-35 stealth fighter program fizzled out last year.
Japanese defense bureaucrats had hoped working on the F-35 as a subcontractor to rear fuselage maker BAE Systems of Britain (BAES.L) would have given Mitsubishi Heavy exposure to global arms markets.
But it proved impossible for Mitsubishi Heavy to compete on pricing of components given the advantage enjoyed by contractors in the initial nine countries due to their governments' funding of specialized tooling for the program.
"Japan recognizes that it should join these international groups to help amortize purchases and make their industry more competitive," said a U.S. executive who works closely with the Japanese government and industry.
"You're going to see them engaged in more and more bilateral, trilateral and multilateral groups in coming years."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:18:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece sends reform plan to EU, sets parliament vote</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/75818pQQsE4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS/FRANKFURT (Reuters) - The Greek government sent a package of reform proposals to its euro zone creditors on Thursday in a race to win new funds to avert bankruptcy and will seek a parliamentary vote on Friday to endorse immediate actions.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece sends reform plan to EU, sets parliament vote
ATHENS/FRANKFURT | By Renee Maltezou and John O'Donnell
ATHENS/FRANKFURT The Greek government sent a package of reform proposals to its euro zone creditors on Thursday in a race to win new funds to avert bankruptcy and will seek a parliamentary vote on Friday to endorse immediate actions.
The chairman of Eurogroup finance ministers, Jeroen Dijsselbloem, confirmed receiving the documents and said through a spokesman that he would not comment until they had been  assessed by experts from the European Commission, European Central Bank and International Monetary Fund.
A Greek official said lawmakers would be asked to authorize the leftist government to negotiate a list of "prior actions" it would take before any fresh aid funds are disbursed, a key step to convince skeptical lenders of its serious intent.
Leftist Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras spent the day with his cabinet drafting a last-ditch package of tax rises, pension reforms and economic liberalization measures on which Greece's survival in the euro zone hinges.
A further vote would be needed to turn them into law next week if euro zone leaders agree at a summit on Sunday that the proposals are a basis for starting negotiations on a three-year loan and releasing some bridging funds to keep Greece afloat.
Greek banks have been closed since June 29, when capital controls were imposed and cash withdrawals rationed after the collapse of previous bailout talks. Greece defaulted on an IMF loan repayment the following day and now faces a critical July 20 bond redemption to the ECB, which it cannot make without aid.
The country has had two bailouts worth 240 billion euros from the euro zone and the International Monetary Fund since 2010, but its economy has shrunk by a quarter, unemployment is more than 25 percent and one in two young people is out of work.
Germany, Athens biggest creditor, meanwhile made a small concession by acknowledging that Greece will need some debt restructuring as part of the new program to make its public finances viable in the medium-term.
The admission by hardline German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble came hours before the midnight deadline for Athens to submit its reform plan.
Schaeuble, who makes no secret of his doubts about Greece's fitness to remain in the currency area, told a conference in Frankfurt: "Debt sustainability is not feasible without a haircut and I think the IMF is correct in saying that.
But he added: "There cannot be a haircut because it would infringe the system of the European Union."
He offered no solution to the conundrum, which implied that Greece's debt problem might not be soluble within the euro zone.
But he did say there was limited scope for "reprofiling" Greek debt by extending loan maturities, shaving interest rates and lengthening a moratorium on debt service payments.
Schaeuble also complained that he had not seen any sign of "prior actions" by the Greek government. Friday's vote should go some way towards disarming such criticism, although a further vote will be required to turn the "prior actions" into law next week if an agreement is reached, the Greek official said.
DEBT RELIEF CHORUS
European Council President Donald Tusk, who will chair an emergency euro zone summit on Sunday to decide Greece's fate, joined growing international calls for Athens to be granted some form of debt relief as part of any new loan deal.
Tusk said a realistic proposal from Greece will have to be matched by an equally realistic proposal on debt sustainability from the creditors.
"Otherwise, we will continue the lethargic dance we have been dancing for the past five months," he said.
Failure to reach a deal on Sunday, including releasing some money to enable Athens to cover debt service over the next few weeks, could lead to a collapse of Greek banks next week.
If there is no agreement, all 28 European Union leaders will discuss measures to limit the damage from a Greek collapse, including humanitarian aid, possible border controls and steps to mitigate the impact on neighbors, EU officials said.
Just how uncertain the coming days are was highlighted when
ECB President Mario Draghi voiced highly unusual doubts about the chances of rescuing Greece.
Italian daily Il Sole 24 Ore quoted the ECB chief, under growing fire in Germany for keeping Greek banks afloat, as saying he was not sure a solution would be found for Greece and he did not believe Russia would come to Athens' rescue.
Asked if a deal to save Greece could be wrapped up, Draghi said: "I don't know, this time it's really difficult."
The ECB is keeping shuttered Greek banks afloat with emergency liquidity capped until the weekend.
Even France, Greece's strongest supporter in the euro zone, acknowledged it was working on scenarios for a Greek exit from the currency area if weekend efforts to clinch a deal fail.
Under the agreed timetable, the three creditor institutions will deliver their initial assessment by Friday evening. If it is broadly positive, Eurogroup finance ministers will decide on Saturday whether to recommend opening negotiations with Athens on a conditional loan from the European Stability Mechanism bailout fund. The decision requires the assent of countries representing 80 percent of the ESM's capital, so talks can go ahead even if one or two smaller member states vote against it.
Having won a thumping referendum majority to reject the austerity terms of a previous bailout plan, fired his turbulent finance minister and secured support from opposition party leaders, Tsipras is in a stronger position to impose tough measures and face down resistance at home.
But in a sign of the some of the challenges he will face, the leader of the far-left wing of his Syriza party came out to denounce any imposition of harsh measures on Greeks.
"We don't want add to the past two failed bailouts a third bailout of tough austerity which will not give any prospects for the country," Energy Minister Panagiotis Lafazanis said.
According to Athens daily Kathimerini, the reform package will be worth 12 billion euros over two years, more than previously planned to offset a return to recession after months of difficult negotiations with creditors.
Instead of growing by 0.5 percent this year, months of uncertainty and almost two weeks of capital controls mean "there are estimates of a recession of about 3 percent", Kathimerini said. Greece emerged only last year from a deep recession that shrank its economy by a quarter over six years.
European officials told Reuters on Wednesday that some large Greek banks may have to be shut and taken over by stronger rivals as part of a restructuring of the sector that would follow any bailout of the country.
One official said Greece's four big banks - National Bank of Greece, Eurobank, Piraeus and Alpha Bank - could be reduced to just two, a measure that would doubtless encounter fierce resistance in Athens.
German Bundesbank chief Jens Weidmann said capital controls should remain in force in Greece until there was any deal, and that the ECB should not increase its liquidity assistance for Greek banks, without which they may collapse next week.
(Additional reporting by Alastair Macdonald in Brussels, Agnieszka Flak in Milan, Deepa Babington , Angeliki Koutantou and Michele Kambas in Athens, Balasz Koranyi and Frank Siebelt in Frankfurt, Julien Ponthus and Laurence Foster in Paris; Writing by Paul Taylor; Editing by Catherine Evans , Toni Reinhold )
A pro-Euro protester holds a European Union and a Greek national flag during a rally in front of the parliament building in Athens, Greece, July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
1 of 15
right
Protesters hold European Union and Greek flags during a Pro-Euro rally in front of the parliament building in Athens, Greece, July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Christian Hartmann
2 of 15
right
A protester holds a European Union flag with the Euro logo during a Pro-Euro rally in front of the parliament building in Athens, Greece, July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Yannis Behrakis
3 of 15
right
Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos (L) and former Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis talk during a parliamentary session in Athens July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Giorgos Kontarinis/Eurokinissi
4 of 15
right
Pensioners wait in front of the main entrance of a National Bank branch to receive part of their pensions in central Athens July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Jean-Paul Pelissier
5 of 15
right
Protesters hold European Union and Greek flags during a Pro-Euro rally in front of the parliament building in Athens, Greece, July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
6 of 15
right
A one Euro coin with a Greek owl is seen in this picture illustration taken in Rome, Italy July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Tony Gentile
7 of 15
right
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras leaves his office in Maximos Mansion in Athens, Greece July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
8 of 15
right
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker meets Dora Bakoyannis (R), member of the Greek opposition New Democracy party, at the EU Commission headquarters in Brussels, Belgium, July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Francois Lenoir
9 of 15
right
A pensioner (R) stands outside a National Bank branch as others line up to receive part of their pensions in the city of Thessaloniki, Greece July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Alexandros Avramidis
10 of 15
right
A pensioner (C) reacts as she tries to enter a National Bank branch to receive part of her pension in the city of Thessaloniki, Greece July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Alexandros Avramidis
11 of 15
right
Pensioners raise their hands to obtain priority tickets in front of the main entrance of a National Bank branch to receive part of their pensions in central Athens, Greece July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Jean-Paul Pelissier
12 of 15
right
A bank official (L) informs people queueing for the ATM that it is working again in central Athens, Greece July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Cathal McNaughton
13 of 15
right
Graffiti is seen scrawled onto a wall of a bank in central Athens, Greece July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Cathal McNaughton
14 of 15
right
People queue at an ATM outside an Alpha Bank branch in Athens, Greece July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Jean-Paul Pelissier
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:14:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan's China-friendly KMT mimics Chiang Kai-shek's fall from pedestal</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/tbN8r_nNGXI/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TAOYUAN, Taiwan (Reuters) - Dumped outside Chiang Kai-shek's mausoleum in Taiwan are nearly 200 unwanted statues of the Nationalist Party hero, a suggestion of the punishment his party faces in January elections for pushing the self-ruled island too close to political foe China.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan's China-friendly KMT mimics Chiang Kai-shek's fall from pedestal
TAOYUAN, Taiwan | By J.R. Wu
A man walks in between statues of the late president and Nationalist leader Chiang Kai-shek in Taoyuan, nothern Taiwan, July 5, 2015.
Reuters/Pichi Chuang
1 of 2
right
A person touches a statue of the late president and Nationalist leader Chiang Kai-shek in Taoyuan, nothern Taiwan, July 5, 2015.
Reuters/Pichi Chuang
2 of 2
right
TAOYUAN, Taiwan Dumped outside Chiang Kai-shek's mausoleum in Taiwan are nearly 200 unwanted statues of the Nationalist Party hero, a suggestion of the punishment his party faces in January elections for pushing the self-ruled island too close to political foe China.
Cast in bronze and in different shades of red, brown, gray and blue, the generalissimo is saluting, holding a book, leaning on a cane, sitting regally or perched on a plinth - a peaceful if surreal gathering that belies the disarray of the party it represents.
Some statues still standing elsewhere around the island have been decapitated or defaced.
The Nationalist Party, or Kuomintang (KMT) in Chinese, is expected to be dealt a thrashing in the presidential poll by the pro-independence Democratic Progressive Party (DPP), a result likely to irritate giant neighbor China which claims the island as its own, though no one expects close economic ties to unravel.
"The KMT is in freezing winter. It will get worse before it gets better," said a party member, who spoke on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the issue.
The party has been in crisis mode since November when it lost power in local elections. The defeat paved the way for Hung Hsiu-chu to step up as its only prospective presidential candidate. But her stated intention of signing a peace treaty with China and appearing to move closer to Beijing's position of "one China", including Taiwan, has rubbed a lot of party cadres the wrong way.
In short, KMT supporters are bailing out. Campaign jockeying and factional infighting are pushing members away from a party that numbered well over a million in 2000 but is now down to about 890,000, with only about a third of them active.
Mainstream public opinion on the island is in favor of maintaining the status quo with China, which is a key campaign message from DPP presidential hopeful Tsai Ing-wen. Economic ties, while seen as imbalanced in favor of China, won't be rolled back however distant the prospect of political talks.
Beijing, for instance, insists Taiwan can be ruled under the "one country, two systems" formula under which Hong Kong, a former British colony, returned to Chinese rule in 1997. Both the DPP and KMT reject this model, which prompted unprecedented pro-democracy protests in Hong Kong last year, blocking streets for months.
SLOWING GROWTH, STAGNANT WAGES
Chiang remains a hero for some in Taiwan, and even in China he is looked upon with increasing favor in certain quarters, despite his forced flight to Taiwan in 1949 with the remains of his Republic of China government after the Communists won the  Chinese civil war.
Chiang died in 1975. China continues to claim Taiwan as its territory, and has never renounced the use of force to bring the now proudly democratic island under its control.
Late last month, legislator Chang Sho-wen publicly quit the KMT. Another member, Hsu Hsin-ying, left the party after last year's local election loss which forced President Ma Ying-jeou to resign as party chief.
The election result was seen as a vote against Ma's China-friendly policies. Democratically minded young and middle-class Taiwanese, unhappy with slowing economic growth and stagnant wages, remain suspicious of China's intentions and see only big business prospering from closer ties.
"The history of the KMT, of Chiang, has been diluted," said Hsu Wen-long, 50, whose father, a KMT soldier, fled to Taiwan with the generalissimo. When Hsu was young, children were taught it was a fight for survival between the KMT and the Communists. That is not the case with the younger generation.
"What you learn in your early years stays with you for a lifetime," Hsu said.
The hundreds of twenty-somethings who occupied parliament last year to stop a trade pact that would bring the island even closer to China were at primary school under the last DPP rule.
But some Nationalists argue that stronger ties with China will help prevent Beijing from taking control any way it wants.
"If the KMT should become weak or split up, there will be no checks and balances against the DPP," said Nationalist Justin Chen. "If in Taiwan society there doesn't exist a voice of unification, then China's Communist Party will reach its hand directly into this island. That is a different stage of confrontation."
As for those busts and statues, the DPP's Chen Shui-bian ordered them to be taken down from public display and sent to the wooded, lakeside park in Taoyuan when he was president between 2000 and 2008.
As late as last year, they were still being delivered.
^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^&gt;
SPECIAL REPORT-How China's shadowy agency is working to absorb Taiwan
^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^&gt;
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:09:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. spy agency tapped German chancellery for decades: WikiLeaks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/wXnx6heOATM/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BERLIN (Reuters) - The U.S. National Security Agency tapped phone calls involving German Chancellor Angela Merkel and her closest advisers for years and spied on the staff of her predecessors, according to WikiLeaks.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. spy agency tapped German chancellery for decades: WikiLeaks
BERLIN
Visitors walk in front of the Chancellory during the second day of an open door weekend of several ministries in Berlin.
Reuters/Fabrizio Bensch
BERLIN The U.S. National Security Agency tapped phone calls involving German Chancellor Angela Merkel and her closest advisers for years and spied on the staff of her predecessors, according to WikiLeaks.
A report released by the group suggested NSA spying on Merkel and her staff had gone on far longer and more widely than previously realized. WikiLeaks said the NSA targeted for long-term surveillance 125 phone numbers of top German officials.
The release risks renewing tensions between Germany and the United States a month after they sought to put a row over spying behind them, with U.S. President Barack Obama declaring in Bavaria that the two nations were "inseparable allies".
A German government spokesman said on Thursday Berlin was looking into the latest report and reiterated that such events strained German and American intelligence cooperation.
U.S. officials could not immediately be reached for comment.
Friends and associates of former NSA contractor Edward Snowden have denied he is the source of the latest WikiLeaks revelations, suggesting that they likely came from a different and still unidentified leaker deep inside U.S. intelligence.
His friends have said Snowden avoided giving the large tranches of classified documents he downloaded while working at NSA installations to WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange, even though Assange helped arrange for Snowden's flight to and current exile in Moscow.
However, some U.S. officials familiar with the latest leaks said they were unaware of other leakers and believe that one way or another the material newly published by WikiLeaks did somehow originate with Snowden, even if he did not give it directly to Assange.
WikiLeaks published what it said were three NSA intercepts of Merkel's conversations, and data it said listed telephone numbers for the chancellor, her aides, her office and even her fax machine.
"The names associated with some of the targets indicate that spying on the Chancellery predates Angela Merkel as it includes staff of former Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder (in office 1998-2002), and his predecessor Helmut Kohl," WikiLeaks added in a statement.
The intercepts detailed communications from Merkel in 2009 on the international financial crisis, with the crown prince of the United Arab Emirates in 2009 on Iran, and with advisers in 2011 on the euro zone crisis.
The targeted phone numbers included those for the cellphones of senior officials at the chancellery and included that of Ronald Pofalla, Merkel's former chief of staff, WikiLeaks said.
Spying is a sensitive issue in Germany because of the abuses of the Nazi and Communist eras. The Snowden revelations have caused outrage in Germany when they first surfaced.
The spying row has also been stirred by allegations that Merkel's staff gave the German BND foreign intelligence agency a green light to help the NSA spy on European firms and officials.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:59:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Poor, hungry, cannot be ignored, pope says in Bolivia</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/fvZy2LyXTWo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia (Reuters) - Pope Francis, at a Mass for hundreds of thousands of people in Bolivia, said on Thursday that everyone had a moral duty to help the poor, and that those with means could not wish they would just "go away."</Description>
        <MainBody>SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia | By Philip Pullella and Sarah Marsh
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia Pope Francis, at a Mass for hundreds of thousands of people in Bolivia, said on Thursday that everyone had a moral duty to help the poor, and that those with means could not wish that they would just "go away."
The 78-year-old pontiff, on the fifth day of his three-nation tour of South America, is showing a few signs of fatigue  but generally appears to be holding up well despite stark  changes in altitude and temperature.
On Wednesday he went from the oxygen-poor air of La Paz, which is more than 3,650 meters (11,975 feet) above sea level, to Santa Cruz, Bolivia's largest and fastest-growing city, which is at 416 meters (1,365 feet).
In one sign of the city's development, the store that was used for the pope to change into his vestments at the mass site had the insignia of the Burger King fast food chain above its door. The glass was covered with white curtains for the occasion.
Santa Cruz has fewer indigenous people than other parts of Bolivia. It's 2.6 million people are mostly of European descent and are wealthier than those in most areas of the country, one of the poorest in the Americas.
In his homily, Francis urged his listeners to beware of an attitude of resignation before the great challenges facing society because "it disorients us, it closes our heart to others, especially to the poor."
"Faced with so many kinds of hunger in our world, we can say to ourselves: 'Things don't add up; we will never manage, there is nothing to be done.' And so our hearts yield to despair," he said.
He used the biblical story of the multiplication of the loaves and fishes, when Jesus' apostles wanted him to send crowds away because there would be no way to feed all of them.
The bible story says Jesus multiplied the food but some modern biblical scholars believe the real miracle was that he convinced everyone to share what they had.
Francis said the story had "particular resonance" in today's world, and told his audience: "No one needs to go away, no one needs to be discarded; you yourselves, give them something to eat. Jesus speaks these words to us, here in this square."
LISTEN TO THE POOR
Later, at a meeting with priests and nuns, he said the Church too, had to ramp up its defense of the poor.
"To pass by, without hearing the pain of our people ... is like listening to the word of God without letting it take root and bear fruit in our hearts," he said.
On Thursday night, the pope was scheduled to make a major address to the second world meeting of popular movements, an international body that brings together organizations of people on the margins of society, including the poor, the unemployed and peasants who have lost their land.
On the first leg of his tour, in Ecuador, the pope on Tuesday appealed to the world not to turn its back on the "reality" of environmental decay and its effects on the poor.
Francis arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday and praised Bolivia's social reforms to spread wealth under leftist President Evo Morales. On Friday, he will walk into Bolivia's notoriously violent Palmasola prison.
Morales' strained relations with the Catholic Church have begun thawing under the Argentine-born pontiff's papacy. Morales warmly embraced the pope seven years after denouncing the Church as "an instrument of domination".
The pope looked bemused when Morales handed him one of the more unusual gifts he has received: a wooden hammer and sickle - the symbol of communism - with a figure of a crucified Christ resting on the hammer.
The pope leaves on Friday for Paraguay, the last stop on his "homecoming" trip.
Pope Francis greets people as he leaves after celebrating a Mass at the Cristo Redentor square in Santa Cruz, Bolivia July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Mariana Bazo
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:52:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As deadline looms, Kerry says U.S. in no rush to get Iran deal</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/DGfAZrfcKZk/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - The United States and other major powers are not in a rush to reach a nuclear deal with Iran, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry said on Thursday, suggesting an accord was unlikely hours ahead of a deadline set by the U.S. Congress for a quick review.</Description>
        <MainBody>VIENNA | By Louis Charbonneau and Parisa Hafezi
VIENNA The United States and other major powers are not in a rush to reach a nuclear deal with Iran, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry said on Thursday, suggesting an accord was unlikely hours ahead of a deadline set by the U.S. Congress for a quick review.
"We're here because we believe we are making real progress," Kerry told reporters in the Austrian capital. "We will not rush and we will not be rushed."
However, Kerry said Washington's patience was not unlimited. "We cant wait forever," he said. "If the tough decisions dont get made, we are absolutely prepared to call an end to this."
He did not say how much longer the talks could continue. Shortly after Kerry spoke, the White House said the talks would not likely drag on for "many more weeks."
Over the past two weeks, Iran, the United States, Britain, France, Germany, Russia and China have twice extended deadlines for completing a long-term deal under which Tehran would curb nuclear activities for more than a decade in exchange for sanctions relief.
Kerry's announcement echoed earlier remarks by Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, who said Iran and major powers would not be hurried.
"We're working hard, but not rushed to get the job done," he said on his Twitter account. Speaking later, Zarif said "We will stay here as long as it is necessary."
France's Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said the parties would continue negotiating overnight to try to resolve the "difficult issues" that remained in nuclear talks. He added that  "things are ... going in the right direction."
Negotiators have given themselves until the end of the day on Friday. But if a deal is not reached by 6:00 a.m. in Vienna (0400 GMT), the skeptical Republican-led U.S. Congress will have 60 days rather than 30 days to review it, extra time U.S. President Barack Obama's administration worries could derail it.
Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Sergei Ryabkov said it was possible there would be an agreement in the coming hours. A spokesman for Russian President Vladimir Putin said the Russian leader hoped for compromises that would enable a deal soon.
Western countries accuse Iran of seeking the capability to build nuclear weapons, while Tehran says its program is peaceful. A deal would depend on Iran accepting curbs on its nuclear program in return for the easing of economic sanctions imposed by the United Nations, United States and European Union.
"96 PERCENT COMPLETE"
Western officials sought to strike a balance between pushing Iran to cut a deal yet suggesting they were not in a hurry to deprive the Iranians of leverage that might come from a belief  that the major powers wanted an accord more than they did.
"We are very close but if the important ... decisions are not made in the next hours, we wont (have) an agreement," EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini told CNN. "That moment of truth will come extremely soon, next hours I think."
Iran's Fars news agency quoted an unnamed source blaming the United States for the standoff.
"While the Iranian team is showing flexibility, the Americans are refusing to accept Iran's obvious right, particularly on sanctions," Fars quoted the source as saying.
A successful deal could be the biggest milestone in decades towards easing hostility between Iran and the United States, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries stormed the U.S. embassy in Tehran in 1979.
It would also be a political success for both Obama and Iran's pragmatic President Hassan Rouhani, who each face scepticism from powerful hardliners at home.
Kerry and Zarif have met almost daily for two weeks to overcome the last remaining obstacles to a deal. French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius and his British and German counterparts have also rejoined the negotiations.
The White House said Obama and his national security team held a video conference on Wednesday with Kerry and the U.S. negotiating team in Vienna.
Iran's Deputy Foreign Minister Abbas Araqchi said the main text of the agreement, as well as five technical annexes, were "around 96 percent complete." While the lifting of sanctions was largely agreed, Araqchi said Tehran's demand for an end to a U.N. Security Council arms embargo was among the most contentious unresolved points.
Other sticking points in the negotiations have included research and development on advanced centrifuges and access to Iranian military sites and nuclear sites.
Tehran says a U.N. embargo on conventional weapons has nothing to do with the nuclear issues at stake and must be lifted in any deal. Western countries are keen not to allow Iran to begin importing arms because of its role supporting sides in conflicts in the Middle East.
Iran has powerful support on this issue from Russia. Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said at a summit of BRICS countries - Brazil, China, India, Russia and South Africa - that the U.N. arms embargo should be among the first sanctions lifted.
Iran's President Rouhani was also at the summit and met with Putin.
(Additional reporting by John Irish and Arshad Mohammed and Shadia Nasralla in Vienna and Katya Golubkova and Denis Pinchuk in Russia, writing by Louis Charbonneau; Editing by Anna Willard, Peter Graff and Giles Elgood )
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, British Foreign Minister Philip Hammond (not seen), Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, German Minister for Foreign Affairs Frank-Walter Steinmeier, French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius, China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi, EU Deputy...
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
1 of 5
right
German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier (L) French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius (3rd L) Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi (4th L) European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy Federica Mogherini (centre row, 2ndR) U.S. Secretary of...
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
2 of 5
right
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry  meets with foreign ministers of Germany, France, China, Britain, Russia and the European Union during the Iran Talks meetings at a hotel in Vienna, Austria July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Carlos Barria
3 of 5
right
Head of the Iranian Atomic Energy Organization Ali Akbar Salehi (2nd R) walks near the hotel where the Iran nuclear talks meetings are being held in Vienna, Austria in Vienna, Austria July 4, 2015.
Reuters/Carlos Barria
4 of 5
right
Iranian Foreign Minister Javad Zarif stands on the balcony of Palais Coburg, the venue for nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria, July 2, 2015.
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:49:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. says Yemen's warring factions agree to humanitarian truce</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/J8a4XSyk8yc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI/SANAA (Reuters) - Yemen's warring factions confirmed their agreement on Thursday to a temporary humanitarian ceasefire set to begin on Friday night, United Nations envoy Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed said.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.N. says Yemen's warring factions agree to humanitarian truce
DUBAI/SANAA | By Noah Browning and Mohammed Ghobari
A man reacts as he stands next to wreckage at the site of a car bomb attack outside his house in Sanaa June 29, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
DUBAI/SANAA Yemen's warring factions confirmed their agreement on Thursday to a temporary humanitarian ceasefire set to begin on Friday night, United Nations envoy Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed said.
The pause in the fighting will last about a week until the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan and aims to allow the delivery of assistance to some of the 21 million Yemenis in need.
The U.N. has worked intensively to broker a ceasefire to halt more than three months of many-sided fighting inside the country and Saudi-led air strikes against the Houthis and their army allies that have killed more than 3,000 people.
"For the humanitarian pause, we are going to start tomorrow evening and we have assurances from all the parties, and we are quite optimistic it will be respected," Ould Cheikh Ahmed told Reuters by phone from Ethiopia, after finishing discussions in the Houthi-held Yemeni capital Sanaa.
"We have agreed to go ahead, based on two major points. The first is the commitment of all parties not to violate this ceasefire, this humanitarian pause. The second is that humanitarian assistance can reach all parts of Yemen," he added.
Relief agencies say the fighting and a near-blockade imposed by an alliance of Arab states, aimed at stopping weapons deliveries to the Houthis, have caused a humanitarian disaster in Yemen, with over 80 percent of its 25 million people now needing some form of emergency aid.
Rights groups have also condemned local blockades by armed groups on supplies headed for war-torn civilian areas.
CHALLENGE
Yemen's president Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi, in exile in Saudi Arabia, has asked the U.N. for "guarantees" to help the truce succeed, which include prisoner releases by the Houthis and withdrawals from vast areas where it is battling local fighters.
Implementing more thorny political points, the envoy said, would not happen immediately and required more discussion, but the Houthis have released a top pro-Hadi politician in Sanaa and allowed the shipment of 50 aid trucks to the embattled southern city of Aden to buttress the truce.
A senior Western diplomat said the intensity of battles raging nationwide would render a swift calm difficult.
"It is still going to be a challenge to have this call heeded within the next 24 hours because of the entrenched fighting on the ground," the diplomat told Reuters.
News of the expected truce helped lift the Saudi stock market. The index closed 2.5 percent higher.
Saudi Arabia and an Arab coalition have been bombing the  Houthis and their allies in Yemen's army in an effort to restore Hadi and bolster armed opponents of the Iran-allied Houthis.
The Houthis, who took over the capital Sanaa last September, deny Saudi accusations that they are an Iranian proxy and describe their armed advance throughout Yemen as a revolution against a corrupt government backed by the West.
The group has previously said it welcomed any ceasefire but has yet to accept a U.N. Security Council Resolution passed in April which recognizes Hadi as the legitimate president and calls on them to quit seized land.
The United States fears the turmoil will strengthen al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula, the deadliest branch of the global militant group.
AQAP's new leader Qassim al-Raymi, appointed after his predecessor was killed in U.S. drone strike last month, called for attacks on the United States in a taped speech released on Thursday.
(Additional reporting by Angus McDowall in Riyadh and Michelle Nichols at the United Nations; Editing by Andrew Roche )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:35:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Yemeni al Qaeda leader calls for attacks on United States</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/dV-C8ITE45k/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - The new leader of al Qaeda's Yemen branch has called for attacks on the United States in his first speech since taking command, the U.S.-based SITE monitoring group reported on Thursday, citing an audio recording.</Description>
        <MainBody>New Yemeni al Qaeda leader calls for attacks on United States
DUBAI
DUBAI The new leader of al Qaeda's Yemen branch has called for attacks on the United States in his first speech since taking command, the U.S.-based SITE monitoring group reported on Thursday, citing an audio recording.
Qassim al-Raymi succeeded Nasser al-Wuhayshi as military commander of Al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula (AQAP) after Wuhayshi was killed in a U.S. drone strike in Yemen's south-eastern city of Mukalla last month.
In the speech, Raymi eulogized Wuhayshi, pledged allegiance to al Qaeda leader Ayman al-Zawahri, and called for attacks on the United States, SITE said.
"All of you must direct and gather your arrows and swords against it," SITE quoted Raymi as telling Muslims in general in the 14 minute and 9 second recording.
"God has helped you against this enemy, for not only did you reach its home, but with praise to God and His grace, you have reached the depths of its heart," he added.
The authenticity of the recording, produced by AQAP's al-Malahem Media Foundation, could not immediately be verified.
Wuhayshis death was seen as a major blow to AQAP, regarded by the United States as al-Qaedas most dangerous affiliate, and to al-Qaeda more broadly.
Addressing Zawahri, he said: "I pledge allegiance to you, to listen and obey, in times of difficulty and prosperity, in hardship and in ease, to endure being discriminated against and not to dispute about rule with those in power, and to wage jihad in the cause of God the Almighty, with the Book of Allah and the Sunnah [traditions] of His Messenger, Allah's peace and blessings be upon him, as much I am able."
Raymi also congratulated a coalition of jihadi factions in Syria that include the Nusra Front for its recent success in Idlib province, and the Afghan Taliban for victories in its Azm spring offensive, SITE said.
(Reporting by Sami Aboudi; Editing by Catherine Evans )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:21:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>12 migrants drown, 500 rescued in Mediterranean off Libya</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/-x7M3zpQKfQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ROME (Reuters) - Twelve migrants died on Thursday when their overcrowded rubber dinghy sank off the coast of Libya, the Italian Coast Guard said, while some 500 were rescued in the latest episodes in the Mediterranean migrant crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>12 migrants drown, 500 rescued in Mediterranean off Libya
ROME
ROME Twelve migrants died on Thursday when their overcrowded rubber dinghy sank off the coast of Libya, the Italian Coast Guard said, while some 500 were rescued in the latest episodes in the Mediterranean migrant crisis.
The corpses of the victims were found in the sea by the Coast Guard ship Dattilo some 40 miles north of Libya, a Coast Guard spokesman said. The Dattilo saved 106 people from the same dinghy, which was "half submerged" when help arrived.
The Dattilo is still involved in other rescue operations involving boats in difficulty, the spokesman said.
A total of 393 other migrants were saved in four different operations carried out by the Dattilo on Thursday. Another 106 migrants were saved by two Coast Guard frigates operating off the southern Italian island of Lampedusa.
No details were available on the nationalities of the victims or those rescued.
Tens of thousands of migrants fleeing war and hunger in Africa and the Middle East have crossed the Mediterranean to Italy and Greece this year, with the vast majority departing from the coast of Libya. More than 2,000 are estimated to have drowned.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:59:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syrian army says it's closing in on Islamic State in Palmyra</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/wKbzWUVdQnI/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - The Syrian army said on Thursday it was closing in on Islamic State militants in control of Palmyra, in a major offensive to recapture the city of Roman ruins from the jihadists.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syrian army says it's closing in on Islamic State in Palmyra
BEIRUT
A general view shows the historical city of Palmyra, October 28, 2007.
Reuters/Nour Fourat
BEIRUT The Syrian army said on Thursday it was closing in on Islamic State militants in control of Palmyra, in a major offensive to recapture the city of Roman ruins from the jihadists.
A newsflash on state television quoted a Syrian army source as saying its forces were in the vicinity of the city.
Footage showed tank and artillery shelling of distant targets in the largely desert terrain.
"The units of the army had delivered concentrated hits to the terrorists' hideouts and killed many of them," an army statement said.
In the last few days the army has intensified its aerial bombardment of the central Syrian city, also known as Tadmur, in the heaviest such raids since it was seized by the Sunni Islamist group last May.
The army said in the last 24 hours it had taken Nuzl Hayal and the Tel al Marmala on the outskirts of the city and hilltops about 10 km (six miles) from the center.
The city of 50,000 people is the site of some of the world's most extensive and best-preserved ancient Roman ruins.
Islamic State is fighting the Kurdish YPG militia along the northern border with Turkey and with the Syrian military around Hasaka city to the east.
The United States said this week it had intensified an aerial campaign against Islamic State in Syria with a wave of strikes in and around Raqqa city, the de facto capital of the militants' self-declared caliphate in parts of Syria and Iraq.
(Reporting by Suleiman Al-Khalidi; editing by Andrew Roche )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:46:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. lawmakers blast State Department over Kabul embassy delays</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/NiTZ3YblBXk/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. lawmakers criticized the State Department for construction delays and cost overruns at the U.S. Embassy in Afghanistan on Thursday, saying they waste taxpayer dollars and put employees' lives at unnecessary risk.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. lawmakers blast State Department over Kabul embassy delays
WASHINGTON | By Alex Wilts
WASHINGTON U.S. lawmakers criticized the State Department for construction delays and cost overruns at the U.S. Embassy in Afghanistan on Thursday, saying they waste taxpayer dollars and put employees' lives at unnecessary risk.
The expansion of the sprawling embassy complex in Kabul is more than three years behind schedule, and at least 27 percent over budget, at $730 million, according to the U.S. Government Accountability Office.
The project is now due to be finished in autumn 2017.
During a House Oversight Committee hearing on cost overruns at the embassy, several members questioned security at the facility. The delays have prolonged the amount of time Americans in Kabul have spent in temporary facilities, which do not have to adhere to the same security standards as permanent facilities.
"The American diplomatic staff in Afghanistan are being exposed to unnecessary danger," said Republican Representative Jason Chaffetz, the panel's chairman.
State Department officials said cost increases and delays were unavoidable, given the evolving situation in Afghanistan where there are frequent attacks by Taliban militants.
"We started with a master plan, and we will continue to make modifications to that plan until we have the right combination of facilities and security features in place in Kabul," said Lydia Muniz, director of the State Department's Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations.
Congress has been scrutinizing security at U.S. diplomatic facilities since attacks in Benghazi, Libya, in September 2012 that killed the U.S. ambassador and three other Americans.
Republicans have accused Democratic President Barack Obama of failing to provide sufficient security. Democrats have suggested that Republican-backed budget cuts were partially responsible for the lack of security in Benghazi.
Chaffetz promised during the hearing that Muniz would be called to testify on other delayed embassy projects.
"You act as if it's your money and there's not going to be some sort of consequence here," Chaffetz said to Muniz, referring to other delayed embassy construction projects in Mexico and Zimbabwe.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:48:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saud al-Faisal, Saudi foreign minister for 40 years, dies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/txNimkAKPGQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>RIYADH (Reuters) - Former Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal died on Thursday, Saudi Arabian sources and media close to the kingdom's ruling family reported, two months after he was replaced following 40 years in the job.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saud al-Faisal, Saudi foreign minister for 40 years, dies
RIYADH
Saudi Foreign Minister Saud al-Faisal gestures during a joint news conference with his French counterpart Laurent Fabius in Riyadh April 12, 2015.
Reuters/Faisal Al Nasser
RIYADH Former Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal died on Thursday, Saudi Arabian sources and media close to the kingdom's ruling family reported, two months after he was replaced following 40 years in the job.
Prince Saud, who was 75, was the world's longest serving foreign minister when replaced on April 29 by Adel al-Jubeir, the then-ambassador to Washington. The Al-Arabiya channel, which is close to King Salman's branch of the ruling family, confirmed the news.
Prince Saud retained an influential position in Saudi foreign policy circles even after his replacement, serving as an official adviser to King Salman, who took power in January, and was sometimes present when foreign leaders met the monarch.
Even before the 2011 Arab Spring, when Saudi Arabia faced unprecedented regional tumult, Prince Saud was a significant player in Middle East diplomacy, a landscape that had changed radically since October 1975 when he was appointed.
Egypt and Israel had not yet made peace, Yasser Arafat led the Palestine Liberation Organisation from shell-pocked refugee camps in Lebanon, Iran's shah ruled from his Peacock Throne and, in Iraq, a young Saddam Hussein was plotting his path to power.
Prince Saud's tenure covered Israeli invasions of Lebanon in 1978, 1982 and 2006, the Palestinian intifadas that erupted in 1987 and 2000, Iraq's invasion of Iran in 1980 and Kuwait in 1990, and a U.S.-led coalition's occupation of Iraq in 2003.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In Baghdad, end of a curfew brings Ramadan joy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/h7ctbFhd0Ag/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BAGHDAD (Reuters) - Its 1.30 a.m. and the Aroma Caf in an affluent district of Baghdad is buzzing, packed with people enjoying a traditional pre-dawn Suhoor meal before starting their daily Ramadan fast.</Description>
        <MainBody>In Baghdad, end of a curfew brings Ramadan joy
BAGHDAD | By Saif Hameed
Iraqi youths eat the pre-dawn Suhoor meal before the start of the daily Ramadan fast in a restaurant in Baghdad, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Thaier Al-Sudani
1 of 6
right
An Iraqi family eats their pre-dawn Suhoor meal before starting the daily Ramadan fast at an Aroma Cafe in Baghdad, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Thaier Al-Sudani
2 of 6
right
An Iraqi family relaxes after eating their pre-dawn Suhoor meal before the start of the daily Ramadan fast at the Aroma Cafe in Baghdad, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Thaier Al-Sudani
3 of 6
right
An Iraqi waiter serves the pre-dawn Suhoor meal before the start of the daily Ramadan fast in a restaurant in Baghdad, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Thaier Al-Sudani
4 of 6
right
Cars drive past at Kahramana square during the holy month of Ramadan in Baghdad, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Thaier Al-Sudani
5 of 6
right
Iraqi youths chat amongst themselves after their pre-dawn Suhoor meal before the start of the daily Ramadan fast at the Aroma Cafe in Baghdad, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Thaier Al-Sudani
6 of 6
right
BAGHDAD Its 1.30 a.m. and the Aroma Caf in an affluent district of Baghdad is buzzing, packed with people enjoying a traditional pre-dawn Suhoor meal before starting their daily Ramadan fast.
Smartly dressed waiters serve soup, tea and shisha pipes, while a constantly re-stocked buffet tempts customers with barbecued meats, salads, fruits and juices.
The lifting of a night-time curfew in the Iraqi capital five months ago means that, for the first time since the 2003 U.S.-led invasion brought violence and turmoil, lavish Ramadan meals can stretch on until dawn.
While the rest of the country fragments, hardline Islamic State fighters battle the army less than 50 km (30 miles) away, and car bombs still regularly inflict their deadly toll across the city, people seize gratefully at any chance to enjoy life.
"This is the first year that we feel the joys of Ramadan in the way that we used to do in the 80s and 70s," said Fawziya at the Aroma Cafe, referring an era which many Baghdad residents now recall as a golden age.
Untroubled by the prospect of a day's work ahead, she sat with her relatives and in-laws, enjoying the spirit of togetherness which Ramadan is meant to foster.
"You feel overjoyed to see this because all families have been through a lot. There is no fear," she said. "We saw this in Turkey and Lebanon when we used to travel, but now its here as well."
Roads in the Tigris river neighborhood of Jadriya around the cafe were filled with cars. Pedestrians walked the well-lit, tree-lined streets, enjoying the relative post-midnight cool compared to daytime temperatures near 50 degrees Celsius.
"Lifting the curfew had a huge impact... Life has sprung up suddenly," says Abbas al-Taii, a 46-year-old father enjoying a meal with his family of six.
"There is life now. Baghdad loves life... Going out at night in itself is a challenge to violence," said the U.S. resident, who chose to bring his family back to his hometown to experience Ramadan in Iraq.
RAMADAN NIGHTS
While the affluence of Jadriya doesn't extend across the whole of Baghdad, Ramadan nights are special throughout the capital.
In the impoverished Shi'ite quarter of Sadr City, children ride bikes after dark, youngsters kick footballs and men play Muhaibis, a traditional game where players have to work out which member of an opposing team is hiding a ring in their hand.
Few families have the money to go out for Suhoor. Instead some raise funds to feed the poorest during the holy month.
In a smart neighborhood west of the Tigris, shoppers fill the brightly lit Mansour mall and cinema complex. One film showing this Ramadan, Mad Max:Fury Road, portrays the mindless violence fueled by a revolt against a despot who hoards the resources of his desert wasteland.
After long years enduring their own war and deprivations, people in Baghdad have learnt to cherish moments of stability, even if they are fragile and fleeting.
"We were thirsty for a good time like this," said Abbas's wife Um Maram. "2003 till 2015 is almost a lifetime.
"I remember the time when I was as young as my daughters, and I used to tell them of these times. Now they can live it as well. We thank God for that. We hope that this safety lasts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:58:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadlines, red lines, bedtimes get no respect at Iran talks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/8bWJsZqrh9k/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - As any parent knows, setting limits is important, especially at bedtime. In the Iran nuclear negotiations, however, the normal rules of diet, discipline and decorum do not always apply.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry sits in the garden of Palais Coburg, the hotel where the Iran nuclear talks meetings are being held in Vienna, Austria July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
1 of 3
right
German Foreign Minister Frank Walter Steinmeier (L), French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius (2nd L), European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy Federica Mogherini (5th R), U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry (3rd R) and British Foreign...
Reuters/Carlos Barria
2 of 3
right
Dark clouds are seen over Palais Coburg, the venue for nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria, July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
3 of 3
right
VIENNA As any parent knows, setting limits is important, especially at bedtime. In the Iran nuclear negotiations, however, the normal rules of diet, discipline and decorum do not always apply.
Diplomats describe the downsides of the talks, among them sleepless nights, separation from spouses and the difficulty of maintaining one's diet, let alone waistline, amid the siren temptations of Vienna's veal schnitzel and Sachertorte.
The U.S. delegation to the talks, which aim to restrain the Iranian nuclear program in exchange for relief from economic sanctions against Iran, brings its own grub.
Seeking to inject some levity into a briefing about the nuclear diplomacy, a senior U.S. official this week cataloged the U.S. delegation's snack habits.
Since the start of June, the team has gone through at least 10 pounds (4.54 kg) of strawberry Twizzlers liquorice, 30 pounds (13.61 kg) of mixed nuts and dried fruit, 20 pounds (9.07 kg) of string cheese, 200 Rice Krispies treats (a mix of marshmallow, rice cereal and butter) and, on Monday alone, three liters of Zanoni &amp; Zanoni gelato to celebrate a delegation birthday.
"We have been here enough to celebrate virtually every member of the teams birthday in Vienna at least once," said the official, saying the delegation was in the Austrian capital 11 times last year and at least half a dozen this year.
The U.S. experts, who deal in the granular details of nuclear physics and economic sanctions, have flown across the Atlantic 69 times since they began seeking to reach a final nuclear agreement with Iran in February 2014, the official said.
One calculates that he has flown 400,000 miles, roughly the equivalent of circumnavigating the earth 16 times.
Getting some sleep, whether in the air or on the ground, is always a challenge. The U.S. and Iranian sanctions teams were up until 3 a.m. on Friday night negotiating.
The next day, July 4, the U.S. delegation celebrated the U.S. Independence Day holiday in Vienna for the second year in a row, dining al fresco on hamburgers and a U.S. flag-shaped cake at the Coburg Palais hotel where the talks take place amid 19th century splendor.
'INTENSE AND MONASTIC'
"It's intense and monastic," a diplomat from another delegation, looking gaunt and exhausted, said of walking the halls of the palace, built by aristocrat and cavalry general Prince Ferdinand von Sachsen-Coburg between 1840 and 1845.
Another bemoaned the long hours and the near impossibility of getting out for dinner, saying he managed to get to a restaurant at 10:30 one night only to find disappointment.
"They let me in and then 15 minutes later they were closing up. Vienna doesnt do itself justice by closing at 11," he said.
One delegation opted to stay far from the Coburg this time.
"I like the reporters, but I didnt want them jumping into the swimming pool asking me about the number of centrifuges." said a diplomat. Sadly, the distant hotel has drained its pool.
By all accounts, the talks have entered their most difficult phase and, at times, turned testy.
Western diplomats said U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry and Iranian Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif had a tense exchange about sanctions on Monday night.
Iran's official news agency IRNA went further, quoting unnamed Palais residents as saying the two could be heard shouting at each other during their one-on-one meeting.
PARKS, PAINTINGS AND TEARS
Ministers escape as best they can. Having broken his leg in May, Kerry cannot cycle or stroll Vienna's streets but has slipped away to sit in one of its parks, his tie loosened.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius, an art connoisseur, has toured the KunsthistorischesMuseum, whose main collections are from Austria's old Habsburg rulers and include Rembrandts, Vermeers and Rubenses.
On Monday night, Zarif and other Iranian negotiators visited an Islamic center in Vienna after midnight to mark the death of Shi'ite Islam's first Imam, Ali, by weeping and praying.
No one seems to know when they will go home.
When Iran and six major powers - Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States - reached an interim deal in Nov. 23, 2013, it was supposed to last six months and a final deal to be done and dusted within a year.
The deadline has since been extended four times, including twice in the last two weeks.
One time limit that once seemed meaningful was 6 a.m. on Friday, by which the U.S. government had to submit any deal to the U.S. Congress to obtain an expedited, 30-day review.
However, with the latest extension - to midnight on Friday - even that seems likely to fall by the wayside.
A Vienna waiter, whose business has surged along with his blood pressure, asked reporters when they were leaving. Met with blank stares, he remarked: "It's a never-ending story."
(Reporting by Arshad Mohammed and John Irish; Additional reporting by Parisa Hafezi and Louis Charbonneau )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:43:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Saudi foreign minister dies: Saudi sources</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/-HfKOyE-3IU/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>RIYADH (Reuters) - Former Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal died on Thursday, two Saudi sources said, two months after he was replaced following 40 years in the job.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thomson Reuters is the world's largest international multimedia news agency, providing investing news , world news , business news , technology news , headline news, small business news , news alerts, personal finance , stock market , and mutual funds information available on Reuters.com, video , mobile , and interactive television platforms. Thomson Reuters journalists are subject to an Editorial Handbook which requires fair presentation and disclosure of relevant interests.
NYSE and AMEX quotes delayed by at least 20 minutes. Nasdaq delayed by at least 15 minutes. For a complete list of exchanges and delays, please click here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:26:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. expects Yemen fighting to halt from Friday until Ramadan ends</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/LXDDQ2Vlsy0/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - The United Nations said it expects an unconditional week-long humanitarian pause in the fighting in Yemen to start on Friday to allow the delivery of assistance to some of the 21 million people in need.</Description>
        <MainBody>UNITED NATIONS | By Michelle Nichols
Damage is seen in the building of the Houthi movement's politburo after it was hit by a Saudi-led air strike in Yemen's capital Sanaa July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
UNITED NATIONS The United Nations said it expects an unconditional week-long humanitarian pause in the fighting in Yemen to start on Friday to allow the delivery of assistance to some of the 21 million people in need.
A Saudi Arabia-led coalition of Arab states has been bombing the Iranian-allied Houthi rebel movement since late March in a bid to restore to power Yemen's President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi, who has fled to Riyadh.
"(U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon) noted that the President has communicated his acceptance of the pause to the coalition to ensure their support and collaboration," said U.N. spokesman Stephane Dujarric on Thursday.
He said the Houthis, the General People's Congress and other parties had ensured U.N. special envoy Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed that the pause will be fully respected and that there will be no violations from any combatants under their control.
"We feel we have the expressions necessary by all parties to announce the start of this pause on Friday," said Dujarric.
"The Secretary-General looks forward to the commitments of all parties to the conflict in Yemen to an unconditional humanitarian pause to start on Friday ... until the end of Ramadan," he said.
More than 3,000 people have been killed in the conflict and over a million displaced, and the United Nations has been urgently pushing for a pause to help the 80 percent of the population in the impoverished Arabian Peninsula country.
Both sides largely observed a five-day humanitarian truce brokered by the United Nations in May.
The United Nations has raised Yemen to its highest level humanitarian crisis, placing it alongside emergencies in South Sudan, Syria and Iraq.
Yemen relies on imports but a near total blockade led by Saudi Arabia has slowed shipments to the war-torn Arabian Peninsula country to a trickle. The Arab coalition is inspecting shipments in a bid to thwart any arms deliveries to the Houthis.
"Full and unhindered access by humanitarian agencies to all parts of the country, including through sea and airports, should be ensured with a view to reaching people in need, including with essential medicines, vaccinations, food and water," Dujarric said.
(Reporting by Michelle Nichols; Editing by Andrew Hay and Tom Brown )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:00:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After gains, Syria rebels face tough fight for Deraa, Aleppo</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/sl79m20eRwc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Momentum that has swept Syrian rebels to a series of swift victories over President Bashar al-Assad appears to have slowed in two major attacks aimed at capturing the cities of Aleppo in the north and Deraa in the south.</Description>
        <MainBody>After gains, Syria rebels face tough fight for Deraa, Aleppo
BEIRUT | By Tom Perry and Suleiman Al-Khalidi
Free Syrian Army fighters fire from a tank during what they said was an offensive against the forces of Syria's President Bashar al-Assad in the southern city of Deraa, Syria June 25, 2015.
Reuters/Alaa Al-Faqir
BEIRUT Momentum that has swept Syrian rebels to a series of swift victories over President Bashar al-Assad appears to have slowed in two major attacks aimed at capturing the cities of Aleppo in the north and Deraa in the south.
The reasons include a determined military effort by the government and its foreign allies to stem the tide of setbacks, and shortcomings in rebel strategy and weaponry that have made it harder for them to capture two cities of strategic value.
This does not necessarily mean Assad, his sway mostly confined to western Syria, is on the cusp of a major fightback. The army and allied militia remain overstretched in a multi-sided war pitting them against Islamic State, al Qaeda, and more moderate rebels.
But rebels say the going is proving harder than expected in cities where government forces are well entrenched and drawing on air power which the insurgents have lacked the means to confront throughout the four-year-long war.
"The battle is difficult and the regime is well fortified," said Bashar al-Zoubi, head of one of the rebel groups battling for Deraa. "It will take a very long time because the regime is fortified among civilians," he told Reuters.
Since late March, Assad has lost nearly all the northwestern province of Idlib to an Islamist alliance including al Qaeda's Nusra Front and important areas of the south including a border crossing and a garrison town to more moderate rebels.
The ultra-hardline Islamic State has also advanced into government-held areas, seizing Palmyra in central Syria - the first time the group has taken a city from Assad.
Seeking to build on their gains, the southern rebels launched the attack to drive remaining government forces from Deraa city in late June. Like Aleppo, Deraa city is already partially under rebel control and largely surrounded by insurgent-held countryside.
"THE OPERATION CONTINUES"
But unlike other recent battles where rebel advances have forced government retreats, the army and militia fighting alongside it have stayed put in Deraa, where tens of thousands of people still live.
The army had deployed heavy air strikes, including the use of barrel bombs, said Zoubi, whose Yarmouk Army is part of the Western-backed Southern Front alliance. "The civilians are the ones suffering."
He said the rebels had recently resubmitted a longstanding request for anti-aircraft missiles, but foreign states that back them had given no answer. "The operation continues," he said.
The Southern Front groups, widely assessed as the main rebel force in the south, have sought to exclude the al Qaeda-linked Nusra Front from the operation. Nusra had responded by trying to obstruct the assault, Southern Front spokesman Isaam al-Rayyes said. "This had an impact."
For Assad, Deraa is more strategically important than other areas lost recently. Were the well-organized Southern Front groups to take the city, it would hasten their advance towards Damascus, just 100 km (60 miles) to the north.
A senior Middle Eastern official close to Damascus said increased Russian and Iranian military and financial support had helped Assad, his government drained by the conflict. "Iranian and Russian support is increasing to the regime," he said.
Deraa, heavily garrisoned because of its proximity to Israel, is defended by elite army units, the source said.
"We must also say the militants did not unite in Deraa as they did in other places such as Idlib, which weakened them. The same can be said for Aleppo."
The rebels' difficulties in Deraa have illustrated the limitations to the support offered by foreign states that have supplied them with military aid via Jordan. The rebels say most of their weapons are seized from the Syrian army.
But foreign support has helped them maintain the upper hand over jihadists, preventing al Qaeda or Islamic State from taking over areas at the border with Jordan and Israel.
IRANIAN SUPPORT FOR ASSAD
Western officials hope the increased military pressure on Assad could help bring him to negotiations to end the conflict that has killed close to a quarter of a million people and triggered the worst refugee crisis since World War Two.
But sources close to Assad forecast a protracted conflict. Lebanon's Hezbollah, an Iranian-backed group fighting alongside Assad, is battling insurgents in areas near Damascus.
And there have been renewed pledges of support from Iran, which has helped to mobilize foreign Shi'ite militias to fight in Syria. Senior Iranian official Ali Akbar Velayati said in a recent newspaper interview that Muslims from countries such as Afghanistan would help "prevent Syria from falling".
Aleppo, 400 km (250 miles) from Damascus, may be a more remote concern than Deraa for Assad, but the rebels there report similar difficulties in advancing into heavily defended areas since they launched their biggest assault there in three years.
"The regime has put all its strength in Aleppo. It's a major center - four or five times the size of Idlib," said Abu Asad Dabeq, military commander of al-Failaq al-Awal, a rebel group fighting under the banner of "The Free Syrian Army".
The insurgent attack on Aleppo has also been hampered by rivalry between jihadist groups and more moderate forces.
Two separate command centers were announced at the start of the attack. One of them included the Nusra Front and said its stated goal was to implement Islamic sharia law in Aleppo. The other comprised non-jihadist groups that are at odds with Nusra.
The insurgent attack in Idlib was led by jihadist groups including Nusra, whereas in Aleppo "there are a range of ideologies ... that mean there is no unity in the military ranks", said an official in the Nour Al-Dein Al-Zenkey Movement, one of the FSA affiliated groups fighting in Aleppo.
The Aleppo rebels are also hindered by fighting with Islamic State, which is vying with them for control of areas north of the city, he said.
"The question of defeating or breaking the regime in Aleppo is difficult, unless the regime collapsed, surrendered and retreated."
(Additional reporting by Laila Bassam, Sylvia Westall and Babak Dehghanpisheh; Editing by Giles Elgood )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:41:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Libya's recognized government warns tankers away from Ras Lanuf port</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/gUsj87dPFsw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TRIPOLI (Reuters) - Libyan security forces guarding the country's major Ras Lanuf oil port will seize any tankers approaching the terminal without permission after a force majeure was lifted there, the country's recognized government said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Libya's recognized government warns tankers away from Ras Lanuf port
TRIPOLI | By Ahmed Elumami
TRIPOLI Libya's recognized government warned its security forces would seize any tankers approaching the Ras Lanuf terminal without permission, saying any attempt to make oil deals with the rival government in Tripoli would be "piracy".
The warning over Ras Lanuf illustrates how the OPEC country's oil industry is caught up in a power struggle between the two rival governments and their armed forces, who have each appointed competing figures in the state oil company.
The internationally recognized government and elected parliament has operated in the east since last year, when an armed faction called Libya Dawn took over the capital, set up its own government and took control of ministries in Tripoli.
Earlier this week, the National Oil Corporation (NOC) based in Tripoli said it was lifting the force majeure measure on the Ras Lanuf oil terminal which had been shut since December because of fighting between the rival factions.
But Ras Lanuf is protected by an armed force allied to the internationally recognized government, which has appointed its own NOC chief who claims to represent the country's industry.
The recognized government's NOC chairman, Yousef Bu Saifi, told Reuters the force majeure was still in effect and orders had been given to the Petroleum Facilities Guard or PFG at Ras Lanuf.
"We have asked the PFG to intercept any tankers trying to approach the oilfields for security and technical reasons. The force majeure is still in place," he said.
Hatem Oraibi, spokesman of Prime Minister Abdullah al-Thinni's recognized government, said any tankers dealing with the Tripoli government could be considered as committing piracy.
Oil guards at Ras Lanuf say they have received orders to warn vessels away and to arrest crew if they did not comply.
Foreign vessels off Libya's coast have in the past come under attack from Libya's armed factions, often because they are believed to be carrying arms or supplies for the rival group.
Four years after the civil war ousted Muammar Gaddafi, Libya is in chaos after brigades of former rebels who once fought together have steadily turned against one another.
Libya's oil industry has been badly hit. Strikes, protests and the conflict have closed down several major oilfields as well as ports. Production is less than half the 1.6 million barrels per day the North African state produced before 2011.
(Writing by Patrick Markey; Additional reporting by Ayman Al-Warfalli in Benghazi; Editing by David Evans and David Holmes )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:39:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>President says anti-foreigner attitudes taking root in Germany</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/RHZRYCdwkf8/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BERLIN (Reuters) - President Joachim Gauck on Thursday condemned a recent rise in "vile" attacks on refugee shelters in Germany and warned that xenophobic attitudes were taking root in the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>President says anti-foreigner attitudes taking root in Germany
BERLIN
German President Joachim Gauck (C) leaves the St. Sixtus church after a memorial service in Haltern am See, March, 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ina Fassbender
BERLIN President Joachim Gauck on Thursday condemned a recent rise in "vile" attacks on refugee shelters in Germany and warned that xenophobic attitudes were taking root in the country.
The comments by the head of state underline growing concern about hostility towards immigrants in Germany, which last year saw the emergence of the grassroots anti-Islam group PEGIDA.
Since the beginning of the year, there have been 150 attacks on refugee shelters -- nearly as many as in the whole of 2014.
"We are seeing xenophobic attitudes taking root and that some people aren't even shying away from carrying out attacks," Gauck said in a speech in Berlin.
"I'm referring to what we have recently experienced again with these vile attacks on refugee homes. It's unbearable."
Gauck called on citizens to stand up and defend Germany's democratic and liberal values by welcoming refugees from countries afflicted by war and human rights abuses.
Germany was shocked in 2011 by revelations that a small neo-Nazi cell, the National Socialist Underground (NSU), had murdered nine immigrants and a policewoman, and carried out bombings and bank robberies. Security services and police had failed for a decade to detect the NSU's existence.
Gauck, a former pastor in old Communist East Germany, has little real power as president but his words carry moral weight.
Chancellor Angela Merkel's government expects the number of people seeking asylum in Germany to more than double this year to a record 450,000.
The federal government has therefore agreed to double its financial support to federal states and cities, which are struggling with a surge of refugees, to 1 billion euros ($1.10 billion) this year.
But Berlin has also vowed to speed up repatriation of those whose asylum applications are rejected.
In the European Union as a whole, the number of arriving migrants -- mainly from Africa and the Middle East -- soared by 68 percent in the first five months of 2015 compared with the year-earlier period, the EU said on Wednesday.
The EU's 28 member states are haggling over the details of a plan for sharing the burden of migrants reaching the bloc.
($1 = 0.9059 euros)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:17:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Malaysia moves on MH17 tribunal plan at U.N., Russia resists</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/hvbfcskLvlE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - Malaysia has asked the United Nations Security Council to set up an international tribunal to prosecute those suspected of downing a passenger airliner last year in eastern Ukraine, but Russia dismissed the move on Thursday as counterproductive.</Description>
        <MainBody>Malaysia moves on MH17 tribunal plan at U.N., Russia resists
UNITED NATIONS
Members of a group of international experts inspect wreckage at the site where the downed Malaysia Airlines flight MH17 crashed, near the village of Hrabove (Grabovo) in Donetsk region, eastern Ukraine August 1, 2014.
Reuters/Sergei Karpukhin
UNITED NATIONS Malaysia has asked the United Nations Security Council to set up an international tribunal to prosecute those suspected of downing a passenger airliner last year in eastern Ukraine, but Russia dismissed the move on Thursday as counterproductive.
Malaysia, a member of the 15-member council, distributed a draft resolution late on Wednesday, which it hoped could be adopted later this month, diplomats said. It is a joint proposal by Malaysia, Australia, the Netherlands, Belgium and Ukraine.
Malaysia Airlines flight MH17 was shot down in July 2014 with 298 passengers on board, two-thirds of them Dutch. It crashed in territory held by Russian-backed separatists.
"It's counterproductive," said Russia's Deputy U.N. Ambassador Petr Iliichev. When asked if Russia would push back against the move, he said: "Yes."
Russia is a veto-wielding permanent member on the 15-member council, along with France, Britain, China and the United States, and therefore, it has the option of blocking the proposal if it is put to a vote.
Ukraine and Western countries accuse the rebels in eastern Ukraine of shooting down the plane with a Russian-made missile. But Moscow has rejected accusations it supplied the rebels with SA-11 Buk anti-aircraft missile systems.
The draft U.N. resolution, seen by Reuters, would "establish an international tribunal for the sole purpose of prosecuting persons responsible for crimes connected with the downing of Malaysia Airlines flight MH17."
It says "that in the particular circumstances of this incident, the establishment of an international tribunal would be an effective guarantee for an independent and impartial accountability process."
(Reporting by Michelle Nichols , editing by G Crosse)
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
