<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:36:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Exclusive: U.S. upgrades Malaysia in annual human trafficking report - sources</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/lKDOxw65vCI/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The United States is upgrading Malaysia from the lowest tier on its list of worst human trafficking centers, U.S. sources said on Wednesday, a move that could smooth the way for an ambitious U.S.-led free-trade deal with the Southeast Asian nation and 11 other countries.</Description>
        <MainBody>A suspected Uighur from China's troubled far-western region of Xinjiang, rests on a ground inside a temporary shelter after being detained at the immigration regional headquarters near the Thailand-Malaysia border in Hat Yai, Songkla March 14, 2014.
Reuters/Athit Perawongmetha
WASHINGTON The United States is upgrading Malaysia from the lowest tier on its list of worst human trafficking centers, U.S. sources said on Wednesday, a move that could smooth the way for an ambitious U.S.-led free-trade deal with the Southeast Asian nation and 11 other countries.
The upgrade to so-called "Tier 2 Watch List" status removes a potential barrier to President Barack Obama's signature global trade deal.
A provision in a related trade bill passed by Congress last month barred from fast-tracked trade deals Malaysia and other countries that earn the worst U.S. human trafficking ranking in the eyes of the U.S. State Department.
The upgrade follows international scrutiny and outcry over Malaysian efforts to combat human trafficking after the discovery this year of scores of graves in people-smuggling camps near its northern border with Thailand.
The State Department last year downgraded Malaysia in its annual "Trafficking in Persons" report to Tier 3, alongside North Korea, Syria and Zimbabwe, citing "limited efforts to improve its flawed victim protection regime" and other problems.
But a congressional source with knowledge of the decision told Reuters the administration had approved the upgraded status. A second source familiar with the matter confirmed the decision.
Some U.S. lawmakers and human-rights advocates had expected Malaysia to remain on Tier 3 this year given its slow pace of convictions in human-trafficking cases and pervasive trafficking in industries such as electronics and palm oil.
This year's full State Department report, including details on each country's efforts to combat human trafficking, is expected to be released next week.
The State Department and the White House both declined comment.
Obama visited Malaysia in April 2014 to cement economic and security ties. Malaysia is the current chair of the 10-nation Association of Southeast Asian Nations. It is seeking to promote unity within the bloc in the face of China's increasingly assertive pursuits of territorial claims in the South China Sea, an object of U.S. criticism.
In May, just as Obama's drive to win "fast-track" trade negotiating authority for his trade deal entered its most sensitive stage in the U.S. Congress, Malaysian police announced the discovery of 139 graves in jungle camps used by suspected smugglers and traffickers of Rohingya Muslims from Myanmar.
Malaysia hopes to be a signatory to Obama's legacy-defining Trans-Pacific Partnership (TPP), which would link a dozen countries, cover 40 percent of the world economy and form a central element of his strategic shift towards Asia.
On June 29, Obama signed into law legislation giving him "fast-track" power to push ahead on the deal.
MALAYSIAN GRAVES
Lawmakers are working on a compromise that would let Malaysia and other countries appearing on a U.S. black-list for human trafficking participate in fast-tracked trade deals if the administration verified that they have taken concrete steps to address the most important issues identified in the annual trafficking report.The graves were found in an area long known for the smuggling of Rohingya and local villagers reported seeing Rohingya in the area, but Malaysia's Deputy Home (Interior) Minister Wan Junaidi Tuanku Jaafar has said it was unclear whether those killed were illegal migrants. The discovery took place after the March cut-off for the U.S. report.
The State Department would have needed to show that Malaysia had neither fully complied with minimum anti-trafficking standards nor made significant efforts to do so to justify keeping Malaysia on Tier 3, which can lead to penalties such as the withholding of some assistance.
In its report last year, the State Department said Malaysia had reported 89 human-trafficking investigations in the 12 months to March 2014, down from 190 the previous year, and nine convictions compared with 21 the previous year.
In the latest year to March, Malaysia's conviction rate is believed to have fallen further, according to human-rights advocates, despite a rise in the number of investigations. That reinforced speculation Malaysia would remain on Tier 3.
"If true, this manipulation of Malaysia's ranking in the State Department's 2015 TIP report would be a perversion of the trafficking list and undermine both the integrity of this important report as well as the very difficult task of confronting states about human trafficking," said Democratic Senator Robert Menendez, who had pushed to bar Tier 3 countries from inclusion in the trade pact.
Phil Robertson, deputy director of Human Rights Watch's Asia division, said he was "stunned" by the upgrade.
"They have done very little to improve the protection from abuse that migrant workers face," he said. "This would seem to be some sort of political reward from the United States and I would urge the U.S. Congress to look long and hard at who was making the decisions on such an upgrade."    Malaysia has an estimated 2 million illegal migrant laborers, many of whom work in conditions of forced labor under employers and recruitment companies in sectors ranging from electronics to palm oil to domestic service.
Last year's report said many migrant workers are exploited and subjected to practices associated with forced labor. Many foreign women recruited for ostensibly legal work in Malaysian restaurants, hotels, and beauty salons are subsequently coerced into prostitution, the report said.
An administration official told Reuters in June that the White House had been working closely with the Malaysian government and stakeholders to fight the problem.
Among the 12 TPP countries, Brunei has also come under attack by human-rights groups for adopting Islamic criminal law, which includes punishing offenses such as sodomy and adultery with death, including by stoning. Vietnam's Communist government has been criticized for jailing dissidents.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:33:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan's Abe: will work with G7, other countries on Greece crisis</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/kxqvqtF_MA4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TOKYO (Reuters) - Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe said on Thursday he will work with Group of Seven countries and other Asian countries to ensure economic and finance market stability as the euro zone grapples with Greece's debt crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Japan's Abe: will work with G7, other countries on Greece crisis
TOKYO
Japan's Prime Minister Shinzo Abe gives a keynote address at Japan Summit 2015 hosted by the Economist magazine in Tokyo, July 9, 2015.
Reuters/Toru Hanai
TOKYO Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe said on Thursday he will work with Group of Seven countries and other Asian countries to ensure economic and finance market stability as the euro zone grapples with Greece's debt crisis.
Abe, speaking at a seminar, also said excessive yen strength has been corrected due to economic policies he put in place when he took office in late 2012.
(Reporting by Stanley White; Editing by Kim Coghill)
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:33:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran says makes new proposal in nuclear talks, West unimpressed</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/DGfAZrfcKZk/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran has offered "constructive solutions" to resolve disputes in nuclear talks with six major powers, the Iranian Students News Agency (ISNA) reported on Wednesday, but Western officials suggested they had heard nothing new from Tehran.</Description>
        <MainBody>VIENNA | By John Irish and Arshad Mohammed
VIENNA Iran has offered "constructive solutions" to resolve disputes in nuclear talks with six major powers, the Iranian Students News Agency (ISNA) reported on Wednesday, but Western officials suggested they had heard nothing new from Tehran.
Iran and the powers are in the last stretch of talks to reach a final agreement to end a more than 12-year standoff over Iran's nuclear program. The aim is to lift sanctions in exchange for at least a decade of curbs on the program.
"Iran has presented constructive solutions to overcome the remaining differences. We will not show flexibility regarding our red lines," an Iranian diplomat, who was not identified, told ISNA.
But Western officials indicated they had yet to see substantive new proposals. The biggest sticking points include issues such as a United Nations arms embargo, U.N. missile sanctions, the speed of sanctions relief, and research and development on advanced nuclear centrifuges.
"I haven't seen anything new from Iran," a Western diplomat close to the talks told Reuters on condition of anonymity. Another Western official echoed the remarks.
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry and Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif have stayed behind in Vienna, along with EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini, in an attempt to break the logjam while most of the other foreign ministers returned to their capitals.
Air-conditioning systems in the luxurious Palais Coburg hotel are struggling with outside temperatures approaching 40 Celsius (104 Fahrenheit), and some negotiators have found it hard to keep their cool during the discussions, officials say.
TENSE EXCHANGE
Kerry and Zarif were involved in a tense exchange over U.N. sanctions on Monday night, diplomats said. Tehran says conventional weapons and missiles have nothing to do with the nuclear issue and embargoes should therefore be removed.
"There was no slamming of doors but it was a very heated exchange of views," one of the senior Western diplomats said.
Iran's official news agency IRNA quoted unnamed residents at the Palais as saying Kerry and Zarif could be heard shouting at each other during a one-on-one meeting on Monday. A Kerry aide had gone in to tell them that they could be heard clearly.
Western countries accuse Iran of seeking the capability to build nuclear weapons, while Tehran says its program is peaceful.
A successful deal could be the biggest milestone in decades towards easing hostility between Iran and the United States, foes since Iranian revolutionaries stormed the U.S. embassy in Tehran in 1979.
It would also be a political success for both U.S. President Barack Obama and Iran's pragmatic President Hassan Rouhani, both of whom face scepticism from powerful hardliners at home.
Iran, the United States, Britain, France, Germany, Russia and China have given themselves at least until Friday, but a source from one of the powers said on Tuesday they had to wrap up in the next 48 hours.
A senior U.S. official told reporters on Tuesday: "I believe we will in the near term either get this deal or find out we can't."
The disagreements over U.N. Security Council sanctions are among the most difficult.
Russia and China, which have never hidden their dislike of sanctions, had indicated they would support the termination of the United Nations arms embargo and missile sanctions on Iran, both of which date back to 2006.
MIXED MESSAGE
In the end, however, they agreed not to break ranks with the Americans and Europeans, who want to maintain the measures given the instability in the Middle East.
"In the current context, it would be pretty obscene as a political message if we resolve the nuclear issue but then give them money and the capacity to import and export arms," a senior Western official said.
Russia is especially sensitive about sanctions, Western officials say, due to the fact that it itself is under U.S. and European Union sanctions over allegations that it is supporting pro-Moscow rebels in eastern Ukraine, which it denies.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius and British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond were expected to return to Vienna on Wednesday evening.
U.S. and European officials have indicated that they are prepared to walk away if there is not a deal soon, while the Iranians have said they are happy to continue negotiating.
Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who has the power to block a deal, last month ruled out either a long freeze of sensitive nuclear work or opening military sites to inspectors. Western officials say Khamenei's "red lines" have made things more difficult for the Iranian delegation.
"There is a sort of 'good-cop/bad-cop' between Zarif and the supreme leader," a Western official said. "Zarif is under a lot of pressure."
The latest extension of the talks to Friday left open the possibility an agreement would not arrive in time to secure a 30-day review period by the Republican-dominated U.S. Congress.
If a deal is sent to Congress after July 9, the period grows to 60 days, increase the chance that the deal could unravel.
(Additional reporting by Louis Charbonneau and Parisa Hafezi ; Editing by Kevin Liffey )
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, British Foreign Minister Philip Hammond (not seen), Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, German Minister for Foreign Affairs Frank-Walter Steinmeier, French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius, China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi, EU Deputy...
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
1 of 5
right
German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier (L) French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius (3rd L) Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi (4th L) European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy Federica Mogherini (centre row, 2ndR) U.S. Secretary of...
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
2 of 5
right
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry  meets with foreign ministers of Germany, France, China, Britain, Russia and the European Union during the Iran Talks meetings at a hotel in Vienna, Austria July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Carlos Barria
3 of 5
right
Head of the Iranian Atomic Energy Organization Ali Akbar Salehi (2nd R) walks near the hotel where the Iran nuclear talks meetings are being held in Vienna, Austria in Vienna, Austria July 4, 2015.
Reuters/Carlos Barria
4 of 5
right
Iranian Foreign Minister Javad Zarif stands on the balcony of Palais Coburg, the venue for nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria, July 2, 2015.
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:15:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope praises Bolivia's reforms, pays tribute to slain priest</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/jGSZQ8gPb5s/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LA PAZ, Bolivia (Reuters) - Pope Francis arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday, praising the government of leftist President Evo Morales, the country's first indigenous leader whose frosty relationship with the Catholic Church has begun to thaw under the Argentine pontiff's papacy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope praises Bolivia's reforms, pays tribute to slain priest
LA PAZ, Bolivia | By Philip Pullella and Daniel Ramos
LA PAZ, Bolivia Pope Francis arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday, praising the government of leftist President Evo Morales, the country's first indigenous leader whose frosty relationship with the Catholic Church has begun to thaw under the Argentine pontiff's papacy.
Morales has nationalized key industries such as oil and gas to finance social programs that have slashed poverty in the Andean country, where animal sacrifices and pagan worship remain widely cherished.
Francis, Latin America's first pope, arrived from Ecuador at La Paz's El Alto airport, at over 4,000 meters (13,000 feet) above sea level, the highest international airport in the world.
Oxygen tanks are always at the ready for passengers to deal with altitude sickness brought on by the thin air.
Locals chew coca leaves and drink coca tea. Coca is the main ingredient for cocaine.
Aboard the plane, the pope drank a tea made of a mix of coca leaves, chamomile and anise seeds to ward off illness, a flight attendant said.
The pope, who lost part of one lung to an infection when he was a young man, will spend only about four hours in the La Paz, the seat of government, before moving on to the provincial city of Santa Cruz for the rest of his two-day stay.
He did not appear to have any difficulties as he left the plane, while he read his arrival speech, and on the ride to the center of the city for a private meeting with Morales.
"Bolivia is making important steps towards including broad sectors in the countrys economic, social and political life," Francis said in his arrival address, wearing a white poncho over his white cassock to warm him against the Andean wind.
Morales, an Aymara native and former coca grower, came to power in 2006 promising to govern in favor of the poor indigenous majority, marginalized by the ruling elite.
In his address to the pope, Morales, who had frequently clashed with Church officials in Bolivia before relations improved when Francis was elected in 2013, welcomed the pope as a homecoming hero.
"In many historic moments, the Church was used for domination, subjugation and oppression. Now the Bolivian people receive you with joy and hope," said Morales, wearing a dark suit with indigenous pattern embroidered around the lapels.
"We welcome you as the chief representative of the Catholic Church coming to support the liberation of our Bolivian peoples."
TRIBUTE TO SLAIN PRIEST
On his way into the center of La Paz, which lies in a bowl beneath mountain peaks, the pope was due to stop at a spot where the body of Jesuit Father Luis Espinal Camps was found in 1980. The priest, who was a strong supporter of the rights of miners, was tortured and murdered by paramilitaries.
"Let us pray for this brother of ours who was a victim of interests," the pope said, asking the roadside crowd to join him in a minute's silence.
Under Morales' brand of "indigenous socialism," Bolivia has vastly expanded the role of the state in the economy, nationalizing key industries and introduced socialist reforms to spread the wealth from a boom in gas exports.
  Bolivia's economy has tripled in size during the nine years under Morales, a prominent member of South America's leftist bloc, and the number of Bolivians living in extreme poverty has fallen to one in five from more than a third of the population of 10 million in 2006.
It remains, however, one of the poorest countries in the Americas. Francis urged Morales to be sure to blend economic growth with social justice.
"A growth which is merely material will always run the
risk of creating new divisions, of the wealth of some being built on the poverty of others," he said.
Morales, who was elected to a third term last October, has been more pragmatic than some of his closest Latin American allies on economic policy at home, winning him praise from some of the world financial institutions he has excoriated, such as the International Monetary Fund (IMF).
The pope, who has made defense of the poor and the planet major planks of his papacy, also praised the fact that the Bolivian constitution "recognizes the rights of individuals, minorities and the natural environment."
Francis flew into Bolivia from Quito, Ecuador, where he showed his sense of humor during the last few hours of his trip to that country, where he drew crowds totaling nearly 2 million people.
"I have a prepared script but I don't want to read it," said the 78-year-old pope to laughs from the crowd, before asking them to pray for him so that he would never forget where he came from.
"Do not fall into a spiritual Alzheimer's, do not forget!" Francis added in a totally improvised speech.
(Additional reporting Sarah Marsh in Santa Cruz, and Diego Ore in La Paz.; Editing Grant McCool, Richard Lough and Lisa Shumaker)
Pope Francis waves after his arrival in El Alto, Bolivia, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/David Mercado
1 of 8
right
Pope Francis rides on a popemobile on a road leading from El Alto to La Paz, on the outskirts of La Paz, Bolivia, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/James Brunker
2 of 8
right
An indigenous faithful waits for the arrival of Pope Francis in El Alto, Bolivia, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Daniel Rodrigo
3 of 8
right
Security walk near placards referring to Pope Francis at the square of Cristo Redentor where he will celebrate a mass during his visit to Bolivia starting on July 8, in Santa Cruz, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Mariana Bazo
4 of 8
right
A woman walks next to a figure of Pope Francis in La Paz, July 7, 2015, ahead of his visit to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay in his Latin-American tour.
Reuters/David Mercado
5 of 8
right
Art students restore religious figures at the 'Nuestra Senora de La Paz' Cathedral in La Paz, July 7, 2015, ahead of Pope Francis' visit to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay in his Latin-American tour.
Reuters/David Mercado
6 of 8
right
Placards referring to Pope Francis are seen at the square of Cristo Redentor where he will celebrate a mass during his visit to Bolivia starting on July 8, in Santa Cruz, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Mariana Bazo
7 of 8
right
A man is seen next to a damaged mural of Pope Francis in El Alto, on the outskirts of La Paz, July 7, 2015, ahead of Pope Francis' visit to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay in his Latin-American  tour.
Reuters/Carlos Sanchez Navas
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:59:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Air Force leader sees Russia as 'biggest threat'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/UqxqehJcy-s/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Russia is the biggest threat to U.S. national security and America must boost its military presence throughout Europe even as NATO allies face budget challenges and scale back spending, U.S. Air Force Secretary Deborah James said on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>WASHINGTON | By Andrea Shalal
WASHINGTON Russia is the biggest threat to U.S. national security and America must boost its military presence throughout Europe even as NATO allies face budget challenges and scale back spending, U.S. Air Force Secretary Deborah James said on Wednesday.
"I do consider Russia to be the biggest threat," James told Reuters in an interview after a series of visits and meetings with U.S. allies across Europe, including Poland.
James said Washington was responding to Russia's recent "worrisome" actions by boosting its presence across Europe, and would continue rotational assignments of F-16 fighter squadrons.
"This is no time to in any way signal a lack of resolve in the face of these Russian actions," she said.
James said she was disappointed that only four of NATO's 28 members had thus far met the NATO target of spending 2 percent of gross domestic product on defense.
"This is not something that came up out of thin air. This is something that we as NATO members agreed to do. All of us need to be advocates," she said.
The top Air Force civilian leader acknowledged that Europe was facing difficult immigration and economic challenges at the moment, but said the NATO military alliance and associated commitments should be a clear priority.
Britain on Wednesday said it would commit to the 2 percent spending pledge for the next five years, which will raise the number of NATO allies meeting the spending goal to five in 2015.
Given the tensions, the Air Force is continuing its effort to reduce U.S. reliance on Russian RD-180 rocket engines for military and intelligence satellite launches, James said.
She said there were huge demands on U.S. Air Force assets now, given the tensions with Russia and the fight against Islamic State, but the Air Force was also working hard to defend its weapons systems and networks against growing cyber attacks.
James said her records were among those involved in a massive breach of personnel records held by the Office of Personnel Management that some U.S. officials have blamed on China. China denies any involvement in hacking U.S. databases.
James said the Air Force took a hard look at its cyber security immediately after the revelations and decided to redouble its efforts, although no new actions were needed.
She said the service was cataloging weapons and IT systems to detect any possible vulnerabilities, while also working to set up 39 cyber security teams around the country.
(Reporting by Andrea Shalal; Editing by Leslie Adler)
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:40:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nigeria's president meets campaigners for girls abducted by Boko Haram</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/_JPN6th_TuQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ABUJA (Reuters) - Nigeria's President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday held his first meeting with campaigners calling for the release of more than 200 schoolgirls abducted by Boko Haram militants in the northeastern town of Chibok last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigeria's president meets campaigners for girls abducted by Boko Haram
ABUJA
President Muhammadu Buhari addresses members of the National Working Committee during the meeting of the All Progressives Congress (APC) party at the headquarters of the party in Abuja, Nigeria July 3, 2015.
Reuters/Afolabi Sotunde
ABUJA Nigeria's President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday held his first meeting with campaigners calling for the release of more than 200 schoolgirls abducted by Boko Haram militants in the northeastern town of Chibok last year.
The militant Islamist group, whose six-year insurgency has seen thousands killed in Africa's most populous nation and top oil producer, caused an international outcry when it took the girls from secondary school dormitories in April 2014.
Buhari praised members of the Bring Back Our Girls group for their efforts to prevent the missing children being forgotten.
"Nobody in Nigeria or outside could have missed your consistency and persistence," said Buhari during the meeting at his presidential villa in the capital, Abuja.
"I think you will agree that the present government takes the issue very seriously," he said, adding that the military was working with neighboring countries to ensure a regional task force could fight the insurgency.
Earlier this year an Amnesty International report said that Boko Haram had kidnapped at least 2,000 Nigerian women and girls since the start of 2014, many of whom were sexually abused or trained to fight.
In a statement, the Bring Back Our Girls campaigners said the safe return of the schoolgirls would "amount to the strongest statement that our government has respect for the sanctity and dignity of every Nigerian life".
The frequency of attacks by suspected Boko Haram militants in northern states has increased since the president vowed in his inauguration speech of May 29 that the group would be crushed.
More than 200 people died in a string of attacks last week and dozens more have been killed in northern Nigeria and Chad in the last few days.
Boko Haram, which has been trying to establish a state adhering to strict sharia law in northeast Nigeria, controlled an area larger than Belgium at the end of 2014.
Nigerian and regional forces pushed the jihadists out of most of that territory in the last few months but the militants have a last stronghold in the Sambisa forest reserve and, with the increase in attacks, appear to be growing in strength.
(Reporting by Felix Onuah; Writing by Alexis Akwagyiram; Editing by Lisa Shumaker )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Despite peace talks breakthrough, Afghan leader under pressure at home</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/gg-i4Rltgec/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KABUL (Reuters) - If Afghan President Ashraf Ghani was savoring inaugural peace talks with Taliban insurgents held in Pakistan on Wednesday, celebrations of the milestone he has worked so hard to reach may be short-lived.</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghanistan President Ashraf Ghani speaks during a news conference in Kabul, Afghanistan May 11, 2015.
Reuters/Mohammad Ismail
KABUL If Afghan President Ashraf Ghani was savoring inaugural peace talks with Taliban insurgents held in Pakistan on Wednesday, celebrations of the milestone he has worked so hard to reach may be short-lived.
Back in Kabul, the 66-year-old faces growing discontent from lawmakers who are making life difficult on several fronts nine months after he took office.
The lower house of parliament is threatening to impeach Ghani's interior minister over his failure to stem violence by Islamist militants. Last week lawmakers rejected the president's third nominee for defense minister.
Casualties among Afghanistan's fledgling armed forces are on the rise, they are losing pockets of territory to insurgents and there are less than 10,000 foreign troops left to support them after most NATO soldiers withdrew last year.
Little wonder the president calls his "the most difficult job in the world."
Ghani's deputy spokesman, Sayed Zafar Hashemi, downplayed the political turmoil.
"There are problems in Afghanistan, and the environment can never be ideal for a leader," he said.
The Senate upper house of parliament has been on strike since Sunday, protesting that the government has failed to respond to members' concerns.
Another problem for Ghani is the lack of cohesion in his unity government, so-called because he and rival presidential candidate Abdullah Abdullah were convinced to share power after months of wrangling over a contested election last year.
"This government is absolutely lacking national unity," said Mohammad Mohaqiq, an influential figure representing the Hazara ethnic minority.
Leaders of Afghanistan's various ethnic groups, including Abdullah's powerful Tajik faction of "mujahideen", complain that Ghani favors his own Pashtun kin when it comes to filling key posts, an issue that has dogged Afghan politics for decades.
A senior diplomat in Kabul said that he had reached "a pessimistic low" over the government's survival prospects.
FEW REAL ALTERNATIVES
For now, a growing number of critics saying Ghani should go have few legal options other than blocking his agenda.
Removing an Afghan president is constitutionally complicated and would require new elections that few would relish after last year's political crisis that threatened to spill into violence.
But in Afghanistan, where some power brokers command well-armed factions, deep discontent is worrying.
Influential northern governor Atta Mohammad Noor, who last year issued veiled threats of a breakaway government, this week issued a list of "suggested" defense ministers after parliament rejected Ghani's latest nominee, Mohammad Masoom Stanekzai.
Atta's loyalists in parliament led a campaign against Stanekzai's nomination, joined by Uzbek lawmakers who are reportedly seeking a member of their own ethnicity as defense minister, said pro-Ghani parliamentarian Qader Zazai.
"The Tajiks and former mujahideen MPs did not vote because they think all security sectors are occupied by Pashtuns and power must be shared," he said.
On Wednesday, parliament also voted down Ghani's nomination for the first woman to the Supreme Court.
Next on its hit list could be Interior Minister Noor ul Haq Ulomi, likely to be called for questioning before lawmakers, some of whom are threatening to remove him.
"We are going to summon the interior minister and will likely dismiss him," said lawmaker Allah Gul Mujahid, citing spiraling violence that included a Taliban attack on the parliamentary compound last month.
However, it was unclear whether Ghani's opponents in parliament have enough votes to remove Ulomi.
Ghani has pushed for peace talks with the Taliban to end the war, and achieved a rare breakthrough when his government met militants formally for the first time this week.
COMPLAINTS TAKE ON ETHNIC HUE
Afghanistan's fledgling democracy set up after the U.S.-sponsored military intervention that toppled the Taliban in 2001 has been hampered by power struggles and corruption throughout.
Ghani campaigned on promises to tackle graft and create a professional administration based on merit.
But he has struggled to balance the competing interests in Afghanistan's labyrinthine politics, described by one diplomat as a "constellation of egos".
Disagreements between Ghani and Abdullah's camps delayed cabinet nominations for months, and the two are still deadlocked over who should lead the electoral reform commission.
Increasingly, complaints against Ghani have taken on an ethnic hue, a worrying trend in a country that fought an ethnic-based civil war in the 1990s.
Hazara protesters last month accused the government of failing to come to the aid of 30 Hazara police massacred by Taliban fighters in Jalrez district, west of Kabul. Ghani ordered an investigation.
Mohaqiq, the Hazara political leader, said he pleaded for hours during the battle for reinforcements that were never sent.
"All I received were fake promises and lies," he said.
(Additional reporting by Jessica Donati; Writing by Kay Johnson; Editing by Mike Collett-White )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:01:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Yemen government tells U.N. it agrees to conditional truce</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/67SOoGLYyFw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - Yemen's government told the United Nations on Wednesday it would agree to a truce to end more than three months of fighting provided key "guarantees" were met, a spokesman said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen government tells U.N. it agrees to conditional truce
DUBAI
A man reacts as he stands next to wreckage at the site of a car bomb attack outside his house in Sanaa June 29, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
DUBAI Yemen's government told the United Nations on Wednesday it would  agree to a truce to end more than three months of fighting provided key "guarantees" were met, a spokesman said.
"The Yemeni authorities have informed the Secretary General of the United Nations Ban Ki-moon of its agreement to implement a truce in the coming days," spokesman Rajeh Badi told Reuters by phone from the government's seat of exile in Saudi Arabia.
Yemen's President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi, the spokesman said, had "set guarantees for the success of the truce".
These included the release of prisoners by Yemen's dominant Houthi group, including the loyalist defense minister, as well as the Houthis' withdrawal from four southern and eastern provinces where they are fighting local militias.
The United Nations has received a letter from the Yemeni government and was "seeking clarification from the parties," said Ban's spokesman Stephane Dujarric.
Saudi Arabia and an Arab coalition have been bombing the Iran-allied Houthis and their allies in Yemen's army in an effort to back armed opponents of the Houthis and restore Hadi.
There was no immediate comment from the Houthi movement, which views its takeover of the capital Sanaa last September, and of much of the country since, as a revolution against a corrupt government backed by the West.
The Houthis have not yet accepted a U.N. Security Council Resolution passed in April which recognizes Hadi as the legitimate president and calls on them to quit seized land.
Aid agencies say the fighting and a near-blockade imposed by an alliance of Arab states aimed at weapons deliveries to the Houthis has caused a humanitarian catastrophe, with most people needing some kind of aid.
More than 3,000 people have been killed in the conflict and over a million displaced, and the U.N. has been urgently pushing for a pause to help impoverished people.
"We're optimistic (the Houthis) will agree, because this will guarantee the sending of aid to Yemenis," Badi said.
(Reporting by Noah Browning, additional reporting by Michelle Nichols at the United Nations; editing by Andrew Roche and G Crosse)
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:57:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece seeks new EU loan deal in race to avert collapse</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/yMYqYjjHm7U/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>STRASBOURG/BRUSSELS (Reuters) - A race to save Greece from bankruptcy and keep it in the euro gathered pace on Wednesday when Athens formally applied for a three-year loan and European authorities launched an accelerated review of the request.</Description>
        <MainBody>STRASBOURG/BRUSSELS | By Barbara Lewis and Alastair Macdonald
STRASBOURG/BRUSSELS A race to save Greece from bankruptcy and keep it in the euro gathered pace on Wednesday when Athens formally applied for a three-year loan and European authorities launched an accelerated review of the request.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called in a speech to the European Parliament for a fair deal, acknowledging Greece's historic responsibility for its plight, after EU leaders gave him five days to come up with convincing reforms.
The government submitted a request to the European Stability Mechanism bailout fund to lend an unspecified amount "to meet Greece's debt obligations and to ensure stability of the financial system". It promised to begin implementing tax and pension measures sought by creditors as early as Monday.
With its banks closed, cash withdrawals rationed and the economy in freefall, Greece has never been closer to a state bankruptcy that would probably force it to leave the euro and print an alternative currency.
Yet the leftist premier seemed almost nonchalant, albeit with a note of humility, when he appeared before EU lawmakers in Strasbourg to cheers and scattered boos.
Speaking hours after euro zone leaders, at another emergency summit in Brussels, set Greece a deadline of the end of the week to come up with far-reaching reform proposals, Tsipras said Greeks had no choice but to demand a way out of "this impasse".
"We are determined not to have a clash with Europe but to tackle head-on the establishment in our own country and to change the mindset which will take us and the euro zone down," he said to applause from the left. But he gave scant details of his reform plans, frustrating many lawmakers.
The head of the Eurogroup of finance ministers of the 19-nation currency area, Jeroen Dijsselbloem, asked the European Commission and the European Central Bank to evaluate the loan request, assess Greek debt sustainability and study whether Greece poses a risk to the financial stability of the euro zone.
IMF chief Christine Lagarde reiterated that Greece's massive debt would need restructuring, something Germany is resisting. "Greece is in a situation of acute crisis, which needs to be addressed seriously and promptly," she said at the Brookings Institution think-tank in Washington.
EMERGENCY FINANCE
The aim is for Eurogroup ministers meeting on Saturday to be in a position to recommend a loan, and some emergency bridging finance, which a full summit of the 28 EU leaders would approve on Sunday if they are satisfied with Greek reform commitments.
That is a big 'if', both due to Athens' checkered record and because many of the liberalization measures required run counter to the leftist ideology of Tsipras' Syriza party.
The prime minister promised to deliver detailed reform plans on Thursday and avoided the angry rhetoric that has alienated many European partners. He did however criticize attempts to "terrorize" Greeks into voting for "never-ending austerity".
The European Central Bank kept Greece's banks on a tight leash, holding a freeze on emergency funding that means they could soon run out of cash. The Greek government said banks would remain closed until July 13, with an ATM withdrawal limit unchanged at 60 euros per day.
European Council President Donald Tusk reiterated that the final deadline for Greece to submit convincing reform plans and start implementing them was this week.
"Our inability to find an agreement may lead to the bankruptcy of Greece and the insolvency of its banking system," Tusk told EU lawmakers. "And for sure it will be most painful for the Greek people.
"I have no doubt that this will affect Europe, also in the geopolitical sense. If someone has any illusion that it will not, they are naive," he said.
In the turbulent chamber, some lawmakers held up "Oxi" (No) signs to back Greek voters' rejection of more austerity, while far-right speakers praised the radical leftist government for standing up to what several called the European "oligarchy".
Euro zone officials want Greece to rush a first wave of measures through parliament before Sunday to prove its serious intent. German Chancellor Angela Merkel has said she would ask parliament in Berlin to authorize the opening of loan negotiations if the Greek measures are deemed satisfactory.
Merkel made clear earlier that she was "not exaggeratedly optimistic" that a deal could be found to save Greece by Sunday.
Euro zone sources said one key question was whether the package will be more ambitious than the spending cuts, tax increases and modest reforms that Greek voters rejected on Sunday in a referendum on a previous bailout plan.
"The numbers have to add up, and the numbers have become vastly more unfavorable since the banks were shut and the economy seized up in the last 10 days," one euro zone finance official said.
"ADMISSION OF IMPOTENCE"
France, which has tried to mediate between Athens and Berlin, nailed its colors to the mast on Wednesday, warning of the perils of a "Grexit".
Socialist Prime Minister Manuel Valls told parliament in Paris: "Keeping Greece in the euro and therefore in the heart of Europe and the EU is something of the utmost geostrategic and geopolitical importance." To let Greece go would be "an admission of impotence", he added.
Despite the last-minute efforts to conjure up a deal, a Reuters poll of economists found the probability of Greece leaving the euro zone had risen to 55 percent from 45 percent last week, the first time it was deemed more likely than not.
Tsipras admitted that after winning power on a promise to end austerity, his government had "spent more time negotiating than governing" but he disappointed those who had hoped to hear concrete immediate measures to transform the shattered economy.
Having secured a referendum victory and the unprecedented support of the five main parties in parliament, Tsipras also made clear he wanted to act fast to pre-empt any possible revolt against the painful concessions he will need to make.
He was strongly critical of Greece's failings as a society, citing a history of clientelism, corruption, tax evasion that had "run riot", inequality and "the nexus of political and economic power".
While Athens has made strides since 2010 in turning around its public finances to post a budget surplus before debt service, it has lagged on implementing structural reforms.
In particular, it has fallen far short of targets on privatizing state assets and struggled to improve tax collection and reform labor laws and a costly pension system.
Centrist EU lawmaker Sylvie Goulard told Tsipras: "In the words of a well known advertising slogan, 'Just do it!'"
(Additional reporting by Renee Maltezou, Foo Yun Chee , Robert-Jan Bartunek, Alastair Macdonald and Tom Koerkemeier in Brussels, Susanna Twidale in Strasbourg, Deepa Babington in Athens, Madeline Chambers in Berlin and Anna Yukhananov in Washington; Ross Finlay in London and Jason Lange and Douwe Miedema in Washington; Writing by Paul Taylor; Editing by Giles Elgood and Andrew Heavens )
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras is followed by Minister of State Nikos Pappas (L) and government spokesman Gabriel Sakelaridis (not pictured) as he leaves his office to visit Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos in Athens July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
1 of 5
right
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras attends a meeting with Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos in Athens July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Christian Hartmann
2 of 5
right
Members of the European Parliament with posters with the word 'No' (Oxi) attend a debate on Greece at the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Vincent Kessler
3 of 5
right
Members of the European Parliament hold placards which reads 'No - Freedom to Greece' ahead of the speech of Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras at the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Vincent Kessler
4 of 5
right
An ATM which is no longer dispensing cash displays a message on its screen in central Athens, Greece July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Cathal McNaughton
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:10:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IMF revamps its lending and support for poor countries</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/4qR02MvIu-o/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Thomson Reuters Foundation) - The International Monetary Fund is boosting by 50 percent its lending for the world's poorest countries as part of a revamp of its operations to help world leaders achieve their ambitious agenda for global development.</Description>
        <MainBody>Children carry firewood for domestic use in Buye a rural town north of capital Bujumbura in this picture taken May 1, 2015.
Reuters/Edmund Blair
WASHINGTON (Thomson Reuters Foundation) - The International Monetary Fund is boosting by 50 percent its lending for the world's poorest countries as part of a revamp of its operations to help world leaders achieve their ambitious agenda for global development.
IMF Managing Director Christine Lagarde announced the changes on Wednesday ahead of a United Nations conference next week on how to finance development when global growth is slowing and foreign aid budgets shrinking.
"This year marks a once-in-a-generation opportunity for global development," LaGarde said in a speech prepared for delivery at the Brookings Institution in Washington.
An estimated $2 trillion to $3 trillion in new investment is needed to achieve the United Nation's bold agenda, which world leaders are due to adopt in September. It has drawn up 17 Sustainable Development Goals on everything from  ending hunger and poverty to achieving gender equality and making cities sustainable and safe by 2030.
These goals, along with climate change which will come up for debate by year's end, present significant financing challenges.
While the IMF's primary role is as emergency lender, Lagarde laid out a series of measures designed to support low-income countries as they pursue faster and more equitable economic development.
It expanded the borrowing limit on its low-interest and interest-free loans, which 73 poor countries are eligible to receive, from 300 percent of their IMF quota to 450 percent. It also lengthened the repayment period on zero-interest loans for fragile states and countries hit by natural disasters.
The IMF coupled this with organizational changes to focus   more staff resource on technical advice and training in the following areas:
* Taxation: Tax collection is less than 15 percent of GDP in almost half the developing countries against 34 percent in OECD countries. The IMF said it will work with developing countries on improving tax systems and would represent their interests in international talks to revamp global corporate tax rules.
* Infrastructure: the World Bank estimates there is $1 trillion a year shortfall in infrastructure investment in developing countries, while IMF research shows that 30 percent of potential gains from public investment is lost. The IMF will work more closely with countries on infrastructure strategies.
* Financial inclusion: The IMF will expand its analytical work on income inequality, gender, youth and access to finance for marginalized people as a means to raise GDP.
"In these concrete ways, the IMF intends to create a more supportive environment for developing countries to prosper in the period ahead. We will play our part," Lagarde said.
(Reporting by Stella Dawson; Editing by Leslie Gevirtz )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:08:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suspected Boko Haram militants kill 26 people in Chad attacks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/IsJ-g-QknSY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>N'DJAMENA (Reuters) - Suspected militants from the Nigerian Islamist group Boko Haram killed 26 people in night attacks on two villages on Lake Chad over the weekend, Chadian officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Suspected Boko Haram militants kill 26 people in Chad attacks
By Madjiasra Nako
N'DJAMENA Suspected militants from the Nigerian Islamist group Boko Haram killed 26 people in night attacks on two villages on Lake Chad over the weekend, Chadian officials said.
Boko Haram has stepped up assaults in recent weeks across the region in what appears to be a fight back against an offensive mounted by soldiers from Nigeria and its neighbors, Chad, Cameroon and Niger.
"The two villages were attacked by surprise on Saturday and Sunday night. There were 13 dead in each attack," said a Chadian official who declined to be named.
Merom village was attacked on Saturday by armed men who slit the throats of their victims and burned houses before fleeing, the source said. Other local officials gave similar accounts.
Militants also attacked a group of camel herders at the village of Tiskra, cutting 13 people's throats before fleeing when guards of the village chief opened fire, the source said.
Boko Haram, fighting to carve out an Islamist state in northeast Nigeria, has also launched a string of cross border raids.
Most of its recent attacks have been in Nigeria but on June 15 suspected Boko Haram militants killed 34 people in two suicide blasts at police stations in Niger's capital.
That attack was claimed by a group called The West Africa Province division of the Islamic State militant group, according to the SITE Intelligence monitoring service.
It was not immediately clear if that was another name for Boko Haram.  The leader of Islamic State, which controls tracts of Syria and Iraq, said in March it had accepted a pledge of allegiance from the Nigerian group.
Last week, more than 200 people died in a string of attacks inside Nigeria, piling pressure on new President Muhammadu Buhari.
(Writing by Matthew Mpoke Bigg; Editing by Andrew Heavens )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:07:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Over 200 Americans have gone or tried to go to Syria to fight: FBI</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/opLPHcTSBiw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - More than 200 Americans have traveled or attempted to travel to Syria to fight for Islamic militants, Federal Bureau of Investigation chief James Comey said on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Over 200 Americans have gone or tried to go to Syria to fight: FBI
WASHINGTON
FBI Director James Comey testifies during a Senate Judiciary Committee hearing on ''Going Dark: Encryption, Technology, and the Balance Between Public Safety and Privacy'' in Washington July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Kevin Lamarque
WASHINGTON More than 200 Americans have traveled or attempted to travel to Syria to fight for Islamic militants, Federal Bureau of Investigation chief James Comey said on Wednesday.
"We continue to identify individuals who seek to join the ranks of foreign fighters ... and also homegrown violent extremists who may aspire to attack the United States from within," Comey told lawmakers on the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence.
The radicalization of Americans by Islamic State is a top concern for the agency, and earlier on Wednesday Comey urged technology companies to allow law enforcement authorities access to encrypted communications to help combat the threat.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:02:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain commits to NATO 2 percent defense spending target for next five years</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/tn7I3gf2Ei8/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Reuters) - The British government said on Wednesday it would commit to NATO's defense spending pledge of two percent of GDP for the next five years, a decision which will help ease U.S. fears about their future ability to rely on a close military ally.</Description>
        <MainBody>LONDON | By Kylie MacLellan
Britain's Chancellor of the Exchequer George Osborne walks out of number 11 Downing Street, before delivering his budget to the Hoiuse of Commons, in London Britain July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Paul Hackett
LONDON The British government said on Wednesday it would commit to NATO's defense spending pledge of two percent of GDP for the next five years, a decision which will help ease U.S. fears about their future ability to rely on a close military ally.
The United States immediately welcomed the pledge and urged all NATO members to do the same.
Britain has reduced defense spending by about 8 percent in real terms since 2010 to help cut a record budget deficit, shrinking the size of the armed forces by around one sixth.
The government has repeatedly come under pressure from lawmakers both in its own Conservatives and the opposition Labour Party to commit to the NATO target but had declined to do so beyond the current financial year, saying it would depend on the outcome of a defense review currently under way.
Several top U.S. military figures, including U.S. Army Chief of Staff General Raymond Odierno, had also expressed concern about declining defense spending by Britain, which still spends more on defense than any other European NATO member.
British finance minister George Osborne told parliament during his budget statement on Wednesday that the government was "not prepared to see the threats we face to both our country and our values go unchallenged."
"So today I commit additional resources to the defense and security of the realm... committing today to meet the NATO pledge to spend 2 percent of our national income on defense, not just this year, but every year of this decade."
Osborne also said the government would guarantee a real increase in the defense budget every year. A Treasury aide said the defense budget would reach 47.7 billion pounds ($73.18 billion) a year by 2020.
U.S. State Department spokesman Mark Toner said the United States appreciated the leadership shown by "one of our greatest friends and our strongest allies" and added:
"We strongly urge all NATO allies to do the same, and it's critically important that NATO be able to respond effectively to existing and future threats, and the only way to do that is for allies to make the necessary investment in their armed forces."
Last month NATO said it expected military spending by the 28 members of its alliance to fall this year in real terms despite increased tensions with Russia and a pledge by leaders last year to halt falls in defense budgets.
It expects five NATO allies, including Britain, to meet the 2 percent spending goal in 2015, up from four in 2014.
Shares of BAE Systems, Britain's biggest defense contractor, traded up 3 percent on the day, making the company one of the top risers on Britain's bluechip index.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:59:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berlusconi found guilty of bribing Italian senator</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/P-hE5hcEaVU/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>NAPLES, Italy (Reuters) - Italy's former prime minister Silvio Berlusconi was found guilty on Wednesday of bribing a senator to switch factions in a move which helped topple the then government in 2008.</Description>
        <MainBody>Berlusconi found guilty of bribing Italian senator
NAPLES, Italy
Former Italian Prime Minister Silvio Berlusconi looks on as he arrives at the Sacred Family Foundation, where he will serve part of his one-year tax fraud sentence by doing community service with the elderly, in Cesano Boscone, a small town on the outskirts of Milan May 9,...
Reuters/Stefano Rellandini
NAPLES, Italy Italy's former prime minister Silvio Berlusconi was found guilty on Wednesday of bribing a senator to switch factions in a move which helped topple the then government in 2008.
The court in southern Italy sentenced Berlusconi to three years in jail and banned him from holding any public office for five years, a judge said in a ruling shown live on television.
The four-times prime minister denied the charges. However, he will not have to serve his sentence because a statute of limitations kicks in later this year before any appeal can be held, preventing the courts from pursuing the case further.
Berlusconi lost his parliamentary immunity when he was ejected from the Senate in 2013 following a conviction for tax fraud. Despite remaining head of his once-triumphant Forza Italia party, he is struggling to revive his political fortunes.
Prosecutors accused Berlusconi, 78, of bribing Sergio De Gregorio, a former senator in the small Italy of Values party, to switch allegiance in 2006 in a move that eventually helped topple the government of Berlusconi's arch rival, Romano Prodi.
De Gregorio admitted receiving 3 million euros ($3.3 million) from Berlusconi and attempting to persuade other senators to change sides. He was separately sentenced to 20 months in jail after a plea bargaining deal.
Berlusconi said he gave De Gregorio the money to help finance a new political movement. "This is a desperately unjust and unjustifiable ruling," his lawyer, Niccolo Ghedini, said on Wednesday.
Berlusconi finished in March a community service sentence tied to the tax fraud case, but fresh judicial woes are lapping at his feet.
A court in the southern city of Bari has ordered him to appear as a witness on Friday in the trial of seven defendants who are accused of procuring prostitutes for the ex-premier's alleged sex parties between 2008 and 2009.
Earlier this year, Berlusconi was acquitted of having sex with an under-aged prostitute at the parties when the judge ruled it could not be proved that he knew the woman was just 17.
Last week, magistrates in Milan completed an investigation into suspicions key witnesses in the case were bribed, saying they believed Berlusconi gave 10 million euros to persuade various women to keep quiet.
Berlusconi has denied the accusations and a court will rule later this year whether to press further charges.
He was ousted as prime minister in 2011 in the midst of the euro zone financial crisis. He has repeatedly said he was forced from office as a result of a plot by European Union officials.
(Writing by Crispian Balmer ; editing by Rosalind Russell)
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:23:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope's 'homecoming' tour moves from Ecuador to Bolivia</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/ATD-yk_KHJw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>QUITO (Reuters) - Pope Francis showed his sense of humor during the last few hours of his trip to Ecuador on Wednesday, straying from a prepared speech to joke with people who came to see him at a shrine near the highland capital Quito.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope's 'homecoming' tour moves from Ecuador to Bolivia
QUITO | By Alexandra Valencia and Girish Gupta
QUITO Pope Francis showed his sense of humor during the last few hours of his trip to Ecuador on Wednesday, straying from a prepared speech to joke with people who came to see him at a shrine near the highland capital Quito.
"I have a prepared script but I don't want to read it," said the 78-year-old pope to laughs from the crowd, before asking them to pray for him so that he would never forget where he came from.
"Do not fall into a spiritual Alzheimer's, do not forget!" Francis added in a totally improvised speech.
The Argentine-born pontiff headed to Bolivia on Wednesday afternoon after drawing about 1.5 million people to Masses in Ecuador on the first leg of a "homecoming" tour, where he urged the world to take better care of the environment and the poor. He also spoke at a home for the elderly in Quito on Wednesday.
"I hope his message allows changes to this country, that it brings peace, ends the problems in Ecuador so we can live with the understanding that we are brothers," said housewife Celia de la Cruz, 59, who came with her family from Ecuador's north to the shrine in Quinche.
Ecuador had been rocked by anti-government protests in the weeks before Francis' visit, but his presence brought a truce.
The pope was flying to high-altitude La Paz, Bolivia, where oxygen tanks are kept at the airport for arriving passengers who may struggle with the thin air. That will focus attention on the pope's health as he had part of one lung removed when he was younger.
Bolivians are speculating over whether or not the pope will follow local customs and chew coca leaves, the primary ingredient in cocaine, to ward off altitude sickness.
Outside La Paz, Francis will stop at the spot where the body of Jesuit Father Luis Espinal Camps was found in 1980. The priest, who was a strong supporter of the rights of miners, was tortured and murdered by paramilitaries.
Francis will then meet with Bolivia's first indigenous president, Evo Morales, a leftist who has won widespread support with folksy charm and prudent spending from a natural gas bonanza to cut poverty.
WARMING RELATIONS
Morales has frequently clashed with the Catholic Church though relations warmed when Francis became pope in 2013.
"We have huge agreements with the pope's economic and social policies, agreements on welfare," said Morales on Tuesday in Santa Cruz, adding that it was the first time he had felt such ideological affinity with a pontiff.
On Wednesday evening, the pope flies to Santa Cruz in eastern Bolivia. There, he will say a Mass on Thursday and the next day visit the notoriously violent Palmasola prison.
In Ecuador, the pope held two Masses, one in the steamy coastal city of Guayaquil and one in Quito. He also met with President Rafael Correa.
"The pope has opened our hearts with his messages, helping us to move forward, especially important in a country where we lack faith, unity and understanding," said Victoria Zambrano, a 38-year-old doctor who traveled across the country to attend Tuesday's Mass in Quito.
Ecuador highlights, possibly more than any other country in the world, the inherent difficulties within the pope's environmental encyclical published last month.
The country earns around one-half of its foreign income from oil, yet is also one of the world's most biodiverse nations, with more endangered species than anywhere else. A large amount of the oil that the socialist government hopes will help feed the poor, though, is locked up under rainforest land.
In his final speech in Quito on Tuesday, the pope focused on this conundrum. "The tapping of natural resources, which are so abundant in Ecuador, must not be concerned with short-term benefits," he said.
"We received this world as an inheritance from past generations, but also as a loan from future generations, to whom we will have to return it!"
During a Mass in Quito, the pope celebrated the region's 200 years of independence from European powers and urged unity.
Yet there are some on the continent who are not impressed with the Catholic Church and accuse it of holding back women's rights and gay rights, and being too close to political leaders.
(Additional reporting by Philip Pullella in Quito and Diego Ore in La Paz.; Editing by Andrew Cawthorne and Grant McCool )
Security walk near placards referring to Pope Francis at the square of Cristo Redentor where he will celebrate a mass during his visit to Bolivia starting on July 8, in Santa Cruz, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Mariana Bazo
1 of 9
right
A woman walks next to a figure of Pope Francis in La Paz, July 7, 2015, ahead of his visit to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay in his Latin-American tour.
Reuters/David Mercado
2 of 9
right
Art students restore religious figures at the 'Nuestra Senora de La Paz' Cathedral in La Paz, July 7, 2015, ahead of Pope Francis' visit to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay in his Latin-American tour.
Reuters/David Mercado
3 of 9
right
Placards referring to Pope Francis are seen at the square of Cristo Redentor where he will celebrate a mass during his visit to Bolivia starting on July 8, in Santa Cruz, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Mariana Bazo
4 of 9
right
A man is seen next to a damaged mural of Pope Francis in El Alto, on the outskirts of La Paz, July 7, 2015, ahead of Pope Francis' visit to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay in his Latin-American  tour.
Reuters/Carlos Sanchez Navas
5 of 9
right
Pope Francis arrives to celebrate mass at the Bicentenario Park in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Bianchi
6 of 9
right
Pope Francis greets the faithful after a meeting with members of the civil society at the San Francisco Church in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Jose Miguel Gomez
7 of 9
right
Pope Francis speaks as he meets members of the civil society at the San Francisco Church in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Guillermo Granja
8 of 9
right
Pope Francis is greeted by a girl as he meets members of the civil society at the San Francisco Church in Quito, Ecuador, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Guillermo Granja
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:21:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. spy agency tapped German chancellery for decades: WikiLeaks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/DP9adKKEt8c/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BERLIN (Reuters) - The U.S. National Security Agency tapped phone calls involving German Chancellor Angela Merkel and her closest advisers for years and spied on the staff of her predecessors, WikiLeaks said on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. spy agency tapped German chancellery for decades: WikiLeaks
BERLIN
Visitors walk in front of the Chancellory during the second day of an open door weekend of several ministries in Berlin.
Reuters/Fabrizio Bensch
BERLIN The U.S. National Security Agency tapped phone calls involving German Chancellor Angela Merkel and her closest advisers for years and spied on the staff of her predecessors, WikiLeaks said on Wednesday.
A report released by the group suggested NSA spying on Merkel and her staff had gone on far longer and more widely than previously realized. WikiLeaks said the NSA targeted for long-term surveillance 125 phone numbers of top German officials.
The release risks renewing tensions between Germany and the United States a month after they sought to put a row over spying behind them, with U.S. President Barack Obama declaring in Bavaria that the two nations were "inseparable allies".
WikiLeaks published what it said were three NSA intercepts of Merkel's conversations, and data it said listed telephone numbers for the chancellor, her aides, her office and even her fax machine.
"The names associated with some of the targets indicate that spying on the Chancellery predates Angela Merkel as it includes staff of former Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder (in office 1998-2002), and his predecessor Helmut Kohl," WikiLeaks added in a statement.
No comment was immediately available from the German government.
The intercepts released on Wednesday detailed communications from Merkel in 2009 on the international financial crisis, with the crown prince of the United Arab Emirates in 2009 on Iran, and with advisers in 2011 on the euro zone crisis.
The targeted phone numbers included those for the cellphones of senior officials at the chancellery and included that of Ronald Pofalla, Merkel's former chief of staff, WikiLeaks said.
Spying is a sensitive issue in Germany because of the abuses of the Nazi and Communist eras. Revelations by former NSA contractor Edward Snowden about wide-ranging U.S. espionage in Germany caused outrage when they surfaced.
The spying row has also been stirred by allegations that Merkel's staff gave the German BND foreign intelligence agency a green light to help the NSA spy on European firms and officials.
The latest WikiLeaks release comes just over a week after it published a report showing the NSA wiretapped the communications of two successive French finance ministers and collected information on French export contracts, trade and budget talks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:48:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inside Palmasola prison, Pope Francis will find inmates rule</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/_vOyjR8Wr74/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia (Reuters) - Guards only secure the perimeter of Palmasola, Bolivia's most notorious prison. Inside each unit, murderers, drug traffickers and rapists make the rules and run a lucrative criminal economy.</Description>
        <MainBody>SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia | By Sarah Marsh
Pope Francis waves to the faithful from a popemobile in El Quinche, Ecuador, July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Guillermo Granja
1 of 2
right
Relatives of inmates wait for news during violent clashes between inmates, at the entrance of Palmasola Penitentiary Complex on the outskirts of Santa Cruz August 23, 2013.
Reuters/Stringer
2 of 2
right
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia Guards only secure the perimeter of Palmasola, Bolivia's most notorious prison. Inside each unit, murderers, drug traffickers and rapists make the rules and run a lucrative criminal economy.
Money can buy inmates everything: a cell, a shower, drugs, protection, prostitutes and prime "real estate" as large as two-story houses, from which to run a business or simply live relatively well.
On Friday, Pope Francis will enter the sprawling maximum-security complex in Bolivia's largest city, Santa Cruz, continuing his practice of visiting prisons when he was Archbishop of Buenos Aires.
"We make sure things are quiet around here," said Leonardo Medina, facing murder charges, one cheek bulging with coca leaves. Sporting a red jacket emblazoned with the word "discipline, Medina, 48, belongs to a team of security officers selected by inmates.
Palmasola is infamous for violence between rival factions. In one of the worst incidents in 2013, at least 30 inmates were killed and dozens wounded in a turf war that spiraled out of control in the prison's PC3 section, which houses the most violent.
Medina, housed in the quieter PC4 section that Pope Francis will visit, said he was under instructions not to reveal the jail's dark underbelly to visitors.
"If we do something wrong you can go, but for us it's ugly. We have to stay behind and pay the price," he said, speaking in a fluent English learned while trafficking cocaine in the United States.
PC4 is more small town than prison wing. Laundry hangs from lines slung between ramshackle buildings, kiosks sell juices and tables from a cafeteria spill out into a square with a statue of Jesus Christ. The unit has alleys that lead from the muddy football field in the center, and inmates elect their leader, like a mayor.
Young children live inside the jail with their incarcerated parents alongside the most dangerous prisoners who can avoid the worst-offender unit with a bribe to officials, said Ramiro Llanos, a former head of Bolivia's prison services.
And like Medina, many of Palmasola's inmates have not been convicted of any crime. Nationwide, nearly 90 percent of Bolivia's 12,000 prisoners are awaiting trial, trapped by the country's gridlocked justice system.
Lined up outside the facility, Irene Pinto, 36 said her elderly mother had been locked up for failing to pay her debts. She said her mother has diabetes and with not enough medicine in the prison, she brought it in from outside.
"She sleeps in a room with four people, drug traffickers and murderers. So she worries and can't sleep easily," Pinto said.
The national prison director and the government declined to comment for this story.
ENTRENCHED CORRUPTION
When Medina is not on security detail he makes leather wallets and hammocks that can fetch up to 450 Bolivianos ($66). Without money, it is a punishing existence inside Palmasola.
Roberth Aquino, 38, said a friend locked up on charges of land theft had paid about 6,850 Bolivianos for a bed, 1,300 Bolivianos for access to outdoor areas and 25 Bolivianos to use the showers.
Those without cash sleep on the floor. Those with wads of pesos swiftly climb a hierarchy in the prisoner ranks. Prisoners with money get more respect and protection.
"The government just locks you up inside and leaves you here," said Enea Cardina, a 61-year-old Italian citizen accused of murder.
The Catholic Church runs primary and secondary education schools, while a sign outside the prison chapel offers Alcoholics Anonymous meetings. It even offers prisoners university-level law classes.
"Human rights are widely violated in prisons," said Zaida Romero, who provides legal counseling inside Palmasola on behalf of the church. "A large percentage are here without trial."
Corruption is so entrenched in Bolivia's prison system that prisoners and families complain they have to bribe officials just to get a trial hearing, in addition to lawyers fees.
In the visitors line, Pinto said she had already put down 800 Bolivianos for her mother's two hearings and knew of another inmate still in prison on drugs charges because she lacked the money for a trial.
"She went in pregnant and now she has an 8-year-old child with her," Pinto said.
Ahead of the pope's arrival, prisoners were laying a stone pathway along a muddy throughway, clearing huge piles of litter and building walls.
Even among Bolivia's most hardened criminals, inmates say the pope will be safe.
"His visit is a benediction for us," said Ambi Vaca, 24, who is serving a 15-year sentence. "So we will look after him."
($1 = 6.85 Bolivianos)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:36:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant arrivals in Europe jump by two-thirds in early 2015, EU seeks deal</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/m1uYRlLoE-c/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - The number of migrants seeking protection in the European Union soared by 68 percent in the first five months of 2015 compared with the year-earlier period, the EU said on Wednesday at a time of haggling between member states over how to share the burden.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant arrivals in Europe jump by two-thirds in early 2015, EU seeks deal
BRUSSELS | By Francesco Guarascio
Migrants check the trailer of a truck during an attempt to make a clandestine crossing to England through the Channel tunnel as lorries wait on a road which leads to the Channel Tunnel terminal in Coquelles near Calais, northern France, July 1, 2015.
Reuters/Vincent Kessler
BRUSSELS The number of migrants seeking protection in the European Union soared by 68 percent in the first five months of 2015 compared with the year-earlier period, the EU said on Wednesday at a time of haggling between member states over how to share the burden.
EU ministers responsible for migrant issues will meet on Thursday to weigh details of a plan aimed at deterring migrants from making dangerous sea crossings to Europe while helping Mediterranean EU countries -- especially Italy and Greece -- bearing the brunt of the influx and struggling to cope.
Member states have rejected a mandatory scheme to share migrants proposed by the European Commission, the EU executive, and are negotiating on voluntary commitments. "The work is still ongoing," a diplomat told Reuters on Wednesday.
The European Asylum Support Office (EASO) gave no figure for the number of arriving migrants in the January-May 2015 period.
But the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees said earlier that more than 135,000 migrants had arrived in Europe by sea in the first half of 2015, mostly landing in Greece and Italy.
EASO said that the full-year 2014 figure was already a record with more than 660,000 migrants seeking asylum in the EU's 28 countries plus Switzerland and Norway.
Many asylum seekers pitch up on the southern shores of Europe after risking their lives in overloaded boats dispatched by human traffickers dispatched across the Mediterranean.
Migrants come mainly from African and Middle Eastern countries plagued by conflict, human rights abuses and poverty.
In June, EU leaders endorsed ways to counter the migration crisis in the Mediterranean by sharing 60,000 refugees and asylum seekers over the next two years, but failed to decide precise national commitments to take people in.
According to the plan to be considered at the meeting in Luxembourg on Thursday, 20,000 refugees would be resettled in Europe directly from their countries of origin or transit, such as Syrians escaping war or displaced in Lebanon or Jordan.
Another 40,000 asylum seekers now in Italy and Greece would be transferred to other EU countries.
Some EU countries have made informal pledges to host migrants but an agreement on how to share out 60,000 migrants remains elusive. Ministers are aiming for a deal by the end of July to allow the plan to run from September.
In preparatory meetings, diplomats agreed to include Iraqis among the nationalities that would benefit from the relocation plan, diplomats said. The criteria initially set concerned only Syrians and Eritreans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:29:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia blocks U.N. condemnation of Srebrenica as a genocide</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/V-cnkSy4Bag/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - Russia vetoed a United Nations Security Council resolution on Wednesday that would have condemned the Srebrenica massacre as a genocide to mark the 20th anniversary of the killing of 8,000 Muslim men and boys.</Description>
        <MainBody>UNITED NATIONS | By Michelle Nichols
UNITED NATIONS Russia vetoed a United Nations Security Council resolution on Wednesday that would have condemned the Srebrenica massacre as a genocide to mark the 20th anniversary of the killing of 8,000 Muslim men and boys.
China, Nigeria, Angola and Venezuela abstained and the remaining 10 council members voted in favor. The vote was delayed a day as Britain and the United States tried to persuade Russia not to veto the text, which would have also condemned denial of the 1995 massacre as a genocide.
Russian U.N. Ambassador Vitaly Churkin had appealed for the council not to vote on the resolution, which he described as "not constructive, confrontational and politically motivated."
"The blame for the past is placed basically on one people," Churkin said, but he added: "Our vote against ... will not however mean that we are deaf to the sufferings of the victims of Srebrenica and other areas of Bosnia and Herzegovina."
Russia had proposed the council instead condemn "the most serious crimes of concern to the international community."
The U.N. war crimes tribunal for the former Yugoslavia has ruled the massacre, the worst mass killing on European soil since World War Two, was genocide.
Britain said it was outraged by the Russian veto. "Genocide occurred at Srebrenica. This is a legal fact, not a political judgment. On this there is no compromise," Deputy U.N. Ambassador Peter Wilson told the council after the vote.
On July 11, 1995, toward the end of Bosnia's 1992-95 war, Bosnian Serb forces swept into the eastern Srebrenica enclave, a U.N.-designated "safe haven." They executed 8,000 Muslim men and boys in the days that followed, dumping their bodies into pits.
"Russia's veto is heartbreaking for those families and it is a further stain on this council's record," said U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations, Samantha Power, who was a 24-year-old journalist in Bosnia when the massacre took place.
Munira Subasic, president of the Mothers of Srebrenica association, who lost husband and son in the massacre, said Russia should be ashamed by its veto. "After 20 years, Russia showed that it backed the crime instead of justice," she said.
Serbia acknowledges that a "grave crime" took place and adopted a declaration condemning the massacre in 2010 as it sought closer ties with the West, but stopped short of describing it as genocide.
The draft resolution angered Bosnian Serbs and Serbia, who branded it as "anti-Serb" and sent a letter of protest to the United Nations. Serbia warned on Tuesday that the resolution would only widen ethnic divides in neighboring Bosnia.
Serbia's President Tomislav Nikolic said in a statement on Wednesday that Russia had "prevented an attempt of smearing the entire Serbian nation as genocidal" and proven itself as a true and honest friend.
(Additional reporting by Daria Sito-Sucic in Sarajevo and Aleksandar Vasovic in Belgrade; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama , Andrew Hay and David Gregorio )
A poster of Russian President Vladimir Putin with the words Republika Srpska (Serb Republic) printed on it is seen inside the main residence of an abandoned agricultural cooperative in Kravica, Bosnia and Herzegovina July 1, 2015.
Reuters/Dado Ruvic
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:19:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraq celebrates return of antiquities, appeals for world help</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/p067M2APAU8/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BAGHDAD (Reuters) - Iraq celebrated on Wednesday the return of hundreds of historical artefacts, from an ancient Assyrian statue to a 20th century presidential tea set, which were looted, lost or loaned abroad over recent decades.</Description>
        <MainBody>Recovered artefacts are seen at the National Museum of Iraq in Baghdad, Iraq July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Khalid al-Mousily
1 of 5
right
Recovered artefacts are seen at the National Museum of Iraq in Baghdad, Iraq July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Khalid al-Mousily
2 of 5
right
A recovered artifact is displayed at the National Museum of Iraq in Baghdad, Iraq July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Khalid al-Mousily
3 of 5
right
Iraqi Foreign Minister Ibrahim al-Jaafari speaks during a news conference at the National Museum of Iraq in Baghdad, Iraq July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Khalid al-Mousily
4 of 5
right
Iraq's Tourism and Antiquities Minister Adel Shirshab speaks during an interview with Reuters at the Iraqi National Museum in Baghdad, Iraq July 8, 2015.
Reuters/Khalid al-Mousily
5 of 5
right
BAGHDAD Iraq celebrated on Wednesday the return of hundreds of historical artefacts, from an ancient Assyrian statue to a 20th century presidential tea set, which were looted, lost or loaned abroad over recent decades.
The recovery of the 800 items from museums, universities and auction houses in the United States, Italy and Jordan marks a small victory for Iraqi authorities struggling to protect their heritage from theft and destruction by Islamic State fighters.
The hardline Islamist militants have taken over some of the world's richest archaeological sites in northern Iraq, home to Assyrian cities dating back 2,700 years and the Graeco-Roman era desert complex of Hatra.
Videos released by Islamic State show several sites bulldozed, blown up or battered with sledgehammers. Officials say priceless antiquities have also been stolen to help fund the militants' self-declared caliphate in Iraq and Syria.
Wednesday's collection of returned items, put on show at Baghdad's national museum, was modest compared to the suspected scale of the ongoing theft and destruction.
It included dozens of metal spearheads which officials said dated back to Iraq's Sumerian era between 4,000 and 2,000 B.C., tiny vases, pottery seals and fragments with cuneiform writing.
Some had been identified when they came up for sale at auction houses. Others were recovered from long-term loans to universities abroad, officials said.
The collection included nearly 200 items that went missing from Iraq's presidential palaces in the turmoil which followed the U.S.-led invasion to overthrow Saddam Hussein, they said.
Alongside the white china tea set - each item marked with an eagle to represent the Iraqi republic - was a large ceremonial sword, silver cutlery and two rifles.
Government ministers attending a ceremony to mark their return called for greater international help to protect Iraq's antiquities, saying the scale of the threat was unprecedented.
Islamic State, which rejects all but its own narrow interpretation of early Sunni Islam as heresy, has destroyed ancient temples, shrines, churches, manuscripts, statues and carvings in territory it has seized. Officials say it has also looted widely, selling artefacts to fund its rule.
"We are not dealing with smugglers but a group that calls itself a state, carries weapons and trades in antiquities," Tourism and Antiquities Minister Adel Shirshab said. "The world must pay attention to the new danger".
More than three months after Islamic State fighters released video footage of them smashing statues and carvings at Mosul museum and the ancient sites of Hatra, Nimrud and Nineveh, Shirshab told Reuters it was hard to assess the damage.
"The region is under terrorist control. We don't have precise, detailed information...The situation is fluid and unclear.
Shirshab said that footage showing destruction at the sites was deliberately put out to obscure Islamic State fighters' real aim. "Many of these antiquities were stolen to fund this terrorist group," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
