<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:09:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eurozone receives Greek economic reform plan</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713574-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>The eurozone has received new bailout reform plans from Greece, a spokesman for Eurogroup chief Jeroen Dijsselbloem has said, less than two hours ahead of a midnight deadline.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Leaders of the 19-country single currency area gave Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras the deadline at an emergency summit on Tuesday, warning that failure to comply risked Greece's place in the euro.
Greeks overwhelmingly voted in a referendum on Sunday to reject previous austerity demands from international creditors in exchange for a new aid programme to replace the one that expired on 30 June.
Greece needs money to reopen its banks which have been closed for nearly two weeks, and eurozone leaders have warned that the European Central Bank will cut emergency funding if it does not reach a new deal.
The new reform proposals will now be scrutinised by officials from Greece's EU-IMF creditors, before going before eurozone finance ministers on Saturday and a full summit of all 28 European Union leaders on Sunday.
"The (creditor) institutions will examine them to give their view to the Eurogroup," a European source told AFP on condition of anonymity.
"They also need these proposals to determine the size of the bailout programme -- that will also depend upon broader economic scenarios," the source said.
Greece's application letter on Wednesday to the eurozone's bailout fund, the European Stability Mechanism, called for a three-year programme but did not say how much money was needed.
As Greece submits new debt proposals to the Eurozone, a reminder of the key numbers in the crisis so far https://t.co/IN5kaabdOo
 RT News (@rtenews) July 9, 2015
Source: AFP/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:21:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cork search for missing man suspended for night</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713591-cork-search/</Link>
        <Description>The search for the body of Barry Davis Ryan, who drowned off Baltimore last week, has finished for the night and will resume at first light tomorrow.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
However, it is expected that no diving will take place beyond lunch time as the weather is expected to deteriorate significantly.
Around 200 dives were planned at the dive site off Baltimore, with teams of eight checking the seabed in set lines.
Mr Davis Ryanwas washed into the sea at the mouth of Baltimore Harbour in a tragedy that claimed the lives of his father,Barry Ryan, 51, and his 20-year-old girlfriend Niamh O'Connoron 30 June.
They were all part of a group of people who had been walking close to the Beacon when one of them fell into the sea and two others attempted a rescuebefore all three got into difficulty.
The bodies of Barry Ryan senior and Niamh O'Connorwere recovered andtheir funerals were held last weekend.
Earlier this week Barry's mother, Anne Davis, appealed to divers to help in the search for her son's body
More than 150 volunteers have joined the search.
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, John Kearney from West Cork Underwater Search and Rescue,said 82 volunteerdivers from around the country are now assisting in the search while 74 other volunteers are assisting with duties on the pier.
Mr Kearney described the response from the community as tremendous and said they have also been supported by theIrish Underwater Council and the Army.
He said they have been searching every day but have only been able to dive five out of the nine days since last Tuesday due to poor weather conditions.
Barry Ryan senior, a son of Penneys founder Arthur Ryan,was asenior executive with the retail clothing company.
Ms O'Connor from Glanmireworked at a Penneys store in Cork city.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:50:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK crime agency to lead NI property deal inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713587-nama-pac/</Link>
        <Description>The UK's top law enforcement body is to lead the investigation into corruption allegations at the heart of the largest ever property deal in Northern Ireland.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
They agreed the Project Eagle portfolio sale in April 2014 wasthe biggest deal it has done to clear property, land and developer loans from bailed-out Irish banks.
NAMA chairman Frank Daly told the PAC the sale process for Project Eaglewas robust, competitive and secured the best outcome for the Irish taxpayer.
Mr Daly said that if a payment did find its way to an account in the Isle of Man, as has been alleged, then wherever such a payment came from, it did not come from NAMA.
He said the agency had no knowledge of the alleged payment until in came into the public domain.
He said he was confident that the NAMA board acted quickly and decisively and took every measure available to it to protect the integrity of the sales process as soon as the proposed fee arrangement came to light.
In his opening statement to the committee, Mr Daly said when the agency became aware of a concern surrounding the participation of one of the bidders it immediately took steps to ensure they withdrew from the process.
He also said that no pressure from any source, "political or otherwise", influenced NAMA in regard to the decision to sell the loans of Northern Irelanddebtors or the decision to accept the bid from US investment companyCerberus Capital Management.
Mr Daly said there was no PSNI investigation into the sale of the assets and any investigation would relate to the purchaser.
Last night PSNIAssistant Chief Constable Will Kerrsaid:"We believe that there is sufficient concern in relation to potential criminal activity, surrounding this property deal, to instigate an investigation.
"PSNI are now engaging with a number of other national and international law enforcement partners to consider how best to take forward this investigation" he said.
Mr Daly also said media reports that NAMA sold assets worth 5bn was a very serious error and the assets were sold for exactly what they were worth.
NAMA Chief Executive Brendan McDonagh told the committee that the net cash loss to NAMA on the NI debtor portfolio was about 280m and he believed that the commercial decision taken by the NAMA Board to dispose of the NI loan portfolio was the right one.
Hesaid the key consideration for NAMA in any loan sale process is that all interested parties are given the opportunity to bid and all bidders are treated equally and fairly.
Sinn Fin'sMary Lou McDonald told Mr Daly that NAMA had a duty of care in ensure nothing improper occurs in their sales.
She said while she accepted that NAMA could not control third-parties, she did not accept the "end justifies the means"approach.
Mr Daly told Ms McDonald he would love to see the Isle of Man allegations investigated and he said he welcomed the PSNI's investigation.
He insisted they had explained how they had fire-proofed the sale but MsMcDonald said the sale should have been aborted and alarm bells should have been ringing "like Big Ben".
Mr Daly said the real test is if we got value for money and "I absolutely believe we did".
Cross-boarder effort needed to restore integrity -John McGuinness
Chairperson of the Public Accounts Committee,Fianna Fil TD John McGuinness, hassaid "there is a need for some cross-border effort to bring all of the agencies and information together to restore the integrity of this bidding system."
Speaking on RT's Six One MrMcGuinnesssaid he believes NAMA "did not get the best value for money for the taxpayer", in relation to the sale of a property portfolio in Northern Ireland, called 'Project Eagle'.
Hesaid "the whole process was compromised" by the time NAMA told the bidder PIMCO that it could not permit them to remain in the bidding process.
Mr McGuinness said "the whole process should have been abandoned and they should have started from fresh because they are questions as to whether or not the one single bundle of properties, of roughly 850 properties should have been put out their in the first place."
He saidthat "smaller bundles" would had "a greater return for the tax payer."
Fleming claims there was 'political imperative' on NAMA
Fianna Fil's spokesperson on Public Expenditure and Reform has said while there may not have been political involvement in the sale of NAMA's Northern Irish property portfolio, there was a political imperative on NAMA to complete the sale.
Speaking on RT's News at One, Sen Fleming said Minister for Finance Michael Noonan wanted the sale completed quickly.
Mr Fleming said:"The only reason they were taking the deal at that time was because they knew Minister Noonanwanted a quick sale."
He added that "NAMA,through their management of that Northern Ireland portfolio, lost 783m of Irish taxpayers money. They had never sold a bunch of loans to that value before. This was three times bigger a job lot sale than NAMA had ever done before and that's because the Minister wanted them to get on and wind up NAMA as urgently as possible to get the cash flow into the Government."
Mr Fleming said there had been political influence on NAMA in relation to the sale of Project Eagle both north and south of the border.
He also said when issues arouse relating to Pimco's bid for the portfolio, NAMAhad acted decisively to a point only, and when they found out the sales process was contaminated they should have canceled it.
Failed bidders' fee to be split, committee told
The PAC alsoheard that the failed bidders for theNorthern Ireland'sNAMA portfolio, Pimco, was to pay a fee of 15mwhich was to be split three ways between US law firm Brown Rudnick, its Northern Ireland representativesand Frank Cushnahan, a former member ofNAMA's Northern Ireland Advisory Committee.
Mr Daly said this information had come to him after Pimco's withdrawal as a bidder. He said Mr Cushnahan resigned as a member of the advisory committee in November 2013.Hefirst heard this information in March 2014 when Mr Cushnahan was three to five months gone, Mr Daly added.
The committee heard that Pimcohad already been asked to withdraw itsbid by NAMA.
Mr Daly gave the information to Independent TD Shane Ross who asked why the sales process was not aborted once it was discovered to be tainted.
Mr Daly earlier told the PAC that they were given an undertaking, an unequivocalstatement, that no fees were paid to any party with a connection to NAMA.
Itwas a 'very difficult portfolio' and they did not want to go through a sales process and then abort it, the committeewas told.
Earlier, a NAMAspokesperson moved to clarify issues around the sale of the NIproperty portfolio.
NAMA's property loans in Northern Ireland were sold to a US company for 1.6bn.
While these loans were originally valued at 5bn, a NAMA spokesperson said this morning that the agency would have paid the banks considerably less than 5bn for them.
Last week in the Dil, Independent Deputy Mick Wallace alleged that 7mwas found in an Isle of Man account, and said the "money was reportedly earmarked for a Northern Ireland politician".
The NAMA spokesperson also reiterated that NAMA received the full proceeds from the sale of these loans, and that the origins of that 7m are not NAMA.
Stormont's finance committee is also examining Mr Wallace's allegations about the Project Eagledeal.
Wallace will speak to PSNI 'if asked'
Mr Wallace said that if askedhe will speak to the PSNI in connection with its investigation.
Speaking on RT's Today with Sean O'Rourke, Mr Wallace said it was good that the PSNI had initiated a criminal investigation into the issue.
He also said if an independent inquiry is set up in the Republic he will also speak to it.
He reiterated that it did not believe the PAC or the Comptroller and Auditor General had the wherewithal to investigate the issue.
Asked if he was going to gardawith information he had relating to the sale, Mr Wallace said garda were already investigating 13 cases relating to NAMA and were "very familiar" with a lot of the information he had seen and he was sure they were working on it.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:20:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>John Bruton says he will forgo pension rise</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713747-pensions/</Link>
        <Description>Former Taoiseach John Bruton has said he will comply with the Taoiseach's request to voluntarily decline the proposed ministerial pension increase.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Speaking in Italy where he is on a two-day visit, Mr Kenny said he understood their frustration and would say to the small number of former politicians involved that as the country is still in a fragile economic situation they should refuse to accept the increase.
Mr Kenny said that constitutionally pensions of retired people were treated differently to serving politicians, which could be reduced or capped.
Eamon Ryan, former minister for communications, energy and natural resources, has said he would consider forgoing the increase in his pension due in January under the deal.
Mr Ryan said he has yet to look at the details of the pension increase.
Former minister Mary O'Rourke said that the Taoiseach's call in relation to former minister's pensions was "worthy of consideration".
Ms O'Rourke who served as minister for education, minister for health and minister for public enterprise, said that she had not been contacted about an impending increase, and neither had she been contacted when her pension was cut in recent years.
She also said it would not be appropriate to call it an increase as she understood what was being proposed was a partial restoration of the pension.
Former minister Michael Woods said that he already gave back half of his pension, before the pension cuts were introduced, every year from 2002 until 2011.
Mr Woods was minister for health, minster for social welfare, minister for agriculture, and minister for marine.
Fianna Fil has said the Government position on the issue has been fraudulent from day one.
In a statement this evening, the party said: "If the Government wants to ensure that those who hold generous state pensions do not benefit from increases they are introducing, the answer is very simple, they should either not introduce them in the first place or impose additional taxation.
"Enda Kenny issuggesting that the onus is on individual retired public servants to reject changes that his Government is introducing is extremely disingenuous and demeans the Office of Taoiseach."
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:59:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman killed in two-car crash in Galway</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713764-galway-fatal/</Link>
        <Description>A woman in her fifties has died after a two-car crash in Co Galway.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The woman was pronounced dead at the scene.
The three others have been taken to University Hospital Galway and their injuries are described as non-life threatening.
The road is closed and local diversions are in place.
Garda are appealing for witnesses to the collision to contact them at Oranmore Garda Station on 091-388030, The Garda Confidential line on 1800-666111 or any garda station.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:59:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>150 jobs announced by two companies</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713729-jobs-announcement/</Link>
        <Description>150 jobs have been announced by a software company based in Dublin and a technology firm.</Description>
        <MainBody>The roles are in the fields of Technical Support, Professional Services, Technical Account Management, Integrations Support, Technical Training, DevOps, Sales, Marketing, Finance and HR.
The jobs are supportedby the Department of jobs through the IDA.
Meanwhile more than 30 new jobs have been announced with technology firm PlanNet 21 Communications.
The roles are mainly in the engineering and professional services area.
It also announced a 20minvestment to the Irish economy today.
The company says the jobs announced today will bring the number employed here to over 100 by the end of 2015.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:23:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Court rejects claim Ireland breached directive</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713756-doctor-ecj/</Link>
        <Description>The European Court of Justice has rejected a claim that the Government breached European law by forcing non-consultant hospital doctors to work excessive hours.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 09 July 2015 18.23
The Working Time Directive sets down rules for working hours and rest periods
The European Court of Justice has rejected a claim that the Government breached European law by forcing non-consultant hospital doctors to work excessive hours.
The court found that the European Commission had not succeeded in establishing that Ireland had failed to fulfil its obligations under the Working Time Directive NCHDs.
The Working Time Directive sets down rules for working hours and rest periods, the key provision being that the working week must not exceed 48 hours.
However, individual states are allowed to set down certain parameters for how those rules are applied.
The Irish Medical Organisation had argued that despite the intention to move towards compliance, the HSE's work practices for the doctors breached the directive, as many still had to work excessive hours.
In 2013 it set up a "24NoMore" campaign to oppose the long working hours, and even went on strike for a day.
Despite reaching an agreement with the HSE to move towards compliance, the IMO says almost 200 doctors are still working in excess of 24 hours, 30% are still working beyond the 48 hour weekly limit, and a third of hospitals continue to impose excessive working hours.
The European Commission had taken Ireland to the ECJ on the basis that the Government was in breach of the directive, arguing that training hours should not be considered working time.
However, the European Court of Justice dismissed the Commission's case.
The court said the Commission had not proven that doctors were able to treat patients during their training, nor that they were required to be physically present at a place determined by the employer and at the employers disposal to provide appropriate services as the need arose.
In addition, the court found that the Standard Contract of Employment between the HSE and the doctors did not prescribe a training requirement, and did not impose specific employment obligations in relation to training.
The judgment also dismissed the Commission's concerns about the extension of the reference period for the calculation of doctors' working hours.
It noted that Ireland had put forward the need to roster non-consultant hospital doctors sufficiently and flexibly as an objective reason for the arrangements.
The Irish Medical Organisation said it was disappointed with the ECJ decision, but would continue to fight for implementation of an agreement on working hours.
In a statement, it said the judgment did not affect the collective agreement reached between the IMO and the HSE on the implementation of legal and safe working hours for NCHDs.
IMO Vice President Dr John Duddy said this was not just an issue for doctors, as long working hours have an adverse effect on patient safety, and were contributing to Irish doctors leaving to work abroad.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:49:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Govt moves to clarify sale of Moore St 1916 site</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713777-moore-st-dail/</Link>
        <Description>The Government has moved to ease concerns among Opposition TDs over the sale of the historic Moore St site.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 09 July 2015 20.49
Opposition TDs had expressed concerns over the site being part of the NAMA portfolio
The Government has moved to ease concerns among Opposition TDs over the sale of the historic Moore St site.
Responding to questions from Sinn Fins Sandra McLellan and Independent TD Maureen OSullivan, Minister of State Aodhn  Rordin said that while the site was being sold, the buyer is the State.
The Minister of State at the Department of Arts, Heritage and the Gaeltacht said it was not being sold to "some banker or vernture capitalist".
Both TDs had expressed concerns over the site being part of the NAMA portfolio.
However, Mr  Riordin said the Government would "not in any way be affected, delayed or otherwise impinged upon by any disposal of NAMA loan books", and he said the national monument site was being removed from the NAMA portfolio sale.
Regarding ownership to the State, the Minister said all loans would be discharged over the monument site and all licenses will be put in place to carry out the national monument works.
The State, he said, would safeguard the site and restore it back to how it was in 1916 and it will develop the 1916 commemorative centre on the site as a solid and fitting tribute to the leaders who held their final war council meeting there.
Mr  Rordin said the decision by the Government was made in order to bring the national monument to public ownership, to secure it's long term future and to complete the development of the proposed 1916 commemorative centre as quickly as possible.
"I want to make it as clear as I possibly can to dispell the confusion that always has been the hallmark of certain parties that seem to be more anxious to see nothing happen than the monument open to the public; and at a risk of repeating myself, the acquisition of number 14-17 Moore street is in progress and will completed as soon as possible", he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:57:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Medical evidence delayed in nanny murder trial</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713748-medical-review-due-in-irish-nanny-murder-trial/</Link>
        <Description>A judge in Massachusetts has ordered the State's Medical Examiner to appear before her court to explain about the delayed review of the medical evidence in the case of an Irish woman accused of murdering a baby in her care in January 2013.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The Massachusetts medical examiner had agreed to undertake a review of the medical evidence following conflicting expert opinion about the nature of the baby girl's injuries.
The original medical examination concluded that the baby had died from traumatic head injuries, which was ruled a homicide, however other evidence showed spinal injuries that occured weeks earlier when the baby was not in the care of the Irish nanny.
The medical review was due to be completed at the beginning of June and circulated to Ms Brady McCarthy's lawyers and prosecutors for the Commonwealth of Massachusetts.
At a court hearing in June, the Medical Examiner indicated that it would need another 30 days to complete the review.
Aisling Brady McCarthy arrived to court today with her husband and other family members and friends expecting to hear an update on the status of a special review of the medical evidence.
The County Cavan woman has been under house arrest since she was released on bail in May, after more than two years spent in jail.
Ms Brady McCarthy must now wait even longer to learn the outcome of a review of the medical evidence.
Judge Maureen Hogan said it was not acceptable for the court, the defendent, and the Commonwealth of Massachusetts to have to "wait indefinitely" for the review of the medical evidence.
Lawyers for the prosecution had told the court that they had not had any information from or communication with the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner in relation to the review.
However David Meier, one of the lawyers representing Ms Brady McCarthy said that he had spoken with the Medical Examiner's attorney, who had said that the reivew was "ongoing" and that it would be at least the end of July before it was completed.
Mr Meier, said the attorney Jacqui Faherty had said that it was then the Medical Examiner's intention to consult with other medical examiners about the review.
Judge Hogan queried whether the Medical Examiner's intention was to consult others before "rendering any conclusion" to the court, to which Mr Meier replied that he didn't know but that they had said they would provide it "as soon as possible".
Judge Maureen Hogan then said that court could not "wait indefinitely" on the outcome of this review, especially given that a trial date has been set for October of this year.
The trial has already been significantly delayed from its original date of April 2014.
Judge Hogan ordered that a representative of the Medical Examiner, its lawyer Jacqui Faherty or another representative, appear in her court within the next two weeks to give the court an exact date of how long the review was actually going to take. This she said would allow the court and the defendent to know they could set a final date to expect a conclusion from the review.
The Office of the Medical Examiner had said in May that it would report back within 30 days. It has now been 60 days and the court has not yet been given a conclusion date.
Judge Hogan asked the prosecuting lawyers for the Commonwealth of Massachusetts to contact the Medical Examiner's office and then to let her know a suitable date within the next fortnight when they could all be present in court.
She said she would also schedule dates for further hearings on motions of discovery of other evidence at that time.
Speaking after the brief hearing, Melinda Thompson, a lawyer for Ms Brady McCarthy, said that she was "hopeful" that the delay in the Medical Examiner's review would mean good news for her client.
She said she was "impressed" that the review had been undertaken at all, and that the longer it took the more "hopeful" she was.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:47:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News in Brief</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713579-news-in-brief/</Link>
        <Description>A round-up of other Irish and international news</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 09 July 2015 22.47
Pope Francis was presented with an image of Christ crucified superimposed on the Marxist symbol
Pope Francis is presented with religious-Marxist symbol in Bolivia
On the fifth day of his three-nation tour of South America, Pope Francis has urged everyone to share with the poor.
Celebrating mass for hundreds of thousands in Bolivia's eastern city, Santa Cruz, the 78-year-old Pontiff warned that those with means could not simply wish the poor away.
Earlier, in the capital, La Paz, the Bolivian President, Evo Morales, presented Francis with a wooden carving of the hammer and sickle with an image of Christ crucified superimposed on the Marxist symbol.
Judge Brian Cregan appointed as new Chair of IBRC investigation
The Government hasappointed Judge Brian Cregan, currently a Judge of the High Court, to replace Judge Daniel O'Keeffe as Chair of the Commission of Investigation into certain transactions conducted by IBRC.
MrJustice O'Keeffe has informed the Government that, for personal reasons, he is unable to continue to act as Chairperson of the Commission.
The work already undertaken by MrJustice O'Keeffe will be available to Mr. Justice Cregan. This includes identifying suitable accommodation and the engagement of a legal team and ancillary services.
The timescale for submission of the Commission's final report is still 31 December 2015.
British tourists warned not to travel to Tunisia
The British Foreign Office has advised British tourists in Tunisia to leave the country amid fears of another terror attack.The Foreign Office has warned against all but essential travel following intelligence that a terrorist attack is "highly likely."
The Department of Foreign Affairs has said it is urgently reviewing its travel advice to Tunisia in consultation with the appropriate agencies.
A department spokesperson said the updated UK Foreign Office advice has been noted.
Meanwhile, Sunway travel company says it has nocustomers in Tunisia at the moment.
They say their flights to the country are suspended until the situation is clarified, following recent terror attacks in which 38 holiday makers were killed.
Salthill beaches closed due to high levels of bacteria
People are being advised not to swim in the sea at Blackrock and Ladies Beach in Salthill, after routine testing found high levels of bacteria in the water.Galway City Council has erected Do Not Swim notices at both beaches this afternoon.
Further tests have been carried out today but it will take three days before the results are known.
Fundraising page for Irishman who drowned in Thailand
A fundraising page set up to help the family of an Irishman who drowned in Thailand bring his body home has raised over 27,500 since it was set up yesterday.
'Helping to bring David home' was set up to show support to the family of David Houlihan, a 24-year-old man from Waterford who drowned in Kao Samui.
So far just under 1,000 people have donated money. The original target was of 1,000.
A statement on the page says: "David's family are looking after everything but we would all love to show our support. Any and all donations welcome".
Tube strike hits London commuters
Commuters in London faced chaos today as a 24-hour strike by London Underground workers continued.
People packed on to buses or walked to work in bright sunshine, with Tube services set to be disrupted until tomorrow morning.
Business groups said the strike will cost London tens of millions of pounds.
Picket lines were mounted outside Tube stations by members of four trade unions involved in the action in a row over the new all-night Tubes, due to start in mid-September.
Four injured in turbulence on Thomson flight
Four people were hurt after an aircraft full of holidaymakers hit turbulence on a flight from Manchester to Cyprus.
Two flight attendants on the Thomson flight were kept in hospital for fractures, police and airport officials said.
Two other flight attendants were discharged after medical treatment.
The aircraft was carrying 328 passengers and ten crew. It landed without further incident at Larnaca airport on last night, police said.
Honda recalls a further 4.5 million cars in airbag scare
Japanese carmaker Honda has said it was recalling another 4.5 million vehicles globally, as a scare over Takata-made airbags widens.
The move takes to 24.5 million the total number of vehicles that the country's number three auto manufacturer has recalled so far.
Israel says two citizens held in Gaza
The Israeli defence ministry has saidtwo Israelis, including an Arab, were being held captive in Gaza, accusing Hamas of holding one of them.
In a statement, the ministry said that "according to credible intelligence" Avraham Mengistu, an Israeli of Ethiopian descent, "is being held against his will by Hamas in Gaza."
"Furthermore, the defence establishment is currently dealing with an additional case of an Israeli Arab also being held in Gaza," it said.
Baltimore police chief sacked
Baltimore police chief Anthony Batts has been sacked following riots and an upsurge in murdersin the US city.
Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake said the police commissioner wasdismissed with immediate effect, adding "this is not an easy decision", but recent weeks had shown that "too many continue to die on our streets".
The city has witnessed 155 murders so far this year and 303 shootings, including a quadruple shooting on Tuesday near a college campus in which three people died.
Mr Batts has come under fire for his handling of riots that erupted after the death of anAfrican-American man,Freddie Gray, 25, in police custody in April.Six police officers were later charged in connection with Gray's death.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:41:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oireachtas members told of 'legal high' deaths</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713652-committees-told-of-impact-of-legal-highs/</Link>
        <Description>Oireachtas members have heard of the devastating effect that drugs known as "legal highs" are having on people as young as 13 in Ireland.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 09 July 2015 13.41
Packie Kelly said two young people died in Monaghan as a result of taking cannabinoids
Oireachtas members have heard of the devastating effect that drugsknown as "legal highs" are having on people as young as 13 in Ireland.
A community leader in Monaghan town told committee membersthat such was the threat posed by the drugs that people were talking about who would die next.
For the first time, members of the Oireachtas committees on health and justice joined forces to hear contributions from those who are dealing with the impact of "legal highs".
Theyare substances with stimulant or mood-altering properties whose sale or use is not banned by current legislation regarding the misuse of drugs.
Packie Kelly of the Teach na Daoine resource centre in Monaghan town told committee members that within 12 months, two young people died as a result of taking cannabinoids, which are drugs that mimic the effects of cannabis.
He saidthe problem was getting worse, with children as young as 13taking the legal high known as Joker which results in psychotic behaviour.
Mr Kelly added thatthe problem in Monaghan town was compounded by its proximity toNorthern Irelandwhere otherherbal drugs can be purchased easily.
Chairman of the Justice CommitteeDavid Stantonsaid an Oireachtas committee with sole responsibility for drugs needed to be established because of the scale of the problem.
Minister of StateAodhn  Rordinsaid new psychoactive substances are a constantly changing phenomenon.
He said the problem was being monitored through the national early warning system, which enables the authorities to identify new drugs, describe new trends and report the serious and unusual consequences of drug use.
Mr Rordin, who has responsibility for Drugs Strategy, told the committee that there has been an increasing trend towards poly-drug use, involving alcohol, illicit drugs and prescription medication, and this was a major concern forGovernment.
The Labour minister also said he would be leading the development of a drugs strategy for the period after 2016 andwould lay the groundwork for a "concise and focused policy, placing a clear emphasis on the practical implementation of actions in the coming months".
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:57:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pensioner awarded almost €60,000 for garda crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713718-garda-pensioner-court/</Link>
        <Description>An 83-year-old pensioner, who will have to undergo a hip replacement operation as a result of his car being hit by a garda vehicle, has been awarded almost €60,000 damages in the Circuit Civil Court.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Thursday 09 July 2015 16.57
The judge heard that since the accident Mr Tierney would not drive more than about five miles from his home
An 83-year-old pensioner, who will have to undergo a hip replacement operation as a result of his car being hit by a garda vehicle, has been awarded almost 60,000 damages in the Circuit Civil Court.
Circuit Court President Mr Justice Raymond Groarke said he was satisfied Brendan Tierney, who had an underlying degenerative condition in his hip, had led an extremely active life before the accident happened in October 2013.
The judge heard that Mr Tierney and his wife, Christine, also in her 80s, had enjoyed a Mediterranean cruise just the month before their Fiat Panda was hit by a car driven by Garda Michael O'Rourke in Blessington, Co Wicklow.
Barrister Timothy Sheehan, counsel for Mr Tierney, said several members of the garda had been chasing a car driven by Michael Cash, of Hazelhill Terrace, Tallaght, Dublin, who had allegedly failed to stop at a check point.
Judge Groarke was told the Tierneys, of Church View, St Margaret's, Co Dublin, had been on their way to their daughter's for a Sunday lunch and the accident had happened when Gda O'Rourke had made a U-turn.
Mr Sheehan said liability had been admitted in the case, which had become an assessment of damages.
The judge heard that since the accident, Mr Tierney was not able to climb up ladders and do some gardening, and he now would not drive more than about five miles from his home.
Mr Sheehan said the accident had exacerbated a degenerative condition, which may have never troubled Mr Tierney, but has left him where he may now need a hip replacement.
The court heard Mr Tierney had been on a waiting list to undergo the operation publicly but he may now have it done by next November privately.
He sued the Motor Insurers Bureau of Ireland; the Minister for Finance and also Michael Cash, for negligence and breach of duty.
Judge Groarke said there was no question Mr Tierney's life had been disrupted since the accident.
He said he was satisfied the surgery he was going to undergo had been partly caused by the accident, and would award him half of its cost in that regard.
The judge awarded Mr Tierney 45,000 damages for pain and suffering, and 13,023 damages for fees and expenses, including future expenses, a total of 58,023.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:57:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK couple found in crashed car after three days</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713666-scotland-car-crash-police/</Link>
        <Description>The father of a woman who is in a critical condition after a car crash in Scotland, which killed her boyfriend, has questioned why police "ignored" the incident for three days.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Police Scotland said officers were called to the M9 near Stirling yesterday following a report that a Renault Clio had gone off the road.
Mr Yuill, who was driving the car,was pronounced dead at the scene, while Ms Bell was taken to hospital in Glasgow.
The force admitted they had received a report on Sunday morning about a car that was off the road, but it had not been followed up at the time.
Assistant Chief Constable Kate Thomson, of Local Policing East, said: "It has come to light that a call was made to police late on Sunday morning regarding a car which was reported as being off the road.
"For reasons currently being investigated, that report was not followed up at the time.
"Officers have notified the families of this update. Our thoughts are with both families at this difficult time.
"A full investigation is currently under way to establish the full circumstances of the incident."
The matter has been referred to the police investigations andreview commissioner (Pirc) by the Crown Office.
At the scene today, a temporary orange barrier has sealed a gap in the fencing where, beyond, a patch of disturbed grass can be seen.
A single police car remains at the scene.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:31:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man jailed after 'vicious' assault on musician</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713648-michael-folan-court/</Link>
        <Description>A 55-year-old man has been sentenced to seven years in prison - with the final three years suspended - for an assault on traditional musician Noel Hill in 2008.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The incident left Mr Hill with lasting injuries and long term psychological damage.
In a lengthy victim impact statement last February, he told the Court that he had been destroyed by the assault - It broke his spirit and compromised his ability to play music.
At this morning's sentencing hearing at Galway Circuit Criminal Court, Judge Rory McCabe described the attack as horrible, nasty and vicious.
He sentenced Folan to seven years.
The final three years of the sentence will be suspended for a period of ten years, after Folan entered into a bond to keep the peace upon his release from prison.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:17:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lenihan not 'overruled' on night of guarantee</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713629-bank-inquiry/</Link>
        <Description>A former adviser to Brian Lenihan has told the banking inquiry that it does not sound accurate that he was "overruled" on the night of the bank guarantee.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
She said she spoke to Mr Lenihan in Government Buildings that night at around 2.30am or 3am after the decision was made and said he was worried about the importance of the decision and whether it would be enough, whether it would stick.
They did not discuss the nationalisation option at that time.
She also said that towards the end of his life, Mr Lenihan said he felt the guarantee was the best decision that could have been made at the time.
Mr Lenihan died in June 2011 after a battle with cancer.
Ms Herbert said she had no role in banking policy. Her work concentrated on communicating the difficult and complex decisions made.
She worked as an adviser to the minister from June 2006 when he was Minister for Children.
She said he was suspicious of the banks but he did not know whether they were misleading him or whether there was ineptitude and he was concerned about the extent of exposures and cross-collateralisation.
She said he was irritated at Mr Honohan's intervention on RT; he was surprised and it made for a difficult day.
Mr Lenihan had a view that some of the anonymous briefings in advance of the bailout were coming from Central Bankers of other member states.
She said there was a fair amount of panic on the other side as well.
She said Mr Lenihan agreed th the findings in the Wright Report about a lack of expertise in the Department of Finance andsaid he did seek advice outside the department, including Mr Honohan and economistsDavid McWilliams and Alan Ahearne, who was later appointedan adviser.
On the night of the guarantee, she was in Government Buildings at the request of Mr Lenihan but did not attend any meetings and said the discussions were held by a small group of officials. 
Ms Herbert said the media strategy around the banks was not to frighten the horses.Details were held very tightly among a small group of officials.
There was a communications strategy in place for a possible bank nationalisation in order to inform customers and the media.
If Mr Lenihan had been overruled, or had a serious disagreement, she would have known.
Mr Lenihan had fought a real battle to keep the country out of a bailout, the inquiry was told.
He was anxious to see if a precautionary bailout could be secured using the four-yearplan andwas concerned about the interest rate and how the bailout would deal with the banks.
Individual countries had pushed for a hike in corporation tax but it was a red line issue for the minister, Ms Herbert said.
McDonagh says NTMA resisted pressure to increase deposits in Irish banks
The former finance director at the National Treasury Management Agency has told the banking inquiry that they resisted considerable pressure from the Central Bank and the Department of Finance in September 2008 to increase its deposits in Irish banks.
Brendan McDonagh, currently head of NAMA, said they refused on the basis that the Central Bank should be the lender of last resort.
He said this caused considerable tension but the NTMA maintained its position.
He said all signs were pointing to Irish Nationwide Building Society and Anglo Irish bank being nationalised, the suggestion of a blanket guarantee came out of nowhere.
Mr McDonagh said the first he heard of a potential blanket bank guarantee was just three days before the decision was made, in an email from a Department of Finance official.
He replied that the exchequer exposure from the banking system had not yet been independently quantified and that made assessment of a bank guarantee extremely difficult.
Credit ratings agencies would be taken aback at the scale of State involvement in a blanket guarantee and there would be an immediate credit ratings downgrade.
Mr McDonagh said there was a very strong view in the NTMA that INBS and Anglo should have been nationalised.
He said they were always sceptical about Anglo, its business model and its funding was also under pressure.
He said Anglo should certainly have been nationalised on the night which might have allowed certain actions to be taken sooner.
The NTMA had stopped placing deposits with Irish banks in August 2007 due to concerns about liquidity shortages.
From December 2007, they were asked by the Central Bank and the Department Finance to place more deposits. They sought a written instruction from the Minister.
Following that meeting, the then minister for finance, Brian Cowen, wrote to the Chief Executive of the NTMA, Dr Michael Somers, on 19 December 2007, directing the NTMA to place deposits with the four banks, namely, Bank of Ireland, AIB, Irish Life &amp; Permanent, and EBS.
Former secretary general of the Department of FinanceKevin Cardiff advised on 28 July 2008 that the minster wished the NTMA to renew the existing 40m unsecured deposit with Anglo Irish Bank on a three-month maturity.
Alongside the placing of deposits, the NTMA had also been discussing with the Department of Finance from April 2008 about the provision of emergency liquidity in circumstances where the Irish banks could not get funding.
Mr McDonagh said by September 2008 these discussions had intensified and the NTMA had put in place arrangements to allow it, in the event that it was directed by the minister, to engage in emergency collateralised lending to Irish banks.
He said there was a dearth of information or analysis available in terms of real insight as to the financial state of the domestic banks and building societies.
He said It surprised them that there appeared to be only one or at the most two Financial Regulator staff engaged in close monitoring of each financial institution, even those institutions with balance sheets of up to 200bn.
Deputy KieranO'Donnell asked MrMcDonagh if Anglo Irish Bank had been nationalised on the night of the guarantee whether it have saved money for the tax payer.
Mr McDonagh said given what had emerged it was hard to see that it would have ultimately saved the taxpayer money because the bank had so many problems.
Mr McDonagh said he believed the markets had made a decision about banks like Anglo and HBOS that they had huge difficulties in March 2008.
Mr McDonagh was asked about correspondence from the NTMA in June 2008 seeking a direction from the Minister for Finance in terms of extending deposits to financial institutions.
Mr McDonagh said the NTMA had taken the view from 2007 onwards that it wasn't worth them placing state money at risk.
He said the view of Dr Michael Somers, then chief executive of the NTMA, and the rest of the senior management team was that this was not the right thing to do but that if the Minister wanted them to do it, he should direct them to do it.
He said this was so that if something went wrong the NTMA could say that it would not have done this voluntarily.
Mr McDonagh said this process was outlined under legislation governing the NTMA.
He said Dr Somers sought a senior counsel's opinion as to whether they would have to comply with a direction from the Minister regarding deposits.
Mr McDonagh said the NTMA had concerns from August 2007 about banks globally.
Deputy John Paul Phelan asked Mr McDonagh about the fact that he expressed surprise during a meeting in September 2008 in his statement that there appeared to be only one or two people from the Financial Regulator's office engaged in close monitoring of each financial institution.
Mr McDonagh said he recalled asking MrCardiff if he thought it was strange that these balance sheets were so big and there was only one or two people looking after them
Somers says powers of NTMA were strictly circumscribed
In his opening statement to the inquiry, Dr Somers said the powers of the NTMA were strictly circumscribed by legislation.
He said the NTMA had no power to provide any assistance to the banking sector and would have been acting outside of its remit to have done so by its own decision.
In his opening statement, Dr Somers said that the enormous amounts the banks lent to individual developers to enable them to buy high extraordinarily high prices for property, and the rolling up of interest, meant that insolvency was almost inevitable.
Dr Somers said he was in the US on the night of the bank guarantee and became aware of it through a text from a colleague.
On the guarantee, he said if there was a risk of a run on the banks then a guarantee on the deposits was probably the best course of action.
He said the decision to establish NAMA was taken very quickly and he supported the Minister for Finance when he announced it.
Dr Somers said he was hesitant about the amount of money that was going to be paid into the banks and the rapidity with which it was to be done.
On the decision to set up NAMA, Dr Somers said he felt that they should just take some loans from the banks and see if that would encourage them to lend.
He said he felt that the banks should be pressed to recover the loans themselves as they knew "where the bodies were buried".
Dr Somers said transferring them to NAMA would be a bonanza for lawyers and other professionals, as well as requiring a large staff in NAMA.
He said that regardless of what happened the likelihood is that the outcome would have been the same.
Dr Somers said that he was surprised that public expenditure was not cut back after the 2007 election, as it had been after the 2002 election, if for no other reason than to increase it again before the next election.
He said he felt the level of house and apartment building was unsustainable by any measure, and, if applied proportionately to other countries, would have given figures that were multiples of what they were actually doing.
He said he believed the same view was held by some persons at government level and the hope was that at least some of the building workers could be employed in other non-housing construction areas.
He said he was aware that costs and prices in Ireland were rising more rapidly than elsewhere in the euro zone.
Dr Somers said these issues are difficult to correct, particularly in the absence of a crisis, and where so many people are benefiting.
Dr Somers said by the time the NTMA was brought into the deliberations on the banking crisis, there were no easy solutions.
However, he said by virtue of the fact that the NTMA existed, and had prudently managed its operations, the State was in much better condition financially to tackle the crisis than would otherwise have been the case.
Dr Somers said the guarantee was required if there was a run on a bank but he would have opted for a more limited measure stopping at deposits.He would need to be persuaded that senior bonds should be included.
He said he would have tried to buy time. He didn't feel as strongly as Mr McDonagh that Anglo should have been nationalised in September but he would have taken his advice.
Mr Somers said Anglo had no long-term future. It was an accident waiting to happen. 
By 2007, they were worried it might collapse so they stopped placing deposits with it until directed to do so by the Minister.
He was in the US for the guarantee decision but the NTMA being left outside the meeting room was "quite typical".
Dr Somers said the bailout was the "ultimate humiliation" and that the IMF was the bogeyman. He saidTrichet's attitude was that a quarter of the ECB's loan book was stuck in Ireland and he was taking a huge risk. 
He said he felt he had done the best he could.
Quinlan tells inquiry of 'feel good factor' in Ireland from 2002-2007
Developer Derek Quinlan has said that apart for some limited exceptions, from 2002-2008 he was not personally involved in dealing with financial institutions to obtain financing for any Quinlan Private project.
He made his comments in his written opening statement to the banking inquiry.
Mr Quinlan said his assistance to the inquiry would relate to providing a high level overview of Quinlan Private's interaction with financial institutions.
He said that during the years from 2002-2007, there was a huge feel good factor in play in Ireland.
The developer said he was deeply saddened at the fallout from banking crisis and that he recognised that for a very large number of people it has had an unprecedented and devastating impact.
Deputy Joe Higgins asked Mr Quinlan if he was alarmed at the level of growth in the banks he was dealing with and in relation to his own level of exposure.
Mr Quinlan said at the time there was no sign out there that any of the Irish banks out there were stressed.
He aknowledged that in hindsight the use of leverage from bank debt had contributed to the financial crash.
Asked if he accepted there was a property bubble in Ireland in the 2000s, Mr Quinlan said in hindsight there was no doubt that prices in Ireland fell more than anywhere else.
Commenting on international views at the time, Mr Quinlan quoted the Chair of the US Federal Reserve in March 2007 predicting the scale of sub-prime losses.
Mr Quinlan said the US Federal Reservedid not see the crash coming.
Mr Higgins asked Mr Quinlan about a report in 2004 in relation to a deal which Quinlan Private organised, involving a site which was purchased in 2000 for 32mand sold four years later for 85m, which Deputy Higgins said was a speculative gain of 53m.
Mr Quinlan said when the land was bought initially there was an intention to put a new hospital there.
He said they spent a lot of time looking at this before looking at any alternatives.
Mr Quinlan said site values went up very significantly in Ireland over this period.
He said they had applied for planning permission and paid tax on the gain, and did nothing that was not correct.
Asked about donations to a Conservative Party event in Britain and his involvement in golf outings and events organised by Irish political parties, Mr Quinlan said what happened was that somebody would have rung from one of the parties, and asked if they would like to put in a team.
He said his company did not look for any political favours.
Mr Quinlan told the inquiry that he had never lobbied any politician in his life ever.
He said prior to the crash he believed in a soft landing theory, and he was not alone in that.
He addedthat was what the ESRI was also saying at the time.
Senator Susan O'Keeffe asked Mr Quinlan if noticed a change in how banks behaved towards him.
Mr Quinlan said it was a bit like if you were playing football and you suddenly had the touch of Ronaldo, that lots of people want to see him.
Mr Quinlan said in the 2000s what happened was more banks wanted to deal with his company, and more international banks wanted to deal with them.
He said they were coming to him and saying 'we want to do business with you'.
Mr Quinlan said in general he refused all corporate invites, but he got to know a lot of very serious bankers.
Deputy Higgins asked Mr Quinlan how much he cost the taxpayer.
Mr Quinlansaid he was very saddened by what had happened but he had lost also.
He described the Irish Glass Bottle site was a "disaster", adding he was one of the backers who paid 413mfor the site.
Different banks were competing to finance them. 
They hired the best professionals but nobody saw what was coming other than a few commentators. 
Inquiry to call Alan Gray to give evidence
The Banking Inquiry is to call consultant Alan Gray to give evidence.
Brian Cowen told the Inquiry he phoned Mr Gray for advice between meetings on Guarantee night. 
Mr Gray works for Indecon consultants and was also on the board of the Central Bank. 
He was also on the golfing outing to Druids Glen in July 2008 with Mr Cowen, Sean Fitzpatrick and other Anglo Irish Bank directors.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:38:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Number of mortgages in arrears down 23% in May</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713726-mortgage-arrears/</Link>
        <Description>Figures from the Department of Finance suggest the number of private residential mortgages in arrears was 23% lower in May than at the same time last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 09 July 2015 16.38
There are now just over 81,000 private residential mortgages in arrears of one day or more
Figures from the Department of Finance suggest the number of private residential mortgages in arrears was 23%lower in May than at the same time last year.
There are now just over 81,000 private residential mortgages in arrears of one day or more, which is11% of all mortgages on private homes.
There has been a sharp increasein the number of restructured mortgages in the past year at the six main banks, which make up 90% of the market. They are up 26% to over 109,000.
The number of buy-to-let mortgages in arrears is also falling. They were down 19% over the year to just over 27,000 accounts.
Nearly 20,000 buy-to-let mortgages have been permanently restructured to date, with about a quarter of them moving to interest only payments.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:56:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Defence Forces emails leaked online</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713654-defence-forces-hacking/</Link>
        <Description>The Defence Forces has said it did not purchase surveillance software from a controversial hacking company, which itself has been hacked.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The company has previously been accused by anti-surveillance campaigners of selling snooping tools to governments with poor human rights records.
Among the 400GB of emails, passwords, product source code and internal files posted online earlier this week were four emails between a Hacking Team employee and a number of Defence Forces personnel.
The first, dated 3 July 2012, is from a Defence Forces employee to Hacking Team's Key Account Manager Massimiliano Luppi, which attempts to organise a follow up meeting after the two met in Prague that month.
The next dated 16 April 2014, from Mr Luppi to two members of the Defence Forces, refers to a meeting at the end of 2013.
Mr Luppi writes: "During our meeting at the end of last year, you anticipated [sic] me that the process of purchasing a solution like ours would have started in spring of 2014.
"I was wondering if you now have a clearer idea of the process and situation".
The third email sent to Mr Luppi from one of the Defence Forces members on 14 December 2014 claims that he has been posted overseas, and that the other Defence Forces member who had been party to the correspondence has retired.
However, the email continues, "...we have planned to attend Prague ISS and will introduce some new friends to you at that point, so keep some time free if you can and we'll bring you you [sic] to speed then."
On its website ISS World Europe, which takes place in Prague, describes itself as "the world's largest gathering of European Law Enforcement, Intelligence and Homeland Security Analysts as well as Telecom Operators responsible for Lawful Interception, Hi-Tech Electronic Investigations and Network Intelligence Gathering."
The last email, dated 28 May this year, from the Defence Forces member who had previously been corresponding with Mr Luppi, states: "Looking forward to meeting you next week."
It is not clear from the released documentation whether there was further email correspondence between the parties in the interim periods or if they met last month as suggested.
In a statement the Defence Forces said that for operational security reasons it cannot comment on specific elements of the questions submitted to it by RT News.
But it did confirm that no services were purchased from the company in question.
Hacking Team has confirmed the breach of its systems took place and that it is being investigated by law enforcement authorities.
It has recommended that clients suspend use of its software until it works out whether specific law enforcement operations have been exposed.
Other documents which it is claimed came from the company's servers identify alleged current and former clients from several European countries, the FBI, the US Drug Enforcement Administration and police and state security organisations in countries with records of human rights abuses such as Egypt, Ethiopia, Kazakhstan, Morocco, Nigeria, Saudi Arabia and Sudan.
Hacking Team was named one of five private-sector "Corporate Enemies of the Internet" in a 2012 report by Reporters Without Borders.
Citizen Lab, a digital rights research group affiliated with the University of Toronto, has published numerous reports linking Hacking Team software to repression of minority and dissident groups, as well as journalists in a number of countries in Africa and the Middle East.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:41:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK abuse inquiry to travel across country</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713672-child-abuse-uk/</Link>
        <Description>Britain's largest ever public inquiry will travel from the "corridors of power" in Westminster to the poorest parts of the country to uncover the true scale of child sex abuse, its chairwoman has vowed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 09 July 2015 16.41
Lowell Goddard said the inquiry 'provides an opportunity to expose past failures of institutions to protect children'
Britain's largest ever public inquiry will travel from the "corridors of power" in Westminster to the poorest parts of the country to uncover the true scale of child sex abuse, its chairwoman has vowed.
Judge Lowell Goddard issued a stark warning to individuals and institutions that they will face scrutiny, "no matter how apparently powerful".
She said both victims and society had been left "scarred" by historic abuse and referred to estimates suggesting that one in 20 children in the UK has fallen victim as evidence of the "sheer scale" of the problem.
Finally opening the troubled inquiry, the judge stressed it will not hesitate to make findings relating to named people and organisations.
The inquiry is expected to take up to five years and cost tens of millions of pounds.
All strands of public life in England and Wales will come under the spotlight - including politics, children's homes, hospitals, GPs' surgeries, schools, churches, charities, local authorities, the Crown Prosecution Service, the NHS, the BBC and the armed forces.
The panel will examine allegations of abuse by prominent figures, with this work including inquiries relating to individuals in central government, political parties, the security and intelligence services, as well as present and former members of the Special Branch.
It may also need to challenge "powerful private interests", such as internet service providers and insurance companies, Justice Goddard suggested.
She said: "We must travel from the corridors of power in Westminster to children's homes in the poorest parts of the country.
"We must put difficult questions to politicians, bishops and other faith leaders, headteachers, police officers, regulators, inspectors and public officials of all kinds. And we will carry on putting those questions until we get answers.
"No-one, no matter how apparently powerful, will be allowed to obstruct our inquiries into institutional failings, and no-one will have immunity from scrutiny by virtue of their position.
"We have the tools we need to get at the truth and we will not hesitate to use them."
The inquiry can compel witnesses to give evidence but is not able to determine criminal or civil liability.
Justice Goddard stressed that her panel will not hesitate to make "findings of fact" about alleged conduct in relation to named individuals or institutions "where the evidence justifies this".
The New Zealand high court judge said "too many individuals and institutions" have been "sheltered from accountability through patterns of indifference or obstruction".
She added: "It is a stark reality that some abusers have abused their positions of trust within institutions as a means of gaining unfettered access to children."
The inquiry provides an opportunity to "expose past failures of institutions to protect children" and to "confront those responsible", she added.
She issued a call for child abuse victims to come forward, as well as laying down a "challenge" to organisations with a duty of care to protect children, telling them: "I urge you to take a pro-active stance towards the inquiry ... rather than waiting for us to come and see you."
The judge conceded that the task facing the five-person panel is "daunting", saying: "This is the largest and most ambitious public inquiry ever established in England and Wales."
She said she hopes their work will be completed by the end of 2020 and is determined that it is not "bogged down" by delays that have "bedevilled" other major investigations.
Home Secretary Theresa May has approved a budget of 17.9 million for the operation of the inquiry over the coming year.
The chairwoman said tackling child abuse "cannot be calculated in monetary terms", adding: "It is the inherent right of every child to experience a childhood free of sexual abuse and intimidation."
The inquiry - set up last July following claims of a high-level cover-up of abuse - has been beset by delays following the resignations of two previous chairwomen.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:49:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>September date likely for Portlaoise hospital plan</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713640-dail-health/</Link>
        <Description>A Health Service Executive report on an action plan for the Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise is now likely to be ready in September.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 09 July 2015 14.49
Leo Varadkar said he is committed to the role of the hospital within the Dublin-Midlands group
A HealthService Executivereport on an action plan for the Midland Regional HospitalPortlaoise is now likely to be ready in September.
Minister for Health Leo Varadkar told the Dil he is committed to securing the role of the hospital within the Dublin-Midlands Hospitals Group.
Fianna Fil'sSean Fleming said that in a recent meeting with public representatives, the minister had indicated he expected to have a report from the HSE within a few weeks.
Mr Fleming said people in the area have welcomed improvements in maternity services at the hospital as a result of the Health Information and Quality Authority inspection.
He also said the aim was to make improvements in the Emergency Department to make it safe rather than closing it down and he did not think there was permanent consultant cover in the department.
Minister Varadkar said we have to ask what does "consultant cover" mean as in some cases consultant cover is from home or not provided at weekends.
He said there was a limited number of specialists and a decision has to be made of what is acceptable.
He said one of the big struggles for the Portlaoise hospitalis hiring paediatricand obstetrics consultants and if it is not possible to staff those units, are people willing to accept an inferior service on that basis?
Minister Varadkar said work is being undertaken to strengthen the hospital and to look at services that are not viable.
He said consultations are ongoing with GPs and other stakeholders and the emphasis is on getting the best outcome for patients and patient safety.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:13:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berkeley tragedy survivor taken off critical list</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0709/713577-berkeley-balcony-collapse/</Link>
        <Description>One of the survivors of the Berkeley balcony tragedy has been taken off the critical list in hospital and has started to wake from an induced coma.</Description>
        <MainBody>A statement on the 'Friends of Aoife Beary' Facebook page said her condition has improved over recent days following successful heart surgery.
It says that Aoife is still in intensive care but no longer on the critical list.
The 21-year-old has slowly started to awaken from an induced coma, but the statement added that this process is expected to take some time.
The statement also saidshe has also started some communication with her parents and the medical team, adding that she has had a tracheotomy within the last week and continues to make progress on her "long road to recovery."
The family of another student seriously injured in the collapse has also spoken of her progress in recent weeks.
Clodagh Cogley is recovering at a rehabilitation centre in San Francisco. In a Facebook post the 21-year-old explained that she had broken her spinal cord, shoulder, knee and five ribs.
Two of the seven people injured have since been released from hospital. Conor Flynn is still in the San Francisco area as he is not yet permitted to fly, while Sean Fahey has returned to Ireland following treatment.
Niall Murray, Jack Halpin and Hannah Waters are all still receiving medical treatment for their injuries.
Five Irish students in California on J1 visas and one Irish-American - Eoghan Culligan, Eimear Walsh, Niccolai Schuster, Olivia Burke, Lorcn Miller and Ashley Donohoe -died in the balcony collapse.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
