<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sbs Africa News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:26:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World News Update, What you need to know</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47f47782/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cworld0Enews0Eupdate0Ewhat0Eyou0Eneed0Eknow/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>World News Update, What you need to know</Description>
        <MainBody>World News Update, What you need to know
World News Update, What you need to know
Source:
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras has vowed to present "credible" reform plans before a Thursday deadline set by exasperated European leaders, as Athens formally asked for a new bailout to avoid crashing out of the euro.
ELSEWHERE:
UNITED NATIONS, New York - Russia has vetoed a draft UN resolution recognising the Srebrenica massacre as genocide, branding the measure "confrontational" and a setback to reconciliation in the Balkans.
NEW YORK, July 8 AFP - The New York Stock Exchange halted trading Wednesday for more than three hours due to technical problems that it said were not caused by hacking.
LONDON - Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif says a nuclear deal with Western powers is "within reach" and could open the way to joint action against extremism, as talks continued in Vienna.
ROME - A court in Naples has sentenced former Italian premier and media tycoon Silvio Berlusconi to three years in prison for bribing a senator as part of a plot to destabilise a 2006-08 centre-left government.
SEMARANG, Indonesia - Boxing superstar Manny Pacquiao says he will visit a Filipina on death row in Indonesia on Friday and also plans to raise her case with President Joko Widodo.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:28:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World News Update, What you need to know</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47eb79d7/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cworld0Enews0Eupdate0Ewhat0Eyou0Eneed0Eknow/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>World News Update, What you need to know</Description>
        <MainBody>World News Update, What you need to know
World News Update, What you need to know
Source:
The EU's 28 member states will hold a "decisive" summit on the Greek debt crisis Sunday, Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi said after an emergency eurozone leaders meeting finished without a deal.
ELSEWHERE:
LONDON - Britons have laid flowers at the sites of the 2005 London suicide bombings and held a nationwide minute of silence for the 52 victims on the tenth anniversary of the attacks.
VIENNA - Global powers wrestling for a historic nuclear deal with Iran gave themselves yet more time Tuesday after foreign ministers failed to bridge what one diplomat called "very, very, very tough" remaining issues.
WASHINGTON - South Carolina prosecutors have announced additional charges against a 21-year-old white supremacist accused of killing nine blacks in an historic Charleston church.
PARIS - At least 150 detonators and a stock of plastic explosives have been stolen from a military base in F   France, triggering immediate probes into a theft that has authorities on high alert.
QUITO, Ecuador - Pope Francis has warned against the "temptation" of "single leaderships" in front of nearly one million people at an outdoor mass in Ecuador's capital, recently rocked by anti-government protests.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:20:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fugitive African warlord Kony &amp;#039;sickly&amp;#039;</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47ddd0d3/sc/32/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cfugitive0Eafrican0Ewarlord0Ekony0Esickly/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Joseph Kony, the fugitive leader of the Lord's Resistance Army, is said to be ill - possibly suffering from diabetes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fugitive African warlord Kony 'sickly'
Joseph Kony - the subject of a viral humanitarian campaign in 2012.
Joseph Kony, the fugitive leader of the Lord's Resistance Army, is said to be ill - possibly suffering from diabetes.
Source:
0
Defectors from the Lord's Resistance Army say the armed group's fugitive leader is sickly and in retreat from an international manhunt that includes US forces.
A Ugandan military spokesman, Lieutenant Colonel Paddy Ankunda, said Monday that defectors report that Joseph Kony is possibly suffering from diabetes.
He said the defectors surrendered to Ugandan troops in Central African Republic last month.
Kasper Agger, a researcher with the watchdog group Enough Project, said he receives many reports of Kony's failing health but it is impossible to independently verify them.
He said the reports from defectors suggest that the apparently ill Kony "doesn't have the same willingness to fight."
Kony is believed to be hiding in Kafia Kingi, a Sudanese-controlled enclave on the border of Central African Republic and South Sudan.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 15:07:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World News Update, What you need to know</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47daaba7/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cworld0Enews0Eupdate0Ewhat0Eyou0Eneed0Eknow/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>World News Update, What you need to know</Description>
        <MainBody>World News Update, What you need to know
World News Update, What you need to know
Source:
Greece's government has claimed "a clear mandate" for less stringent bailout conditions as voters looked set to overwhelmingly back its rejection of further austerity in a key referendum.
ELSEWHERE:
QUITO - Pope Francis has arrived in Ecuador to kick off his first South American trip in two years that will also take him to Bolivia and Paraguay and see him highlight the plight of the poor.
VIENNA - The UN atomic watchdog says "senior officials" are flying to Tehran, confirming comments from Iranian sources as talks continued in Vienna towards a major nuclear deal.
LONDON - Britain's Princess Charlotte has been christened in an intimate ceremony in the royal baby's second public appearance since her birth nine weeks ago.
TUNIS - The Tunisian jihadist behind last month's massacre of foreigners at a seaside resort had previously worked in tourism, officials say.
BERLIN - As Germany swelters in temperatures near 40C, at least 12 people have drowned in swimming accidents across the country.
KANO, Nigeria - A suicide bomber has blown himself up inside a church in the restive northeastern Nigerian city of Potiskum, killing five worshippers in the latest in a series of attacks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 09:59:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mozambique to destroy ivory, rhino horns</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47d60cc4/sc/32/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A50Cmozambique0Edestroy0Eivory0Erhino0Ehorns/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>More than a tonne of confiscated ivory and rhino horn will be destroyed by authorities in Mozambique as a blow against poaching, a conservation group says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mozambique to destroy ivory, rhino horns
A file image of soldiers destroying elephant ivory tusks (AP Photo/Joel Bouopda Tatou, File)
More than a tonne of confiscated ivory and rhino horn will be destroyed by authorities in Mozambique as a blow against poaching, a conservation group says.
Source:
0
Mozambique plans to destroy more than one tonne of confiscated ivory as well as 53 rhino horns to show its resolve in the fight against poaching, a New York-based conservation group says.
Citing Mozambican authorities, the Wildlife Conservation Society said on Saturday that the destruction of the stockpile will happen Monday in Maputo, the capital.
Some 340 elephant tusks and 65 rhino horns were seized in a May 12 raid in the southern city of Matola, said the conservation group, which co-manages Niassa National Reserve, a major wildlife park in Mozambique.
Ten days later, 12 of the horns were stolen from a police warehouse, and at least four officers suspected of involvement in the theft were arrested.
Authorities are investigating whether the rhino horns came from neighbouring South Africa, where rhino poaching has surged in recent years to meet growing demand for the horn in parts of Asia.
The rhino population in South Africa's Kruger National Park is frequently targeted by poachers who cross over from Mozambique. Experts believe Mozambique's rhino population has been virtually wiped out.
The demand for rhino horn is based partly on a belief that it has medicinal benefits. There is no scientific evidence to support that: the horn is made of keratin, a protein also found in human fingernails.
In May, conservationists said the number of elephants in Mozambique had dropped nearly 50 per cent to about 10,300 in the last five years because of poaching.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 15:32:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World News Update, What you need to know</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47c9f776/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cworld0Enews0Eupdate0Ewhat0Eyou0Eneed0Eknow/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>World News Update, What you need to know</Description>
        <MainBody>World News Update, What you need to know
World News Update, What you need to know
Source:
Suspected Boko Haram militants have killed nearly 150 people in northeastern Nigerian villages, mowing down men and children while they prayed in mosques and shooting women preparing food at home, witnesses say.
ELSEWHERE:
ORMOC CITY, Philippines - A ferry loaded with nearly 200 people has capsized off a central Philippine port, killing at least 38 people in the latest of the country's long string of maritime tragedies.
ATHENS - Greece's top administrative court, the Council of State, is to rule on the legality of the government's rushed bailout referendum set for this weekend, judicial sources say.
TUNIS - Tunisia has arrested eight people in connection with last week's jihadist massacre at a seaside resort, as the remains of more British victims were set to be flown home.
LONDON - British energy giant BP says it has agreed to pay a record $US18.7 billion ($A24.47 billion) to compensate the US government and five states for damages stemming from the deadly 2010 Gulf of Mexico oil spill.
LOS ANGELES - Health authorities have announced the first US death from measles in 12 years, after an autopsy showed a woman's fatal pneumonia was caused by the contagious disease.
MIAMI - If left unchecked, global warming will cause irreversible damage to marine life in the world's oceans, forcing fish to search for cooler waters and destroying valuable coral reefs, an international study says.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 01 17:29:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IS attacks kill at least 15 Egypt soldiers</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47bc2ed2/sc/40/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A10Cattacks0Ekill0Eleast0E150Eegypt0Esoldiers/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>IS jihadists have launched a wave of attacks against military checkpoints in Egypt's Sinai Peninsula, killing at least 15 soldiers.</Description>
        <MainBody>IS attacks kill at least 15 Egypt soldiers
More than 60 women and girls abducted by Boko Haram militants reportedly escaped. (AAP)
IS jihadists have launched a wave of attacks against military checkpoints in Egypt's Sinai Peninsula, killing at least 15 soldiers.
Source:
0
A wave of attacks in Egypt's Sinai Peninsula claimed by the Islamic State group has killed at least 15 soldiers, with the toll expected to rise with troops fighting a running battle with militants.
The jihadists launched simultaneous attacks against military checkpoints in the region, one with a powerful car bomb, the authorities said on Wednesday.
"It's war. The battle is ongoing," a senior military official told AFP.
Other security and medical officials said ambulances could not get to the scene of the attacks because of heavy fighting in which the military brought in Apache helicopters.
"Ambulances are waiting in front of the hospital. They can't leave. People are bring in the casualties," a health official said.
At least 15 soldiers have been confirmed dead, they said.
Troops regularly come under attack in the Sinai, where jihadists linked to the Islamic State group are waging a bloody insurgency.
Security officials said the attacks took place in Sheikh Zuweid, east of the provincial capital El-Arish where a car bomb, mortar shells, and rocket propelled grenades were used.
A security official said the militants had mined the exits from the Sheikh Zuweid police station to block reinforcements.
In a statement released online, IS said it carried out the multi-pronged assault.
"In a blessed raid enabled by God, the lions of the caliphate have simultaneously attacked more than 15 checkpoints belonging to the apostate army," the group said.
It said the attacks involved three suicide bombers.
It came two days after the country's state prosecutor Hisham Barakat was killed in a Cairo bombing targeting his convoy.
Barakat was the most senior government official killed since jihadists launched an insurgency following the military's overthrow of Islamist president Mohamed Morsi in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 01 02:29:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused over Boko Haram girls&amp;#039; abduction</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47b88122/sc/40/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A10Cman0Eaccused0Eover0Eboko0Eharam0Egirls0Eabduction/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A man has been arrested in Nigeria over Boko Haram's mass abduction of nearly 300 schoolgirls last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>IS attacks kill at least 15 Egypt soldiers
More than 60 women and girls abducted by Boko Haram militants reportedly escaped. (AAP)
IS jihadists have launched a wave of attacks against military checkpoints in Egypt's Sinai Peninsula, killing at least 15 soldiers.
Source:
0
A wave of attacks in Egypt's Sinai Peninsula claimed by the Islamic State group has killed at least 15 soldiers, with the toll expected to rise with troops fighting a running battle with militants.
The jihadists launched simultaneous attacks against military checkpoints in the region, one with a powerful car bomb, the authorities said on Wednesday.
"It's war. The battle is ongoing," a senior military official told AFP.
Other security and medical officials said ambulances could not get to the scene of the attacks because of heavy fighting in which the military brought in Apache helicopters.
"Ambulances are waiting in front of the hospital. They can't leave. People are bring in the casualties," a health official said.
At least 15 soldiers have been confirmed dead, they said.
Troops regularly come under attack in the Sinai, where jihadists linked to the Islamic State group are waging a bloody insurgency.
Security officials said the attacks took place in Sheikh Zuweid, east of the provincial capital El-Arish where a car bomb, mortar shells, and rocket propelled grenades were used.
A security official said the militants had mined the exits from the Sheikh Zuweid police station to block reinforcements.
In a statement released online, IS said it carried out the multi-pronged assault.
"In a blessed raid enabled by God, the lions of the caliphate have simultaneously attacked more than 15 checkpoints belonging to the apostate army," the group said.
It said the attacks involved three suicide bombers.
It came two days after the country's state prosecutor Hisham Barakat was killed in a Cairo bombing targeting his convoy.
Barakat was the most senior government official killed since jihadists launched an insurgency following the military's overthrow of Islamist president Mohamed Morsi in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jun 30 21:32:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Ebola death in Liberia</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47b06e9c/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C30A0Cnew0Eebola0Edeath0Eliberia/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A teenage boy has died from Ebola in Liberia - more than a month after the country was declared Ebola free.</Description>
        <MainBody>30 Jun 2015 - 3:42pm
New Ebola death in Liberia
A teenage boy has died from Ebola in Liberia - more than a month after the country was declared Ebola free.
Source:
0
The corpse of a 17-year-old has tested positive for Ebola in Liberia.
The country's deputy health minister Tolbert Nyenswah, who is also head of the country's Ebola response, told The Associated Press that the teenage boy died on June 24 and was given a safe burial the next day.
Liberia had been the country hardest hit by last year's Ebola outbreak in West Africa.
The World Health Organisation declared Liberia to be Ebola free on May 9 after the country went 42 days without reporting a case.
"We have said over and over again there was possibility that there could be a resurgence of the virus in Liberia," Nyenswah said.
The deadly virus, which has killed over 11,100 people mostly in West Africa in its worst outbreak ever, is hanging on stubbornly in Guinea, where the Ebola outbreak was first reported in March 2014, and in Sierra Leone.
It was not known how the 17-year-old contracted Ebola.
The town where the teenager died is far from the borders with Sierra Leone and Guinea, so Nyenswah said they are investigating whether his case might be linked to travel.
UN Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon had warned earlier this month that as long as there is one Ebola case in West Africa "all countries are at risk".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jun 30 15:15:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Car bomb attack kills Egypt&amp;#039;s top public prosecutor</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47aeef92/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C30A0Ccar0Ebomb0Eattack0Ekills0Eegypts0Etop0Epublic0Eprosecutor/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Egypt's top public prosecutor was killed by a car bomb attack on his convoy on Monday, the most senior state official to die at the hands of militants since the toppling of an Islamist president two years ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Egypt's top public prosecutor was killed by a car bomb attack on his convoy on Monday, the most senior state official to die at the hands of militants since the toppling of an Islamist president two years ago.
By
Reuters
30 Jun 2015 - 7:15 AM UPDATED30Jun2015-7:54AM
There was no confirmed claim of responsibility. Security sources said a bomb in a parked car was remotely detonated as Hisham Barakat's motorcade left his home, after saying earlier a car bomber had rammed into the convoy.
Judges and other senior officials have increasingly been targeted by radical Islamists opposed to President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi and angered by hefty prison sentences imposed on members of the now-outlawed Muslim Brotherhood.
Last month, the Islamic State militant group's Egyptian affiliate urged followers to attack judges, opening a new front in an Islamist insurgency in Egypt.
Chief prosecutor Barakat was the highest-ranking state official to die in a militant attack since Sisi, a former army chief, ousted Islamist president Mohamed Mursi in mid-2013 after mass protests against his rule.
Mursi, a Brotherhood leader who was freely elected as Egypt's president in 2012, was sentenced this month to death over a mass jailbreak in 2011.
Monday's attack stirred fears of yet more turmoil in Egypt, which has been struggling since the 2011 popular uprising that toppled Hosni Mubarak to regain full-fledged stability and revive the economy of the Arab world's most populous country.
The bombing also showed the risk of militant Islam threatening the Egyptian state leadership, as it did in the 1980s and 1990s.
State media confirmed the death of Barakat, 64, at a hospital in the residential district of Heliopolis where he had undergone surgery hours earlier, and said he would receive a military funeral.
The Brotherhood denies any link to violence and says it is committed to peaceful activism. Its spokesman said on the group's Facebook page it rejected killing, but that responsibility for the attack on the public prosecutor lay with the authorities.
Judges determined
Health Minister Adel Adawi told reporters outside al-Nozha hospital where Barakat was admitted that the cause of death was "ruptures in the lung and stomach, and internal bleeding".
State news agency MENA said the bomb blast wounded at least nine other people including police and civilians.
Hours after the explosion, which sent a large plume of black smoke aloft in front of a row of apartment buildings near the military academy, six burnt cars clogged up a street strewn with broken glass and fragments of metal. Windows were shattered in surrounding buildings up to nine stories high.
"It felt like the apartment was lifted up and dropped right back on the ground. When I felt it I said to my family, this is it, death has come for us," said 17-year-old Khaled Youssef.
Sisi's office mourned Barakat's death and cancelled celebrations prepared for Tuesday to mark the anniversary of mass unrest that led to Mursi's fall, and said the perpetrators would draw "the most severe punishment".
The government, however, declared June 30 a national holiday in commemoration of the 2013 protests, state media said.
"These kinds of vicious attacks will not deter the state from continuing its path of development, the adoption of rights, and realising the hopes and aspirations of the Egyptian people," the presidency's office said in a statement according to MENA.
The Egyptian judiciary says it is independent of the government and military. But some of Egypt's judges have drawn accusations of blatant bias by handing down lengthy jail terms and mass death sentences against Islamists.
"Terrorism killed the top man of our prosecution but despite this we will not be scared and we will continue our work," said Judge Ashraf Abdelhady as he left the hospital.
A presidential spokesman told MENA that the interior ministry would increase security measures ahead of the June 30 anniversary, including heightening the alert level and reinforcing security at vital installations.
Barakat's place of work was also targeted earlier this year when a bomb exploded near the High Court in central Cairo, killing two people.
Egypt is grappling with a Sinai-based insurgency that has killed hundreds of policemen and soldiers since Mursi's fall. The most active group is Sinai Province, which has pledged allegiance to Islamic State, the ultra-hardline jihadist group that has seized control of significant areas of Iraq and Syria.
At least two people were killed and 12 wounded in a blast later on Monday likely caused by a roadside bomb near Sheikh Zuweid in North Sinai, security sources said.
Last month, suspected Islamist gunmen killed three judges in the Sinai city of al-Arish.
(Additional reporting by Stephen Kalin, Ahmed Aboulenein, Shadi Bushra, Lilian Wagdy and Ali Abdelaty; Writing by Yara Bayoumy; Editing by Andrew Roche)
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 06:31:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly Islamic state terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/479ec5f4/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Ctourists0Eflee0Etunisia0Eafter0Edeadly0Eislamic0Estate0Eterror0Eattack/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including foreign tourists.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 4:45pm
Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly Islamic state terror attack
Five British citizens have been killed in the gun massacre at a packed holiday resort in Tunisia. (AAP)
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including foreign tourists.
Source:
Britons, Germans and Belgians among 39 killed
Many wounded when gunman opens fire
Man hid weapon in an umbrella - witnesses
Holiday-makers are being evacuated back to the UK from Tunisia on special flights after a gunman killed 38 people at a beach resort.
Travel firms Thomson and First Choice confirmed that "a number of fatalities" and those injured are their customers and said around 2500 people will be brought back to the UK on Saturday.
At least five Britons have been confirmed dead in the attack in Sousse.
The holiday operators said all its trips to Tunisia for the next week will be cancelled.
"We would like to extend our deepest sympathies to the friends and families of those involved in this tragic event," Thomson said in a statement.
"We are actively working with the families and friends affected to provide support in resort and a special assistance team is en route to Tunisia to assist our customers."
Thomas Cook said it has arranged for an additional aircraft to fly to Tunisia, which would be used to support its operations to accommodate customers wanting to return home as soon as possible.
The company is offering customers due to travel to Tunisia the opportunity to cancel or amend their holiday free of charge.
Downing Street said Prime Minister David Cameron will chair a meeting of the Cobra emergency committee on Saturday morning and the government "will do everything we can to help those affected".
Attack killed 39 including foreign tourists
Militant group Islamic State claimed responsbility for the Tunisia tourist hotel attack on Friday that killed 39 people including Britons and Germans, according to a statement on a Twitter account.
"Our brother, the soldier of the Caliphate, Abu Yihya al-Kairouni, reached his target the Imperial hotel despite the security measures," the statement said. It said he had attacked a "bordel" and killed 40 "infidels'.
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel on Friday with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including British, German and Belgian tourists, as they lounged at the beach and pool in a popular resort town.
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire and an explosion erupted at the Imperial Marhaba in Sousse resort town, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis, before police shot the gunman dead, witnesses and security officials said.
"This was always a safe place but today was horror," said an Irish tourist who gave only his first name, Anthony. "He started on the beach and went to the lobby, killing in cold blood."
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, on a day in which a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found in France, a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait and at least 145 civilians were reported killed by Islamic State militants in northern Syria.
Islamic State claimed the Kuwait attack and had urged its followers to step up assaults during Ramadan but it was not known whether the Tunisian attacker was inspired by the group.
Rafik Chelli, a senior interior ministry official, said the gunman killed was a student, unknown to authorities and not on any watchlist of potential jihadists.
After pulling out a weapon hidden inside an umbrella, the assailant strolled through the hotel grounds, opening fire at the pool and beach, reloading his weapon several times and tossing an explosive, witnesses said.
A security source said another bomb was found on his body, which lay with a Kalashnikov assault rifle where he was shot.
Local radio said police captured a second gunman, but officials did not immediately confirm the arrest or his role in the attack.
"It was just one attacker," said a hotel worker at the site. "He was a young guy dressed in shorts like he was a tourist himself."
Related
PM Abbott condemns overseas terror attacks
Prime Minister Tony Abbott says it's too early to say whether three overseas terrorist attacks were co-ordinated.
"Run, run run!"
It was the worst attack in Tunisia's modern history and the second major massacre this year following the Islamist militant assault on Tunis Bardo museum when gunmen killed 21 foreign visitors.
A health ministry statement said British, German and Belgian nationals were among the 37 dead. The health minister told French radio 36 others were wounded in the shooting.
Ireland's foreign ministry also confirmed at least one Irish citizen had been killed.
Tunisia, which has been hailed as a model of democratic transition since its 2011 'Arab Spring' uprising, is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world. Its beach resorts and nightclubs on the Mediterranean are popular with foreigners.
No one immediately claimed the attack. But Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because of their open Western lifestyles and tolerance of alcohol.
Irishwoman Elizabeth O'Brien, who was staying at a neighbouring hotel with her two sons, said there was panic on the beach when gunfire erupted.
"I honestly thought it was fireworks and then when I saw people running... I thought, my God, it is shooting," she told Irish radio station RTE. "The waiters and the security on the beach started to say 'Run, run, run!'"
Catastrophe
In Sousse, many tourists were already packing their suitcases into busses and checking out of hotels to leave after the attack.
German tour operator TUI said on Friday it was organising flights for tourists wishing to return from Tunisia and said those who booked Tunisian holidays for this summer could rebook or cancel the trips free of charge.
Sousse, alongside nearby Hammamet and the island of Djerba, is the heartland of Tunisia's most popular beach resorts, drawing visitors from Europe and neighbouring North African countries like Algeria.
Six million tourists, mostly Europeans, visited Tunisia's beaches, desert treks and medina souks last year, providing seven percent of its gross domestic product, most of its foreign currency revenues and more jobs than anything but farming.
"This is a catastrophe for the economy," Tourism Minister Salma Loumi said. "Our losses will be great, but the loss of human life was even greater."
Since its 2011 uprising to oust autocrat Zine el-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has been praised for its peaceful democratic transition bringing free elections and a new constitution seen as a model for the region.
But the country has also struggled with the rise of Islamist movements as ultra-conservative preachers took advantage of the upheaval and young democracy to take over mosques and spread their hardline message.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have left the country to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up jihadist training camps and promised to return to attack their homeland.
Islamic State made some claim to the Bardo museum attack, but authorities blamed possible splinter fighters from the Okba Ibn Nafaa, a brigade of al Qaeda-affiliated fighters, operating in the Chaambi mountains along the Algerian border.
(Reporting by Tarek Amara; writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Mark Trevelyan and Philippa Fletcher)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 06:31:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gun attack kills at least 37, including Europeans, at Tunisian beachside hotel</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/479ce3f0/sc/38/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cgun0Eattack0Ekills0Eleast0E370Eincluding0Eeuropeans0Etunisian0Ebeachside0Ehotel/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 37 people, including foreign tourists.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 4:45pm
Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly Islamic state terror attack
Five British citizens have been killed in the gun massacre at a packed holiday resort in Tunisia. (AAP)
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including foreign tourists.
Source:
Britons, Germans and Belgians among 39 killed
Many wounded when gunman opens fire
Man hid weapon in an umbrella - witnesses
Holiday-makers are being evacuated back to the UK from Tunisia on special flights after a gunman killed 38 people at a beach resort.
Travel firms Thomson and First Choice confirmed that "a number of fatalities" and those injured are their customers and said around 2500 people will be brought back to the UK on Saturday.
At least five Britons have been confirmed dead in the attack in Sousse.
The holiday operators said all its trips to Tunisia for the next week will be cancelled.
"We would like to extend our deepest sympathies to the friends and families of those involved in this tragic event," Thomson said in a statement.
"We are actively working with the families and friends affected to provide support in resort and a special assistance team is en route to Tunisia to assist our customers."
Thomas Cook said it has arranged for an additional aircraft to fly to Tunisia, which would be used to support its operations to accommodate customers wanting to return home as soon as possible.
The company is offering customers due to travel to Tunisia the opportunity to cancel or amend their holiday free of charge.
Downing Street said Prime Minister David Cameron will chair a meeting of the Cobra emergency committee on Saturday morning and the government "will do everything we can to help those affected".
Attack killed 39 including foreign tourists
Militant group Islamic State claimed responsbility for the Tunisia tourist hotel attack on Friday that killed 39 people including Britons and Germans, according to a statement on a Twitter account.
"Our brother, the soldier of the Caliphate, Abu Yihya al-Kairouni, reached his target the Imperial hotel despite the security measures," the statement said. It said he had attacked a "bordel" and killed 40 "infidels'.
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel on Friday with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including British, German and Belgian tourists, as they lounged at the beach and pool in a popular resort town.
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire and an explosion erupted at the Imperial Marhaba in Sousse resort town, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis, before police shot the gunman dead, witnesses and security officials said.
"This was always a safe place but today was horror," said an Irish tourist who gave only his first name, Anthony. "He started on the beach and went to the lobby, killing in cold blood."
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, on a day in which a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found in France, a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait and at least 145 civilians were reported killed by Islamic State militants in northern Syria.
Islamic State claimed the Kuwait attack and had urged its followers to step up assaults during Ramadan but it was not known whether the Tunisian attacker was inspired by the group.
Rafik Chelli, a senior interior ministry official, said the gunman killed was a student, unknown to authorities and not on any watchlist of potential jihadists.
After pulling out a weapon hidden inside an umbrella, the assailant strolled through the hotel grounds, opening fire at the pool and beach, reloading his weapon several times and tossing an explosive, witnesses said.
A security source said another bomb was found on his body, which lay with a Kalashnikov assault rifle where he was shot.
Local radio said police captured a second gunman, but officials did not immediately confirm the arrest or his role in the attack.
"It was just one attacker," said a hotel worker at the site. "He was a young guy dressed in shorts like he was a tourist himself."
Related
PM Abbott condemns overseas terror attacks
Prime Minister Tony Abbott says it's too early to say whether three overseas terrorist attacks were co-ordinated.
"Run, run run!"
It was the worst attack in Tunisia's modern history and the second major massacre this year following the Islamist militant assault on Tunis Bardo museum when gunmen killed 21 foreign visitors.
A health ministry statement said British, German and Belgian nationals were among the 37 dead. The health minister told French radio 36 others were wounded in the shooting.
Ireland's foreign ministry also confirmed at least one Irish citizen had been killed.
Tunisia, which has been hailed as a model of democratic transition since its 2011 'Arab Spring' uprising, is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world. Its beach resorts and nightclubs on the Mediterranean are popular with foreigners.
No one immediately claimed the attack. But Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because of their open Western lifestyles and tolerance of alcohol.
Irishwoman Elizabeth O'Brien, who was staying at a neighbouring hotel with her two sons, said there was panic on the beach when gunfire erupted.
"I honestly thought it was fireworks and then when I saw people running... I thought, my God, it is shooting," she told Irish radio station RTE. "The waiters and the security on the beach started to say 'Run, run, run!'"
Catastrophe
In Sousse, many tourists were already packing their suitcases into busses and checking out of hotels to leave after the attack.
German tour operator TUI said on Friday it was organising flights for tourists wishing to return from Tunisia and said those who booked Tunisian holidays for this summer could rebook or cancel the trips free of charge.
Sousse, alongside nearby Hammamet and the island of Djerba, is the heartland of Tunisia's most popular beach resorts, drawing visitors from Europe and neighbouring North African countries like Algeria.
Six million tourists, mostly Europeans, visited Tunisia's beaches, desert treks and medina souks last year, providing seven percent of its gross domestic product, most of its foreign currency revenues and more jobs than anything but farming.
"This is a catastrophe for the economy," Tourism Minister Salma Loumi said. "Our losses will be great, but the loss of human life was even greater."
Since its 2011 uprising to oust autocrat Zine el-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has been praised for its peaceful democratic transition bringing free elections and a new constitution seen as a model for the region.
But the country has also struggled with the rise of Islamist movements as ultra-conservative preachers took advantage of the upheaval and young democracy to take over mosques and spread their hardline message.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have left the country to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up jihadist training camps and promised to return to attack their homeland.
Islamic State made some claim to the Bardo museum attack, but authorities blamed possible splinter fighters from the Okba Ibn Nafaa, a brigade of al Qaeda-affiliated fighters, operating in the Chaambi mountains along the Algerian border.
(Reporting by Tarek Amara; writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Mark Trevelyan and Philippa Fletcher)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 06:31:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At least 27 dead in Tunisia attack</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/4799a559/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cleast0E270Edead0Etunisia0Eattack/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It's believed foreign tourists are among the at least 27 people who have been killed in an attack by a gunman on a hotel in Tunisia.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 4:45pm
Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly Islamic state terror attack
Five British citizens have been killed in the gun massacre at a packed holiday resort in Tunisia. (AAP)
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including foreign tourists.
Source:
Britons, Germans and Belgians among 39 killed
Many wounded when gunman opens fire
Man hid weapon in an umbrella - witnesses
Holiday-makers are being evacuated back to the UK from Tunisia on special flights after a gunman killed 38 people at a beach resort.
Travel firms Thomson and First Choice confirmed that "a number of fatalities" and those injured are their customers and said around 2500 people will be brought back to the UK on Saturday.
At least five Britons have been confirmed dead in the attack in Sousse.
The holiday operators said all its trips to Tunisia for the next week will be cancelled.
"We would like to extend our deepest sympathies to the friends and families of those involved in this tragic event," Thomson said in a statement.
"We are actively working with the families and friends affected to provide support in resort and a special assistance team is en route to Tunisia to assist our customers."
Thomas Cook said it has arranged for an additional aircraft to fly to Tunisia, which would be used to support its operations to accommodate customers wanting to return home as soon as possible.
The company is offering customers due to travel to Tunisia the opportunity to cancel or amend their holiday free of charge.
Downing Street said Prime Minister David Cameron will chair a meeting of the Cobra emergency committee on Saturday morning and the government "will do everything we can to help those affected".
Attack killed 39 including foreign tourists
Militant group Islamic State claimed responsbility for the Tunisia tourist hotel attack on Friday that killed 39 people including Britons and Germans, according to a statement on a Twitter account.
"Our brother, the soldier of the Caliphate, Abu Yihya al-Kairouni, reached his target the Imperial hotel despite the security measures," the statement said. It said he had attacked a "bordel" and killed 40 "infidels'.
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel on Friday with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including British, German and Belgian tourists, as they lounged at the beach and pool in a popular resort town.
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire and an explosion erupted at the Imperial Marhaba in Sousse resort town, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis, before police shot the gunman dead, witnesses and security officials said.
"This was always a safe place but today was horror," said an Irish tourist who gave only his first name, Anthony. "He started on the beach and went to the lobby, killing in cold blood."
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, on a day in which a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found in France, a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait and at least 145 civilians were reported killed by Islamic State militants in northern Syria.
Islamic State claimed the Kuwait attack and had urged its followers to step up assaults during Ramadan but it was not known whether the Tunisian attacker was inspired by the group.
Rafik Chelli, a senior interior ministry official, said the gunman killed was a student, unknown to authorities and not on any watchlist of potential jihadists.
After pulling out a weapon hidden inside an umbrella, the assailant strolled through the hotel grounds, opening fire at the pool and beach, reloading his weapon several times and tossing an explosive, witnesses said.
A security source said another bomb was found on his body, which lay with a Kalashnikov assault rifle where he was shot.
Local radio said police captured a second gunman, but officials did not immediately confirm the arrest or his role in the attack.
"It was just one attacker," said a hotel worker at the site. "He was a young guy dressed in shorts like he was a tourist himself."
Related
PM Abbott condemns overseas terror attacks
Prime Minister Tony Abbott says it's too early to say whether three overseas terrorist attacks were co-ordinated.
"Run, run run!"
It was the worst attack in Tunisia's modern history and the second major massacre this year following the Islamist militant assault on Tunis Bardo museum when gunmen killed 21 foreign visitors.
A health ministry statement said British, German and Belgian nationals were among the 37 dead. The health minister told French radio 36 others were wounded in the shooting.
Ireland's foreign ministry also confirmed at least one Irish citizen had been killed.
Tunisia, which has been hailed as a model of democratic transition since its 2011 'Arab Spring' uprising, is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world. Its beach resorts and nightclubs on the Mediterranean are popular with foreigners.
No one immediately claimed the attack. But Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because of their open Western lifestyles and tolerance of alcohol.
Irishwoman Elizabeth O'Brien, who was staying at a neighbouring hotel with her two sons, said there was panic on the beach when gunfire erupted.
"I honestly thought it was fireworks and then when I saw people running... I thought, my God, it is shooting," she told Irish radio station RTE. "The waiters and the security on the beach started to say 'Run, run, run!'"
Catastrophe
In Sousse, many tourists were already packing their suitcases into busses and checking out of hotels to leave after the attack.
German tour operator TUI said on Friday it was organising flights for tourists wishing to return from Tunisia and said those who booked Tunisian holidays for this summer could rebook or cancel the trips free of charge.
Sousse, alongside nearby Hammamet and the island of Djerba, is the heartland of Tunisia's most popular beach resorts, drawing visitors from Europe and neighbouring North African countries like Algeria.
Six million tourists, mostly Europeans, visited Tunisia's beaches, desert treks and medina souks last year, providing seven percent of its gross domestic product, most of its foreign currency revenues and more jobs than anything but farming.
"This is a catastrophe for the economy," Tourism Minister Salma Loumi said. "Our losses will be great, but the loss of human life was even greater."
Since its 2011 uprising to oust autocrat Zine el-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has been praised for its peaceful democratic transition bringing free elections and a new constitution seen as a model for the region.
But the country has also struggled with the rise of Islamist movements as ultra-conservative preachers took advantage of the upheaval and young democracy to take over mosques and spread their hardline message.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have left the country to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up jihadist training camps and promised to return to attack their homeland.
Islamic State made some claim to the Bardo museum attack, but authorities blamed possible splinter fighters from the Okba Ibn Nafaa, a brigade of al Qaeda-affiliated fighters, operating in the Chaambi mountains along the Algerian border.
(Reporting by Tarek Amara; writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Mark Trevelyan and Philippa Fletcher)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:31:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic state claims responsibility for Tunisia hotel attack: reports</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/479da977/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cislamic0Estate0Eclaims0Eresponsibility0Etunisia0Ehotel0Eattack0Ereports/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including foreign tourists.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 4:45pm
Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly Islamic state terror attack
Five British citizens have been killed in the gun massacre at a packed holiday resort in Tunisia. (AAP)
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including foreign tourists.
Source:
Britons, Germans and Belgians among 39 killed
Many wounded when gunman opens fire
Man hid weapon in an umbrella - witnesses
Holiday-makers are being evacuated back to the UK from Tunisia on special flights after a gunman killed 38 people at a beach resort.
Travel firms Thomson and First Choice confirmed that "a number of fatalities" and those injured are their customers and said around 2500 people will be brought back to the UK on Saturday.
At least five Britons have been confirmed dead in the attack in Sousse.
The holiday operators said all its trips to Tunisia for the next week will be cancelled.
"We would like to extend our deepest sympathies to the friends and families of those involved in this tragic event," Thomson said in a statement.
"We are actively working with the families and friends affected to provide support in resort and a special assistance team is en route to Tunisia to assist our customers."
Thomas Cook said it has arranged for an additional aircraft to fly to Tunisia, which would be used to support its operations to accommodate customers wanting to return home as soon as possible.
The company is offering customers due to travel to Tunisia the opportunity to cancel or amend their holiday free of charge.
Downing Street said Prime Minister David Cameron will chair a meeting of the Cobra emergency committee on Saturday morning and the government "will do everything we can to help those affected".
Attack killed 39 including foreign tourists
Militant group Islamic State claimed responsbility for the Tunisia tourist hotel attack on Friday that killed 39 people including Britons and Germans, according to a statement on a Twitter account.
"Our brother, the soldier of the Caliphate, Abu Yihya al-Kairouni, reached his target the Imperial hotel despite the security measures," the statement said. It said he had attacked a "bordel" and killed 40 "infidels'.
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel on Friday with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people, including British, German and Belgian tourists, as they lounged at the beach and pool in a popular resort town.
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire and an explosion erupted at the Imperial Marhaba in Sousse resort town, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis, before police shot the gunman dead, witnesses and security officials said.
"This was always a safe place but today was horror," said an Irish tourist who gave only his first name, Anthony. "He started on the beach and went to the lobby, killing in cold blood."
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, on a day in which a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found in France, a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait and at least 145 civilians were reported killed by Islamic State militants in northern Syria.
Islamic State claimed the Kuwait attack and had urged its followers to step up assaults during Ramadan but it was not known whether the Tunisian attacker was inspired by the group.
Rafik Chelli, a senior interior ministry official, said the gunman killed was a student, unknown to authorities and not on any watchlist of potential jihadists.
After pulling out a weapon hidden inside an umbrella, the assailant strolled through the hotel grounds, opening fire at the pool and beach, reloading his weapon several times and tossing an explosive, witnesses said.
A security source said another bomb was found on his body, which lay with a Kalashnikov assault rifle where he was shot.
Local radio said police captured a second gunman, but officials did not immediately confirm the arrest or his role in the attack.
"It was just one attacker," said a hotel worker at the site. "He was a young guy dressed in shorts like he was a tourist himself."
Related
PM Abbott condemns overseas terror attacks
Prime Minister Tony Abbott says it's too early to say whether three overseas terrorist attacks were co-ordinated.
"Run, run run!"
It was the worst attack in Tunisia's modern history and the second major massacre this year following the Islamist militant assault on Tunis Bardo museum when gunmen killed 21 foreign visitors.
A health ministry statement said British, German and Belgian nationals were among the 37 dead. The health minister told French radio 36 others were wounded in the shooting.
Ireland's foreign ministry also confirmed at least one Irish citizen had been killed.
Tunisia, which has been hailed as a model of democratic transition since its 2011 'Arab Spring' uprising, is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world. Its beach resorts and nightclubs on the Mediterranean are popular with foreigners.
No one immediately claimed the attack. But Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because of their open Western lifestyles and tolerance of alcohol.
Irishwoman Elizabeth O'Brien, who was staying at a neighbouring hotel with her two sons, said there was panic on the beach when gunfire erupted.
"I honestly thought it was fireworks and then when I saw people running... I thought, my God, it is shooting," she told Irish radio station RTE. "The waiters and the security on the beach started to say 'Run, run, run!'"
Catastrophe
In Sousse, many tourists were already packing their suitcases into busses and checking out of hotels to leave after the attack.
German tour operator TUI said on Friday it was organising flights for tourists wishing to return from Tunisia and said those who booked Tunisian holidays for this summer could rebook or cancel the trips free of charge.
Sousse, alongside nearby Hammamet and the island of Djerba, is the heartland of Tunisia's most popular beach resorts, drawing visitors from Europe and neighbouring North African countries like Algeria.
Six million tourists, mostly Europeans, visited Tunisia's beaches, desert treks and medina souks last year, providing seven percent of its gross domestic product, most of its foreign currency revenues and more jobs than anything but farming.
"This is a catastrophe for the economy," Tourism Minister Salma Loumi said. "Our losses will be great, but the loss of human life was even greater."
Since its 2011 uprising to oust autocrat Zine el-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has been praised for its peaceful democratic transition bringing free elections and a new constitution seen as a model for the region.
But the country has also struggled with the rise of Islamist movements as ultra-conservative preachers took advantage of the upheaval and young democracy to take over mosques and spread their hardline message.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have left the country to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up jihadist training camps and promised to return to attack their homeland.
Islamic State made some claim to the Bardo museum attack, but authorities blamed possible splinter fighters from the Okba Ibn Nafaa, a brigade of al Qaeda-affiliated fighters, operating in the Chaambi mountains along the Algerian border.
(Reporting by Tarek Amara; writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Mark Trevelyan and Philippa Fletcher)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 12:04:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10 die in Nigeria suicide bomb by girl, 12</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47822fb6/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C240C10A0Edie0Enigeria0Esuicide0Ebomb0Egirl0E12/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Ten people are dead and 30 have been injured in a suicide blast in Nigeria, carried out by a girl believed to be just 12 years old.</Description>
        <MainBody>24 Jun 2015 - 8:18am
10 die in Nigeria suicide bomb by girl, 12
Ten people are dead and 30 have been injured in a suicide blast in Nigeria, carried out by a girl believed to be just 12 years old.
Source:
0
Ten people have been killed at a market in northeast Nigeria when a girl thought to be aged just 12 detonated explosives she was carrying.
Hussaini Aisami, a relative of one of the injured victims and a health worker, said the blast, in Wagir, in the Gujba district south of the state capital Damaturu, killed 10 and injured more than 30.
"It was a suicide attack by a girl of around 12 years," said Hussaini Aisami.
"She went into the market and headed straight to the grain section. She detonated her explosives in the middle of traders and customers.
"Ten people died from the explosion. We brought 30 people to the hospital."
Tuesday's attack bore all the hallmarks of Boko Haram Islamists, who have used young women and girls in the past as human bombs and regularly attacked "soft" civilian targets such as markets.
On Monday, a girl thought to be aged about 17 killed at least 20 at a bus station near a fish market in the Borno state capital, Maiduguri, when the explosives she was carrying went off.
A girl about the same age was also killed nearby in a suicide blast but there were no other casualties.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 21:04:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Girl suicide bomber kills 16 in Nigeria</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/47818f98/sc/40/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C240Cgirl0Esuicide0Ebomber0Ekills0E160Enigeria/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 16 people have been killed by a 12-year-old female suicide bomber in Nigeria, officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>24 Jun 2015 - 8:18am
10 die in Nigeria suicide bomb by girl, 12
Ten people are dead and 30 have been injured in a suicide blast in Nigeria, carried out by a girl believed to be just 12 years old.
Source:
0
Ten people have been killed at a market in northeast Nigeria when a girl thought to be aged just 12 detonated explosives she was carrying.
Hussaini Aisami, a relative of one of the injured victims and a health worker, said the blast, in Wagir, in the Gujba district south of the state capital Damaturu, killed 10 and injured more than 30.
"It was a suicide attack by a girl of around 12 years," said Hussaini Aisami.
"She went into the market and headed straight to the grain section. She detonated her explosives in the middle of traders and customers.
"Ten people died from the explosion. We brought 30 people to the hospital."
Tuesday's attack bore all the hallmarks of Boko Haram Islamists, who have used young women and girls in the past as human bombs and regularly attacked "soft" civilian targets such as markets.
On Monday, a girl thought to be aged about 17 killed at least 20 at a bus station near a fish market in the Borno state capital, Maiduguri, when the explosives she was carrying went off.
A girl about the same age was also killed nearby in a suicide blast but there were no other casualties.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 02:57:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Shabaab kills at least 15 in Somalia</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/476a0fa6/sc/40/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C20A0Cal0Eshabaab0Ekills0Eleast0E150Esomalia/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 15 people have died in clashes in the town of Afgoye in southern Somalia.</Description>
        <MainBody>20 Jun 2015 - 10:42pm
Al-Shabaab kills at least 15 in Somalia
At least 15 people have died in clashes in the town of Afgoye in southern Somalia. (AAP)
At least 15 people have died in clashes in the town of Afgoye in southern Somalia.
Source:
0
At least 15 people have been killed in clashes between Somalia's military and the Islamist terrorist group al-Shabaab.
Heavily armed al-Shabaab fighters attacked army bases overnight in the town of Afgoye in southern Somalia's Lower Shabelle region, 30 kilometres south of Mogadishu.
"We have lost a number of our soldiers, and several others were injured," a senior military commander, Ahmed Yare, said.
The al-Qaeda-linked militants briefly seized Afgoye's police station and a military base, but were soon pushed back by army and peacekeeping reinforcements, Lower Shabelle governor Abdulkadir Mohamed Nur Sidii told local media.
"Our troops received reinforcements from the African Union and other Somali troops in the area and repelled the militants," Sidii said.
"The people of the town were sleeping when a heavy battle erupted," Afgoye resident Siraaji Yusuf said. "It was fierce fighting, and I saw three Somali military vehicles destroyed near the police station."
Al-Shabaab claimed responsibility for the attack on the pro-insurgent website Somalimemo, claiming it killed more than 20 Somali soldiers and police officers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 19 10:44:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Forty dead in Boko Haram attack in Niger</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/475f275d/sc/40/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C190Cforty0Edead0Eboko0Eharam0Eattack0Eniger/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Forty people have been killed in Boko Haram attacks on two Niger villages, with the attackers pillaging stores and burning homes.</Description>
        <MainBody>19 Jun 2015 - 6:47am
Forty dead in Boko Haram attack in Niger
The Nigerian military on patrol after flushing out Boko Haram Islamic militants from Michika, North East Nigeria, 19 March 2015 (EPA/STR)
Forty people have been killed in Boko Haram attacks on two Niger villages, with the attackers pillaging stores and burning homes.
Source:
0
The governor of the Diffa region in Niger says that an attack by the extremist group Boko Haram based in neighbouring Nigeria has killed 40 people in two villages.
Governor Yakouba Soumana Goah said on Thursday the attackers pillaged stores and burned homes in the early hours of the morning before withdrawing from the villages located near the border with Nigeria.
He added that the army went in pursuit of the attackers.
Boko Haram last attacked Niger in April and killed at least 58 people.
The Islamic group took control of a large swath of northeast Nigeria until a multinational force this year forced them out of towns and villages but it still engages in cross-border hit and run attacks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 19 09:03:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Sudan fighting kills 129 children</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/475f275e/sc/40/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C190Csouth0Esudan0Efighting0Ekills0E1290Echildren/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>UNICEF says 129 children were killed in fighting in South Sudan in May, with girls being raped and boys being castrated and left to bleed out.</Description>
        <MainBody>19 Jun 2015 - 6:26am
South Sudan fighting kills 129 children
UNICEF says 129 children were killed in fighting in South Sudan in May, with girls being raped and boys being castrated and left to bleed out.
Source:
0
The UN children's agency says at least 129 children were killed - with boys castrated and girls raped - during a government offensive last month in South Sudan.
UNICEF said the killings took place over three weeks in May in Unity state as the government battled rebels.
Speaking in New York on Wednesday, UNICEF Executive Director Anthony Lake said survivors reported that boys were castrated and left to bleed out, while girls were gang raped and killed.
South Sudanese military spokesman, Colonel Philip Aguer on Thursday questioned the credibility of the report, saying it is not in South Sudanese culture to commit such atrocities.
He called for full investigations, saying whoever is responsible must face justice.
South Sudan has been fighting rebels led by the former deputy president since December 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jun 16 14:37:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bashir leaves South Africa, avoids arrest</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637532/s/474315e8/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C160Cbashir0Eleaves0Esouth0Eafrica0Eavoids0Earrest/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Sudanese President Omar al-Bashir flew out of South Africa on Monday in defiance of a Pretoria court that later said he should have been arrested to face genocide charges at the International Criminal Court.</Description>
        <MainBody>16 Jun 2015 - 6:37am
Bashir leaves South Africa, avoids arrest
Sudanese president Omar al-Bashir at the opening session of the AU summit in Johannesburg, June 14, 2015. (AP Photo/Shiraaz Mohamed)
Sudanese President Omar al-Bashir flew out of South Africa on Monday in defiance of a Pretoria court that later said he should have been arrested to face genocide charges at the International Criminal Court.
By
Reuters
16 Jun 2015 - 6:37 AM UPDATED16Jun2015-6:37AM
Despite a legal order for him to stay in the country ahead of the ruling on his detention, the government let Bashir leave unhindered, with South Africa's ruling party accusing the ICC of being biased against Africans and "no longer useful".
Bashir has been indicted by the ICC over war crimes and crimes against humanity but South Africa gave him immunity along with all delegates attending an African Union summit in Johannesburg this week.
As an ICC signatory, South Africa was obliged to implement arrest warrants. The decision to let Bashir leave represented an affirmation of shifting diplomatic priorities for the government, with African interests trumping those of the West.
ADVERTISING
It also represented a blow for the Hague-based ICC, which has convicted just two minor African warlords since it started work in 2002 and has struggled to create accountability for those who are too powerful to be tried at home.
The veteran Sudanese leader flew out of the Waterkloof Air Base at around 1000 GMT, headed for Sudan's capital, Khartoum.
Hours later, judge Dunstan Mlambo found in favor of an application by a rights group calling for him to be detained, saying the failure to arrest him contravened the constitution.
"The respondents are forthwith compelled to take all reasonable steps to arrest President Bashir," Mlambo said.
Government lawyer William Mokhari said the home affairs department would be investigating Bashir's departure.
Bashir arrived in Khartoum to throngs of well-wishers and government officials inside the airport.
Wearing traditional white robes, Bashir waved his trademark cane greeting the cheering crowd in an open-topped vehicle. Waving the Sudanese flag, the crowd chanted God is Great and some carried pictures of Bashir with the banner 'Lion of Africa'.
Sudan's foreign minister Ibrahim Ghandour said Africa's enemies were behind the failed bid.
"The participation could have been normal and without a fuss, but Africa's enemies, Sudan's enemies and the enemies of peace-loving countries wanted to try and turn it into a drama, to prevent the president from important participations," Ghandour said.
Ghandour said the South African government had assured Sudan that Bashir's participation at the summit was a source of pride and that President Jacob Zuma had blamed opposition parties trying to embarrass Pretoria.
"This is a case of state sovereignty. Here we have a president elected and supported by his people. I don't have to point to the elections as I can simply point to this scene right here," he said referring to the boisterous crowd.
Bashir was re-elected in April in a vote boycotted by most of the opposition, thereby extending his quarter-century rule.
"LONG GAME"
The ruling provided fresh ammunition for Zuma's critics, who accused him of ignoring his own judiciary. The presidency and foreign ministry did not respond to requests for comment.
"It is completely unacceptable. The South African government has been complicit in assuring Mr Bashir is able to flee the country," Democratic Alliance Chief Whip John Steenhuisen told Reuters, calling for "heads to roll".
"Our international reputation lies in tatters," he added.
The ICC issued arrest warrants for Bashir in 2009 and 2010, accusing him of masterminding genocide and other atrocities in his campaign to crush a revolt in the Darfur region - a conflict that killed as many as 300,000 people, the United Nations says.
He has long rejected the court's authority, but the warrants have curtailed his ability to travel freely. Monday's ruling means that he will not be able to come back to South Africa.
ICC deputy prosecutor James Stewart said he was disappointed Bashir had managed to escape, but told Reuters he did not see it as a setback for the court, which was playing "a long game".
"I think that what happened over the past couple of days and in particular today, demonstrates that an ICC warrant of arrest actually means something and clearly the court in South Africa took that view," he said.
The US State Department said it was disappointed South Africa did not prevent Bashir from leaving Johannesburg.
Spokesman Jeff Rathke declined to say South Africa should have arrested Bashir but said "clearly, some action should have been taken".
The ICC and the U.N. criticized Pretoria for rolling out the red carpet for Bashir.
"The International Criminal Courts warrant for the arrest of President al-Bashir on charges of crimes against humanity and war crimes is a matter I take extremely seriously," U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon told reporters in Geneva.
"The authority of the ICC must be respected and its decision implemented," Ban said.
(Additional reporting by Peroshni Govender in Johannesburg, Tom Miles in Geneva, Yara Bayoumy, Ahmed Aboulenein and Omar Fahmy in Cairo and Anthony Deutsch in Amsterdam; Writing by Joe Brock; Editing by Crispian Balmer and Giles Elgood)
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
