<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sbs South America News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 19:45:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cat-astrophe averted: Pilot discovers stowaway cat mid-flight</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/4779d2ff/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C230Ccat0Eastrophe0Eaverted0Epilot0Ediscovers0Estowaway0Ecat0Emid0Eflight/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A video has emerged of a stowaway cat holding on for dear life onboard an open air flight in South America. And it’s fur real.</Description>
        <MainBody>A video has emerged of a stowaway cat holding on for dear life onboard an open air flight in South America. And its fur real.
By
SBS
23 Jun 2015 - 11:45 AM UPDATED23Jun2015-12:19PM
The incredible footage captures the moment South American pilot Romain Jantot realises he has an unexpected passenger, who was absent at his mandatory safety briefing and is not strapped down with a seatbelt.
After the initial shock, the pilot brings the presence of the thrill-seeking feline to the attention of his sole human passenger.
She looks very amused watching the cat cling on to the wing of the glider while the pilot lands the plane to safety.
Mr Jantot says it was A standard flight until [the incident] I still dont know if it got in after the pre-flight check or if I missed it. The cat is doing well, she is still our mascot.
The pilot has gato be careful next time to check the plane for other guests travelling without a ticket.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 16:50:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chilean grandmother &amp;#039;carried calcified foetus for 50 years&amp;#039;</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/4771bb5d/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C220Cchilean0Egrandmother0Ecarried0Ecalcified0Efoetus0E50A0Eyears/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Doctors have discovered a calcified foetus inside a 92-year-old woman in Chile.</Description>
        <MainBody>22 Jun 2015 - 1:30pm
Chilean grandmother 'carried calcified foetus for 50 years'
Doctors in Chile say that a woman has been carrying a calcified foetus for some 50 years.
Doctors have discovered a calcified foetus inside a 92-year-old woman in Chile.
By
SBS
22 Jun 2015 - 8:50 AM UPDATED22Jun2015-1:30PM
Estela Melendez says doctors told her decades ago her stomach pains were due toan abdominal tumour.
Local media reported the 92-year-old grandmother recently suffered a fall, and went to a hospital in SanAntoni, where doctors made the discovery.
X-ray tests revealed the presence of a foetus which weighed around 2 kilos.
Mrs Melendez said the large size was uncomfortable.
"I had no clothes to wear. I was very obese," she added.
The director of the hospitalwhich discovered thefoetussaid it appears to have survived into the third trimester.
Her son, Luis, denies that his mother was ever informed of the pregnancy.
"The doctor never told her she was pregnant," he told a local journalist.
A calcifiedfoetusis the result of a rare medical phenomena known as lithopedion where afoetusdoes not develop in the uterus but the abdomen.
Abdominal pregnancy reportedly occurs in every 11,000 pregnancies, of which only about 1.5 per cent develop into lithopedion.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 00:30:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>6.4-magnitude quake jolts Chile</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/476956e4/sc/31/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C20A0C640Emagnitude0Equake0Ejolts0Echile/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A 6.4-magnitude earthquake has hit the coast of central Chile.</Description>
        <MainBody>20 Jun 2015 - 5:07pm
6.4-magnitude quake jolts Chile
A picture made available on 10 June 2015 shows a general view of the Estadio Nacional stadium in Santiago, Chile. (EPA)
A 6.4-magnitude earthquake has hit the coast of central Chile.
Source:
There were no immediate reports of injuries or damage.
Saturday's quake struck about 75km off the port city of Talcahuano on the Bay of Concepcion.
Talcahuano hosts a key naval base and is the main industrial and fishing port in the region.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sat Jun 20 19:33:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colombia cops bust drug implants bid</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/47690dff/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C20A0Ccolombia0Ecops0Ebust0Edrug0Eimplants0Ebid/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police in Colombia have arrested a woman from Honduras with breast implants containing 1.5 kilograms of liquid cocaine.</Description>
        <MainBody>20 Jun 2015 - 2:02pm
Cops bust woman with breast implants containing 1.5 kilos of liquid cocaine
Police in Colombia have arrested a woman  with breast implants containing 1.5 kilograms of cocaine. (AAP)
Police in Colombia have arrested a woman from Honduras with breast implants containing 1.5 kilograms of liquid cocaine.
Source:
0
A Honduran woman has been arrested in the Colombian capital with breast implants containing 1.5 kilograms of liquid cocaine.
Colonel Diego Rosero, police commander at El Dorado international airport in Bogota, said security personnel found the size of the 22-year-old's breasts suspicious.
The suspect eventually confessed that implants with an unknown substance had been put inside her breasts during surgery in the central Colombian city of Pereira, and that she was supposed to take them to Barcelona, Spain.
The woman was taken to a hospital, where the cocaine was removed from her body.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 20 19:33:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cops bust woman with breast implants containing 1.5 kilos of liquid cocaine</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/4768ed93/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C20A0Ccops0Ebust0Ewoman0Ebreast0Eimplants0Econtaining0E150Ekilos0Eliquid0Ecocaine/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police in Colombia have arrested a woman from Honduras with breast implants containing 1.5 kilograms of liquid cocaine.</Description>
        <MainBody>20 Jun 2015 - 2:02pm
Cops bust woman with breast implants containing 1.5 kilos of liquid cocaine
Police in Colombia have arrested a woman  with breast implants containing 1.5 kilograms of cocaine. (AAP)
Police in Colombia have arrested a woman from Honduras with breast implants containing 1.5 kilograms of liquid cocaine.
Source:
0
A Honduran woman has been arrested in the Colombian capital with breast implants containing 1.5 kilograms of liquid cocaine.
Colonel Diego Rosero, police commander at El Dorado international airport in Bogota, said security personnel found the size of the 22-year-old's breasts suspicious.
The suspect eventually confessed that implants with an unknown substance had been put inside her breasts during surgery in the central Colombian city of Pereira, and that she was supposed to take them to Barcelona, Spain.
The woman was taken to a hospital, where the cocaine was removed from her body.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 21 13:53:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colombian mudslide death toll rises to 83</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/467f88a6/sc/40/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A50C210Ccolombian0Emudslide0Edeath0Etoll0Erises0E83/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Authorities say the death toll in the Colombian mudslide has risen to 83, with the number of people still missing unclear.</Description>
        <MainBody>21 May 2015 - 8:12am
Colombian mudslide death toll rises to 83
The death toll in a flood and mudslide that ravaged a rural area in Colombia has risen to 83. (AAP)
Authorities say the death toll in the Colombian mudslide has risen to 83, with the number of people still missing unclear.
Source:
The death toll in a flood and mudslide that ravaged a rural area in north-western Colombia has risen to 83.
Of those, 54 have been identified, in some cases using DNA, forensic authorities said on Wednesday.
The Liboriana stream overflowed with mud and debris and swept away many victims while they were asleep early on Monday.
Rescue teams remained active in a 40-kilometre perimeter around Las Margaritas, in the municipality of Salgar, about 560 km north-west of Bogota. The authorities believe more bodies may have been dragged away by the rushing water.
About 50 people had been treated in local hospitals for their injuries, and authorities in Antioquia province estimated 800 people had suffered property damage.
It's not clear how many people are still missing. Authorities have mentioned 150 are unaccounted for, but some may have already been confirmed as dead.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 21 13:50:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chilean spy amasses 500 years in prison</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/467f88a7/sc/24/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A50C210Cchilean0Espy0Eamasses0E50A0A0Eyears0Eprison/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Eighty-six-year-old General Manuel Contreras has racked up 500 years in prison sentences as the former chief of a fear spy agency in Chile.</Description>
        <MainBody>21 May 2015 - 6:00am
Chilean spy amasses 500 years in prison
Eighty-six-year-old General Manuel Contreras has racked up 500 years in prison sentences as the former chief of a fear spy agency in Chile.
Source:
The former chief of the feared spy agency responsible for kidnapping, torturing and killing thousands during Chile's military dictatorship has accumulated 500 years in prison sentences.
Eighty-six-year-old General Manuel Contreras has been serving a combined sentence for crimes against humanity.
On Wednesday, the Supreme Court sentenced him to 15 more years for the 1974 killing of Ana Maria Puga and Alejandro de la Barra Villarroel.
Four former spy agency members were also sentenced for the killing of the couple.
After the 1973 military coup led by General Augusto Pinochet, Contreras created and commanded the DINA spy agency and became the most powerful and feared figure of the dictatorship after Pinochet.
According to an official report, 40,018 people were imprisoned, tortured or slain during the 1973-90 dictatorship.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun May 17 16:49:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chilean teen dies after public euthanasia campaign</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/466102e1/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A50C170Cchilean0Eteen0Edies0Eafter0Epublic0Eeuthanasia0Ecampaign/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Chilean teenage girl who made a YouTube video in an unsuccessful plea to end her life, has died from lung problems caused by cystic fibrosis.</Description>
        <MainBody>17 May 2015 - 10:22am
Chilean teen dies after public euthanasia campaign
File image of the late Valentina Maureira taking a photo of herself with President Michelle Bachelet, at the Catholic University hospital in Santiago, Chile on February 28, 2015.
A Chilean teenage girl who made a YouTube video in an unsuccessful plea to end her life, has died from lung problems caused by cystic fibrosis.
Source:
Hundreds of people have attended the funeral of a Chilean teenage girl who made a YouTube video in an unsuccessful plea to end her life.
Fourteen-year-old Valentina Maureira died on Thursday from lung problems caused by cystic fibrosis.
In February Valentina posted a heart-wrenching YouTube video in which she asked Chilean President Michelle Bachelet to allow her to end her suffering.
Her brother had died of cystic fibrosis when he was six.
Bachelet visited the girl but said she could not approve her request to be euthanised.
Valentina later changed her mind after meeting people who responded to her video.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun May 17 16:49:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chile teen dies after euthanasia plea</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/466084c6/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A50C170Cchile0Eteen0Edies0Eafter0Eeuthanasia0Eplea/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Chilean teenage girl who made a YouTube video in an unsuccessful plea to end her life, has died from lung problems caused by cystic fibrosis.</Description>
        <MainBody>17 May 2015 - 10:22am
Chilean teen dies after public euthanasia campaign
File image of the late Valentina Maureira taking a photo of herself with President Michelle Bachelet, at the Catholic University hospital in Santiago, Chile on February 28, 2015.
A Chilean teenage girl who made a YouTube video in an unsuccessful plea to end her life, has died from lung problems caused by cystic fibrosis.
Source:
Hundreds of people have attended the funeral of a Chilean teenage girl who made a YouTube video in an unsuccessful plea to end her life.
Fourteen-year-old Valentina Maureira died on Thursday from lung problems caused by cystic fibrosis.
In February Valentina posted a heart-wrenching YouTube video in which she asked Chilean President Michelle Bachelet to allow her to end her suffering.
Her brother had died of cystic fibrosis when he was six.
Bachelet visited the girl but said she could not approve her request to be euthanised.
Valentina later changed her mind after meeting people who responded to her video.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun May 17 01:38:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>54 dead in Brazil bus crash: Rousseff</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/446b79d4/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A30C160C540Edead0Ebrazil0Ebus0Ecrash0Erousseff/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The death toll following a horror bus crash into a ravine in Brazil's south has climbed to 54.</Description>
        <MainBody>0
The death toll from a tour bus's horrific plunge into a densely wooded ravine in southern Brazil has risen to 54.
The vehicle went off a twisting mountain road on Saturday and crashed 400 metres to the bottom of the ravine, where it lay a twisted mass of metal.
Firefighters pulled the victims from the wreckage despite the difficult terrain and the bodies were taken to a morgue, officials say.
"It is with sadness that I learned the news of the death of 54 people in a bus accident in the Sierra Dona Francisca," President Dilma Rousseff said in a statement issued on Sunday.
"In this hour of pain and suffering, I want to extend my condolences to the families and friends who lost their loved ones."
Among the dead are the driver and eight children.
Ten people were taken to hospital but their conditions were not immediately known.
A government official in Santa Catarina said the vehicle was likely carrying 59 people. The bus was supposed to be carrying 50 people, authorities said.
Several ambulances and a helicopter were dispatched to the area and recovery efforts were set to resume on Sunday afternoon.
Authorities said on Saturday the chance of finding any more survivors was slim.
Investigators will study the crash site and then the bus will be removed from the area.
According to witnesses, the driver lost control on a downhill turn.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed May 13 18:38:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Haiti fights to end child adoption rackets</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/46427a89/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A50C130Chaiti0Efights0Eend0Echild0Eadoption0Erackets/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Haitian government is launching a public awareness campaign to educate Haitian parents about dodgy international adoption schemes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Haiti fights to end child adoption rackets
Haiti tightens adoption rules as children disappear
The Haitian government is launching a public awareness campaign to educate Haitian parents about dodgy international adoption schemes.
By
0
Haiti is cracking down on international adoptions in a bid to warn poor Haitians about orphanage recruiters roaming the countryside with money or false promises.
Armed with megaphones, women have been taking to Haiti's streets, warning parents in rural areas about the dangers of handing their children over for adoption.
Since the devastating 2010 earthquake, serious flaws in the country's adoption system have been exposed.
There have been reports of Haitians putting their children in orphanages for temporary stays, only to find their children had been removed when they returned to collect them.
Navilia Fontulus says her two-year-old grandson Edson spent three months in an orphanage after a recruiter paid his mother to take him away.
"I thought I was going to lose him, because he was so small," Ms Fontulus says. "After three months, we asked for him to be given back into the hands of his parents, because there have been people who gave up their children over 12 or 18 years ago and they've never found them again, not even a photo of their children. I thought I had lost him."
Since April last year, the Haitian government has sought to overhaul the country's adoption system.
It prohibited private adoptions, restricted the accreditation of foreign adoption agencies and set a limit on how many children can be adopted internationally per year.
The govenment also introduced regulations to address long-time complaints that parents were often pressured or manipulated into giving up children without understanding the ramifications.
"We are all aware that, in the past, there were a lot of issues in the process of having children adopted," says Kristine Peduto, who heads the child protection unit in Haiti for the United Nations Children Agency, UNICEF. "For example, corruption, lack of regulation by the state, et cetera."
Ms Peduto says it will take time for the changes to fully take hold, though.
"We know that moving away from the old system to have a country fully compliant with the Hague Convention (on International Adoption) will take time, and it demands tremendous effort from everyone at each step to ensure that all processes are fully respected."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat May 09 15:01:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uruguyan judge denies abortion order for 11yo</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/4624ca90/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A50C0A90Curuguyan0Ejudge0Edenies0Eabortion0Eorder0E11yo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A mentally disabled 11-year-old girl will be able to keep her baby, after a Uruguayan judge ruled the courts don't have the authority to order an abortion.</Description>
        <MainBody>9 May 2015 - 8:47am
Uruguyan judge denies abortion order for 11yo
A mentally disabled 11-year-old girl will be able to keep her baby, after a Uruguayan judge ruled the courts don't have the authority to order an abortion.
Source:
0
A judge in Uruguay has ruled it is not up to the courts to decide whether an 11-year-old mentally disabled girl has an abortion even though her mother sought its authorisation.
Judge Raquel Gini says the girl wants to "continue with the pregnancy" and to maintain her relationship with the 41-year-old man who is accused of sexually abusing her and is now imprisoned.
A court spokesman said on Friday that the judge determined that under Chilean law "a decision should be reached between the girl, her mother and the doctors".
The judge said doctors found the pregnancy poses no medical risks to the girl, although she lacks the ability to fully understand her situation.
In light of the court's ruling, the mother was expected to drop efforts to seek an abortion.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat May 09 15:01:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge refuses to order abortion for 11yo</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/46248540/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A50C0A90Cjudge0Erefuses0Eorder0Eabortion0E11yo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A mentally disabled 11-year-old girl will be able to keep her baby, after a Uruguayan judge ruled the courts don't have the authority to order an abortion.</Description>
        <MainBody>9 May 2015 - 8:47am
Uruguyan judge denies abortion order for 11yo
A mentally disabled 11-year-old girl will be able to keep her baby, after a Uruguayan judge ruled the courts don't have the authority to order an abortion.
Source:
0
A judge in Uruguay has ruled it is not up to the courts to decide whether an 11-year-old mentally disabled girl has an abortion even though her mother sought its authorisation.
Judge Raquel Gini says the girl wants to "continue with the pregnancy" and to maintain her relationship with the 41-year-old man who is accused of sexually abusing her and is now imprisoned.
A court spokesman said on Friday that the judge determined that under Chilean law "a decision should be reached between the girl, her mother and the doctors".
The judge said doctors found the pregnancy poses no medical risks to the girl, although she lacks the ability to fully understand her situation.
In light of the court's ruling, the mother was expected to drop efforts to seek an abortion.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat May 09 14:47:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>About 20 sei whales beached along Chile</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/46244f0d/sc/32/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A50C0A90Cabout0E20A0Esei0Ewhales0Ebeached0Ealong0Echile/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>More than 20 endangered whales have been founded beached on the Chilean coast.</Description>
        <MainBody>About 20 sei whales beached along Chile
More than 20 endangered whales have been founded beached on the Chilean coast.
Source:
0
Chilean officials say about two dozen endangered sei whales have been found beached along the South American country's southern coast.
Foreign scientists discovered the whales on the Gulf of Penas on Friday and reported them to the National Fisheries Service.
While a statement from government officials said there were around 20 whales, the scientists said they counted more than 30.
It's not unusual to find beached whales along Chile's 4,200km coast. However, it's the first time sei whales have been found beached in the country, the Fisheries Service said.
The International Union for Conservation of Natures lists the sei as an endangered species. Adults can be longer than 15 metres and weigh 20 tons or more.
Officials said they were trying to determine what caused the whales to wind up on the beach.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Apr 15 21:18:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Streetlamps from old soda bottles making streets safer for women</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/45667117/sc/4/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A40C150Cstreetlamps0Eold0Esoda0Ebottles0Emaking0Estreets0Esafer0Ewomen/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Low-cost street lights are brightening up public spaces and creating a safer environment for women in Bogotá, Colombia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Streetlamps from old soda bottles making streets safer for women
Student volunteers erect a lamp. (Jack Aldwinckle/Quartz)
Low-cost street lights are brightening up public spaces and creating a safer environment for women in Bogot, Colombia.
Source:
0
In the tiny barrio of San Luis, perched precipitously on the hills above Bogot, a hundred university students are hard at work. Split into 10groups, they glue, drill and screw thingstogether to make 50low-cost street lights.
The lights beauty lies in theirsimplicity: A3-watt LED lamp is connected to a controller and a battery pack, which is powered by a small solar panel. Thelight fixtures protective casingisan old plastic soda bottle. Each lampcosts around 176,000 Colombian pesos ($70) to build, and nothing to run. Parts are sourced locally and the battery can power the lamp for three consecutive nights without charging. Once completed, the students install the lights throughout the neighbourhood, brightening dimly lit alleyways and dark clearings.
Its the latest project from Liter of Light , an NGO which illuminates communities in the developing world. Illac Diaz , the organisations Filipino founder, was a student at MIT when he came across the  Moser lamp , invented by a Brazilian mechanic, Alfredo Moser. He had found that by filling an old plastic bottle with water and inserting it into peoples roofs you could refract sunlight into their homes, creating a light with a brightness equivalent to a 55w electric bulb. Inspired by the design, Diaz returned to the Philippines in 2011 to found Liter of Light. So far it has lit up 28,000 homes in Manila alone and many thousands more across the world. Last year it went a step further, developing solar-powered street lights that can brighten public spaces too.
Completed street lamps with solar panels on top.(Jack Aldwinckle/Quartz)
What makes Liter of Lights approach stand out is its open-source, easily replicated technology. In the past, efforts to bring light to remote communities have been hampered by the cost of importing expensive parts. During an emergency if you want a thousand lights, it takes five months to order them from China or India and another two or three months to bring it over by ship, says Diaz. Once installed, lights are prone to break after a year or two, and without someone on hand to repair them, the expensive technology becomes redundant.
Liter of Light is trying to devolve and simplify the process. It share its designs with everyone, publishing how-to videos on YouTube that enable communities to build their own lights. The parts are cheap and the circuit board can be made using a marker pen . The NGO now has 53 chapters around the world, who between them have installed over 250,000 bottle lights and over 15,000 night lights. Each chapter is self-sufficient: Illac Diaz had only met the Colombian team once before and has never met the organisers in Ethiopia.
The neighbourhood of San Luis is ideal for the project. Located in a dark, forgotten part of Bogot, its home to around 16,000 residents, many of whom arrived after being forcibly displaced by Colombias civil war. Their homes were built without planning permission and their families get little in the way of state attention or public services. Unemployment is high and the dark alleyways are a magnet for drug traffickersmicro-traffickers. Public lighting is scarce or non-existent, posing a particular threat to women and girls, many of whom face sexual harassment or worse. We need to create a safer environment for women and girls who live in these places, says Diaz. Street lights are the first step in creating a safer community.
Darkness doesnt just cause problems in Colombia. According to the UN , 1.5 billion people around the world have to make do either with very poor quality light or no light at all. There are 1.3 billion who rely on kerosene lamps which emit toxic fumes, causing respiratory illnesses such as asthma, bronchitis and pneumonia. Inhaling kerosene smoke is equivalent to smoking four packets of cigarettes a day and kills an estimated 1.5 million people each year.
The philosophy is to spread lamps out illuminate a wide area rather than concentrate them in a few spots. (Jack Aldwinckle/Quartz)
A lack of light also stunts education. Children who have to work to earn money for their families during the dayas many do in poorer countriescant study without light in the evenings. Unesco is calling 2015 the International Year of Light in an effort to draw attention to the issue.
As well as the new technology, Liter of Light also brings a different philosophy to street lighting. It installs more lights across a wider area rather than bunching a few bright lights in one central location, such as a town square. The organization says this approach reduces crime by 60-70%.
We put them in front of shops, so people can get more sales and see whats happening in the street. says Diaz. Instead of bigger, brighter lights we prefer smaller, cheaper ones. That particularly helps women. As developing countries establish 24/7 economies, women are an increasingly active part of the workforce and are especially vulnerable when commuting after dark.
As well as tackling crime, public lighting can also make a big difference in the aftermath of a natural disaster. When Typhoon Haiyan battered the Philippines in November 2013, Liter of Light lit up over 2,000 homes in the some of the hardest-hit areas. In Pakistan last year a hundred street lights were installed at the UNs Jalozai refugee camp in Pakistan, supporting 10,000 families who had fled the Afghan war. The camp is due to receive another 450 lights this year. In Egypt, the NGO is teaming up with Pepsi to light 35 schools in an effort to alleviate the blackouts associated with the countrys energy crisis .
Pepsi is also helping to raise funds for the organisation more generally. It recently teamed up with the designer Nicola Formichetti , who made a luminous dress made out of plastic bottles in an effort to shine a light on those who live in darkness. As part of its new marketing drive, the company has also promised to donate a dollar to Liter of Light every time someone includes the hashtag #PepsiChallenge on Instagram, Facebook, Twitter or YouTube.
That could give extra fizz to the programme in Latin America, which is already growing very quickly. In Colombia, 14 locations have already been illuminated and there are plans to install another 2,000 street lights across the country in 2015. The organisation also hope to expand the programme to Mexico, Peru and Brazil. Across the world, Liter of Light has pledged to install a million new lights this year.

This article was originally published on Quartz . Click here to view the original.  All rights reserved. Distributed by Tribune Content Agency.
This article was originally published on Quartz .  All rights reserved. Distributed by Tribune Content Agency .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Mar 31 12:05:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Death toll in Chile floods rises to 18</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/44f52460/sc/32/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A30C310Cdeath0Etoll0Echile0Efloods0Erises0E18/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Several of the 33 Chilean miners who were trapped underground in 2010 have lost their homes in floods in the same region.</Description>
        <MainBody>31 Mar 2015 - 2:36pm
Death toll in Chile floods rises to 18
An undated photograph provided by Chilean Navy shows members of Marine Corps squad of Chilean Navy during cleaning works at Tal Tal locality, 1200 km. at northern Santiago de Chile, Chile. (EPA/CHILEAN NAVY)
Several of the 33 Chilean miners who were trapped underground in 2010 have lost their homes in floods in the same region.
Source:
0
At least 18 people have been killed in flash floods that hit a normally arid region of northern Chile last week, and about the same number remain missing.
The latest death toll from the devastating floods was released after six more bodies were found late Sunday and Monday, as rescue workers continued dealing with the aftermath of the torrential rains in Atacama region, home to the world's driest desert.
Chilean President Michelle Bachelet had warned at the weekend that the situation in the area was "bleak" and that the death toll was likely to rise.
Those who lost their homes in the floods included several of the 33 miners who were trapped underground in the same region for more than two months in 2010, then rescued in an operation that captured worldwide attention.
Rescued miners Ariel Ticona, Esteban Rojas, Victor Segovia and Victor Zamora all lost their houses to the raging floodwaters in small mining towns in the Atacama interior.
Ticona, Rojas and Segovia had initially been reported missing, but the leader of the group that survived the mine collapse ordeal, Luis Urzua, said they had been located.
"Physically they're fine, but ... they lost everything," he told AFP.
"The region is going to take a long time to recover. It's like a tsunami hit us."
The downpour began late on Tuesday and lashed the area for hours, turning riverbeds that had been dry for years into torrents.
The interior ministry declared a state of emergency on Wednesday and sent in the military to maintain order and help with the cleanup effort.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Mar 31 06:36:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>17 killed, 20 missing after Chile floods</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/44f31eff/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A30C310C170Ekilled0E20A0Emissing0Eafter0Echile0Efloods/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Last week's heavy rains in Chile, which swelled rivers and led to flash-flooding, have killed 17 people and left a further 20 still missing.</Description>
        <MainBody>31 Mar 2015 - 2:36pm
Death toll in Chile floods rises to 18
An undated photograph provided by Chilean Navy shows members of Marine Corps squad of Chilean Navy during cleaning works at Tal Tal locality, 1200 km. at northern Santiago de Chile, Chile. (EPA/CHILEAN NAVY)
Several of the 33 Chilean miners who were trapped underground in 2010 have lost their homes in floods in the same region.
Source:
0
At least 18 people have been killed in flash floods that hit a normally arid region of northern Chile last week, and about the same number remain missing.
The latest death toll from the devastating floods was released after six more bodies were found late Sunday and Monday, as rescue workers continued dealing with the aftermath of the torrential rains in Atacama region, home to the world's driest desert.
Chilean President Michelle Bachelet had warned at the weekend that the situation in the area was "bleak" and that the death toll was likely to rise.
Those who lost their homes in the floods included several of the 33 miners who were trapped underground in the same region for more than two months in 2010, then rescued in an operation that captured worldwide attention.
Rescued miners Ariel Ticona, Esteban Rojas, Victor Segovia and Victor Zamora all lost their houses to the raging floodwaters in small mining towns in the Atacama interior.
Ticona, Rojas and Segovia had initially been reported missing, but the leader of the group that survived the mine collapse ordeal, Luis Urzua, said they had been located.
"Physically they're fine, but ... they lost everything," he told AFP.
"The region is going to take a long time to recover. It's like a tsunami hit us."
The downpour began late on Tuesday and lashed the area for hours, turning riverbeds that had been dry for years into torrents.
The interior ministry declared a state of emergency on Wednesday and sent in the military to maintain order and help with the cleanup effort.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Mar 30 22:36:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French probe into Argentina chopper crash</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/4448ee48/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A30C120Cfrench0Eprobe0Eargentina0Echopper0Ecrash/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Investigators are continuing to comb the wreckage of two helicopters that crashed in Argentina while filming a French reality TV show.</Description>
        <MainBody>12 Mar 2015 - 8:14am
French probe into Argentina chopper crash
A civil aviation accident investigator stands at the site of the wreckage of one of two helicopters that collided in midair in Argentina (AAP)
Investigators are continuing to comb the wreckage of two helicopters that crashed in Argentina while filming a French reality TV show.
Source:
0
A team of French investigators has arrived in Argentina to probe a twin helicopter crash that killed 10 people during a reality TV shoot, including three of France's best-known sports stars.
The officials from France's air accident investigation authority, the BEA, held meetings at the French embassy on Wednesday after arriving in Buenos Aires.
They were then due to travel to the crash site in the northwestern province of La Rioja, where Argentine investigators continued combing through the charred wreckage.
Monday's crash killed Olympic champion swimmer Camille Muffat, yachtswoman Florence Arthaud and Olympic boxer Alexis Vastine, as well as five French TV crew members and two Argentine pilots.
The two BEA investigators were accompanied by a representative of Airbus Helicopters, the company that made the two Eurocopters involved in the crash, and another from engine manufacturer Turbomeca.
The French consul in Argentina, Raphael Trannoy, was already in La Rioja to meet with judicial officials leading the investigation and visit the morgue where the victims' badly burnt remains were being identified.
In Paris, several hundred people from the French sporting world paid an emotional tribute to the three late stars.
Pictures of the trio, covered with flowers, were laid out at the National Institute of Sport and Physical Education, France's leading sports institute, whose head said it was like a "death in the family".
The victims - and five other sports stars including former France and Arsenal footballer Sylvain Wiltord - were contestants in the reality TV series Dropped, which involved sports personalities testing their survival skills in inhospitable environments.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Mar 29 01:45:31 EET 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens killed in extreme storms in Ecuador and Chile</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/44e582cd/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A30C280Cdozens0Ekilled0Eextreme0Estorms0Eecuador0Eand0Echile/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of people have been killed during storms which brought intense rains, landslides and high waves to Ecuador and Chile, with many more missing.</Description>
        <MainBody>29 Mar 2015 - 8:16am
Dozens killed in extreme storms in Ecuador and Chile
Chilean soldiers help a group of people that were crossing the river flow formed after torrential floods and rains in Charaal, 1000 km north of Santiago de Chile, Chile, 27 March 2015.
Dozens of people have been killed during storms which brought intense rains, landslides and high waves to Ecuador and Chile, with many more missing.
Source:
0
The death toll has reached three dozen and is expected to rise in extreme storms along Pacific coastal regions of South America, reports say.
At least 25 people had died during intense rains, landslides and high waves in Ecuador, officials said on Saturday.
Lightning strikes on a police school in the capital Quito injured 52 people, 15 of whom required hospitalisation.
The extreme weather also caused heavy economic damage to farmland and the fishing industry, including boats smashed against rocks and piers, reports said.
In the northern Chilean desert region of Atacama, rare heavy storms caused flash floods and mudslides that killed at least 11 people and destroyed many homes and roads.
"As we go on opening up the routes, there could be a rising death toll, said Ricardo Toro, director of the Office of National Emergencies.
He said there were at least 19 people officially listed as missing, and more than 5000 had been displaced by the destruction.
Local officials also warned that faults in upstream dams could be releasing toxic material from desert mines including arsenic and mercury down on inhabited areas.
They demanded help from the central government to remove tons of mud that accumulated in coastal towns, for fear that it contains dangerous heavy metals.
"That must be done as soon as possible," said Senator Alejandro Guillier, who represents the region around Antofagasta port.
The 700 kilometre-long Atacama desert region between the Andes range and the sea is considered to be one of the driest places on Earth.
"This is the most anomalous event that has happened here," local meteorologist Anthony Sagliani told state television.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun Mar 29 01:45:31 EET 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens killed in South American storms, many missing</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637534/s/44e57076/sc/40/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A30C280Cdozens0Ekilled0Esouth0Eamerican0Estorms0Emany0Emissing/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of people have been killed during extreme storms in Ecuador and Chile.</Description>
        <MainBody>29 Mar 2015 - 8:16am
Dozens killed in extreme storms in Ecuador and Chile
Chilean soldiers help a group of people that were crossing the river flow formed after torrential floods and rains in Charaal, 1000 km north of Santiago de Chile, Chile, 27 March 2015.
Dozens of people have been killed during storms which brought intense rains, landslides and high waves to Ecuador and Chile, with many more missing.
Source:
0
The death toll has reached three dozen and is expected to rise in extreme storms along Pacific coastal regions of South America, reports say.
At least 25 people had died during intense rains, landslides and high waves in Ecuador, officials said on Saturday.
Lightning strikes on a police school in the capital Quito injured 52 people, 15 of whom required hospitalisation.
The extreme weather also caused heavy economic damage to farmland and the fishing industry, including boats smashed against rocks and piers, reports said.
In the northern Chilean desert region of Atacama, rare heavy storms caused flash floods and mudslides that killed at least 11 people and destroyed many homes and roads.
"As we go on opening up the routes, there could be a rising death toll, said Ricardo Toro, director of the Office of National Emergencies.
He said there were at least 19 people officially listed as missing, and more than 5000 had been displaced by the destruction.
Local officials also warned that faults in upstream dams could be releasing toxic material from desert mines including arsenic and mercury down on inhabited areas.
They demanded help from the central government to remove tons of mud that accumulated in coastal towns, for fear that it contains dangerous heavy metals.
"That must be done as soon as possible," said Senator Alejandro Guillier, who represents the region around Antofagasta port.
The 700 kilometre-long Atacama desert region between the Andes range and the sea is considered to be one of the driest places on Earth.
"This is the most anomalous event that has happened here," local meteorologist Anthony Sagliani told state television.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
