<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sbs Asia Pacific News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 10:01:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rainbow Warrior bombing, 30 years on</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47fb4228/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C10A0Crainbow0Ewarrior0Ebombing0E30A0Eyears/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Friday marks 30 years since the Rainbow Warrior was bombed in New Zealand and Greenpeace is using the anniversary to celebrate acts of courage and protest.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rainbow Warrior bombing, 30 years on
Friday marks 30 years since the Rainbow Warrior was bombed in New Zealand. (AAP)
Friday marks 30 years since the Rainbow Warrior was bombed in New Zealand and Greenpeace is using the anniversary to celebrate acts of courage and protest.
Source:
AAP
10 Jul 2015 - 2:01 AM UPDATED53MINSAGO
Sometimes Bunny McDiarmid can remember everything about the bombing of the Rainbow Warrior in vivid detail.
Other times it can seem a very long time ago.
Ms McDiarmid had been a deckhand on the Greenpeace vessel before two French agents slipped into Auckland's Waitemata Harbour under the cover of darkness on July 10, 1985 to attach two bombs to its hull.
The blast left Portuguese-Dutch photographer Fernando Pereira dead and the New Zealand government and public reeling.
Ms McDiarmid - now the outgoing head of Greenpeace New Zealand - was among the tight-knit group of activists who had embarked on campaigns in the Pacific to protest against French nuclear testing and draw attention to the terrible legacy it left on the people, the land and the ocean.
When she thinks back to the bombing 30 years ago, she recalls just how shocking it was.
"It was very, very hard to comprehend that it had happened, particularly because we lost Fernando," Ms McDiarmid told AAP.
"It was shocking, not only for Greenpeace - it was shocking for New Zealand, it was shocking for New Zealanders."
That shock did not fade in the months that followed as the extent of the French government's involvement was revealed.
While much attention is always focused on the bombing and its political fallout, Ms McDiarmid says Greenpeace wants to use this anniversary as a chance to celebrate acts of courage and protest.
"Much of New Zealand has been defined by our activism, whether it was women getting the vote, or Bastion Point, or a nuclear free New Zealand," she said.
It is that activist streak - and the need for people to continue to have the courage to speak out to effect social change - that connects the events of 30 years ago with today.
Ms McDiarmid thinks the Rainbow Warrior is a symbol that inspires hope in that sense.
"Sometimes just raising your voice is a big thing," she said.
"It can be a really incredible act of courage, depending on where you are, or who you are, or what the context is.
"Just opening your mouth can be incredibly significant - you can risk your life, it can change the course of history."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 10:00:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd to appeal sentence</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47fb422c/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C10A0Cacdc0Edrummer0Ephil0Erudd0Eappeal0Esentence/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Craig Tuck, the lawyer for AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd, says he's filed an appeal against his client's home detention sentence in New Zealand.</Description>
        <MainBody>AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd to appeal sentence
AC/DC's former drummer Phil Rudd is appealing his home detention sentence in New Zealand. (AAP)
Craig Tuck, the lawyer for AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd, says he's filed an appeal against his client's home detention sentence in New Zealand.
Source:
10 Jul 2015 - 2:00 AM UPDATED51MINSAGO
AC/DC's estranged drummer Phil Rudd is appealing his home detention sentence in New Zealand.
The 61-year-old drummer was sentenced at Tauranga District Court on Thursday to eight months' home detention, after he earlier admitted charges of threatening to kill and possessing methamphetamine and cannabis.
Rudd will be electronically monitored at his Tauranga waterside mansion and must also complete a rehabilitation programme.
Judge Thomas Ingram told Rudd there "was nowhere to hide" and he would be jailed if he was found with any traces of drugs or alcohol in his system.
But Rudd's lawyer Craig Tuck confirmed to AAP on Thursday evening that he's filed an appeal against the sentence.
Mr Tuck had argued for a discharge without conviction, saying a conviction would leave Rudd unable to travel to Japan, Canada and the US with the band resulting in the loss of tens of millions of dollars.
Mr Tuck said Rudd's actions were the result of methamphetamine psychosis.
But Judge Ingram said Rudd had been discharged twice before, on assault and cannabis charges, and there was no evidence to suggest he was with the band anymore.
The judge was not convinced Rudd's drumming was integral to the AC/DC sound.
"Queen replaced Freddie Mercury," Judge Ingram said.
AC/DC's global Rock or Bust tour continues without Rudd, with the band confirming Chris Slade will be in the drummer's seat when it plays in Australia and New Zealand later this year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:49:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AFP tracking pro-IS pilots: report</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47f5f3d5/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cafp0Etracking0Epro0Epilots0Ereport/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Australian police have been gathering intelligence on two Indonesian pilots who appear to have been radicalised by pro-Islamic State elements, a report says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Australian police have been gathering intelligence on two Indonesian pilots who appear to have been radicalised by pro-Islamic State elements, a report says.
Source:
AAP
9 Jul 2015 - 12:49 PM UPDATEDYESTERDAY5:54PM
Australian Federal Police are monitoring two Indonesian pilots who appear to have been influenced by pro-Islamic State elements, on concerns they may pose a security threat, an intelligence website says.
The apparent radicalisation of the two pilots - which SBS cannot name for legal reasons - was detailed in a March 18 operational intelligence report compiled by the AFP and obtained by website The Intercept .
The AFP report - marked "for official use only" - analyses Facebook posts by the two pilots that appear to support IS.
The Intercept reports that 'pilot A' formerly worked for AirAsia Indonesia, while Premiair says 'pilot B' ceased working for them on June 1.
'Pilot A' graduated from the AirAsia academy in 2010 and flew international and domestic routes, the intelligence report states.
He began posting material indicating his support for IS from September 2014 - posts which 'pilot B' "liked".
The AFP also noted that 'pilot A' had commented on the page of Heri Kustyanto, who it's believed left his Indonesian family to fight with IS in Syria or Iraq.
At the time of the report, 'pilot A' was active on Facebook, was befriending radicals, and listed his current city as Raqqa, Syria.
The AFP report says 'pilot B', meanwhile, lives in Bogor, near Jakarta, and was a pilot for the Indonesian Navy before Garuda and Premiair.
He had posted photos of trips around the world, including to Australia, but by December 2014 was posting pro-Islamic State material.
His friends list included many military and commercial pilots.
The report concluded that radicalised pilots were an obvious threat, "as witnessed by past global events" and noted that a recent edition of the al-Qaeda magazine had encouraged aviation attacks.
Both men were trained pilots with contacts in the industry, it said.
The AFP distributed the report to partners in Turkey, Jordan, London, the US and Europol, The Intercept reported.
In a statement, the AFP said it did not comment on matters of intelligence.
"The AFP maintains strong relationships with its domestic and foreign law enforcement partners to ensure the ongoing safety of Australians both within Australia and abroad," it said.
The Intercept was initially created to report on documents provided by NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:54:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why China’s stock market is tanking</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47f4a7d1/sc/24/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cwhy0Echinas0Estock0Emarket0Etanking/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A guide to understanding the sell-off and its possible impact.</Description>
        <MainBody>9 Jul 2015 - 8:04pm
Why Chinas stock market is tanking
A stock investor in a brokerage house in Fuyang in central China's Anhui province, 8 July 2015. (EPA/AN MING CHINA OUT)
A guide to understanding the sell-off and its possible impact.
By
Los Angeles Times
9 Jul 2015 - 8:54 AM UPDATEDYESTERDAY8:04PM
Stock prices in China have plummeted in the last month , raising concern about the outlook for the world's second-largest economy and the spillover effect on global markets.
As the world focused on Greece's debt woes in recent weeks, the rout in the Chinese stock market caught some by surprise. In hindsight, though, a reversal was not unexpected given the astonishing run-up in Chinese share prices.
Here's a guide to understanding the sell-off and its possible impact:
Just how bad is China's market turmoil?
It's severe. The market's benchmark indicator, the Shanghai Composite Index, tumbled nearly 6% Wednesday and now has plunged 32% since hitting a record high June 12. That means nearly one-third of the market's total value has been wiped out. Market volatility isn't new in China, but this decline has been pronounced.
What led up to the collapse?
China's stock market displayed many of the signs that it had reached a speculative bubble. A year ago, the Shanghai index stood at 2,038.61. It then more than doubled over the next 12 months, reaching 5,166.35 on June 12.
Stocks kept rising despite a number of red flags, including a slowdown in China's economy and the fact that share prices had become exceptionally rich compared with many of their companies' underlying earnings.
One reason: A growing number of working-class Chinese families bought stocks to cash in on the rally and often did so by buying on margin, a term for borrowing money and using the stocks as collateral.
Has the drop affected other markets?
It has rattled some stock exchanges elsewhere, mostly in Hong Kong and other Asian markets, but seems to have had a limited effect on U.S. stock markets so far. Wall Streets benchmark Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index is down about 2% in the last month.
China's sell-off has been felt in commodities and other markets. Crude oil prices have tumbled $10 a barrel in the last month, to about $51.50, partly amid growing concern that China's stock-market woes will further dampen Chinese demand for oil.
Analysts also fret that China's economic engine could sputter further, causing problems generally for economies around the globe and specifically for U.S. exports to China. Foreign investors also might shy away from Chinese stocks for an extended period.
What is China's government doing about it?
The government has taken several extraordinary steps to stem the collapse, including cutting interest rates, using government pension funds to buy stocks, halting initial public offerings and relaxing terms for margin borrowing.
Those measures, however, haven't stopped the heavy selling. And as analysts at Bank of America Merrill Lynch Global Research said in note to clients this week, whether or when these policies can stabilize market sentiment is highly uncertain in our view.
The Los Angeles Times 2015

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:49:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AFP intel on radicalised pilots published</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47f5b750/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cafp0Eintel0Eradicalised0Epilots0Epublished/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An intelligence report by the Australian Federal Police on two Indonesian pilots who appear to have been radicalised has been published online.</Description>
        <MainBody>Australian police have been gathering intelligence on two Indonesian pilots who appear to have been radicalised by pro-Islamic State elements, a report says.
Source:
AAP
9 Jul 2015 - 12:49 PM UPDATEDYESTERDAY5:54PM
Australian Federal Police are monitoring two Indonesian pilots who appear to have been influenced by pro-Islamic State elements, on concerns they may pose a security threat, an intelligence website says.
The apparent radicalisation of the two pilots - which SBS cannot name for legal reasons - was detailed in a March 18 operational intelligence report compiled by the AFP and obtained by website The Intercept .
The AFP report - marked "for official use only" - analyses Facebook posts by the two pilots that appear to support IS.
The Intercept reports that 'pilot A' formerly worked for AirAsia Indonesia, while Premiair says 'pilot B' ceased working for them on June 1.
'Pilot A' graduated from the AirAsia academy in 2010 and flew international and domestic routes, the intelligence report states.
He began posting material indicating his support for IS from September 2014 - posts which 'pilot B' "liked".
The AFP also noted that 'pilot A' had commented on the page of Heri Kustyanto, who it's believed left his Indonesian family to fight with IS in Syria or Iraq.
At the time of the report, 'pilot A' was active on Facebook, was befriending radicals, and listed his current city as Raqqa, Syria.
The AFP report says 'pilot B', meanwhile, lives in Bogor, near Jakarta, and was a pilot for the Indonesian Navy before Garuda and Premiair.
He had posted photos of trips around the world, including to Australia, but by December 2014 was posting pro-Islamic State material.
His friends list included many military and commercial pilots.
The report concluded that radicalised pilots were an obvious threat, "as witnessed by past global events" and noted that a recent edition of the al-Qaeda magazine had encouraged aviation attacks.
Both men were trained pilots with contacts in the industry, it said.
The AFP distributed the report to partners in Turkey, Jordan, London, the US and Europol, The Intercept reported.
In a statement, the AFP said it did not comment on matters of intelligence.
"The AFP maintains strong relationships with its domestic and foreign law enforcement partners to ensure the ongoing safety of Australians both within Australia and abroad," it said.
The Intercept was initially created to report on documents provided by NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Giant Buddha statue in Vietnam collapses</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47ee457e/sc/21/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cgiant0Ebuddha0Estatue0Evietnam0Ecollapses/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A towering 45-metre high statue depicting a young, slender Buddha sitting in the lotus position has collapsed in northern Vietnam.</Description>
        <MainBody>8 Jul 2015 - 4:46pm
Giant Buddha statue in Vietnam collapses
A towering 45-metre high statue depicting a young, slender Buddha sitting in the lotus position has collapsed in northern Vietnam.
Source:
0
A 45-metre statue of Buddha in Vietnam has suddenly collapsed in the final phase of a three-year construction project.
The towering statue, temporarily the tallest in northern Vietnam, depicted a young, slender Buddha sitting in the lotus position at the popular Sac Thien Vuong Quan Am pagoda in Thai Binh province.
The statue was in the last stage of construction when it came crashing down late on Tuesday, said Pham Hong Thai, deputy chairman of the district.
No one was injured.
Local authorities are investigating the cause of the collapse.
The giant artwork was funded by tens of millions of dollars worth of contributions by Buddhists.
Buddhism is the largest faith in Vietnam.
A rash of construction accidents in Vietnam has recently prompted authorities to tighten safety rules.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:51:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aussie helps police in Bali murder case</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47edc5ce/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A80Caussie0Ehelps0Epolice0Ebali0Emurder0Ecase/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An Australian man who tried to help a Bali family who reported their daughter missing may not be the only foreigner they tried to extort.</Description>
        <MainBody>8 Jul 2015 - 3:54pm
Aussie helps police in Bali murder case
An Australian man who tried to help a Bali family who reported their daughter missing may not be the only foreigner they tried to extort.
Source:
0
An Australian man who tried to help a Bali family who reported their daughter missing demanded a photo of the girl from her supposed kidnappers before handing over any money.
Chris Burns told Bali police on Wednesday about his experience with the sisters of Engeline, eight, whose body was found buried in her backyard three weeks after a social media campaign was mobilised to find her.
Mr Burns told reporters that when he responded to the campaign, Engeline's sister Yvonne claimed the adopted girl was being held by kidnappers.
"I offered to help her if she could prove that Engeline was safe and could be traded," he said.
Police have broadened their murder investigation, which at first focused on a staff member at the family's Sanur home, to the woman who adopted Engeline and her family.
Children's rights activist Siti Sapurah says after Mr Burns offered to prepare cash to give the kidnappers when the proof was supplied, Yvonne became demanding.
Ms Siti says Yvonne was forwarding text messages to Mr Burns, claiming they were from the kidnappers.
"They said, 'why hasn't it been transferred yet? We're not fooling around. If you want something happen to your sister, it's your choice. Transfer it quick!'" she said.
"The language was always like that."
Mr Burns gathered Rp 10 million ($1000) of the Rp 150 million that was asked, but never handed it over, she said.
"He was sympathetic. Chris thought this girl was really missing," she said.
"He has a three-year-old child and he was thinking, what if it happened to him?"
She suspects he was not the only kind foreigner to have been tangled in the case.
"I've brought some documentation and we will ask the police to trace them," she said, referring to copies of the text messages, Facebook posts and bank details.
Engeline's sad story has gripped Indonesia for weeks, leading to calls for harsher punishments for child abuse and tighter laws around adoption.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:50:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Villagers recount incredible stories of survival after Cyclone Pam</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47edc5d2/sc/32/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cvillagers0Erecount0Eincredible0Estories0Esurvival0Eafter0Ecyclone0Epam/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It's nearly four months since Cyclone Pam pummelled Vanuatu, killing up to 15 people and leaving more than 3,000 homeless. In one small village on the island of Tanna, the stories of survival are extraordinary.</Description>
        <MainBody>Villagers recount incredible stories of survival after Cyclone Pam
Villagers recount incredible stories of survival after Cyclone Pam. (SBS)
It's nearly four months since Cyclone Pam pummelled Vanuatu, killing up to 15 people and leaving more than 3,000 homeless. In one small village on the island of Tanna, the stories of survival are extraordinary.
By
8 Jul 2015 - 3:50 PM UPDATED8Jul2015-8:22PM
Life's uncomplicated in the small village of Iwel, home to 40.
There's no electricity, no phones or computers.Just a dozen or so huts crafted from the scrub, and a remarkable spirit of survival.
In a borrowed wheelchair outside his reconstructed bamboo home sits Iaris Niere. Disabled since birth, Mr Niere feared the worst when strong winds ripped through the village, toppling the traditional houses one by one.
Without a wheelchair and frightened for his life, Mr Niere used his hands to propel himself about 200 metres to a safehouse, which remarkably survived the wind and rain.
He says that he was here by himself and there were trees lying around here and how he can walk using his hands he managed to go there, interpreter John John Kawiel said.
Mr Niere escaped his home in the nick of time.
His house fell as soon as he left the house - by chance he left the house at the time the house collapse - the old house, Mr Kawiel said.
Simon David was one of 40 people who was crammed into the villages one home which was still standing. He said Mr Nieres arrival was met with high emotion.
When we found disabled coming we were very sad and some are crying for him and we took him inside and give him a clothes to wear, Mr David said.
Almost four months on from Cyclone Pam and Iwel has rebuilt, but even in the days and weeks after the category five front hit, there were dangers.
A month after the cyclone, Iawillum Charlie was weaving beneath a huge Banyan tree when a branch fell and knocked her unconscious.
The mother-of-six said she was lucky to survive.
She was unconscious but she still alive she's getting better - the treatments she still receiving the treatments from the accident, Mr Kawiel said.
Simon David sayid the small community had grown even closer since Pam arrived and departed in March
We feel very strong because we are facing the strong cyclone and we get a new ideas to build a strong houses, we help each other to re-build the house for each other, he said.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 00:11:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thai paralysed after collision with Aussie</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47e544cc/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cthai0Eparalysed0Eafter0Ecollision0Eaussie/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A member of the Australian embassy in Thailand has allegedly offered $400 to the family of a man paralysed in a collision with his superbike.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 9:12pm
Thai paralysed after collision with Aussie
A member of the Australian embassy in Thailand has allegedly offered $400 to the family of a man paralysed in a collision with his superbike.
Source:
0
A member of the defence section at the Australian embassy in Thailand who allegedly crashed his motorbike into a Thai man and left him permanently paralysed has offered just $400 in compensation, according to the injured man's family.
In the June 14 accident, an Australian warrant officer riding an unregistered superbike collided with 62-year-old Suchart Rotkaew, according to an official police report into the incident.
The police report, seen by AAP, said the collision occurred in central Bangkok when the superbike struck Mr Suchart's bicycle.
Both parties were injured and unable to make statements. They were taken to hospital, the police report says.
The warrant officer cited the Australian embassy in Bangkok as his address.
Mr Suchart's son, Veerachon Rotkaew, told AAP his father would never be able to work again.
"The doctor said he had a brain haemorrhage," and had surgery to the left side of his brain.
"(His left) body, hands, feet, he can't move at all. He can only move on his right side of the body," Mr Veerachon said.
Mr Suchart worked as a security guard and owned a small garage.
Mr Veerachon said there had been little contact with the warrant officer since the accident.
"Fees for helping, the travelling expenses, they gave us 10,000 baht ($A400) for that," he said.
The family will have to rely on Thai social security to care for Mr Suchart. They had hoped funds would be available from insurance payments, but the Thai police report says the Australian's bike was unregistered, leaving in doubt any insurance claims.
A longstanding restriction on Australian military personnel in Thailand riding motorcycles was recently lifted despite Thailand's high record of motorbike accidents.
A Defence Department spokesperson said in an email Australian Defence Force members working at overseas posts must adhere to the local road rules.
"Defence generally does not place limitations on personnel operating any type of motor vehicle overseas, provided they meet host-nation licensing and other regulatory requirements for the vehicle they are operating," the spokesperson said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 01:24:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two killers jailed in Bali expat murder</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47dd45e0/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A60Ctwo0Ekillers0Ejailed0Ebali0Eexpat0Emurder/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Two men who fled Bali after murdering Australian businessman Robert Ellis have been found guilty of premeditated murder and sentenced to 15 years' jail.</Description>
        <MainBody>6 Jul 2015 - 7:00pm
Two killers jailed in Bali expat murder
Two more people have been jailed over the murder Australian businessman Robert Ellis (L) in Bali. (AAP)
Two men who fled Bali after murdering Australian businessman Robert Ellis have been found guilty of premeditated murder and sentenced to 15 years' jail.
Source:
0
Two men jailed for the murder of an Australian businessman in Bali have responded angrily after getting heavier sentences than the victim's wealthy wife, who planned the hit.
Adolf Malo Rangga and Martin Ngongo Bili have been sentenced to 15 years in jail for their parts in the murder of Robert Ellis, 60, in October last year.
Noor Ellis, his wife of 25 years, was last month jailed for 12 years for arranging five men to ambush her husband in their Sanur villa, and directing two maids to clean up the mess after his throat was slashed on the kitchen floor.
Mr Ellis' family slammed the lenient sentence, which the prosecution will not appeal.
Rangga hit back at the judges in Denpasar District Court on Monday, asking why they were punished more harshly.
Chief Judge Ahmad Peten Sili said he "should be grateful".
"You killed a man. A planned killing should be punished with death," he said.
"It's so easy for you to kill people ... You're dangerous.
"If someone told you to carry a bag of rice, that would be OK.
"But you were told to kill a man, and you were willing?"
Martin, meanwhile, sat alongside Rangga crying.
Their lawyer, Hari Purwanto, said he would consider an appeal.
The men were the last of the five to be arrested for the crime, after a manhunt on the island of Sumba.
Police alleged Martin made arrangements for the hit "starting from the strategy, finance and recruiting the killers".
Rangga's role, said police, was to hold Mr Ellis down while another man slit his throat.
Mr Ellis's body was found wrapped in plastic in a rice field.
His wife eventually confessed to involvement in the crime, telling police her husband had been unfaithful and withheld money from her.
Friends of the late businessman have since tried to straighten the record, saying his Indonesian wife was well provided for, and it was she who was the unfaithful partner.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:54:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aussie to assist Bali girl murder case</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47dca322/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A60Caussie0Eassist0Ebali0Egirl0Emurder0Ecase/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An Australian man who responded to a campaign for a missing Bali girl will help police with their investigation into her adopted family.</Description>
        <MainBody>6 Jul 2015 - 4:08pm
Aussie to assist Bali girl murder case
An Australian man who responded to a campaign for a missing Bali girl will help police with their investigation into her adopted family.
Source:
0
An Australian who tried to help the family of a missing Bali girl, who was later found murdered, will reportedly help the police investigation into the family who adopted her.
The case of Engeline has gripped Indonesia since she was reported missing from her Sanur home in May.
Three weeks after a social media-led campaign to find her, the eight-year-old's body was found buried under the chicken coop of her home, clutching a doll.
Police first arrested a guard who worked at the house but have since named Engeline's adopted mother, Margaret Christine Megawe, a suspect, and are investigating other family members.
In the latest twist in the case, Margaret's daughter is being investigated for trying to extort an Australian man who responded to the missing girl campaign.
Indonesian media reports say Sydney man Chris Burn contacted Yvonne and was told kidnappers were demanding a Rp 150 million ($15,000) ransom for Engeline.
He became suspicious when the woman continued to ask for money.
Bali police intend to interview him on Wednesday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:32:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Third death in Taiwan water park disaster</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47dc3a9b/sc/31/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cthird0Edeath0Etaiwan0Ewater0Epark0Edisaster/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A third personhas died after suffering horrific burns in a fireball that engulfed spectators at an event at a Taiwan water park.</Description>
        <MainBody>6 Jul 2015 - 4:26pm
Third death in Taiwan water park disaster
A third personhas died after suffering horrific burns in a fireball that engulfed spectators at an event at a Taiwan water park.
Source:
0
A third person has died from injuries suffered in a water park explosion in Taiwan.
The 20-year-old man died shortly after being taken home on Monday morning from Linkou Chang Gung Memorial Hospital in New Taipei, the state-run Central News Agency reported.
He had arrived in hospital with burns to over 50 per cent of his body after the flammable powder exploded at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei on June 27, The Apple Daily reported.
The accident has caused three deaths.
A 20-year-old woman and a 19-year-old man died last week.
The Ministry of Health and Welfare said late on Sunday that 282 people remained in intensive care, with 237 of them in life-threatening condition.
The cause of the explosion remains under investigation, according to New Taipei City Government.
Investigators said last week that the probe had focused on more than 40 cigarettes left at the scene.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:07:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Foreigner tests positive to MERS in Manila</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47dbff3b/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cforeigner0Etests0Epositive0Emers0Emanila/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Authorities in the Philippines are trying to trace hundreds of people who came in contact with a foreigner who tested positive to the MERS virus.</Description>
        <MainBody>6 Jul 2015 - 3:14pm
Foreigner tests positive to MERS in Manila
Authorities in the Philippines are trying to trace hundreds of people who came in contact with a foreigner who tested positive to the MERS virus.
Source:
0
Health officials say a 36-year-old foreigner who arrived in the Philippines from the Middle East is under quarantine after testing positive for the MERS virus.
Health Secretary Janette Garin said authorities were trying to trace 200-odd passengers who were on the same flight to Manila as the foreigner.
At least seven people who had close contact with the patient are under home quarantine.
The patient initially arrived in the Philippines from Saudi Arabia, but also stayed in Dubai before flying to Manila.
The patient's home country has not been disclosed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 10:24:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two killers jailed in Bali over Australian expat&amp;#039;s murder</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47dd152b/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A60Ctwo0Ekillers0Ejailed0Ebali0Eover0Eaustralian0Eexpats0Emurder/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Two men who fled Bali after murdering Australian businessman Robert Ellis have been found guilty of premeditated murder and sentenced to 15 years' jail.</Description>
        <MainBody>6 Jul 2015 - 7:00pm
Two killers jailed in Bali expat murder
Two more people have been jailed over the murder Australian businessman Robert Ellis (L) in Bali. (AAP)
Two men who fled Bali after murdering Australian businessman Robert Ellis have been found guilty of premeditated murder and sentenced to 15 years' jail.
Source:
0
Two men jailed for the murder of an Australian businessman in Bali have responded angrily after getting heavier sentences than the victim's wealthy wife, who planned the hit.
Adolf Malo Rangga and Martin Ngongo Bili have been sentenced to 15 years in jail for their parts in the murder of Robert Ellis, 60, in October last year.
Noor Ellis, his wife of 25 years, was last month jailed for 12 years for arranging five men to ambush her husband in their Sanur villa, and directing two maids to clean up the mess after his throat was slashed on the kitchen floor.
Mr Ellis' family slammed the lenient sentence, which the prosecution will not appeal.
Rangga hit back at the judges in Denpasar District Court on Monday, asking why they were punished more harshly.
Chief Judge Ahmad Peten Sili said he "should be grateful".
"You killed a man. A planned killing should be punished with death," he said.
"It's so easy for you to kill people ... You're dangerous.
"If someone told you to carry a bag of rice, that would be OK.
"But you were told to kill a man, and you were willing?"
Martin, meanwhile, sat alongside Rangga crying.
Their lawyer, Hari Purwanto, said he would consider an appeal.
The men were the last of the five to be arrested for the crime, after a manhunt on the island of Sumba.
Police alleged Martin made arrangements for the hit "starting from the strategy, finance and recruiting the killers".
Rangga's role, said police, was to hold Mr Ellis down while another man slit his throat.
Mr Ellis's body was found wrapped in plastic in a rice field.
His wife eventually confessed to involvement in the crime, telling police her husband had been unfaithful and withheld money from her.
Friends of the late businessman have since tried to straighten the record, saying his Indonesian wife was well provided for, and it was she who was the unfaithful partner.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 10:24:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two more jailed for Bali expat&amp;#039;s murder</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47dd09dc/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A60Ctwo0Emore0Ejailed0Ebali0Eexpats0Emurder/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Two men who fled Bali after murdering Australian businessman Robert Ellis have been sentenced to 15 years' jail.</Description>
        <MainBody>6 Jul 2015 - 7:00pm
Two killers jailed in Bali expat murder
Two more people have been jailed over the murder Australian businessman Robert Ellis (L) in Bali. (AAP)
Two men who fled Bali after murdering Australian businessman Robert Ellis have been found guilty of premeditated murder and sentenced to 15 years' jail.
Source:
0
Two men jailed for the murder of an Australian businessman in Bali have responded angrily after getting heavier sentences than the victim's wealthy wife, who planned the hit.
Adolf Malo Rangga and Martin Ngongo Bili have been sentenced to 15 years in jail for their parts in the murder of Robert Ellis, 60, in October last year.
Noor Ellis, his wife of 25 years, was last month jailed for 12 years for arranging five men to ambush her husband in their Sanur villa, and directing two maids to clean up the mess after his throat was slashed on the kitchen floor.
Mr Ellis' family slammed the lenient sentence, which the prosecution will not appeal.
Rangga hit back at the judges in Denpasar District Court on Monday, asking why they were punished more harshly.
Chief Judge Ahmad Peten Sili said he "should be grateful".
"You killed a man. A planned killing should be punished with death," he said.
"It's so easy for you to kill people ... You're dangerous.
"If someone told you to carry a bag of rice, that would be OK.
"But you were told to kill a man, and you were willing?"
Martin, meanwhile, sat alongside Rangga crying.
Their lawyer, Hari Purwanto, said he would consider an appeal.
The men were the last of the five to be arrested for the crime, after a manhunt on the island of Sumba.
Police alleged Martin made arrangements for the hit "starting from the strategy, finance and recruiting the killers".
Rangga's role, said police, was to hold Mr Ellis down while another man slit his throat.
Mr Ellis's body was found wrapped in plastic in a rice field.
His wife eventually confessed to involvement in the crime, telling police her husband had been unfaithful and withheld money from her.
Friends of the late businessman have since tried to straighten the record, saying his Indonesian wife was well provided for, and it was she who was the unfaithful partner.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 23:02:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Malaysian PM faces risk of criminal charge</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47d6e75e/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A50Cmalaysian0Epm0Efaces0Erisk0Ecriminal0Echarge/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Documents sent to Malaysia's attorney general pave the way for possible criminal charges against Prime Minister Najib Razak.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 Jul 2015 - 3:06pm
Malaysian PM faces risk of criminal charge
Documents sent to Malaysia's attorney general pave the way for possible criminal charges against Prime Minister Najib Razak.
Source:
0
Malaysia's prime minister is facing the risk of a criminal charge over allegations that millions of dollars were funnelled from an indebted state fund to his personal bank accounts.
The attorney general confirmed late on Saturday he had received documents from an official investigation that made the link between Prime Minister Najib Razak and the investment fund 1MDB.
The existence of the documents was first reported by the Asian Wall Street Journal on Friday, showing about $US700 million ($A916.71 million) were wired from entities linked to the fund into Najib's accounts.
The documents sent to the attorney general pave the way for possible criminal charges.
This is the first time a Malaysian leader faces criminal allegations.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 10:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Exercise key to staying ahead in rat race</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47d230b9/sc/14/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cexercise0Ekey0Estaying0Eahead0Erat0Erace/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers say rats that exercise daily just fly through their rat to-do-lists at a much quicker pace.</Description>
        <MainBody>Exercise key to staying ahead in rat race
(AAP)
Researchers say rats that exercise daily just fly through their rat to-do-lists at a much quicker pace.
Source:
0
Some hard-working rats may have proven exercise is just what you need to stay on top of your work, researchers say.
In a new study from Otago University, psychologists have found lab rats that had one 20-minute session of exercise, five days a week, did significantly better in productivity tests than their couch-potato counterparts.
The study's author, psychology lecturer Kristin Hillman, said the exercised rats completed more tasks to earn food and did so more quickly and efficiently.
She said the test was a great way of demonstrating the importance of fitness on mental wellbeing for humans too.
"Links between exercise and occupational or educational achievement are starting to be noted in humans, but these links are largely correlations and can be riddled with confounding psychosocial factor," she said.
"By using an animal model we obviously eliminate such factors, and are able to demonstrate a causal relationship between regular exercise and generalised industriousness."
The study appears in US scientific journal PLOS ONE.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 21:12:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Murder-accused Napier man &amp;#039;just too big&amp;#039;</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47cb49a6/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cmurder0Eaccused0Enapier0Eman0Ejust0Etoo0Ebig/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A New Zealand man awaiting trial for murder says the whole thing is an "amazing romance" gone wrong.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 Jul 2015 - 1:14pm
Murder-accused Napier man 'just too big'
A New Zealand man awaiting trial for murder says the whole thing is an "amazing romance" gone wrong.
Source:
0
At more than two metres tall and weighing 180kg, a former Napier councillor charged with murder was just too big to save his drowning wife, he says.
Peter Beckett, a Hastings-born 59-year-old is awaiting trial in Canada, accused of not only killing his wife, but also with trying to arrange the murder of five witnesses, including his wife's parents, a policeman who investigated his case and a lawyer.
Beckett's wife, Canadian school teacher Laura Letts-Beckett, drowned in August 2010 while fishing on Arrow Lake, 200km east of Kamloops, where the trial will be heard.
The man, described as having a booming voice with a thick Kiwi accent and calling himself "the real Mr Big", says it was all an "amazing love story" that ended in tragedy.
The pair met in 1995, while then-35-year-old Ms Letts was travelling New Zealand as a tourist.
Beckett was married with four kids at the time.
Sparks flew between the pair after a chance meeting, he told a local radio station.
"I'd had break-ups before, I'd fallen in love before but this was different than that."
Eight years later Beckett sold everything he owned and moved to Canada, with the pair marrying shortly after.
But the relationship turned rocky and they filed for divorce in 2007 after Mrs Letts-Beckett accused Beckett of abuse, although they reconciled later.
He claims he and his wife were fishing when a gust of wind blew an umbrella off their boat, causing her to fall overboard, and he tried to rescue her but failed because he was too big to stay submerged.
He ran to collect a rock to weigh himself down and later tried to resuscitate her on the shore, he said.
But the Crown says Beckett is a calculating killer who killed Mrs Letts-Beckett by shoving her off the boat.
Beckett has changed lawyers a number of times and alleges abuse of process, bias by police and court officials, and failure of the Crown to disclose documents.
"The [Royal Mounted Canadian Police] are financially given incentive to solve crimes," he told local newspaper Kamloops This Week.
"In this case, they tried to invent a crime that didn't exist. The RCMP want to get their man, even though there was no crime in the first place."
More than four years after Mrs Letts-Beckett's death a jury was picked for the Supreme Court trial from Kamloops, a town of 85,000 people, in January.
He was arrested in August 2011 and has been awaiting trial since.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 19:24:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ashburton tragedy linked to car</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47cb0486/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cashburton0Etragedy0Elinked0Ecar/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Car in garage likely to have gassed a family found dead in house in Ashburton.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 Jul 2015 - 4:52pm
NZ family could have been dead a week
New Zealand police have named a mother and her three children who are believed to have died after a car was left running in a garage in Ashburton.
Source:
0
New Zealand police say a mother and her three young children killed when a car was left running in a garage in Ashburton, on South Island, could have been dead a week.
Police believe Cindy George, 31, was checking the house for family and friends who were away, and started the car belonging to the house owner to charge the battery.
The garage door was closed, but the internal door connecting the garage to the modern air-tight house was open.
Relatives found Ms George in the hallway near the garage of the house in Tinwald on Thursday afternoon.
Her three children - Pio Scarlet Jetejura Raukete, five, Teuruaa Junior George, three, and Telyzshaun Gordon Ricardo Nelder Kruz George, two - were found sitting in the lounge with the television they were watching still on.
Police don't know exactly when they died.
"It could be a matter of days, up to possibly a week," Superintendent John Price, the Canterbury district police commander, said on Friday afternoon.
"We believe that what has happened here is simply a terrible accident."
Officers were trying to establish the family's movements and working to establish exactly what happened.
Toxicology samples had been taken, but those results won't be released for a few more weeks, he said.
Their bodies have been taken to Christchurch where post-mortems will take place on Monday.
"At that stage we'll have a better idea of the cause of death," Supt Price said.
The children's father, who was separated from Ms George, lives in Ashburton.
He is being supported by the community, Supt Price said.
The matter will be referred to the coroner.
There was no trauma to any of the deceased and there was no forced entry to the house, Supt Price said.
The car in the garage had run out of petrol and the battery was flat when emergency services arrived.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 16:09:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Paper fell &amp;#039;sadly short&amp;#039; in ponytail yarn</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637529/s/47ca2299/sc/25/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cpaper0Efell0Esadly0Eshort0Eponytail0Eyarn/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A New Zealand newspaper story on the Prime Minister's ponytail-pulling saga has seen the NZN Herald slapped on the wrist.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 Jul 2015 - 8:12am
Paper fell 'sadly short' in ponytail yarn
A New Zealand newspaper story on the Prime Minister's ponytail-pulling saga has seen the NZN Herald slapped on the wrist.
Source:
0
The country's biggest newspaper, the New Zealand Herald, fell "sadly short" of highest professional standards in a story about the waitress who had her hair pulled by Prime Minister John Key, the media watchdog says.
In a newly released ruling, the Press Council says then-Herald columnist Rachel Glucina failed to properly represent herself to Aucklander Amanda Bailey, who anonymously complained Mr Key had tugged her hair on numerous occasions at her cafe.
Ms Bailey wrote on the left-wing Daily Blog complaining about the incidents in April, prompting an apology from the prime minister and a media uproar.
Shortly after, the Herald ran a story by Glucina revealing Ms Bailey's name and featuring photos and an interview with the waitress.
Ms Bailey complained she had been duped into doing the article, saying her employers, friends of Glucina's, had told her she was a PR consultant who would release a media statement for her.
The council said there was an "element of subterfuge" in what Glucina had done in not making clear to Ms Bailey she was a reporter and there was not enough public interest to justify it.
"The onus was on Ms Glucina as a professional media person to make the position completely clear to all parties, particularly to Ms Bailey, with whom she had had no previous contact, who was in a vulnerable position, and whose interests could well have been in conflict with those of the cafe owner's," it said.
The Press Council was concerned with maintaining the press in accordance with the highest professional standards, it said.
"The NZ Herald has fallen sadly short of those standards in this case."
The multiple complainants did not include Ms Bailey herself.
The Herald has denied the accusations of subterfuge and Glucina has since left the company.
It remains unclear whether Ms Bailey's employers knew the article would be printed in the Herald.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
