<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sbs North America News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 10:53:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US state to take down Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47f73ce7/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cus0Estate0Etake0Edown0Econfederate0Eflag/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The US state of South Carolina's House of Representatives has voted to remove the Confederate flag, seen as a symbol of racism, after a 13-hour debate.</Description>
        <MainBody>US state to take down Confederate flag
South Carolina's House of Representatives has voted to remove the Confederate flag. (AAP)
The US state of South Carolina's House of Representatives has voted to remove the Confederate flag, seen as a symbol of racism, after a 13-hour debate.
Source:
AAP
9 Jul 2015 - 5:53 PM UPDATEDYESTERDAY6:34PM
The House of Representatives in the southern US state of South Carolina has voted overwhelmingly to remove the Confederate flag from the Capitol grounds.
The bill achieved its required two-thirds majority after a 13-hour debate, media reports said.
The votes followed the bill's passage by the Senate this week, three weeks after a shooting at an African American church killed nine people in Charleston, South Carolina.
Photographs surfaced after the slayings of the white 21-year-old charged with the killings, Dylann Roof, showing him posing with the Confederate flag and prompting a drive to take it down from the state Capitol grounds.
The flag was flown by separatist Southern states during the 1861-65 US Civil War, which was fought over slavery.
Many consider it to be a racist symbol, but many white Southerners see it as a symbol of their heritage and a way to honour their ancestors' sacrifices in the war.
The legislation must now be signed by Governor Nikki Haley to become law.
She had called for the removal of the flag after the shootings at Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church.
South Carolina in 1860 became the first Southern state to secede from the United States, and the first shots of the Civil War were fired the following year in Charleston.
The state re-erected the Confederate flag, which features white stars on a diagonal blue cross against a red background, on the Capitol grounds more than 50 years ago to protest the civil rights movement.
Haley said removing the flag would create a more inclusive state government.
"That flag, while an integral part of our past, does not represent the future of our great state," she said days after the church shootings, which killed six women and three men, ages 26 to 87, during a Bible study.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:52:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three dead in shooting near US university</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47f0b8fd/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cthree0Edead0Eshooting0Enear0Eus0Euniversity/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Three people have been shot dead in a residential neighbourhood blocks from the University of Maryland campus in the US city of Baltimore.</Description>
        <MainBody>9 Jul 2015 - 5:58am
Three gunned down near college as killings surge in Baltimore
In this image taken from video, police investigate the scene of a shooting, Tuesday, July 7, 2015, in Baltimore. Baltimore police say four people have been shot, three fatally, near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, campus. (WMAR via AP)
Three people have been shot dead in a residential neighbourhood blocks from the University of Maryland campus in the US city of Baltimore.
Source:
0
Gunmen killed three people and wounded one overnight near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, police said on Wednesday, the latest killings in a city that has seen an upturn in homicides following the death of Freddie Gray in April.
Two gunmen emerged from two vans and began shooting just before 11 p.m. on Tuesday (0300 GMT on Wednesday), campus police said in a statement.
A man died at the scene, Baltimore police said, and a man and a woman died while receiving medical treatment. The fourth victim, a woman, was hospitalized.
"Three to four suspects are believed to be involved at this time. This was not a random act of violence but was a targeted incident," police said in a statement.
The shooting was not related to the university, the statement said. The Baltimore Sun reported that shots had been fired into a vehicle traveling on the same block five days ago.
The shootings came as Baltimore is grappling with an upsurge in killings following the death of Gray, a 25-year-old black man, from an injury suffered in police custody.
His death triggered protests and a day of rioting and arson. Police said looting of pharmacies during the unrest and a subsequent drug turf war was behind a surge in killings in May.
Police had originally recorded 43 homicides in May, the highest number since 1972, but dropped the total to 42 when one killing was reclassified as justified. A police spokeswoman on Wednesday put the May homicide number at 41, the highest monthly tally since August 1990, without explaining the new total.
Baltimore, a largely black city of about 620,000 people, has notched 155 homicides this year, compared with 105 for the same period last year, the spokeswoman said.
Police said on Tuesday the Police Executive Research Forum, a non-profit policy group, would evaluate the department's performance during the April unrest.
Police had said the Forum and the International Association of Chiefs of Police would take part in the department's internal review. The Baltimore police union also released an after-action report on Wednesday.

(Reporting by Victoria Cavaliere in Los Angeles and Ian Simpson in Washington; Editing by Robin Pomeroy and Mohammad Zargham)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:55:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Estonian pleads guilty to cyber fraud</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47f52067/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cestonian0Epleads0Eguilty0Ecyber0Efraud/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An Estonian citizen has pleaded guilty in a New York court to a cyber scam that infected more than four million computers in more than 100 countries.</Description>
        <MainBody>9 Jul 2015 - 9:00am
Estonian pleads guilty to cyber fraud
An Estonian citizen has pleaded guilty in a New York court to a cyber scam that infected more than four million computers in more than 100 countries.
Source:
A man portrayed as a ringleader in an international cyber scam has pleaded guilty.
Vladimir Tsastsin, an Estonian citizen, entered the plea on Wednesday in a Manhattan federal court.
The plea related to a scheme that, authorities said, infected more than four million computers in more than 100 countries with software that disabled anti-virus protections and steered users to websites they did not choose.
Sentencing was set for October 14.
Prosecutors say more than a half a million computers were infected in the United States, including computers belonging to government agencies such as NASA.
Prosecutors say infected computers also belonged to educational institutions, non-profit organisations, commercial businesses and individuals.
They said Tsastsin and co-conspirators profited by receiving payments for higher internet traffic after they digitally hijacked internet searches and rerouted computers to certain websites and advertisements.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:04:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spike series on computer pioneer McAfee</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47f4341d/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cspike0Eseries0Ecomputer0Epioneer0Emcafee/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Spike TV is making a six-part series on controversial and eccentric anti-virus software pioneer John McAfee.</Description>
        <MainBody>9 Jul 2015 - 8:08am
Spike series on computer pioneer McAfee
Spike TV is making a six-part series on controversial and eccentric anti-virus software pioneer John McAfee.
Source:
The Spike television network says it is making a six-part TV series based on the life of anti-virus software entrepreneur John McAfee, centred around interviews with him.
McAfee, 69, formed a software security company named for himself and sold it, earning a fortune.
He's lived an eccentric life that included being the subject of a manhunt after a US expatriate who lived near McAfee's home in the Central American nation of Belize was found dead in late 2012. He has denied any involvement in the shooting.
The series and its format are reminiscent of HBO's The Jinx, the series about millionaire murder suspect Robert Durst that was a sensation for the pay cable network earlier this year.
But Sharon Levy, executive vice president of original series for Spike, said it was more about an attempt to make a non-fiction series with the drive of a fictional series.
The series will be filmed this northern summer and air on the cable network sometime next year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:05:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York Stock Exchange shut down for nearly four hours by technical glitch</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47f4e7ff/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cnew0Eyork0Estock0Eexchange0Eshut0Edown0Enearly0Efour0Ehours0Etechnical0Eglitch/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A technical glitch forced the New York Stock Exchange to suspend trading for several hours on Wednesday in the biggest outage to strike a US financial market in nearly two years.</Description>
        <MainBody>9 Jul 2015 - 8:00pm
New York Stock Exchange shut down for nearly four hours by technical glitch
A trader at the New York Stock Exchange after trading was halted due to a technical glitch in New York, 8 July 2015. (EPA/JUSTIN LANE)
A technical glitch forced the New York Stock Exchange to suspend trading for several hours on Wednesday in the biggest outage to strike a US financial market in nearly two years.
Source:
Reuters
9 Jul 2015 - 5:05 AM UPDATEDYESTERDAY8:00PM
The New York Stock Exchange wasforced to suspend trading for several hours on Wednesday in thebiggest outage to hit a U.S. financial market in nearly twoyears, unnerving investors already rattled by the meltdown inChinese stocks and the Greek debt crisis.
The exchange, a unit of Intercontinental Exchange Inc, reopened at 3:10 p.m. EDT (1910 GMT) after being haltedshortly after 11:30 a.m. EDT. NYSE said the outage was due to aninternal technical issue and not the result of a cyberattack.
Other exchanges were trading normally.
"It's not a good day, and I don't feel good for ourcustomers who are having to deal with the fallout," NYSEPresident Thomas Farley told CNBC during the halt.
NYSE, which traces its roots back to an agreement under aButtonwood tree on Wall Street in 1792, handled 6.12 percent ofU.S. stock volume for the day, with much of that coming afterthe exchange reopened, according to statistics from BATS GlobalMarkets. That compares to an average of about 13.4 percent lastmonth.
Traders had awaited the reopening anxiously because much ofthe NYSE's business happens when portfolio managers put inorders designed to occur at the exact market close to ensureend-of-day pricing.
However, many traders said that it did not matter that theNYSE was down. That's because there are 11 U.S. stock exchanges,including those run by Nasdaq OMX Group and BATS, alongwith more than 40 private stock-trading venues, so the tradingof NYSE-listed stocks was uninterrupted.
"This is one of the rare cases where the fragmented marketswe live in actually serve a purpose," said Dave Nadig, directorof exchange-traded funds at FactSet Research Systems. "If thishappened at (the London Stock Exchange), you would just besitting staring at a blank screen."
Glitches galore
NYSE had been experiencing technical issues even before themarket opened. The exchange had said it was experiencingconnectivity problems that may have prevented some of itscustomers from getting acknowledgements on orders submitted insome 220 stocks.
NYSE's glitch came on the same day that computer problemsled United Airlines to ground all its flights for about twohours and the home page of the Wall Street Journal's websitetemporarily went down.
The U.S. Department of Homeland Security said there were nosigns that the problems at NYSE and United Airlines stemmed from"malicious activity." The SEC said on Wednesday that it was closely monitoring the situation at NYSE. The White House saidPresident Barack Obama had been briefed on the matter.
Nearly all U.S. trading is done electronically, and the NYSEoutage again raised questions about the robustness of thetechnology at exchanges after a raft of major glitches in recentyears.
A technical problem at NYSE's Arca exchange in March causedsome of the most popular exchange-traded funds to be temporarilyunavailable for trading. And in August 2013, trading of allNasdaq-listed stocks was frozen for three hours, leading U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Mary Jo White to callfor a meeting of Wall Street executives to insure "continuousand orderly" functioning of the markets.
The NYSE accounts for more than 60 percent of S&amp;P 500volume at the close of the market, according to Credit Suisseanalyst Ana Avramovic. Most of this is at the "market-on-close,"when those orders are processed for funds and institutions.
"If you don't have all the orders on that marketplace on theclose, the pricing on the close would be definitely notaccurate," said Empire Executions Inc President Peter Costa, whotrades on the NYSE floor.
The benchmark S&amp;P index closed down 1.7 percent onWednesday, as investors continue to focus on turmoil in Chinaand Greece.
(Reporting by John McCrank; Additional reporting by RodrigoCampos, Jonathan Spicer, Caroline Valetkevitch, Sinead Carew,and Jessica Toonkel; Editing by Lisa Von Ahn, Bernard Orr)
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:52:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three gunned down near college as killings surge in Baltimore</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47f423d4/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cthree0Egunned0Edown0Enear0Ecollege0Ekillings0Esurge0Ebaltimore/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Three people have been shot dead in a residential neighbourhood blocks from the University of Maryland campus in the US city of Baltimore.</Description>
        <MainBody>9 Jul 2015 - 5:58am
Three gunned down near college as killings surge in Baltimore
In this image taken from video, police investigate the scene of a shooting, Tuesday, July 7, 2015, in Baltimore. Baltimore police say four people have been shot, three fatally, near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, campus. (WMAR via AP)
Three people have been shot dead in a residential neighbourhood blocks from the University of Maryland campus in the US city of Baltimore.
Source:
0
Gunmen killed three people and wounded one overnight near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, police said on Wednesday, the latest killings in a city that has seen an upturn in homicides following the death of Freddie Gray in April.
Two gunmen emerged from two vans and began shooting just before 11 p.m. on Tuesday (0300 GMT on Wednesday), campus police said in a statement.
A man died at the scene, Baltimore police said, and a man and a woman died while receiving medical treatment. The fourth victim, a woman, was hospitalized.
"Three to four suspects are believed to be involved at this time. This was not a random act of violence but was a targeted incident," police said in a statement.
The shooting was not related to the university, the statement said. The Baltimore Sun reported that shots had been fired into a vehicle traveling on the same block five days ago.
The shootings came as Baltimore is grappling with an upsurge in killings following the death of Gray, a 25-year-old black man, from an injury suffered in police custody.
His death triggered protests and a day of rioting and arson. Police said looting of pharmacies during the unrest and a subsequent drug turf war was behind a surge in killings in May.
Police had originally recorded 43 homicides in May, the highest number since 1972, but dropped the total to 42 when one killing was reclassified as justified. A police spokeswoman on Wednesday put the May homicide number at 41, the highest monthly tally since August 1990, without explaining the new total.
Baltimore, a largely black city of about 620,000 people, has notched 155 homicides this year, compared with 105 for the same period last year, the spokeswoman said.
Police said on Tuesday the Police Executive Research Forum, a non-profit policy group, would evaluate the department's performance during the April unrest.
Police had said the Forum and the International Association of Chiefs of Police would take part in the department's internal review. The Baltimore police union also released an after-action report on Wednesday.

(Reporting by Victoria Cavaliere in Los Angeles and Ian Simpson in Washington; Editing by Robin Pomeroy and Mohammad Zargham)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 07:55:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Subway suspends spokesman Jared Fogle after police raid home</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47edb96b/sc/8/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A80Csubway0Esuspends0Espokesman0Ejared0Efogle0Eafter0Epolice0Eraid0Ehome/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Authorities conducted a day-long search inside the Indiana home of Subway sandwich chain pitchman Jared Fogle on Tuesday, two months after the executive director of Fogle's foundation was arrested on federal child pornography charges.</Description>
        <MainBody>8 Jul 2015 - 2:57pm
Subway suspends spokesman Jared Fogle after police raid home
Jared Fogle, the unofficial mascot for dieters - seen here on Tuesday, Aug. 7, 2001 - holds up a pair of jeans he used to wear.(AAP)
Authorities conducted a day-long search inside the Indiana home of Subway sandwich chain pitchman Jared Fogle on Tuesday, two months after the executive director of Fogle's foundation was arrested on federal child pornography charges.
Source:
Reuters
8 Jul 2015 - 2:55 PM UPDATED8Jul2015-2:57PM
As authorities concluded their search for the day, Subway said it was suspending its relationship with Fogle due to the investigation, which the company said it believed was linked to the probe of a former foundation executive.
"Jared continues to cooperate with authorities and he expects no actions to be forthcoming," Subway said in a statement. "Both Jared and Subway agree that this was the appropriate step to take."
By early evening on Tuesday, promotional references to Fogle had been removed from Subway's website.
Authorities were observed on Tuesday removing numerous items from Fogle's home, carrying them out in bags, boxes and briefcases. Fogle was present for part of the search, but he left his home in the Zionsville suburb northwest of Indianapolis around midday as the search continued.
Authorities, who first arrived at the home about 6:30 a.m., ultimately pulled out around 5 p.m.
It was not clear whether Fogle, a father of two, is a target of what authorities have said is a joint investigation by local, state and federal law enforcement.
FBI spokeswoman Wendy Osborne declined to comment about the activity at Fogle's home, other than to confirm investigative efforts in the area. She said she could not discuss whether the actions at Fogle's home were connected to the child porn case against Russell Taylor, the former foundation executive.
Fogle's attorney said Fogle has not been detained or arrested or charged "with any crime or offense."
"Jared has been cooperating, and continues to cooperate, with law enforcement in their investigation of unspecified charges and looks forward to its conclusion," attorney Ron Elberger said in a statement.
A neighbor who asked not to be identified by name said Fogle and his family had lived in their home for about four years and generally were very "private."
Fogle became a Subway spokesman after losing a reported 245 pounds (111 kg) in part by eating regularly at the sandwich chain. Fogle made his first Subway commercial in 2000 and appeared in a new one last year, according to Subway.
Along with the FBI, the Indiana State Police assisted the U.S. Attorney's Office for the Southern District of Indiana in the investigation, according to state police spokesman Sergeant Richard Myers. U.S. Postal Service agents also assisted in the investigation.
Taylor, the Jared Foundation's former executive director, is currently in federal custody facing seven counts of production of child pornography and one count of possession of child pornography. He has not yet entered a plea, said his attorney Brad Banks.
Banks would also not comment on the investigation.
Authorities said they found videos they believe Taylor produced by secretly filming minor children at his home. The investigators said they found more than 400 videos of alleged child pornography in his Indianapolis home.
Subway restaurant spokesman Jared Fogle walks to a waiting car as he leaves his home Tuesday, July 7, 2015. (AAP)
Subway restaurant spokesman Jared Fogle walks to a waiting car as he leaves his home Tuesday, July 7, 2015. (AAP)
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:51:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canadian nabbed for chair balloon flight</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e7df66/sc/6/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Ccanadian0Enabbed0Echair0Eballoon0Eflight/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Canadian man has been arrested for flying on a chair, strapped to more than a 100 helium-filled balloons, over the city of Calgary.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 9:40pm
Canadian nabbed for chair balloon flight
A Canadian man has been arrested for flying on a chair, strapped to more than a 100 helium-filled balloons, over the city of Calgary.
Source:
A man has been arrested for flying over the Canadian city of Calgary on a chair, strapped to more than a 100 helium-filled balloons, in a scene straight out of the computer-animated film Up.
Calgary police said Daniel Boria, 26, was arrested and charged with mischief causing danger to life.
In a press conference on Monday, the police said Boria used a parachute to land, spraining his ankle in the process.
Boria was released on a $US1,200 ($A1,600) bail and will appear before a judge on July 13.
Police said the incident was a publicity stunt for his cleaning products company.
According to the Calgary Sun daily, the chair used by Boria was found some 65km south of Calgary.
Speaking to the newspaper, Boria said he didn't know what height he managed to reach, but at one point he was flying over a Boeing 747 aeroplane.
"It was the most surreal experience you can ever imagine," he exclaimed.
Boria's stunt on Sunday coincided with the celebration of the Calgary Stampede, considered the world's largest rodeo event and attended by a million people annually.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:40:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama shows a looser side on Twitter</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e5e50c/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cobama0Eshows0Elooser0Eside0Etwitter/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings - at all hours of the day.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 5:44pm
Obama shows a looser side on Twitter
US President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings - at all hours of the day.
Source:
0
Forget the prime-time interviews or the formal, choreographed news conferences.
The White House has used Twitter to promote the president's views for years, but mostly in a highly scripted manner, with tweets composed by press aides and released at strategic times.
Only occasionally would Obama post to Twitter himself, identifying a bona fide presidential tweet by appending his initials.
Now Obama is composing his own tweets almost daily, weighing in on issues of the day from any location, without the filter of his press office.
He's been tweeting with increased frequency since inaugurating his personal twitter account, (at)POTUS, earlier this summer.
"Hello, Twitter! It's Barack. Really!" Obama wrote in May.
"Six years in, they're finally giving me my own account."
So how, exactly, does a president tweet?
Obama, who has been known to use an iPad and a Blackberry, can send tweets from a variety of secure devices, according to the White House.
Obama gives his team a heads up before he tweets, and his staff says he sometimes agrees to tweet about topics his aides suggests.
In the six weeks since Obama kicked off the account, he's already amassed more than three million followers.
He follows only 66 Twitter users - mostly sports teams, federal agencies and top government officials.
He briefly set a record for the attracting a million followers faster than any other Twitter user.
But Obama's record was quickly broken by Caitlyn Jenner.
Josh Earnest, the White House press secretary, says Obama was enthusiastic about having the chance to use venues like Twitter to communicate with people.
"He's really taken to the idea," Earnest said.
A LOOK AT SOME OF OBAMA'S RECENT TWEETS:
GAY MARRIAGE
Obama's first reaction to the Supreme Court's historic ruling legalising gay marriage nationwide came not in a press release or a Rose Garden appearance, but through his Twitter account.
"Today is a big step in our march toward equality," Obama tweeted on June 26.
"Gay and lesbian couples now have the right to marry, just like anyone else."
HOLY GUACAMOLE
When an enthusiastic debate broke out on Twitter this month about including peas in guacamole, Obama took to Twitter to say he had no appetite for the added ingredient.
He responded to the pea-laden recipe in The New York Times during a "Twitter town hall" - a medium the White House has been trying out in which the president takes questions from Americans directly on Twitter.
"Respect the NYT, but not buying peas in guac," the president wrote, offering his personal recipe: "Onions, garlic, hot peppers. Classic."
BRING IN THE BAND
After Obama tweeted that he'd spent his morning listening to the new album from The Black Keys, the rock band tweeted back asking if they could use Air Force One for their upcoming gigs.
A few hours later - at 8pm on a weeknight - Obama tweeted his response to the band: "It's not mine; just a loaner. Maybe you can come play at the White House sometime instead?"
No word on whether the group will be rocking out at 1600 Pennsylvania Ave.
NO. 1 FAN
Obama congratulated the American team and midfielder Carli Lloyd for their victory on Sunday night in the Women's World Cup.
"What a win for Team USA!" Obama wrote, adding: "Your country is so proud of all of you. Come visit the White House with the World Cup soon."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:14:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dalai Lama celebrates 80th birthday in US</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e42d88/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cdalai0Elama0Ecelebrates0E80Ath0Ebirthday0Eus/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Dalai Lama has celebrated his 80th birthday in the United States.</Description>
        <MainBody>Dalai Lama celebrates 80th birthday in US
The Dalai Lama has celebrated his 80th birthday in the United States.
Source:
0
The 14th Dalai Lama, spiritual leader of Tibetan Buddhism, has turned 80 surrounded by admirers at a public summit in southern California.
The Dalai Lama, whose name is Tenzin Gyatso, celebrated on Monday at the Global Compassion Summit, a three-day conference in the cities of Anaheim and Irvine.
The monk spent the day as the guest of honour at public discussion panels on the subjects of climate change action and "wisdom, vision and experience" at the University of California, Irvine.
He was lauded by admirers from Nobel laureate Jody Williams to singer Gloria Estefan and applauded by the more than 5000 people in the audience.
At the conference's start the day before, thousands of fans sang Happy Birthday as the spiritual leader blew out candles on a towering golden cake, then cut himself a slice.
His birthday wish was "the same as all beings. I wish to live a happy life," he said on Sunday, according to his website.
"My life is dedicated to the well-being of others. If humanity is happy, then I'll be happy, because each of us is dependent on others," the Dalai Lama said.
Organisers began the celebration on Sunday, to mark the birthday in his birthplace of Tibet.
The Dalai Lama has lived in exile in Dharamsala, India, since 1959.
The Central Tibetan Authority, Tibet's government in exile, celebrated his birthday there according to the Tibetan calendar, on June 21.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:16:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boston Marathon bomber files for new trial</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e2062f/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cboston0Emarathon0Ebomber0Efiles0Enew0Etrial/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Lawyers for Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev have applied for a new trial, saying it is "required in the interests of justice".</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 8:00am
Boston Marathon bomber files for new trial
This courtroom sketch shows Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, right, stands before US District Judge George O'Toole Jr. as he addresses the court during his sentencing on June 24, 2015
Lawyers for Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev have applied for a new trial, saying it is "required in the interests of justice".
Source:
0
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev has filed a motion for a new trial, less than two weeks after he was formally sentenced to death for the 2013 attack.
Tsarnaev's lawyers filed a preliminary motion for a new trial on Monday for his conviction and death sentence. The motion did not contain any details on what grounds they plan to argue, saying only that a new trial is "required in the interests of justice."
The 21-year-old Tsarnaev was convicted of 30 charges in the bombing, which killed three people and injured more than 260.
The same jury recommended the death penalty, and a federal judge on June 24 sentenced him to death.
Tsarnaev's lawyers call the motion a "placeholder" until they can file a more detailed motion next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:09:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oreos go thin for &amp;#039;sophisticated&amp;#039; air</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e20630/sc/23/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Coreos0Ego0Ethin0Esophisticated0Eair/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Oreo Thins are being added to Mondelez International's permanent lineup as the company goes for a "grown-up" snack.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 6:04am
Oreos go thin for 'sophisticated' air
Oreo Thins are being added to Mondelez International's permanent lineup as the company goes for a "grown-up" snack.
Source:
0
Oreos are getting a skinny new look, and its maker says the new cookie is a "sophisticated" snack for grown-ups that isn't meant to be twisted or dunked.
Mondelez International Inc says it will add Oreo Thins to its permanent lineup in the US starting next week.
The cookies look like regular Oreos and have a similar cookie-to-filling ratio, except that they're slimmer.
That means four of the cookies contain 140 calories, compared with 160 calories for three regular Oreos.
And since they're for adults, Oreo says they weren't designed to be twisted open or dunked.
"If people want to do that, it's clearly up to them," said Janda Lukin, senior director of Oreo for North America at parent company Mondelez International.
In explaining what exactly made them more grown-up, she said that if regular Oreos are like pancakes, then Oreo Thins would be like crepes.
Although the original Oreos started in the US in 1912, Americans won't be the first to taste the Thins.
The slimmer cookies were rolled out last year in China to address the company's tumbling cookie sales in the country.
Lukin said the slimmer cookies helped win back "lapsed users" in China, or younger women who wanted something that wasn't quite as rich. In the first eight months, she said Oreo Thins generated $US40 million ($A53 million) in sales.
Mondelez CEO Irene Rosenfeld has noted the success of the Thins in China and says the company will make them available "around the world".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 00:58:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hillary Clinton accuses China of hacking US computers</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d646e5/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A50Chillary0Eclinton0Eaccuses0Echina0Ehacking0Eus0Ecomputers/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton accused China on Saturday of stealing commercial secrets and "huge amounts of government information," and of trying to "hack into everything that doesn't move in America."</Description>
        <MainBody>5 Jul 2015 - 7:58am
Hillary Clinton accuses China of hacking US computers
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Rodham Clinton speaks during a campaign event, Friday, July 3, 2015, in Hanover, N.H. (AP Photo/Elise Amendola)
U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton accused China on Saturday of stealing commercial secrets and "huge amounts of government information," and of trying to "hack into everything that doesn't move in America."
Source:
Reuters
5 Jul 2015 - 7:58 AM UPDATED5Jul2015-7:58AM
Clinton's language on China appeared to be far stronger thanthat usually used by President Barack Obama's Democraticadministration.
Speaking at a campaign event in New Hampshire, Clinton saidshe wanted to see China's peaceful rise.
"But we also have to be fully vigilant, China's military isgrowing very quickly, they're establishing militaryinstallations that again threaten countries we have treatieswith, like the Philippines because they are building oncontested property," said Clinton, who was secretary of statefrom 2009 to 2013.
"They're also trying to hack into everything that doesn'tmove in America. Stealing commercial secrets ... from defensecontractors, stealing huge amounts of government information,all looking for an advantage," she said.
Clinton is the front-runner to win the Democraticnomination for the November 2016 presidential election.
Asked about the remarks, a White House official declined tocomment.
In the most recent case involving suspicions of Chinesehacking, Obama administration officials have said China is thetop suspect in the massive hacking of a U.S. government agencythat compromised the personnel records of at least 4.2 millioncurrent and former government workers.
China has denied hacking into the computers of the U.S.Office of Personnel Management.
Iran and Putin
Clinton also addressed the current talks over Iran's nuclearprogram and had strong words for Tehran.
She said that even if a deal is reached with Iran, Tehran's"aggressiveness will not end" and it will remain a principalstate sponsor of terrorism.
Clinton said she hoped that "a strong verifiable deal" wouldbe reached at talks in Vienna between world powers and Iran.
But she added that even with an agreement, "They willcontinue to be the principal state sponsor of terrorism. Theywill continue to destabilize governments in the region andbeyond. They will continue to use their proxies like Hezbollah. And they will continue to be an existential threat to Israel."
The United States, other world powers and Iran have set aJuly 7 deadline to reach a deal to curb Tehran's nuclear programin exchange for a lifting of sanctions that have crippled Iran'seconomy.
At the campaign event, Clinton also said the United Stateshas to be "much smarter" about how it deals with RussianPresident Vladimir Putin's territorial ambitions.
She said Putin's moves to expand Russia's boundaries, suchas the annexation of Crimea last year, posed a challenge for theUnited States but she touted her experience as America's chiefdiplomat.
She noted that because of NATO members' agreement to protectfellow members, had Ukraine been a member of NATO when Crimeawas annexed, "that would have caused us to have to respond."
She added on Putin: "I've dealt with him. I know him. He'snot an easy man ... But I don't think there is any substituteother than constant engagement."
Reporting by Amanda Becker; Writing by Eric Beech; Editing byFrances Kerry and Tomasz Janowski.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 00:15:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Girl killed by jumping fish in Florida</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d662cb/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A50Cgirl0Ekilled0Ejumping0Efish0Eflorida/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A leaping sturgeon has struck and killed a five-year-old girl in a boat on Florida's Suwanne River.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 Jul 2015 - 7:24am
Girl killed by jumping fish in Florida
A leaping sturgeon has struck and killed a five-year-old girl in a boat on Florida's Suwanne River.
Source:
0
A five-year-old Florida girl riding in a boat has died after a sturgeon leapt from the Suwannee River and struck her.
Wildlife officials said Jaylon Rippy died after being struck on Thursday night. Her mother and nine-year-old brother were also injured and taken to a Gainesville hospital. Their condition was not known.
The Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission said it was the first fatality recorded from a sturgeon strike on the Suwannee River. Four people have been injured by jumping sturgeon this year.
The fish are known for leaping more than two metres above the water. They can grow up to 2.4 metres long, weigh up to 90kg and can cause serious injuries.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 18:54:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Truth commission on US invasion of Panama</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d26182/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Ctruth0Ecommission0Eus0Einvasion0Epanama/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A truth commission will examine the 1989 US invasion of Panama, the country's foreign minister says.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 3:07pm
Truth commission on US invasion of Panama
A relative of victims of the US invasion to Panama in 1989 adjusts a little flag as he visits a cemetery in Panama City
A truth commission will examine the 1989 US invasion of Panama, the country's foreign minister says.
Source:
0
A truth commission will examine the US invasion of Panama, which took place more than 25 years ago and toppled military dictator General Manuel Noriega.
The commission will look at victims of the military operation launched by the United States at the end of 1989, Panama Foreign Minister Isabel Saint Malo said.
The number of people estimated killed in operation Just Cause is more than 3000, including numerous civilians.
But the exact number of victims and their identities isn't known because many bodies were buried in mass graves.
After a long period of co-operation with the US, Noriega fell out of favour with the country toward the end of the 1980s because of his ties with the Medellin drug cartel and human rights abuses.
Noriega, 81, spent more than two decades in prison in the US and France on drug trafficking and money laundering charges.
He is serving out the last years of his sentence in Panama.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 18:33:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mexico close to releasing vigilante leader</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d2a3fe/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cmexico0Eclose0Ereleasing0Evigilante0Eleader/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mexican authorities may soon release a founder of the vigilante movement who fought against a powerful drug cartel in the western state of Michoacan.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 10:36am
Mexico close to releasing vigilante leader
Mexican authorities may soon release a founder of the vigilante movement who fought against a powerful drug cartel in the western state of Michoacan.
Source:
0
Mexican authorities say they are near to freeing Jose Manuel Mireles, a founder of the self-defence movement that rose up to fight an entrenched drug cartel in the western state of Michoacan.
The Attorney General's office says it is withdrawing an appeal to a petition filed by Mireles' lawyer to free him, essentially allowing his release.
Mireles, who became the face of the vigilante movement, has been held for a year after being arrested in an armoured vehicle carrying weapons and drugs.
His arrest came around the time that he refused to co-operate with the federal government's conversion of self-defence groups to rural police.
Michoacan's vigilante movement began in February 2013 after farmers and ranchers grew tired of the Knights Templar drug cartel's reign of kidnapping, murder and extortion.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 17:24:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NZ entrant takes on US hot dog comp rivals</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d259e1/sc/13/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cnz0Eentrant0Etakes0Eus0Ehot0Edog0Ecomp0Erivals/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>New Zealander Nela Zisser says she can out-eat her rivals in the US July Fourth hot dog eating contest.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 2:28pm
NZ entrant takes on US hot dog comp rivals
Brooklyn Borough President Eric Adams watches Joey Chestnut, left, and Matt Stonie, right, during a news conference to promote the upcoming Nathan's Famous Fourth of July Hot-Dog Eating Contest  Friday, July 3, 2015, at Brooklyn Borough Hall in New York. (AP Photo/Frank Franklin II)
New Zealander Nela Zisser says she can out-eat her rivals in the US July Fourth hot dog eating contest.
Source:
0
Four avid eaters, including a New Zealander, have hit the scales ahead of the United States' annual July Fourth hot dog eating contest at Coney Island's Nathan's Famous.
Reigning champion Joey Chestnut joined past winners at the weigh-in on Friday ahead of the 99-year-old Independence Day boardwalk tradition.
The hot dogs will be served on Saturday morning.
Chestnut tipped the scales at a hearty 230 pounds (104.33kg) while Michelle Lesco ranked the lightest competitor at 112 pounds (50.80kg).
New Zealand native Nela Zisser says she can out-eat her male counterparts. She previously won a pizza-eating contest.
The event also featured a ceremonial stare down between the competitors.
Chestnut broke a world record in 2013 when he scoffed down 69 soggy dogs in 10 minutes.
As an eight-year champion, he holds the Mustard Yellow International Belt after eating 61 hot dogs at last year's contest.
This year, he'll face off against former champ Takeru Kobayashi.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 17:22:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Mormon leader Boyd K Packer dies at 90</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d259e3/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cus0Emormon0Eleader0Eboyd0Ek0Epacker0Edies0E90A/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mormon leader Boyd K Packer has died at the age of 90, a church spokesman says.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 9:50am
US Mormon leader Boyd K Packer dies at 90
This April 6, 2014, file photo, shows President Boyd K. Packer, of the Quorum of Twelve Apostles, of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, addressing the 184th Annual General Conference of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, in Salt Lake City.  (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer, File)
Mormon leader Boyd K Packer has died at the age of 90, a church spokesman says.
Source:
0
Mormon leader Boyd K Packer, president of the faith's highest governing body, has died at the age of 90.
Packer died on Friday afternoon at his home in Salt Lake City from natural causes, church spokesman Eric Hawkins said in a statement.
Packer was next in line to become president of the Salt Lake City-based Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.
He had been a member of the church's Quorum of the Twelve Apostles since 1970.
The group is modelled after Jesus Christ's apostles and serves under the church president and his two councillors.
He is the second member of quorum to die in recent months. L Tom Perry died on May 30 from cancer.
Replacements for both of them are expected in the coming months, possibly at the church's conference in October.
Quorum member Russell M Nelson, 90, now becomes the leader who would take Mormon President Thomas S Monson's place.
Monson is 87 years old and church officials have said he's feeling the effects of his age.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 08:02:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wheelchair man charged with US bank theft</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d310ce/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cwheelchair0Eman0Echarged0Eus0Ebank0Etheft/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A man in a wheelchair, who is said to have robbed a New York bank, was recognised from police images when he went to a hospital two days after the theft.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 4:18pm
Wheelchair man charged with US bank theft
A man in a wheelchair, who is said to have robbed a New York bank, was recognised from police images when he went to a hospital two days after the theft.
Source:
0
A New York City man in a wheelchair has been arrested two days after he pocketed $US1212 ($A1585) in a daytime bank robbery, authorities say.
Kelvin Dennison, 23, was picked up by officers at a hospital two days after he rolled into a Santander Bank branch in Queens on Monday afternoon and claimed to be armed, police said.
"Give me all you have," he told a teller, according to court papers. "I have a gun."
The teller then passed him the cash before he pushed himself out of the bank and then fled down the street in his wheelchair, police said.
Authorities released an image of a man in a wheelchair leaving the bank taken from a store's surveillance camera.
When Dennison went to a Queens hospital two days later, someone recognised him and called police, prosecutors said.
Authorities didn't say why Dennison went to the hospital.
When he was questioned by investigators, Dennison told them he was in a wheelchair after being injured in a shooting, a spokeswoman for the Queens district attorney's office told the New York Times.
Dennison was charged with robbery and is being held on $US15,000 bail.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 04:17:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alligator kills swimmer in southern US</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d294a7/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Calligator0Ekills0Eswimmer0Esouthern0Eus/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US police say an alligator has killed a man in Texas.</Description>
        <MainBody>Alligator kills swimmer in southern US
(Stock/AAP)
US police say an alligator has killed a man in Texas.
Source:
A US man has been killed after being attacked by an alligator while he was swimming in a Texas bayou, news reports say.
The 28-year-old man ignored warning signs posted along the edge of the water, the reports said.
He was attacked immediately after jumping into the water, KFDM television in Beaumont, Texas reported, quoting eye-witnesses.
A female companion who had gone swimming with him tried to pull the screaming man out of the water.
She was uninjured.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
