<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="scrippsobfeeds">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:47:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore mayor fires police commissioner</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/baltimore-mayor-fires-police-commissioner-amid-homicide-rise</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Baltimore mayor fires police commissioner amid homicide rise
Juliet Linderman, Associated Press
8:47 PM, Jul 8, 2015
Previous
Next
FILE - In this April 30, 2015, file photo, Baltimore Police Department Commissioner Anthony Batts listens as Deputy Commissioner Kevin Davis speaks at a news conference, in Baltimore. Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake announced the firing of Batts in a news release Wednesday, July 8. (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky, File)
Patrick Semansky
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake, right, listens as Interim Baltimore Police Department Commissioner Kevin Davis speaks at a news conference, Wednesday, July 8, 2015, in Baltimore, after Rawlings-Blake announced her firing of Commissioner Anthony Batts. (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky)
Patrick Semansky
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Interim Baltimore Police Department Commissioner Kevin Davis, left, listens to Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake at a news conference, Wednesday, July 8, 2015, in Baltimore. Rawlings-Blake announced that she fired Commissioner Anthony Batts. (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky)
Patrick Semansky
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
BALTIMORE - Baltimore's mayor fired the troubled city's police commissioner Wednesday, saying that a recent spike in homicides in the weeks after an unarmed black man died of injuries in police custody required a change in leadership.
Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake thanked Police Commissioner Anthony Batts for his service  and praised the job he had done  but said growing criticism of his performance had become a "distraction" that was preventing the city from moving ahead.
Deputy Police Commissioner Kevin Davis, who has only been with the department since January, will serve as interim commissioner, Rawlings-Blake said.
"We need a change," the mayor told a news conference, which was attended by Davis. "This was not an easy decision but it is one that is in the best interest of Baltimore. The people of Baltimore deserve better and we're going to get better."
The firing comes 2 1/2 months after the city broke out in riots following the death of Freddie Gray, who died in April of injuries he received in police custody. Six police officers have been criminally charged in Gray's death.
After the unrest, arrests in the city plummeted and homicides spiked. Baltimore's homicide total this year is 155, according to police. That's a 48 percent increase compared with the same time last year. Shootings have increased 86 percent. In one of the latest examples, gunmen jumped out of two vans and fired at a group of people a few blocks from an urban university campus Tuesday night, killing three people.
Police said Wednesday that the shooting wasn't random, but no arrests have been made.
"As we have seen in recent weeks, too many continue to die on our streets," Rawlings-Blake said. Referring to Batts, she said "recent events proved that his being here was a distraction."
"We cannot continue to debate the leadership of the department," the mayor said. "We cannot continue to have the level of violence we've seen in recent weeks in this city."
Batts and Rawlings-Blake are African-American, as is the city's top prosecutor, Baltimore State's Attorney Marilyn Mosby. Davis is white. Sixty percent of the city's population is black, while the police department is 48 percent African-American.
Mosby said her office has already met with Davis and she looks forward to working with him.
The Rev. Alvin Gwynn Sr., president of the city's Interdenominational Ministerial Alliance, said the firing was long overdue. Gwynn, who began calling for Batts' resignation within days of Gray's death, blamed the bloody spike in violence on the mayor's previous reluctance to fire the commissioner.
"We have people who died because they delayed," he said Wednesday.
Keonna Stokes, 22, a resident of the housing development in front of which Gray was arrested, said she was glad to see Batts removed from his position, and hopes a new commissioner will have a lower tolerance for police misconduct.
"The police wouldn't do the things they do if the commissioner didn't allow it," she said. "He should have been fired. We call the police when we really need them, when people hurt us. But now we don't call them, because they hurt us. If they didn't Freddie would still be here."
The U.S. Justice Department is conducting a civil rights review of the department, and on Tuesday, Batts announced that an outside organization will review the police response to the civil unrest that followed Gray's death. Most of the unrest took place on April 27, prompted by Gray's death on April 19.
The Baltimore police union released its own scathing post-mortem report Tuesday accusing Batts and other top brass of instructing officers not to engage with rioters and to allow looting and destruction to occur.
"The officers repeatedly expressed concern that the passive response of the Baltimore police commanders to the civil unrest allowed the disorder to grow into full-scale rioting," Gene Ryan, president of the Baltimore Fraternal Order of Police Lodge 3, wrote in the report.
Following Batts' firing Wednesday, the union issued a statement reiterating the report's concerns but also said it would work with Davis to improve the situation.
Davis was previously chief of police in Anne Arundel County, Maryland, and assistant chief in Prince George's County, Maryland. The mayor said that in addition to reducing crime, Davis would "bring accountability to police, hold officers who act out of line accountable for their actions."
Rod J. Rosenstein, U.S. Attorney for Maryland, praised Davis, saying he helped reform the Prince George's County Police Department, "raising morale and professionalism while dramatically reducing crime."
In his own remarks to the news conference, Davis said his goals would include improving the relationship with the officers who work for him. "I will walk with them and serve with them and be with them every step of the way," he said.
But Davis also has indicated a willingness in the past to speak out against police abuses.
As Anne Arundel chief, he issued a news release disagreeing with a decision by the county Fraternal Order of Police Lodge 70 to donate $1,070 to a defense fund for Officer Darren Wilson in Ferguson, Missouri. Wilson, who is white, fatally shot Michael Brown, an unarmed black man, on Aug. 9.
Rawlings-Blake appointed Batts as police commissioner in September 2012.
His contract with the city paid him $190,000 and was to run through June 2020. It includes a provision for a severance payment equal to his annual salary if he is terminated without cause.
Hours after he was fired, Batts sent a short statement to the Baltimore Sun.
"I've been honored to serve the citizens and residents of Baltimore," he said. "I've been proud to be a police officer for this city."
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:26:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More restaurant space coming to Estero</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-government/more-restaurant-space-coming-to-estero_51895736</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>More restaurant space coming to Estero
Maryann Batlle
8:26 PM, Jul 8, 2015
2 hours ago
local government
Estero shot glasses and pens are handed out at an election night event at the Elks Lodge in Bonita Springs on Nov. 4. Residents voted to approve incorporation, which will make the Village of Estero a new city. Carolina Hidalgo/Staff
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Next
ESTERO, Fla. - A Nevada developer intends to build more restaurant space in Estero.
CFT NV Developments LLC, of Las Vegas, owns almost two commercial acres along Lyden Drive. The vacant property is just east of the Marsh Landing community and is across U.S. 41 from Coconut Points main entrance.
The developer has applied for permission to build two adjacent restaurants to create the Shoppes of Coconut Trace. The first eatery would be 2,452 square feet. The second would be 3,248 square feet. Plans also include a 7,480 square foot future building pad.
At a Wednesday public information hearing hosted by the Estero Design Review Board, project architects said the restaurants would fall somewhere on the scale between fast food and fine dining.
They indicated the developer has some idea what those tenant restaurants may ultimately be but shared no official names.
Joe McHarris, a member of design review board, cautioned project architects to look beyond their own property when choosing visual elements such as paint colors.
Right across the street is your competition, so were going to want to see some thought about how your project relates to that, said McHarris.
The project has to come before the Design Review Board at least one more time for a vote.
Another Estero project in the works is a temporary sales center for a proposed 205-unit multi-family project known as Genova.
Genovas developers want to build the housing project and the temporary sales center on an about 17-acre property on the southeast corner of Via Coconut Point and Corkscrew Road.
The location had been home to The Farm, a local fresh produce and U-Pick operation that leased the land.
The 2,200 square foot Genova sales center would sit on a northeast corner of property that is zoned for commercial use. The sales center will also have its own parking lot and buffer landscaping.
Though temporary, the sales center would be constructed like any other permanent, Mediterranean-style structure in the village because of building rules in Estero, said Jim Wallace, Genovas developer.
The sales center will use temporary signs though, he said.
The intent is to tear down the sales center about two years after building it, Wallace said.
Esteros Design Review Board will meet with Wallace and Genovas architects in public at least once more before making a decision.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:01:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lee Memorial presents plans for Estero, Bonita</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-government/growth-spurts-continue-in-bonita-and-estero_53597118</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Next
Patrick RIley
Business owners, city officials and members of the public gathered at the Bonita Springs Chamber of Commerce on Wednesday, July 8, 2015, for the Bonita Springs-Estero Economic Development Council's second quarterly open meeting. The meeting included a presentation by Lee Memorial Health System about two upcoming expansion projects in South Lee County. (Patrick Riley/Staff)
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
There seems to be no end in sight to South Lee Countys recent growth spurts.
As new senior housing facilities and corporate headquarters continue to sprout up in both Estero and Bonita Springs, residents can soon look forward to new medical facilities in their backyard.
Lee Memorial Health System officials Wednesday presented business owners, city officials and members of the public at the Bonita Springs Estero Economic Development Councils second quarterly open meeting with updates to plans that will bring a comprehensive medical village to Coconut Point and medical practices to Bonita Bays lifestyle center.
In 2005, 2006, Lee Memorial Health System recognized that South Lee County was the next hot pocket of growth in Lee County, said Suzanne Bradach, special projects manager for Lee Memorial, to open her 30-minute power point presentation on the two expansion projects. And so we acquired about 31 acres located right behind the Bonita Community Health Center in Estero.
After the original plan to build an 80-bed hospital on the land had to be tossed out because it did not get state approval, Lee Memorial shifted its focus to building a 136,900 square foot medical campus that will include specialty care physicians, primary care physicians, a freestanding 24/7 emergency room, surgery center, a healthy life center for chronic disease management, a clinical-decision support unit to hold patients for under 24 hours and ancillary services, such as imaging, rehab and laboratories.
We started to rethink how we could deliver health care in a unique and progressive way, Bradach said. We want it to be a health and wellness destination.
The price tag for the project is estimated at $70 million, Bradach said, and requests for qualifications from architects and construction management firms have been sent out and are expected back by July 16.
So far some 40 firms have expressed interest, and the top three in each category will be selected to present their proposals in late August.
Once contracts are approved in October, Bradach said, a nine-month long design process will start the following month with construction expected to begin in February 2017. The facility will open in mid-2018 and create between 200 and 250 new jobs, Bradach said.
The design of the project will be sensitive to Esteros aesthetic guidelines.
Were going to try to keep that kind of Mediterranean flowing campuslike feel to the best of our ability, Bradach said.
Additionally, in collaboration with Bonita Bay, Lee Memorial will soon open an integrative medicine practice, internal medicine practice and rehabilitation center on the third floor of the Bonita Bay Lifestyle Center located at 26800 U.S. 41 S., north of the Promenade Shopping Center.
Integrative medicine takes both the Eastern and Western approach to a persons health, Bradach said, adding that it combines spiritual and medical aspects. It looks at the whole entire person and not just a piece of the body.
The third floor of the Bonita Bay-owned facility will house a fellowship-trained physician, primary care physicians and a rehab team and will be open to the public, Bradach said. It is expected to open in about a month.
Bonita Springs Councilman Bill Lonkart, who was one of the dozens in attendance Wednesday, said both projects are needed.
Its a great idea, Lonkart said. 70 percent of the people [in Bonita] that have to go to the hospital go to a Naples location.
So its a good thing. Its going to be a modern thing.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Effort would tap disaster fund for wildfires</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/politics/house-gop-effort-would-tap-disaster-fund-for-some-wildfires</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>House GOP effort would tap disaster fund for some wildfires
Kevin Freking, Associated Press
7:47 PM, Jul 8, 2015
FILE - In this Aug. 25, 2013 file photo, firefighter A.J. Tevis watches the flames of the Rim Fire near Yosemite National Park, Calif. House Republicans are proposing that some forest fires be treated like federal disasters, an attempt to win broader support for legislation that targets overgrown national forest lands. Robert Bonnie, who oversees natural resource issues at the Agriculture Department, said fires such as the "Rim Fire" should be treated as federal disasters regardless of when they occur. (AP Photo/Jae C. Hong, File)
Jae C. Hong
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
WASHINGTON - House Republicans are proposing that some forest fires be treated like federal disasters, an attempt to win broader support for legislation that targets overgrown national forest lands.
The legislation focuses on speeding up timber harvests and the removal of underbrush the Forest Service deems necessary to improving the health of a forest. Some Democratic lawmakers and environmental groups have been critical of the bill because they say it would erode key environmental safeguards.
With a House vote expected this week, GOP lawmakers added the federal disaster language to the bill, something the Obama administration first proposed early last year, but with some key differences.
Under current policy, the agencies fighting wildfires divert money toward firefighting from other programs during particularly busy years. But that practice delays the very efforts designed to prevent fires in the first place, such as the thinning of dead trees and the removal of thick underbrush. Supporters say that letting federal agencies tap into a disaster fund will prevent such borrowing and lessen the risk of catastrophic forest fires in the coming years.
This year's fire season appears to be shaping up as a busy one, adding some urgency to tackling the funding problem. A report Monday from the National Interagency Fire Center showed 51 active large fires across 10 states, with more than half taking place in Alaska and Washington.
"My colleagues on both sides of the aisle agree that current efforts to combat the growing threat of catastrophic wildfires are failing our communities. This package charts a new course," said Rep. Rob Bishop, R-Utah., the chairman of the House Natural Resources Committee.
Bishop said the bill should garner broad support. But Robert Bonnie, who oversees natural resource issues at the Agriculture Department, which houses the Forest Service, indicated the GOP has more work to do to win over the administration.
He described the bill as a step forward but said the changes don't go far enough to address financial challenges that the Forest Service faces as more and more of its budget is eaten up by fighting forest fires.
The White House issued a statement Wednesday afternoon strongly objecting to the bill, which it said "falls short of fixing the fire budget problem" and undermines public trust in forest management projects.
One of the biggest differences between what House Republicans are backing and what the administration proposed is when federal agencies could tap into a disaster account.
The government estimates its firefighting needs based on the average costs of the 10 previous years. The administration supports funding the agencies at 70 percent of the 10-year average and using the Federal Emergency Management Agency's disaster fund to cover the cost of fighting other fires. The certainty of that funding will allow federal agencies to director more resources toward treating forests before fires occur.
Bonnie said fires such as the "Rim Fire" in California two years ago should be treated as federal disasters regardless of when they occur. That fire scorched 400 square miles and cost $125 million to fight.
"You can give the Forest Service new authority, but unless you solve the budget problem, the Forest Service lacks the resources to increase the pace and scale of forest restoration," Bonnie said.
House Republicans would let the agencies tap into a disaster fund only after they've exhausted that year's firefighting budget, and the extra money could only be used for putting out fires. The money would also be part of a separate account within FEMA so that it wouldn't take money from recovery efforts for hurricanes, tornadoes and other natural disasters.
And while the administration wants to put more money into treating forests before fires occur, the House bill is focused on lowering regulatory hurdles to speed timbering projects. Also, House Republicans want to require that groups suing the federal government over a thinning project buy an insurance bond in the event they lose. That way, the federal government could recoup the expense of defending itself in court. Rep. Jared Polis, D-Colo., said the provision will be a "poison pill" for many Democratic lawmakers.
Bonnie cited the bonding requirement as one of the most troubling provisions in the bill. Still, he sought to maintain an environment where the two sides could potentially iron out some of their differences.
"We want to work with them," Bonnie said. "The current design of those provisions we think can be a lot better."
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:36:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rubio inspires, yet experience question lingers</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national-elections/rubio-inspires-yet-experience-question-lingers</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Rubio inspires, yet experience question lingers
Steve Peoples, Associated Press
7:36 PM, Jul 8, 2015
Presidential hopeful Marco Rubio speaks to a crowd of people attending a fundraiser for Iowa House Representative Chris Hagenow on Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at the Windsor Heights Community Center in Windsor Heights, Iowa. (Kelsey Kremer/The Des Moines Register via AP)
Kelsey Kremer
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
URBANDALE, Iowa - Marco Rubio is campaigning for president on the promise of a better future and on his powerful personal story about the American Dream.
As he treks across Iowa this week, however, he often leaves unmentioned a record of accomplishment that is thin next to that of some rivals, thanks to his youth if nothing else. Opponents compare him to another rookie senator who sought the White House: Barack Obama.
"These are major differences between me and the person who's there now, and I hope you'll see that in the weeks and months ahead," Rubio, 44, told an Iowa voter Wednesday who raised the comparison.
Yet as Iowa's February caucuses approach, a clearer picture is emerging of the rationale behind a Rubio candidacy that draws heavily from Obama's playbook. The Republican senator's principal appeal to voters relies not on his governing experience or proven accomplishment, but on the less tangible markers of leadership and ability to inspire.
"The presidency is not a bookkeeping office  it is much more than just an administrative position," he said in an interview with The Associated Press. "It is also someone of capable of leading our country and our people to take on the great causes of our time, to rally and unify the country behind the great challenges we have."
Experience matters, Iowa voters say, and national polls suggest. Particularly in a 2016 Republican contest with more than a dozen candidates with tangible accomplishments to run on.
Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker, for example, transformed his state labor laws while enacting deep tax cuts. Jeb Bush aggressively cut spending while overhauling Florida's education system as governor.
"Relative to our current president, Rubio has plenty of experience," said Mary Kramer, a former ambassador to the eastern Caribbean who attended a Rubio event Wednesday. "Relative to some other people in the Republican field, not so much." She favors Bush.
Indeed, Rubio has no executive experience. An attorney by trade, he was elected to the Florida Statehouse in 2000 and became a U.S. senator in 2011.
In response to a request from The Associated Press, he released a list of his legislative accomplishments. The list may highlight his challenge.
The freshman senator has been the lead sponsor of just one bill that became law in the last four and a half years. The law, crafted with Sen. Jeanne Shaheen, D, N.H., establishes birth registries in developing countries to support the rights of women and girls.
Rubio's campaign says he has also "been key" on two other laws, one that imposed new sanctions on Venezuela for human rights abuses in December, and another in 2014 that overhauled the Department of Veterans Affairs.
Rubio was on the conference committee that crafted the final version of the VA bill. Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders, a Democratic presidential candidate who chaired the Senate Veterans Affairs Committee, did much of the heavy lifting along with two Republicans, Sen. John McCain of Arizona and Rep. Jeff Miller of Florida.
He was an architect of an immigration proposal that would have created a pathway to citizenship for immigrants in the country illegally and brought other sweeping changes to the immigration system, but was blocked by his own party. It's not something he highlights now.
His team calls him a "key co-sponsor" on 16 additional pieces of legislation, a varied list that addresses sex trafficking, the U.S.-Israel partnership, a stamp to raise money for breast cancer research, regulation of pilots, and more. In many of those cases, Rubio was among dozens of Senate co-sponsors.
Rubio blames Senate Democrats for the short list: "In the first four years I was in the Senate nothing passed because Harry Reid basically shut down the Senate," he said.
If he is proud of his accomplishments on Capitol Hill, there is little sign of it as he campaigns. He typically spends just a minute or two talking about more than a decade in elected office and often avoids his experience in Congress altogether.
But the voter who raised similarities to Obama left him no choice but to talk about it.
Rubio called Obama "a backbencher" in Illinois' minority party who often avoided tough votes. "I was the speaker of the Florida House," Rubio said. "I led that institution both legislatively and administratively. I ran it."
Rubio also pointed out Obama had served just two years in the Senate when he launched his presidential campaign. Rubio will be coming up on a full six-year term by Election Day next year.
In a Pew poll in March, nearly 60 percent of Republicans said "experience and a proven record" in a presidential candidate is more important than "new ideas and a different approach."
State Sen. Jack Whitver, chairman of Rubio's Iowa campaign, says charisma is most important because "you need someone that's going to inspire the country if you want to accomplish anything."
Paula Mayheim, a 65-year-old Republican from Des Moines who attended Rubio's Urbandale event, sees it another way. "He's young. He's exciting. He brings new ideas to the table," she said. But "I just don't think he has the experience."
Whether he does or doesn't, he'll have the money to get his message out.
The Rubio campaign must report its initial fundraising totals by next week, but two allied outside groups say they have raised more than $30 million.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rep. Grayson to enter race for Sen. Rubio's seat</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/politics/florida-rep-grayson-to-enter-race-for-sen-rubios-seat</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Florida Rep. Grayson to enter race for Sen. Rubio's seat
Brendan Farrington, Associated Press
7:28 PM, Jul 8, 2015
FILE - In this Oct. 1, 2009, file photo, Rep. Alan Grayson, D-Fla., listens during a hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington. Grayson will enter the race to replace Republican Sen. Marco Rubio, a close friend and major Democratic Party donor said Wednesday. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci, File)
Evan Vucci
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
TALLAHASSEE - U.S. Rep. Alan Grayson, an unapologetically outspoken critic of Republicans who calls himself a congressman with guts, will enter the race to replace Republican Sen. Marco Rubio, a close friend and major Democratic Party donor said Wednesday.
Trial lawyer John Morgan said he exchanged a series of emails with Grayson in which the congressman confirmed he is going to seek the seat Rubio is giving up to run for president and asked for Morgan's help with the campaign. The announcement will be made Thursday morning.
"He's going to do it," Morgan said.
His entry into the race will set up a primary pitting a darling of the far left wing of the Democratic Party against lesser-known U.S. Rep. Patrick Murphy, a former Republican who is running as a moderate.
While many Democratic leaders fear Grayson is too divisive to win a general election, he has built a national support base through his blunt assessment of the Republican Party and the tea party movement.
Grayson, 57, is known for using fiery rhetoric to knock down opponents. He made headlines for describing the GOP health plan as "don't get sick, and if you do get sick, die quickly." He called a Republic opponent "Taliban Dan" in an effort to paint him as a religious extremist for his conservative Christian beliefs and compared the tea party to the Ku Klux Klan.
He's also been involved in a messy divorce that has created unflattering headlines, and recently critics have raised ethical questions about three hedge funds he created.
Morgan said he encouraged Grayson not to run, both during a lunch several weeks ago and in their email exchanges. He said Grayson replied that he needed help, not advice.
"Alan Grayson right now has a great position in America," Morgan said. "I told him he's in a unique positon. He is in a safe district, he has a national voice and he serves a lot of good for the progressive cause and he's unelectable statewide."
Grayson was first elected in 2008, then lost his seat to current U.S. Rep. Dan Webster. Grayson returned to Congress two years later running in a new, safely Democratic district.
On the Republican side, U.S. Rep. Ron DeSantis has announced he is running, and Lt. Gov. Carlos Lopez-Cantera and U.S. Rep. Jeff Miller are considering runs.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:24:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI probing Broward deputy's shooting of man</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/fbi-probing-broward-deputys-shooting-of-man-with-air-rifle</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FBI probing Broward deputy's shooting of man with air rifle
Curt Anderson, Associated Press
7:24 PM, Jul 8, 2015
In this photo taken on June 19, 2007, released by Jennifer Young, her son Jermaine McBean poses with his grandmother Sylvia Mc Donald at McBean's graduation from Pace University, in New York. McBean was shot by a Broward County Sheriff Deputy after several people called 911 to report a suspicious person carrying a gun down a busy street. McBean was carrying an air rifle when he was shot while entering an apartment complex, where he lived in Florida. (Jennifer Young via AP)
Jennifer Young
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
MIAMI - The FBI has opened an investigation into the fatal 2013 shooting by a sheriff's deputy of a man carrying an air rifle who may not have heard commands to drop it because he was listening to music through earbuds.
The FBI's top agent in South Florida told Broward Sheriff Scott Israel about its investigation into Jermaine McBean's death in a recent letter. The letter was included in a filing Tuesday by the sheriff's office in a civil lawsuit brought by McBean's family. Agent George Piro said the Justice Department's Civil Rights Division asked the FBI to open the probe after receiving a complaint.
"The Department of Justice has requested that the FBI review the incident to determine if McBean's civil rights were violated," Piro said in the June 26 letter.
McBean, 33, was shot July 31, 2013, outside his apartment complex near Fort Lauderdale by Deputy Peter Peraza after 911 callers reported a man openly carrying what appeared to be a real rifle down a busy street. McBean's family says it's likely the music in his earbuds prevented him from hearing commands by deputies to drop what they later discovered was an authentic-looking air rifle.
State prosecutors are also investigating the shooting and intend to take the case before a grand jury for possible criminal charges. The FBI civil rights probe, which could result in federal criminal charges, would focus on whether Peraza used excessive force in a "willful" or "unreasonable" manner, according to the bureau.
Peraza insisted in a sworn statement he never noticed any earbuds. But a photo taken by an apartment resident after the shooting clearly shows them in at least one of McBean's ears. It's not clear why McBean decided to buy the air rifle that day at a pawn shop and walk back to his apartment carrying it in open view.
The wrongful death lawsuit  filed in May in federal court against Israel, Peraza and Broward County  contends among other things that law enforcement officials covered up evidence about the earbuds, which were found later in McBean's pocket. The sheriff has denied any improprieties in the deputies' actions.
Attorney David Schoen, who represents McBean's mother and brothers, said in an email Wednesday that the family welcomes the FBI probe and hopes that it will "bring to justice the shooter and anyone else responsible for the cover-up."
"The man who shot and killed Jermaine remains on the street with a gun and a badge," Schoen added.
The FBI letter was attached to a filing seeking a temporary halt in the family's lawsuit because of the ongoing criminal investigations. Schoen said the family opposes any delays. A judge did not immediately rule on the request.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:34:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Collier deputy tops in nation at helping kids</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/collier-deputy-tops-in-nation-when-it-comes-to-helping-kids_46858104</Link>
        <Description>When it comes to making a difference in the lives of kids, Collier County Cpl. Ken Vila is the best in the country. And he's got the awards to prove it.</Description>
        <MainBody>Collier deputy tops in nation when it comes to helping kids
Katie Egan
local news
ONeill, Jon
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
When it comes to making a difference in the lives of kids, Collier County Cpl. Ken Vila is the best in the country. And he's got the awards to prove it.
Vila has been named the 2015 National D.A.R.E. Officer of the Year, honoring him as the top officer in a program that aims to keep kids away from drugs and out of other teen dramas, like gangs and cyberbullying.
For Vila, 52, helping kids has been a theme throughout his law enforcement career.
"I think it's my personality," he said in a phone interview. "I'm also a third generation law enforcement officer. Something I've always striven to do is help other people. It's something I just enjoy doing."
Youth Relations Capt. Beth Jones agreed.
"That's probably one of the reasons why he's been in Youth Relations," she said. "That's where he feels he can do the most good. As he interacts with kids, he treats them with respect and develops relationships with them."
In addition to the national honor, Vila also has been named as the premier D.A.R.E. officer in Florida.
"It was surreal. I called my wife and said, Hey, what do you think about this?' She was hugely supportive. I try to be as humble as I can," he said. "It's such an honor."
Vila credits his supervisors, fellow deputies and Collier County educators with helping him win the awards.
"We're all on the same mission," he said. "We're all just spokes in the wheel."
D.A.R.E. stands for Drug Abuse Resistance Education, and it's a national program that teaches fifth-graders how to avoid drugs, alcohol, tobacco use, over-the-counter and prescription drugs, bullying, gangs, cyberbullying, violence and other negative activities.
Fifth-graders are at an impressionable age, Vila said, because they're in an "exit grade." When they enter middle school, he said, they will be subjected to more temptation.
Vila began his law enforcement career with the Collier County Sheriff's Office in 1989 and has been a youth relations deputy since. He's been a D.A.R.E. instructor for a little over two decades.
"I do think it's important. It's the future," he said. "It's so clich, but it's the truth."
Vila says it touches his heart when students from twenty-something years ago see him around town and still remember him.
"It makes me realize I'm doing something right. I'm being a good guy and they see that," he said. "The way we present ourselves to people is huge. We have to be the counselor and the parent to them and who knows what issue they're dealing with at home. You could be that person who says hi to them and make a difference in their lives."
Vila became a certified D.A.R.E. instructor in 1993. In 2012, he became a D.A.R.E. mentor, meaning he teaches the program to other deputies. D.A.R.E. has changed a lot since its early days.
"If you asked someone years ago, What do you know about D. A. R. E.? They'd probably say it's about drugs," Vila said. "But it's completely different now and there's only one real lesson about drugs. All the other lessons are about being a good person, helpful, making the right decision and being a good citizen.
"If you can be good person, make the right decisions and pick good friends, the chances of you being involved in drugs and alcohol are much less."
In August, Vila will travel to New Orleans to get his national award. Monday, Collier Sheriff Kevin Rambosk. gave Vila the honor as Florida's top D.A.R.E. cop.
"Without exception, Cpl. Vila has molded and influenced at least two generations of Collier County citizens," Rambosk said in a news release. "No question, Cpl. Vila is certainly the go-to-guy when it comes to D.A.R.E."
For Vila, the real rewards come from the doing the job itself. The awards are just an affirmation of the difference he's made.
"I walked away thinking, Oh jeez, Ken, it didn't take you 25 years to make a difference. It took you 25 years to realize that you did."
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:31:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dream job: Dust, sweat and horse manure</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/for-naples-man-job-of-a-lifetime-means-dust-sweat-and-horse-manure_54797052</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>For Naples man, job of a lifetime means dust, sweat and horse manure
Alexi C. Cardona
6:31 PM, Jul 8, 2015
4 hours ago
Previous
Next
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, files the hoof of "Buddy," a 20-year-old quarter horse, who tries to lick his ear, was outfitted with new shoes, Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro bull rider, Alaskan commercial fisherman, dental
Corey Perrine
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, works to size up a hot shoe on "Snickers," a 20-year-old quarter horse, Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. Snickers, because of her personality, was being fickle and was resisting the reshoeing. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro
Corey Perrine
Horseshoes are seen Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro bull rider, Alaskan commercial fisherman, dental technician, tree trimmer, equipment and truck operator, feed store owner and lawn care business owner. "Nobody wants to do this job because
Corey Perrine
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, works out "Snickers," a 20-year-old quarter horse, as Thomas "Spider" Eppley, Assistant Barn Manager, looks on Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. Snickers, because of her personality, was being fickle and was resisting the reshoeing. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years
Corey Perrine
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, walks back from a water break to work on "Snickers," a 20-year-old quarter horse, not shown, Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro bull rider, Alaskan commercial fisherman, dental technician, tree
Corey Perrine
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, works on a horseshoe Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro bull rider, Alaskan commercial fisherman, dental technician, tree trimmer, equipment and truck operator, feed store owner and lawn care
Corey Perrine
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, works to get the shoe on "Snickers," a 20-year-old quarter horse, Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. Snickers, because of her personality, was being fickle and was resisting the reshoeing. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro bull
Corey Perrine
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, files the hoof of "Buddy," a 20-year-old Quarter Horse, who was just outfitted with new shoes, Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro bull rider, Alaskan commercial fisherman, dental technician, tree
Corey Perrine
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, reshoes the hoof of "Buddy," a 20-year-old Quarter Horse, Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro bull rider, Alaskan commercial fisherman, dental technician, tree trimmer, equipment and truck operator,
Corey Perrine
Scott Weidner of his self-named farrier services, shows his working hands Tuesday, July 7, 2015 at Naples Equestrian Challenge in Naples, Fla. The camp is currently hosting its 16th annual inclusion camp, a week-long program for special needs and normally developing persons 4-16 years of age. The camp runs through the end of the month. Weidner, 44, a Naples native, has been in the farrier industry for the past 10 years and has worked many jobs including pro bull rider, Alaskan commercial fisherman, dental technician, tree trimmer, equipment and truck operator, feed store owner and lawn care
Corey Perrine
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:59:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Medicare to cover end-of-life counseling</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/health/medicare-to-cover-end-of-life-counseling</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Medicare to cover end-of-life counseling
Matt Sedensky and Ricardo Alonso-Zaldivar, Associated Press
5:59 PM, Jul 8, 2015
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
WASHINGTON - Medicare said Wednesday it plans to pay doctors to counsel patients about end-of-life care, the same idea that sparked accusations of "death panels" and fanned a political furor around President Barack Obama's health care law six years ago.
The policy change, to take effect Jan. 1, was tucked into a massive regulation on payments for doctors. It suggests that what many doctors regard as a common-sense option is no longer seen by the Obama administration as politically toxic. Counseling would be entirely voluntary for patients.
Some doctors already have such conversations with their patients without billing extra. Certain private insurers have begun offering reimbursement. But an opening to roughly 55 million Medicare beneficiaries could make such talks far more common. About three-quarters of the people who die each year in the U.S. are 65 and older, making Medicare the largest insurer at the end of life, according to the Kaiser Family Foundation.
"As a practicing physician, and a son, and someone who has dealt with this in his own family, I would say these are discussions ... that are critical to high-quality care," said Patrick Conway, Medicare's chief medical officer. "I would want any American who wanted to have this conversation with their clinician to have the opportunity to do so."
Medicare is using a relatively new term for end-of-life counseling: advance care planning. That's meant to reflect expert advice that people should make their wishes known about end-of-life care at different stages of their lives, as early as when they get a driver's license.
The counseling aims to discern the type of treatment patients want in their last days, with options ranging from care that's more focused on comfort than extending life to all-out medical efforts to resuscitate a dying patient.
Before former Alaska Gov. Sarah Palin ignited the "death panels" outcry, there was longstanding bipartisan consensus about helping people to better understand their end-of-life choices and decisions.
A 1992 law passed under Republican President George H.W. Bush requires hospitals and nursing homes to help patients who want to prepare living wills and advance directives. Similar efforts gained resonance after the 2005 death of Terri Schiavo, the brain-damaged Florida woman whose family fought for years over whether she'd want to be kept alive in a vegetative state.
Then-Florida Gov. Jeb Bush got embroiled in the family's ordeal, ordering feeding tubes reinserted for Schiavo against her husband's wishes. The husband ultimately prevailed in a legal battle with Schiavo's parents, who wanted her kept alive.
In 2008, a year before debate over the Affordable Care Act spiraled into tea-party protests, Congress overwhelmingly passed legislation requiring doctors to discuss issues like living wills with new Medicare enrollees.
And, just months before being tapped as running mate for GOP presidential nominee John McCain, Palin herself signed a proclamation recognizing Healthcare Decision Day in Alaska, with the goal of a statewide effort of spreading the word about the importance of advance directives.
That history dissipated almost instantly when Palin said the provision on end-of-life conversations in Obama's health care legislation would result in bureaucrats deciding whether sick people get to live. The language, modeled after a bill by Rep. Earl Blumenauer, D-Oregon, was ultimately removed.
Blumenauer said Wednesday the nation now seems to have come to a consensus. "There was a time when the federal government could have been a leader on this, but now it's basically responding to where the rest of America is going," he said.
Nothing in the discussions approved by Medicare will be focused on cost, but many experts believe if patients truly understood their alternatives, and doctors listened to them, bills would inherently go down.
A landmark report last year from the Institute of Medicine found that few people make their wishes known and too many deaths are filled with breathing machines, feeding tubes, powerful drugs and other treatments that fail to extend life and make its final chapter more painful and unpleasant. The report was called "Dying in America," and the institute  an independent organization that advises the government  has a section on its website distilling the issues for families.
After the report, Medicare said it would consider a change in policy for 2016.
"End-of-life discussions should be part of the life cycle," said Dr. Philip Pizzo, former dean of Stanford University medical school and the report's co-chair. "Beginning Medicare is one of those times, since it can be a point of awareness and reflection."
Supporters say counseling would give patients more control and free families from tortuous decisions. Even so, there are often no simple answers. Patients may want less invasive care if they believe they will soon die, but predicting when death will happen is notoriously inexact. Terminal patients can live for years, potentially complicating a choice of less intensive treatment.
Interested parties will have 60 days to comment on the new regulation before it is finalized.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:42:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Video: Emergency responders also cause crashes</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/video-daily-news-analyzes-crashes-involving-emergency-responders</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>5:42 PM, Jul 8, 2015
Previous
Next
Ryan Mills
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
In 2013, two unborn babies were killed in crashes caused by distracted Southwest Florida emergency responders.
Last summer, a 15-year-old Lee County boy riding his bicycle to school was hit and killed by a deputy who investigators later said was distracted by his in-car computer  accusations the deputy denies.
Using four years of state crash data, as well as self-reported numbers from 24 Collier and Lee police, EMS and fire agencies, the Daily News is examining how often local emergency responders are involved in crashes (more than four times per week) and how often they are at least partially to blame for distracted driving wrecks (more than once a month).
Coming Thursday: Collier, Lee emergency responders in over 600 crashes per year
Coming Friday: Driven to Distraction  Southwest Floridas best trained drivers distracted at higher rate
Coming Saturday: Collier, Lee agencies look for technology to cut down on distractions

Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:18:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10 college dorm room decorating ideas</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/10-college-dorm-room-decorating-ideas</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>10 college dorm room decorating ideas
DealSpotr.com
1:45 PM, Jul 7, 2015
4:18 PM, Jul 8, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Many teens and some in their early 20s will soon be calling a 15 x 15 dorm room home for the next several months.
But what steps can students take to make it feel like a home away from home, and how can they accomplish this without cluttering the limited new space?
If a student's old bedroom is littered with last weeks clothes, habits need to change. Belongings discarded on the floor of a dorm room will make it appear even more crowded.
If a student knows his roommate ahead of time they may work together to develop compatible concepts and color schemes. Students: Remember to check with the college for decorating regulations and rules.
When making any purchase, be certain to have the right sizes by pre-measuring room specifications.
Dealspotr.com has compiled tips for making the most of the new (limited) space by putting the fun into functional pieces.
SUGGESTED ITEMS
Posters, murals, pictures, temporary wallpaper or decals
Beanbag chairs or floor cushions
A room divider
Floor mirror or coat rack
Flowers and plants
WHERE TO SHOP
Besides the usual go-to discount and department stores like Target and Macy's, thrift shops and art museum gift stores are great choices for unusual finds. There are also plenty of summer garage sales for the budget-conscious, so now is the time to visit your local neighborhoods.
WHERE TO START
Use your major for more than a college degree to create a theme for your dorm. Whether you are a music or an accounting major, interesting choices can be plumbed to set you on the right course, points out Sophie Leon and Daley Quinn from TheFrisky.com.
FUN-CTIONALITY
1. Bedspread: The anchor of your room in terms of selecting a bold pattern and colors. If your taste is more subtle, then try adding a jazzy throw blanket or decorative pillows to your sleep ensemble.
2. Curtains: If your room isnt already provided with a window treatment, then choose ruffles, lace or no-frills colorful blinds. Whatever your preference, tie it in with the bedspread scheme.
3. Rug or carpet: The purpose is to keep your tootsies warm when you land out of bed for that early class so find an area rug that is soft and soothing. This choice is one of the most important decorating decisions as it pulls together your room dcor.
4. Lamps: Not only will they add extra warmth and brightness to your room, they provide an opportunity to show your personality. Whether you are the studious bankers-desk-lamp type or retro-lava-lamp type, there are many excellent choices to go with a tall lamp to make your quarters appear larger. Height draws the eye upwards, observes Julie from EveryCollegeGirl.com.
5. Posters, murals, pictures, temporary wallpaper, and decals: The best way to add a personal touch to your blank walls is by hanging photos of loved ones. Familiar faces will also give you a feeling of comfort during times when youre stressed. You can use BlockPosters.com's free online tool to make any picture into a large poster.
Also, giant printable murals will make your room feel more spacious as explained by Gabby Noone from Buzzfeed. You can also buy temporary wallpaper and wall decals from sites like Fathead, Art.com and others.
Another great resource for making your wall art pop is by using washi tape. It is a colored paper tape that wont leave a residue and can be purchased on Amazon as well as at craft stores like Michaels.
6. Coat rack: Add a touch of style while storing extra clothes, belts, purses and of course, coats. Again, the racks height also will help create the impression of a larger room.
7. Bean bag chairs, floor cushions, room divider: These are useful accent pieces that will make your room inviting to everyone while giving you a little extra privacy when your roomies guests stop by for a visit.
8. Flowers and plants: These inexpensive embellishments will add life to your dorm and Elizabeth Palermo from LiveScience.com says they will also keep the air purified by absorbing toxic gases. Another bonus is making or purchasing decorative pots for your indoor foliage.
9. Plastic storage bins: Splashes of neon colors with plastic organizers also double as great extra tables for your printer or those extra plants. With the purchase of bed risers, bins can be shoved under the bed. Or you can buy upright bins containing drawers for even more space to stash that laundry you still havent washed.
10. Floor Mirror: A large mirror will make a room expand by creating the illusion of extra square footage. There are many different sizes and styles to reflect your individual flair.
Venturing out on your own for college is a great time to practice decorating techniques. By the time you graduate and move into your first apartment, however, you might want to reconsider that lava lamp.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:11:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Congress aims to rewrite No Child Left Behind</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/congress-aims-to-rewrite-no-child-left-behind-education-bill</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Congress aims to rewrite No Child Left Behind education bill
Jennifer C. Kerr, Associated Press
4:10 PM, Jul 8, 2015
4:11 PM, Jul 8, 2015
FILE - In this Jan. 21, 2015 file photo, Senate Health, Education, Labor and Pensions Committee Chairman Sen. Lamar Alexander, R-Tenn. listens to testimony on Capitol Hill in Washington. It's something most everyone on both sides of the aisle can agree on _ an update to the Bush-era No Child Left Behind education law is much needed and long overdue. This week, the Senate and House take up rewrites of the 2002 law, with lawmakers seeking to finally resolve a key question Congress has struggled with for many years (AP Photo/Susan Walsh, File)
Susan Walsh
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
WASHINGTON - The House is trying again to pass a GOP-led rewrite of the Bush-era No Child Left Behind education law, with conservatives aiming to dramatically shift the role of the federal government in education policy away from Washington.
The bill, sponsored by Minnesota Rep. John Kline, would give states and local school districts much more control over accountability for school and teacher performance, similar to a bipartisan bill being debated this week in the Senate. But the House bill includes a provision that has drawn sharp criticism from Democrats  it would allow federal money to follow low-income children to different public schools, an issue known as portability.
Several Democrats went to the House floor Wednesday morning to oppose the bill, with a final vote expected later in the day.
Rep. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas urged her colleagues in the House to go back to the drawing board to craft a new bill. "Portability is a ruse, one that takes resources from, rather than gives to, our most underserved and needy children," said Johnson.
Votes on several amendments are expected later in the afternoon, including one pushed by conservatives to allow states to completely opt out of No Child Left Behind requirements, but still receive federal money in the form of block grants. It's sponsored by Reps. Mark Walker, R-N.C. and Ron DeSantis, R-Fla.
The House canceled a vote on the Kline bill in February when it became clear it didn't have enough support from conservatives to pass. This time around, they may have that support.
"We did tell our leadership, if they gave us the chance to vote on some amendments, that we could support the bill even if the amendments fail, and that's what I intend to do on this bill," said Rep. Mick Mulvaney, R-S.C. "A lot of just want to be heard and have our chance to try to make the bill better."
As the House moved forward with debate, the Senate considered a version sponsored by Sen. Lamar Alexander, R-Tenn., and Sen. Patty Murray, D-Wash. Much like the House bill, the measure would whittle away the federal government's involvement in public schools. It would retain the annual reading and math tests outlined in No Child, but instead it would let states decide how to use the required assessments to measure school and teacher performance.
The bill also would expressly prohibit the federal government from requiring or encouraging any specific set of academic standards  a reference to the Common Core standards, which were drafted by the states with the support of the administration but have become a rallying point for those who want a smaller federal involvement in education.
Alexander has said he expects the Senate bill would lead to fewer tests for America's children, something many in the education community have complained about, including Education Secretary Arne Duncan.
Murray said she would like stronger measures in the bill that would require states to identify their lowest-performing schools and require those schools to have plans for improvement.
"When we don't hold our schools and states accountable for educating every child, it is the kids from our low-income backgrounds, kids with disabilities, kids who are learning English and kids of color who too often do fall through the cracks," Murray said.
No Child Left Behind, which expired in 2007, mandated annual testing in reading and math for students in grades three through eight and again in high school. Schools had to show student growth or face consequences. But critics complained that the law was rigid and overly ambitious and punitive, and said there was too much testing.
In 2012, the Obama administration began granting states waivers from meeting some of the requirements of the law after it began clear they would not be met. Forty-two states, Puerto Rico and the District of Columbia have been granted waivers.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:10:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Star chef cancels restaurant for Trump hotel</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/star-chef-jose-andres-cancels-restaurant-for-trump-hotel</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Star chef Jose Andres cancels restaurant for Trump hotel
Brett Zongker, Associated Press
4:09 PM, Jul 8, 2015
4:10 PM, Jul 8, 2015
FILE - This March 15, 2011, file photo, shows chef Jose Andres at his Minibar restaurant in Washington. Andres is backing out of a plan to open a flagship restaurant in Donald Trump's new hotel under construction in Washington. Andres issued a statement July 8, citing Trump's statements "disparaging immigrants" in his decision to cancel plans for a new eatery at the Trump International Hotel. Andres is a Spanish immigrant and recently became a U.S. citizen. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)
Jacquelyn Martin
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
WASHINGTON - Celebrity chef Jose Andres is backing out of plans to open a flagship restaurant in Donald Trump's new hotel under construction in Washington.
Andres issued a statement Wednesday citing Trump's statements "disparaging immigrants" in his decision to cancel restaurant plans at the Trump International Hotel. Andres is a Spanish immigrant and recently became a U.S. citizen.
Real estate mogul and Republican presidential candidate Trump said in a speech June 16 that some Mexican immigrants bring drugs and crime to the U.S., and some are rapists. Various organizations are severing relationships with Trump.
Andres says Trump's statements "make it impossible for my company and I to move forward."
Donald Trump Jr., Trump's son and a Trump Organization executive, issued a statement threatening legal action and noting that Andres has a 10-year lease.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:06:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Panther killed by vehicle in Collier</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/environment/collier-county-marks-14th-florida-panther-death-of-2015_13157857</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Next
A Florida panther was found dead on Immokalee Road after being hit by a vehicle.
The Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission collected the remains of the female panther, an endangered species, on Sunday about a half-mile south of Wild Turkey Drive.
The panther, estimated to be about 2 years old, did not have a radio tracking collar.
A necropsy is planned for Wednesday at the Conservation Commissions research lab in Gainesville.
So far this year, 14 panthers have been killed by vehicles. In all, 22 panthers have been found dead.
The official panther population estimate is between 100 and 180 wildcats, but increasing numbers of roadkill are fueling calls for a new count and changes to the way Florida manages the population.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
