<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="scrippsobfeeds">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:50:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Golden Gate man holds burglar at gunpoint</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/golden-gate-man-holds-burglar-at-gunpoint-until-deputies-arrive_28155813</Link>
        <Description>Robert Dixon woke up early Wednesday morning to the sound of his house's alarm going off.</Description>
        <MainBody>Golden Gate man holds burglar at gunpoint until deputies arrive
Jessica Lipscomb
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Robert Dixon woke up early Wednesday morning to the sound of his house's alarm going off.
His wife got out of bed and crept into the living room, where she saw a stranger by the sliding glass door. She ran and grabbed a gun, which she handed to her husband. He pointed it at the intruder and waited for deputies to arrive.
"Basically he was scared to death when he had a gun pointed at him," said Dixon, who lives on Green Boulevard in Golden Gate. "Once he saw the gun, he was a deer in headlights. He wasn't going to do anything."
The suspect, later identified as 27-year-old Kenneth Paul, told deputies he broke into the home because he needed money. Reports say Paul, who now faces charges of burglary and petty theft, was found with a flashlight and jacket stolen from Dixon's truck outside the home.
Dixon said he had children in the home, including some from his wife's family, who were in town visiting.
"I was more worried for the children," he said. "Family is what's important."
About six years ago, Dixon said someone knocked on his door at another home in the Golden Gate area. When he answered the door, one guy jumped him and another came at him with a gun. Now, he doesn't answer the door at night without carrying his weapon, just in case.
"This isn't the crime-free Naples that people think it is," Dixon said. "You've got to be worried about what's out there. There's too many wackos out there."
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:42:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Collier family named on Forbes land-owning list</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/two-florida-families-among-countrys-largest-landowners-according-to-forbes_45354699</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Previous
Next
Two local families ranked among the countrys largest landowners, according to Forbes: the Lykes family from Tampa, who ranked No. 3, and the Collier family from Naples, No. 8.
Agustino Fontevecchia, who put together the list for Forbes, explained that the list referenced land that was used for the land itself: preservation, ranching, agriculture or oil exploitation. Metropolitan properties or land used for urban developments were not included.
The Collier family owns approximately 280,000 acres in Southwest Florida. Their net worth is estimated at $2.3 billion, which makes them the 119th wealthiest family in the United States, according to Forbes.
Originally from Memphis, Baron Gift Collier Sr. made his fortune in streetcar advertising. Collier first visited Florida in 1911 and later bought Useppa island for $100,000 before acquiring more than a million acres in Southwest Florida. He transformed the area, notably building the Tamiami Trail and draining the Everglades, according to Barron Collier Companies website. Collier County was created in his honor by the state government in 1923.
Colliers legacy today is divided among two major companies that have ventures in real estate, agribusiness, oil and golf courses.
The Lykes family ranked third among the countrys largest landowners, with more than 600,000 acres across South Florida and Texas. According to Forbes, they are the 193rd richest family in the country with their net worth estimated at $1.2 billion.
Howell Tyson Lykes first worked as a doctor before he moved to Tampa in 1904 with his family. He invested in citrus production and cattle ranching. The family is the biggest citrus producer in Florida, according to the companys website. They own 30,000 acres of groves in the state, while the Lykes Pasco citrus-processing plant is estimated at $15 million. Lykes Bros Inc. also has investments in insurance and real estate.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:30:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>SC Confederate flag comes down Friday</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/south-carolina-governor-confederate-flag-comes-down-friday</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>South Carolina governor: Confederate flag comes down Friday
Jeffrey Collins, Associated Press
4:29 PM, Jul 9, 2015
2 hours ago
A Confederate battle flag flies in front of the South Carolina statehouse Wednesday, July 8, 2015, in Columbia, S.C. The House is expected to debate a measure Wednesday that would remove the flag from the Capitol grounds. (AP Photo/John Bazemore)
John Bazemore
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
COLUMBIA, S.C. - South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley signed a bill into law Thursday that will bring down the Confederate flag outside the Statehouse, a move that seemed unthinkable only a month ago in this Deep South state that was the first to secede from the Union.
The law requires the battle flag to be gone within 24 hours; her staff said it would be removed during a ceremony at 10 a.m. Friday and relegated to the state's Confederate Relic Room.
"The Confederate flag is coming off the grounds of the South Carolina Statehouse," Haley said. "We will bring it down with dignity and we will make sure it is stored in its rightful place."
The flag first flew over the Statehouse dome in 1961 to mark the 100th anniversary of the Civil War and was kept there as a symbol of official opposition to the civil rights movement. Mass protests decades later led to a compromise in 2000 with lawmakers who insisted that the flag symbolized Southern heritage and state's rights.
They agreed then to move it to a 30-foot pole next to a Confederate monument out front. But even from that lower perch, the historic but divisive symbol remained clearly visible in the center of town, and flag supporters remained a powerful bloc in the state.
The massacre 22 days ago of nine people inside their historic black church in Charleston suddenly changed this dynamic, not only in South Carolina but around the nation.
Police said the shootings inside the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church were racially motivated, and by posing with the Confederate flag before the shootings, suspect Dylann Storm Roof, who has not yet entered a plea to nine counts of murder, re-ignited a debate over the flag's history as a symbol of white superiority and racial oppression.
Haley moved first, calling on South Carolina lawmakers to vote the flag down, and very quickly thereafter, other Republican lawmakers who have long cultivated the votes of Confederate flag supporters were announcing that other Civil War symbols no longer deserve places of honor.
"These nine pens are going to the families of the Emanuel Nine," Haley said after signing the bill into law. "Nine amazing individuals who have forever changed South Carolina history."
South Carolina's flag removal bill passed easily in the Senate, where state Sen. Clementa Pinckney, the pastor gunned down at the church, had served, but was stalled by debate in the House as dozens of amendments were proposed. Any changes to the Senate bill could have delayed the flag's removal by weeks or months, perhaps blunting momentum that has grown since the massacre.
House members deliberated well into the night, amid anger, tears and shared memories of Civil War ancestors.
Supporters of the flag talked about grandparents passing down family treasures. Some lamented that the flag had been "hijacked" or "abducted" by racists.
Rep. Mike Pitts recalled playing with a Confederate ancestor's cavalry sword while growing up. He said that for him, the flag is a reminder of how many dirt-poor Southern farmers fought Yankees, not because they hated blacks or sought to preserve white supremacy, but because their land was being invaded.
Black Democrats, frustrated at being asked to honor the Civil War soldiers who also fought to preserve slavery, offered their own family histories as a counterpoint. Rep. Joe Neal talked about tracing his ancestry back to four brothers who were brought to America in chains. A slave owner named Neal bought them, changed their last names and pulled them apart from their families.
"The whole world is asking, is South Carolina really going to change, or will it hold to an ugly tradition of prejudice and discrimination and hide behind heritage as an excuse for it?" Neal said.
Rep. Jenny Horne, a white Republican who said she is a descendent of Confederate President Jefferson Davis, scolded her party members for stalling.
"I cannot believe that we do not have the heart in this body to do something meaningful such as take a symbol of hate off these grounds on Friday. And if any of you vote to amend, you are ensuring that this flag will fly beyond Friday. And for the widow of Sen. Pinckney and his two young daughters, that would be adding insult to injury and I will not be a part of it!" Horne screamed into the microphone.
The bill ultimately passed 93-27 in the House  well above the two-thirds supermajority needed to make changes to the state's "heritage" symbols. Some lawmakers hugged, cried and high-fived, while others snapped selfies and pumped their fists.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:21:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 21M affected by government data breach</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/us-more-than-21-million-affected-by-government-data-breach</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>US: More than 21 million affected by government data breach
Jack Gillum, Associated Press
4:21 PM, Jul 9, 2015
FILE - In this June 5, 2015, file photo, the Homeland Security Department headquarters in northwest Washington. The Obama administration says hackers stole Social Security numbers from more than 21 million people and took other sensitive information when government computer systems were compromised. The number affected by the breach is higher than the 14 million figure that investigators gave The Associated Press in June. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh, File)
Susan Walsh
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
WASHINGTON - The Obama administration says hackers stole Social Security numbers from more than 21 million people and took other sensitive information when government computer systems were compromised.
The Office of Personnel Management says more than 19 million who had applied for background investigations were affected. The government also said nearly 2 million people were also affected who weren't applicants, but rather their spouses or other family members.
The number affected by the breach is higher than the 14 million figure that investigators gave The Associated Press last month. They said the government was increasingly confident that China's government, and not criminal hackers, was responsible for the extraordinary theft of personal information.
China has publicly denied involvement in the break-in.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:16:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Honored vintners chosen for 2016 festival</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/honored-vintners-chosen-for-2016-naples-winter-wine-festival_28489113</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Honored vintners chosen for 2016 Naples Winter Wine Festival
Alexi C. Cardona
9:35 PM, Jul 7, 2015
2 hours ago
local news
Paul and Emily Michael of Californias Peter Michael Winery
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Although the 16th annual Naples Winter Wine Festival is half a year away, the galas honored vintners have already been chosen: Paul and Emily Michael of Californias Peter Michael Winery.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:04:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sneak Peek: Get creative, see a film, hear so...</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/sneak-peek-get-creative-see-a-film-hear-some-music_69767354</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Sneak Peek: Get creative, see a film, hear some music
MONDAY
Start the week of with some creativity, using colored glazes, stamp or slip-trail designs on a ceramic bowl in Great Bowls of Fire. Its from 5:30 to 8:30 p.m. at the Centers for the Arts Bonita Springs, 26100 Old 41 Road. $55 per person. 239-495-8989 or artcenterbonita.org
THURSDAY, JULY 16
The new superhero action film Ant-Man with Paul Rudd opens nationally this weekend but you can see it in 3-D at 9:45 p.m. in Bonita Springs. Its at Prado Stadium 12, 25251 Chamber of Commerce Drive. pradostadium12.com
FRIDAY, JULY 17
David C. Johnson performs in the Neville Brothers Band but plays throughout Southwest Florida often. See him at Parrot Key Caribbean Grill, 2500 Main Street, Fort Myers Beach, from 7 to 10 p.m. myparrotkey.com or 239-463-3257
SATURDAY, JULY 18
Comedian Erik Rivera performs standup at 7:30 and 9:30 p.m. at Belushis Comedy Bar, 13851 U.S. 41 S., Fort Myers. Tickets are $15, excluding fees. 239-433-5299 or belushiscomedybar.com
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:35:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jefferson Davis descendant spurs SC flag vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/plea-by-jefferson-davis-descendant-spurred-sc-flag-vote</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Plea by Jefferson Davis descendant spurred SC flag vote
Meg Kinnard, Associated Press
3:46 PM, Jul 9, 2015
1 hour ago
Rep. Jenny Horne, R-Summerville, speaks in favor of taking down the Confederate flag during debate over a Senate bill calling for the flag to be removed from the Capitol grounds, Wednesday, July 8, 2015, in Columbia, S.C. The House is under pressure to act after the state Senate passed its own measure, which is supported by Gov. Nikki Haley. (AP Photo/John Bazemore)
John Bazemore
Previous
Next
COLUMBIA, S.C. - An impassioned plea by a descendant of the Confederate president seemed to swing momentum as South Carolina legislators debated whether to remove the rebel battle flag from the Statehouse grounds.
Republicans offered dozens of amendments during the 14-hour debate, and even one would have delayed the flag's removal. Many spoke of Southern heritage and cited family connections to Confederate soldiers.
Related story: South Carolina governor: Confederate flag comes down tomorrow
Rep. Jenny Horne, a 42-year-old white Republican lawyer, then took the microphone to scold her colleagues.
"I have heard enough about heritage," Horne said, her tearful voice rising to a shout. "I am a descendent of Jefferson Davis, OK? But that does not matter. It's not about Jenny Horne. It's about the people of South Carolina who have demanded that this symbol of hate come off of the Statehouse grounds."
The debate seemed to turn after that. By early Thursday, representatives approved the same bill that already passed the Senate, enabling Gov. Nikki Haley's office to announce that the flag would come down on Friday.
Horne, whose district includes the overwhelmingly white Charleston suburb of Summerville, cried as she remembered the funeral of Sen. Clementa Pinckney, who was killed along with eight other African-American worshippers during their Bible study in a Charleston church last month.
"I cannot believe that we do not have the heart in this body to do something meaningful such as take a symbol of hate off these grounds on Friday!" she shouted. "For the widow of Sen. Pinckney and his two young daughters, that would be adding insult to injury and I will not be a part of it!"
It took several more hours after Horne's plea, but the chamber met her deadline, voting overwhelmingly to remove the flag within 24 hours.

Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:36:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miami couple creates a stir at Inn of Naples</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/miami-couple-causes-a-stir-at-the-inn-of-naples_20965557</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Miami couple causes a stir at the Inn of Naples
Kristine Gill
2:36 PM, Jul 9, 2015
1 hour ago
crime
Bryan Chao
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
A Miami couple caused a stir Wednesday during their stay at the Inn of Naples when police say they got drunk and pulled the fire alarm.
The disturbance forced guests of the hotels 99 rooms outside while police and firefighters responded.
Until the fire marshal resets fire system those alarms are blaring, General Manager Sue Soldan said.
Police reports show a husband and wife were swimming at the hotels pool and drinking when one of them decided to pull the fire alarm. The alarm sent cruisers racing to the scene at 4055 U.S. 41 N as guests looked on.
When police arrived, they found 24-year-old Bryan Chao intoxicated in the water, talking loudly. Chao refused to leave the pool despite numerous request from police, according to reports. And once he finally complied, police had him lay down on the ground.
With slurred speech, Chao repeatedly asked police to tickle him, causing more of a scene, reports show. Onlookers watched as police tried to handcuff Chao with several different pairs of handcuffs, all of which were too small for his wrists. Chao was eventually cuffed and take to the Naples Jail Center.
He faces charges for disorderly intoxication.
His wife was taken into custody under the Marchman Act because she too was highly intoxicated, according to reports, and could not take care of herself if released.
We basically let the police and fire department do their jobs, Soldan said.
The hotel was back to normal Thursday, staff said. Despite a rough second night at the Inn of Naples, staff had no problems with the couple their first evening.
Soldan said police took both of them away Wednesday, along with their belongings and had them trespassed from the property.
And hopefully we never see them again, Soldan added.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:01:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman gets 50 years in botched holdup</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/accomplice-in-golden-gate-shooting-get-gets-50-years_87531935</Link>
        <Description>When Michelle Postaski saw two men bleeding from gunshot wounds, the outcome of a botched burglary-turned-shooting in Golden Gate, the 25-year-old faced a choice: call for help, or run from the scene with her accomplice.</Description>
        <MainBody>Accomplice in Golden Gate shooting get gets 50 years
Jacob Carpenter
crime
Carpenter, Jacob
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
When Michelle Postaski saw two men bleeding from gunshot wounds, the outcome of a botched burglary-turned-shooting in Golden Gate, the 25-year-old faced a choice: call for help, or run from the scene with her accomplice.
Postaski chose the latter option, a decision that loomed large as a judge sent her to prison for 50 years on Thursday.
"She left them there to die," Collier Circuit Judge Fred Hardt said. "And today, I was waiting for Ms. Postaski to say that she's sorry. I didn't hear that."
Even though the victims survived, and even though the shooter received 40 years in prison under a plea agreement, Postaski's lack of sympathy and remorse  combined with her decision to go to trial  resulted in a prison sentence that will keep her behind bars for decades.
Jurors convicted Postaski, now 26, last month on one count of armed burglary and two counts of aggravated battery with a deadly weapon. Although Postaski's co-defendant, then-boyfriend Kyle Smith, was pegged as the shooter, Postaski's involvement in planning and executing the October 2013 burglary allowed prosecutors to charge her with the three felonies.
Postaski faced a minimum of 12.5 years in prison under Florida's sentencing guidelines. Prosecutors asked for a life sentence, the maximum allowable penalty, while Postaski's mother pleaded for leniency. Donna Butler described her daughter as a tenderhearted woman in the grips of drug addiction at the time of the shooting.
"She knows better now," Butler said. "She knows to ask for help."
Investigators said Postaski and Smith schemed to steal drugs and money from two men at Mer Soleil Apartments. Postaski's job was to lure the men out of the apartment while Smith ransacked the place. When that didn't work, Postaski went inside and hid in a bathroom while Smith held up the men.
Postaski said she came out to find Smith aiming a rifle that would fire six bullets at the victims, who were hospitalized with serious injuries.
The victims, Gabriel Castineira and Mukhesh Lopez, both were present for Thursday's sentencing. Castineira said he was shot in the back of the head and has several lasting injuries, including poor eyesight, pain in his legs and persistent headaches.
"Since this situation, I have problems sleeping at night," Castineira said. "I can't even hear a door opening behind my back without getting scared. This was real traumatic."
Lopez didn't speak Thursday, but Assistant State Attorney Lisa Mead said he still has ammunition lodged in his body and pain in his jaw.
Under Florida law, which requires defendants to serve at least 85 percent of their prison terms, Postaski will remain in prison until her late 60s. She rejected a 30-year plea offer made just before the start of her trial.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:04:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>SWFL police, fire, EMS crash four times a week</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/daily-news-analysis-swfl-emergency-responders-crash-more-than-four-times-a-week_70293448</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Previous
Next
More than four times a week, Collier and Lee county emergency responders crash into something: cars, pedestrians, trees, bushes, overhangs and bay doors.
Most crashes are minor, but occasionally they end with major damage, serious injuries and, in rare cases, death. As a result, local emergency response agencies have averaged nearly $1 million in liability payouts every year since 2011, according to a Daily News crash analysis.
As part of its analysis, the Daily News requested crash numbers and liability payments from 24 law enforcement, medic and fire agencies in Collier and Lee counties from 2011 through 2014. Over the four-year period, the 24 agencies were involved in 2,423 crashes (an average of just over 600 per year). They were at fault  or the crash was deemed avoidable  about 40 percent of the time. Not all crashes are serious enough to generate a crash report to the state.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:08:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Family: CA vacation rental turned into nightmare</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/family-says-vacation-rental-turned-into-nightmare-070815</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Colorado family says vacation rental in California turned into nightmare
Property manager said family violated terms
10:32 PM, Jul 8, 2015
4 hours ago
Manager called police to condo twice.
KGTV
CARLSBAD, Calif. -- A family of eight says their vacation rental turned into an awful experience.

They said they paid $6,000 for a condo in Carlsbad and now the property manager is trying to kick them out.

The property manager told Team 10 it's the family that's violating the terms of the lease.

"Our family hasn't taken a nice big vacation, ever," said Rachel Hawkins.

The Hawkins family had just sold their home in Aurora, Colorado and it was time for a getaway.

"This was supposed to be a time to relax and recoup and get some mental health back," said Hawkins.

She said they needed a break from the worst thing that's happened to their town--the mass shooting at the movie theater in Aurora.

"My husband was a first responder there. He's done and seen things no human being should ever have to see," said Hawkins.

She said she booked a condo in Carlsbad for her husband and six kids through Homeaway.

They paid $6,000 for 40 days.

"They have one rule here--relax, relax, relax," said Hawkins.

The description for the home said seven people could sleep there and it was family friendly. Hawkins said it was perfect for her husband and children, including a 1-year-old.

"That's when I realized--oh goodness only two beds in here," said Hawkins.

Hawkins said they had to turn half of the living room into a bedroom for the kids, the smoke detectors were missing batteries or missing altogether and an electrical outlet was exposed.

"My son shocked himself," said Hawkins.

She said her son was napping upstairs when a neighbor saw him poke his head out the window.

"Just the thought of my kid falling out a window, just terrified me," said Hawkins.

When Hawkins complained to the property manager she said he fixed the microwave and bought them air mattresses.

She said things changed when she brought up the other issues.

"He canceled my reservation with the website and said that I'm trespassing. (He said) if I don't get out by 10, they'll show up with the sheriff's office and try and evict me," said Hawkins.

She said he called police twice to the apartment.

Hawkins called an attorney, Edwin Schwartz of the Edwin Schwartz Law Firm. 

"When the question is, I have these issues in my place and response is you have to leave, we are evicting you--that falls under retaliatory evictions," said Schwartz.

Hawkins paid in full until the middle of July and is hoping to get half of her money back.

"I feel like someone has stole money and vacation from my family," said Hawkins.

The property manager, Ryan Danz, released this email in part to Team 10:

The renter is a vacation rental guest and not a tenant (in landlord / tenant capacity) Who breached numerous provisions of the rental agreement, caused damages to the property, was a nuisance and threatening to our neighbors, parked illegally numerous times in the complex (violating fire codes and other blocking other vehicles &amp; garages). we retain various communications substantiating these claims and rely on them for our decisions to terminate the rental contract.

During her stay, as part of our initial good faith and fair dealings, we credited:refunded (without questioning further) and she received a $200 refund for cleaning, a new $100 microwave after she reported the one on site stopped working 2 full weeks after she took possession, and $430 in additional and new bed/bedding even though the number of people she brought into the home was greater than the number disclosed -- another violation of our agreement. 

The website she booked is defined as vacation rental by owner -- we are not a multi million dollar corporation with onsite maintenance or staff for round the clock issues- some of which were created by the guest outright.

This unit has only 5 star reviews, and cost less than nearly every hotel in the area by a considerable margin, working out to $100/night for a 2 bed /3 bath condo, 1 mile from the beach with pools, washer/dryer, full kitchen, wifi, TV, and two parking spaces.

We stand by our full breadth of testimonials as a company which can be found here: http://www.airconcierge.net/testimonials/ and are overwhelming positive, professional and evidence the great lengths we go to work with our guests, property owner clients and their homes.

Hawkins showed Team 10 her agreements and numerous text messages with Danz and disagrees with his account of the situation.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:27:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US provides marriage benefits to gay couples</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/us-provides-marriage-benefits-to-gay-couples-in-all-states</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>US provides marriage benefits to gay couples in all states
Associated Press
1:27 PM, Jul 9, 2015
In this June 26, 2015 photo, supporters celebrate outside the U.S. Supreme Court in Washington after the court declared that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States. Attorney General Loretta Lynch says the government will make federal marriage benefits available to same-sex couples following a Supreme Court decision last month that legalized same-sex marriage. (AP Photo/Manuel Balce Ceneta)
Manuel Balce Ceneta
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
WASHINGTON  Same-sex married couples can now receive Social Security and veterans benefits for spouses in all 50 states, as the federal government implements the Supreme Court ruling that allowed gay couples to marry nationwide.
Attorney General Loretta Lynch announced Thursday the federal government is making all marriage benefits available to same-sex couples in every state.
The vast majority of federal marriage benefits were already available to same-sex couples, following a 2013 Supreme Court ruling that struck down the federal ban on gay marriage. However, some Social Security and veterans benefits for spouses were still denied to these couples if they lived in states that did not recognize their marriages.
"I am proud to announce that the critical programs for veterans and elderly and disabled Americans, which previously could not give effect to the marriages of couples living in states that did not recognize those marriages, will now provide federal recognition for all marriages nationwide," Lynch said in a statement. "The agencies are currently working towards providing guidance to implement this change in law."
The Supreme Court ruled in a 5-4 decision last month that the Constitution provides a right to same-sex marriage.
In her statement, Lynch said the government will strive to "fulfill our commitment to equal treatment for all Americans."
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:10:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FL Supreme Court rejects congressional districts</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/state/florida-supreme-court-rejects-congressional-districts-orders-legislature-to-redraw-maps</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Florida Supreme Court rejects congressional districts; orders Legislature to redraw maps
Associated Press
1:09 PM, Jul 9, 2015
3 hours ago
Old Florida State Capitol in Tallahassee.
Scott McIntyre
Copyright 2014 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
TALLAHASSEE  The Florida Supreme Court ruled Thursday that the state's congressional maps don't meet the requirements of a voter-approved constitutional amendment that prohibits political lines from being drawn to favor incumbents or a political party. The court ordered the Legislature to try drawing the maps again.
The ruling means there could be an upheaval as incumbents seek re-election and candidates from both parties seek to fill open seats. Florida has 27 congressional districts and the ruling could affect 22 of them. The court ordered eight districts be redrawn, but in doing so, 14 districts that border might also have to be changed.
The court told the Legislature to act swiftly since qualifying for congressional races is approaching. Candidates must file their paperwork to get on the 2016 ballot during the first week in May.
The ruling chastised the Republican-led Legislature not only for working with political operatives to violate the constitution in order to benefit the GOP, but also for making important decisions behind closed doors and destroying documents and deleting emails when they knew the maps would be challenged in court.
"The Legislature itself proclaimed that it would conduct the most open and transparent redistricting process in the history of the state, and then made important decisions, affecting numerous districts in the enacted map, outside the purview of public scrutiny," the ruling said.
The court questioned whether the full extent of the political maneuver was exposed in the case.
"Since many of the e-mails were deleted or destroyed, we still may have only a partial picture of the behind-the-scenes political tactics," Justice Barbara Pariente wrote for the majority in the 5-2 opinion. Justices Charles Canady and Ricky Polston dissented.
The court recommended the Legislature make all its decision in public when it redraws the maps and to save all emails and documents related to the effort.
The Legislature will have to have the new maps ready by October, which will require a special session to approve them. House Speaker Steve Crisafulli and Senate President Andy Gardiner were reviewing the decision and neither planned to comment on it Thursday.
Florida has 17 Republican U.S. House members and 10 Democrats despite Democrats having an advantage in voter registration. Florida has 4.6 million Democrats and 4.2 million Republicans.
The ruling will affect districts held by Democratic Reps. Corrine Brown, Kathy Castor, Ted Deutch and Lois Frankel and Republican Reps. Mario Diaz-Balart, Carlos Curbelo, Ileana Ros-Lehtinen and David Jolly.
Brown, who's long, narrow, oddly-shaped district is often used as the most obvious case of a gerrymandered district, criticized the opinion. Her district is designed to contain a majority of African-Americans.
"Minority communities do not live in compact, cookie-cutter like neighborhoods, and excessive adherence to district 'compactness,' while ignoring the maintenance of minority access districts, fragments minority communities across the state," she said in a statement emailed by her office.
A coalition that included the League of Women Voters challenged the lines, saying Republicans who drew them up ignored the new constitutional requirements approved by voters in 2010. A lower court agreed that GOP leaders and operatives made a mockery of the amendment, but only ordered two central Florida districts be redrawn.
The Supreme Court said that wasn't good enough.
"This is a complete victory for the people of Florida who passed the Fair Districts Amendment. The court has made it abundantly clear that partisan gerrymandering will not be tolerated. We look forward to the legislature following the constitution and the directives of the court," said David King, a lawyer for the coalition.
House Speaker Steve Crisafulli and Senate President Andy Gardiner were reviewing the decision and neither planned to comment on it Thursday.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:44:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deputies seek help IDing man who grabbed woman</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/deputies-seek-help-in-identifying-man-who-grabbed-woman-in-golden-gate-community-park</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>12:44 PM, Jul 9, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Collier deputies are asking for the public's help to identify a man who grabbed a woman Tuesday in Golden Gate Community Park. The suspect then offered the woman money and scratched her neck when he tried to grab her.
The victim told deputies she was walking through the park near the baseball fields about 9:30 p.m. when she noticed a dark, four-door sedan parked near a boat ramp at 3300 Santa Barbara Blvd.
The victim walked past the car and the driver called out to her, asking what her name was and saying she was attractive.
The woman ignored the man and began walking in the opposite direction. But the woman had to pass the car again on her way home and saw the same man standing outside his vehicle.
As she walked past, he spoke to her again, saying he could give her $200.
The woman walked faster and the man followed, reaching out to grab her and scratching her neck in the process.
The woman broke away and ran home.
Deputies released a composite sketch hoping to find the man, who is described as Hispanic and in his mid 20s. He has brown hear and was wearing designer sunglasses at the time. He had on a white tank top and dark sweatpants.
His dark, four-door sedan did not have any distinctive markings.
Anyone with information is asked to call the Collier County Sheriffs Office at 239.252.9300. Or, to remain anonymous and be eligible for a reward contact Crime Stoppers at 1.800.780.8477.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:53:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Panther found dead in Lee County is year's 23rd</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/environment/another-panther-hit-killed-by-car</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Panther found dead in Lee County is year's 23rd, 15th death-by-vehicle
10:59 AM, Jul 9, 2015
12 mins ago
An example of a Florida panther.
Dennis Guyitt
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
LEE COUNTY - For the second time in almost as many days, a Florida panther was found killed by a car Wednesday night.
The remains of a 10-11 month-old male panther were found on Daniels Parkway, one mile south of State Road 82, according to the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.
This marks the 22nd Florida panther death of 2015 and the 15th death by vehicle.
Most of the panthers killed were males. Eleven of the 22 deaths have been in Collier County and three have been in Lee.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
