<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:12:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Submits New Debt Proposals To Eurozone</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1516318</Link>
        <Description>Greece has submitted new plans for tackling its debt as the country aims to avoid a eurozone exit, officials have confirmed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece Submits New Debt Proposals To Eurozone
22:12, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
The new plan could be the last chance for Greece to stay in the eurozone
Share by email
Greece has submitted new plans for tackling its debt as the country aims to avoid a eurozone exit, officials have confirmed.
The proposals were received by Eurogroup chairJeroenDijsselbloem, his spokesman confirmed around two hours before a midnight deadline.
Michel Reijns wrote on Twitter: "New Greek proposals received by Eurogroup President Dijsselbloem. Important for institutions to consider these in their assessment."
The heads of all 28 EU member states will discuss the proposals at a "decisive" summit on Sunday.
Greek PM Alexis Tsipras and his cabinet spent the day drafting a package of tax rises, pension reforms and economic liberalisation measures that could decide their country's future in theEU.
Play video "What Next For Athens?"
Video: What Next For Athens?
A Greek official said lawmakers would be asked to authorise the Syriza-led government to negotiate a list of "prior actions" it would take before any fresh aid funds are disbursed - a key step to convince sceptical lenders of its serious intent.
The plan was put forward as Germany, Greece's biggest creditor, appeared to make a small concession by acknowledging Athens would need some debt restructuring as part of any new bailout programme.
The hardlineGerman finance minister Wolfgang Schaeublesuggested there could be movement on Greek debt as the deadline approached on Thursday night.
Eurozone leaders decided at an emergency meeting earlier this week that Greece should have one more chance to present a credible rescue plan.
Athens had already promised to start reforming its tax and pension systems next week.
Play video "We're An 'Austerity Laboratory'"
Video: We're An 'Austerity Laboratory'
It promised the economic reforms as it announced a new bid for funds from the European Stability Mechanism (ESM), the EU organisation that provides financial assistance for eurozone members.
The three-year loan would enable Greece to cover its debt obligations, the Greek finance ministry said, preventing it from defaulting and ensuring it does not have to drop out of the euro.
Banks in Greece are staying closed until at least next Monday and cash machine withdrawals are limited to60 (42) per day as the country teeters on the brink.
The country has had two bailouts worth 240bn from the eurozone and the International Monetary Fund since 2010, but its economy has shrunk by a quarter, unemployment is more than 25% and one in two young people is out of work.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:32:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watch: RAF Reaper Drone Destroys IS Trucks</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1516231</Link>
        <Description>Footage released by the MOD shows armoured vehicles used by the militants being wiped out by Hellfire missiles.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Watch: RAF Reaper Drone Destroys IS Trucks
Footage released by the MOD shows armoured vehicles used by the militants being wiped out by Hellfire missiles.
18:32, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
Play video "Reaper Drone Destroys IS Vehicles"
Video: Reaper Drone Destroys IS Vehicles
Share by email
Two Islamic State armoured vehicles have been wiped out by Hellfire missiles fired by drones piloted thousands of miles away.
The devastating power of the RAF'sReaper aircraft is demonstrated in a video released by the Ministryof Defence.
The footage shows a Reaper tracking an IS armoured personnel carrier which was used in combat against Iraqi troops on 6 July.
The militants tried to hide their vehicle in a palm grove, but it was easily picked out by the drone.
It subsequently destroyed an armoured pick-up truck, which had been converted to a large car bomb and positioned to hamper Iraqi troop movements.
Play video "October - Reaper Drones Footage"
Video: October - Reaper Drones Footage
The UK has carried out dozens of drone strikes against IS targets in Iraq since the Reaper aircraft were deployed there in October 2014.
The missions are carried out by RAF's 13 Squadron from inside an aircraft hangar in Lincolnshire.
The drones had been based at Kandahar in Afghanistan but wereredeployed to fight IS as part of the British draw down from Afghanistan.
1/5
Gallery: US Reaper Drone Facts
It is armed with 14 Hellfire missiles, or a weapons combo including two 500lb Paveway II laser-guided bombs
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:45:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inside Mexico's Infamous Meth 'Super Labs'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515628</Link>
        <Description>One of Mexico's most infamous cartels gives Sky News unprecedented access to one of its industrial-scale methamphetamine labs.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Inside Mexico's Infamous Meth 'Super Labs'
One of Mexico's most infamous cartels gives Sky News unprecedented access to one of its industrial-scale methamphetamine labs.
13:45, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
Play video "Industrial Crystal Meth Production"
Video: Industrial Crystal Meth Production
Share by email
By Stuart Ramsay, Chief Correspondent
In the central mountains of Mexico lies the city of Culiacan. By rights it should be a sleepy backwater, a one-donkey rural nowheresville, but it is not.
Alongside manicured parks and pristine government buildings it boasts shopping malls, designer clothes shops, five star hotels,shi-shi restaurants and nightclubs.
What makes Culiacan so different to other rural cities is that it is the home of one of the country's most powerful and ruthless gangs, the Sinaloa Cartel. Where there are cartels, there is money - lots of it.
The Sinaloa deal exclusively in drugs, vast quantities of them.
It's a multi-million dollar business that takes place under the nose of the country's anti-narcotics units which patrol the ganglands of the city day and night.
1/9
Gallery: Warring Factions: Mexcio's Powerful Drugs Cartels
In recent years the profitability of their business has soared.
The reasons are twofold, firstly they are focusing on the production and export of methamphetamine or crystal meth, rather than cocaine and heroin, and secondly they have developed ways to produce the drug on an industrial scale.
The cartels generally, but the Sinaloa obsessively, maintain incredibly high levels of security. It's why they have lasted and indeed thrived for so long.
After eight months of negotiation they agreed to allow us to see their meth production process and with it see a 'super lab' at work. It has never been allowed before.
Inside a heavily-guarded factory, men in overalls and wearing gloves and face masks mix together a series of chemicals into huge drums.
Play video "Narco State: Meeting The Cartel"
Video: Narco State: Meeting The Cartel
There is an instant reaction, sending clouds of foul smelling, toxic and highly explosive gas into the air.
They barely speak to avoid identification and they are wary of the chemicals.
They move back and forth as the ingredients react. The reaction process only takes 15 minutes or so but to get to the point where they have created the meth will take a few days.
The reason why meth is so popular with the cartels is that it is completely synthetic and can be made cheaply at home.
The cartels control ports that allow them to bring in some of the most important ingredients in bulk from India and China. Their distribution network to markets in the United States, Europe and further afield have been in place for years.
Play video "Narco State: Packing Meth"
Video: Narco State: Packing Meth
But the ability to produce huge amounts of the drug marked something of a 'narco revolution' for the Mexican cartels.
They were so confident of the purity and quality of their meth that initially they used to include batches of the "product" with cocaine and marijuana shipments that had already been ordered - they sent it for free.
They were convinced the foreigners would be hooked; they were right.
The production of the drug is one aspect of the process but making money from it means preparation, packing and shipping.
The 'super lab' is made up of a number of different locations.
1/3
Gallery: The Dark Side Of Mexico
We crossed town to another secret building where we found 10 men in masks and gloves sitting around tables laden with crystal meth.
For the next 48 hours they will pack the powder into tiny capsules before it is shipped abroad.
There is a quarter of a million pounds-worth of drugs on the table and the gang leader told me he can produce that amount once a week.
"We are making 12m a year profit and we are a medium-sized operation," he told me.
"It all goes to the US because it sells for more, the product goes directly to the United States," he said, adding that the value of the drugs increases nine times by the time they get to Europe.
Play video "Grad Cooking Meth To Pay For PhD"
Video: Grad Cooking Meth To Pay For PhD
"The majority of it is taken in trailers - that's how they take it from here," he said.
This huge, highly-organised business is not actually about making drugs, it is quite simply about making money.
Most experts who study the cartels believe it is unlikely that given their reach across society they will ever be beaten, well not any time soon.
"They become a form of an alternative justice system or alternative police and that is very worrying for the country," Mexico-based British journalist and author Ioan Grillo told me.
"And that leads you to understand how the conflict has led to more than 84,000 cartel-related murders in the last seven years.
Play video "Gang Leader Shows Off Crack Lab"
Video: Gang Leader Shows Off Crack Lab
"Corruption is extremely bad to the point where you have police officers who are not simply turning a blind eye to organised crime, they're full on assassins for organised crime, they are full on cartel members," he said.
The Mexican authorities and the United States drug enforcement agencies are struggling to even remotely control the trafficking of drugs across Mexico's borders.
Like a multinational company it is driven by the market. For now the demand is high. So the supply keeps coming.
:: Watch our Special Report Narco State: Inside Mexicos Drug Cartels on Sky News at 9.30pm on Friday, or on Sky News Catch Up, skynews.com and mobile apps from today.
Play video "Narco State: Mexico's Drugs War"
Video: Narco State: Mexico's Drugs War
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:46:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fourth Of July Terror Plots Thwarted In US</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1516256</Link>
        <Description>Authorities arrest more than 10 people allegedly inspired by Islamic State to carry out attacks close to the Independence holiday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Fourth Of July Terror Plots Thwarted In US
Authorities arrest more than 10 people allegedly inspired by Islamic State to carry out attacks close to the Independence holiday.
19:46, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
Authorities were put on high alert ahead of the July 4 celebrations
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
US investigators thwarted terror plots aimed at killing Americans around the July 4 holiday, FBI Director James Comey has said.
More than 10 people were arrested in the four-week period leading up to the Independence Day celebration.
The alleged plotswere inspired by Islamic State online recruitment, Mr Comeytold reporters on Thursday.
The FBI boss did not provide any other details on the arrests.
Mr Comey says better access to encrypted data is needed to thwart attacks
Police departments across the country were told by the FBI and Department of Homeland Security to be on high alert for potential attacks during the holiday weekend.
No such attacks occurred.
Mr Comey told a Senate judiciary committee on Wednesday that he estimates upwards of 200 Americans have travelled or attempted to travel to Syria to join IS.
He also called on technology companies to provide law enforcement agencies with better access to encrypted communications, which he said is making it more difficult to thwart potential attacks on US soil.
Upwards of 200 Americans have joined or attempted to join IS, the FBI says
"The tools we are asked to use are increasingly ineffective," he said. "ISIL says go kill, go kill ... we are stopping these things so far ... but it is incredibly difficult.
"I cannot see me stopping these indefinitely."
On Thursday, Mr Comeysaid that people in the US, who authorities believe are under the influence of the extremist group, have "gone dark" because of encrypted data.
Technology firms have argued that building in such access for law enforcement would undermine encryption and weaken systems against criminals and computer hackers.
They also accuse the government of seeking backdoor access to encrypted data.
Deputy Attorney General Sally Yates rejected the claim on Wednesday.
"We are not seeking a front door, back door, or any kind of door ... but we are seeking to work with the industry," she told the Senate committee.
Ms Yates urged Congress to work with Silicon Valley and said they were looking to tailor solutions to individual companies.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:39:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China Restricts Share Sales As Stocks Struggle</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515860</Link>
        <Description>Police say they will investigate "hostile" short sellers as the country attempts to get to grips with a 30% stock market fall.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
China Restricts Share Sales As Stocks Struggle
Police say they will investigate "hostile" short sellers as the country attempts to get to grips with a 30% stock market fall.
12:39, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
A man stands on front of a screen showing Chinese stock market moves
Share by email
China has threatened to arrest people who sell shares as the country's stock markets experience one of their worst crashes in history.
The Shanghai composite index lost 5.9% on Wednesday, leaving it down more than 30% since its peak on 12 June - equal to losses of $3.5 trillion.
The Ministry of Security announced it will investigate anyone involved in "hostile" short selling - a type of stock dealing that is used to take advantage of a falling market.
It involves the selling of stock that is not actually held, in anticipation of a future fall in prices.
Chinese police were seen visiting the office of the country's securities regulator as part of the investigation on Thursday.
China's authorities have also banned anyone who owns a large number of shares from selling their stock for six months.
The ban applies to "big" shareholders - defined as those with stakes of more than 5% - company directors, board supervisors and senior executives, the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) said.
Shares in Hong Kong were also hit by the crash
Trading in more than 1,400 companies has also been suspended, representing around half of listed stocks.
The crash comes after a year during which the value of the market has more than doubled.
The measures led to the market recovering 5.3% on Thursday, after an earlier further fall of 3.6%.
"Investor confidence is recovering," Zhang Gang, an analyst from Central China Securities, told AFP.
Some commentators have likened the conditions to those which saw Wall Street crash in 1929, when billions of dollars were wiped off America's stock market.
A report by Credit Suisse issued in May said the large numbers of the public had borrowed cash, using mortgage extensions and credit card loans to do so, in order to buy into the rising markets.
Unlike the 1929 crash, China's stock exchanges are relatively isolated from the rest of the world because only Chinese residents are allowed to trade.
China's containment measures saw prices rise again on Thursday
But there are fears that contagion could spread and Hong Kong's Hang Seng index fell nearly 6% on Wednesday with falls also seen in South Korea and Japan.
The crash rattled investor confidence elsewhere in the world and has raised concerns that it could pose an even bigger threat to the world economy than the Greek debt crisis.
The crash resulted in sharp falls in the prices of copper and iron ore - the raw component of steel - putting pressure on mining firms in Australia and Brazil.
There are also fears that such a huge loss of wealth caused by the fall in share prices could lead to a political backlash in the world's second largest economy, or precipitate a recession.
Among other measures taken to help stem the crash, China's central bank - the People's Bank of China - provided money for a state-owned lending firm to finance the buying of more shares.
Societe Generale, in a research report into the crash, said: "The Chinese government is having a 'whatever it takes' moment with the stock market.
"The impact on the market remains muted and so more resources will probably be ramped up for the battle in the coming days."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:12:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hackers Stole Government Data On 21.5m People</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1516304</Link>
        <Description>Chinese hackers are suspected of the massive attack, which targeted a database of government background checks.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hackers Stole Government Data On 21.5m People
Chinese hackers are suspected of the massive attack, which targeted a database of government background checks.
22:12, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
The OPM conducts more than 90% of federal background checks
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
Hackers stole information including Social Security numbers on 21.5 million people in a cyber-attack on a US federal government database, say officials.
The Office of Personnel Management (OPM) said those affected were 19.7 million people who underwent background checks and 1.8 millionothers, mostly spouses or co-habitants of applicants.
This is in addition to the information of about 4.2 million current and former federal workers stolen in a separate but related incident, revealed by the OPM last month.
There is thought to be overlap between the two groups.
House Speaker John Boehner called on Thursday for the firing of OPM director Katherine Archuleta.
Play video "Mystery Of US Government Data Theft"
Video: Mystery Of US Government Data Theft
The US has fingered China as the main suspect in the hack, but the Beijing foreign ministry said the allegation was "absurd logic".
The OPM said it was in June, while investigating the first breach, that it discovered the cyber-attack affecting 21.5 million people.
It included the fingerprints of some 1.1 million people.Usernames and passwords were also stolen.
The OPM said there was no evidence that health, financial, payroll or retirement records of federal personnel or applicants had been compromised in the wider attack.
Play video "2014: China Source Of Most Attacks"
Video: 2014: China Source Of Most Attacks
"If you underwent a background investigation through OPM in 2000 or afterwards," the OPM said, "it is highly likely that you are impacted by the incident involving background investigations.
"If you underwent a background investigation prior to 2000, you still may be impacted, but it is less likely."
The OPM conducts more than 90% of federal background checks, according to its website.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:44:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two Israelis 'Being Held Captive In Gaza'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1516127</Link>
        <Description>Avraham Mengistu crossed over into the Hamas-controlled territory on 7 September last year, but it is unclear why.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Two Israelis 'Being Held Captive In Gaza'
Avraham Mengistu crossed over into the Hamas-controlled territory on 7 September last year, but it is unclear why.
15:44, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
Avraham Mengistu's mother (L) and brother (R)
Two Israelis are being held captive in the Gaza Strip, according to officials.
Mr Mengistu comes from the southern city of Ashkelon
One has been held by Hamas since crossing into the territory last year, the Israelis said in what appears to be the first public statement on the matter.
According to "credible intelligence" Avraham Mengistu "is being held against his will by Hamas in Gaza", a statement from the defence ministry said.
Play video "Brutality Video Sparks Violence"
Video: Brutality Video Sparks Violence
The 28-year-old Israeli, who is of Ethiopian descent, had "independently crossed the security fence" into Gaza, the Palestinian territory ruled by Islamist movement Hamas on 7 September, the statement said.
"Israel has appealed to international and regional interlocutors to demand his immediate release and verify his well-being," the ministry statement added.
Mr Mengistu crossed the frontier soon after the end of a 50-day war between Israel and Hamasbut no-one knows why.
Israel operates a strict blockade against Gaza and forbids its citizens from entering the territory, partly because of fears they may be used as bargaining chips.
"Furthermore, the defence establishment is currently dealing with an additional case of an Israeli Arab also being held in Gaza," it said, without providing further details on the second person.
The case had previously been kept out of the public eye because of a gagging order but a judge in the southern city of Ashkelon - where Avraham Mengistu lives - lifted the order.
Information on the unidentified Israeli Arab is still subject to a gagging order.
1/7
Gallery: Palestinian Attacks Israeli Officer In Jerusalem
An Israeli paramilitary police officer was critically injured when he was stabbed in the neck by a Palestinian
The authorities have decided to put the story out into the public eye is because they hope it may help speed up the men's release.
"This is a humanitarian issue, and we expect those holding him to behave accordingly and return him in good health," President Reuven Rivlin told journalists as he toured southern Israel.
The family of Mr Mengistu are reportedly angry at its government's slow response to his situation, arguing there would have been more effort to find him if he were white.
"The family chose until now to remain discreet," said brother Asho Mengistu, surrounded by other family members, including his tearful mother.
There are 135,000 Ethiopians Jews in Israel and many say they have suffered racism and discrimination. They have held a number of rallies in recent weeks, protesting at alleged police brutality and racism.
Hamas has not yet commented.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:41:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kim Jong-Un's 'Reign Of Terror': 70 Executed</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1516029</Link>
        <Description>The killings include the execution of the country's defence chief with an anti-aircraft gun for falling asleep in a meeting.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Kim Jong-Un's 'Reign Of Terror': 70 Executed
The killings include the execution of the country's defence chief with an anti-aircraft gun for falling asleep in a meeting.
12:41, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
Kim Jong-Un has carried out a series of purges since taking power in 2011
North Korean leader Kim Jong-Un has executed 70 officials since taking power in 2011, South Korean officials have said.
The "reign of terror" exceeds the bloodshed of his father's early rule, they added.
South Korean Foreign Minister Yun Byung-se said Kim's late father, Kim Jong-Il, had executed around 10 officials during his early years in power.
South Korea's National Intelligence Service believes the younger Kim has executed around 70 officials, but will not reveal how it obtained the information, an unnamed official from the spy agency said.
Yun said the younger Kim's "reign of terror affects significantly" North Koreans working abroad, because it inspires them to defect to the South.
1/4
Gallery: North Korea Carries Out Live Firing Exercises
North Korean artillery undertakes a night firing drill
North Korea has been ruled by the Kim family since the nation was founded in 1948.
The authoritarian nation is secretive about the inner workings of its government and information collected by outsiders is often impossible to confirm.
Daniel Pinkston, Deputy Project Director of International Crisis Group, told Sky News such regimes are "plagued by violence".
"As a prudent dictator you use the instrument of violence," he said.
Play video "February: North Korean Brutality"
Video: February: North Korean Brutality
"But you have to be careful how you use that instrument. It might cause a backlash.
"He seems to be impatient and driven.
"He is willing to be using instrument of violence more readily than others. That may explain the frequency."
There is a long history of high-level government purges in North Korea.
Play video "March: Defectors 'Human Scum'"
Video: March: Defectors 'Human Scum'
North Korea's founder, Kim Il Sung, removed pro-Soviet and pro-Chinese factions from within the country's leadership in the aftermath of the 1950-53 Korean War in a bid to strengthen his power.
The victims included Pak Hon Young, who was once the vice chairman of the ruling Workers' Party of Korea and North Korea's foreign minister.
He was executed in 1955 after being accused of spying for the United States.
Kim Jong-Un has carried out a series of purges since taking over after the death of his father.
Play video "April: Loyalty Display In N Korea"
Video: April: Loyalty Display In N Korea
The most notable to date was the execution in 2013 of his uncle, Jang Song Thaek, for alleged treason.
He was married to Kim Jong-Il's sister and was at one time considered the second most powerful man in North Korea.
South Korea's spy agency said in May that Kim had ordered his then-defence chief, Hyon Yong Chol, to be executed with an anti-aircraft gun for complaining about the young ruler, talking back to him and falling asleep in a meeting.
Experts say Kim could be using fear to strengthen his grip on power, but this might fail if he does not improve the country's shattered economy.
1/9
Gallery: Kim Jong Un Watches Missile Test-Fire
North Korea has claimed it has successfully test-fired a submarine-based ballistic missile "developed on the personal initiative" of leader Kim Jong-Un
North Korea is currently suffering what has been described by official media as the "worst drought in 100 years".
The UN's childrens fund, UNICEF, has warned urgent action is required to stop the deaths of children already weakened by widespread malnutrition.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:31:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brits Told To Leave Tunisia Amid Terror Warning</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1516234</Link>
        <Description>The Foreign Office also warns people against travelling there as more terror attacks are "highly likely" after the beach massacre.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Brits Told To Leave Tunisia Amid Terror Warning
The Foreign Office also warns people against travelling there as more terror attacks are "highly likely" after the beach massacre.
21:31, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
Play video "Britons Told To Tunisia"
Video: Britons Told To Tunisia
Share by email
Britons in Tunisia have been told to leave the country as the Foreign Office warns more terror attacks are "highly likely" after last month's beach shootings.
Extra flights are being put on to bring tourists home and two holiday companies, Thomson and First Choice, are returning their staff to the UK.
The Foreign Office said Britons should leave unless they definitely have to stay, adding that people planning to travel there should not unless it was "essential".
An estimated 3,000 Britons are currently on holiday in Tunisia and about 300 others are travelling independently.
Holidaymakersshould contact their tour operators while independent travellers should make their own arrangements to leave as commercialairlines are operating, said the Foreign Office.
The Foreign Office has updated its travel advice
They should contact the British embassy in Tunis if they need consular assistance.
Play video "Brits Told To Avoid Tunisia"
Video: Brits Told To Avoid Tunisia
Thirty-eight tourists, including 30 Britons, were killed when a gunman opened fire on a beach and hotel resort in Port El Kantaoui, near Sousse on 26 June.
Thomas Cook has said it is cancelling all future bookings to Tunisia until 31 October.
And it is bringing all its customers in the country back to the UK as soon as possible using "third party carriers and on our10 scheduled flights over the weekend".
Thomas Cook "strongly advises" people to return on these flights.
Thomson and First Choice - the companies all the Britons killed in the Sousse massacre were travelling with - have cancelled all of their outbound flights to Tunisia for the summer season which is up to 31 October.
Play video "Tunisia Silence"
Video: Tunisia Silence
The two firms no longer have any British tourists in the country but are bringing back their staff in the next 24 hours.
Thomson and First Choice said: "Customers due to travel to Tunisia up to and including 31 October will be given the opportunity to amend their holiday free of charge to any of our destinations currently on sale, or receive a full refund."
ABTA said: "Holidaymakers should be aware that travelling out to Tunisia at this time is likely to invalidate travel insurance policies.
"Most insurance policies will still provide cover for travellers in a country at the time of Foreign Office advice change.
"Those with holidays booked within the next 48 hours to Tunisia are advised to contact their travel company to discuss available options.
Play video "Minute Silence Held In Tunisia"
Video: Minute Silence Held In Tunisia
"If you have booked a package you will be entitled to a refund or alternative holiday."
The Foreign Office said British authorities have been working closely with their Tunisian counterparts over the attack and although extra security measures have been put in place "the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably".
And it deemed the measures were not adequate enough to protect British tourists.
It said in a statement: "Further terrorist attacks are highly likely, including in tourist resorts, and by individuals unknown to the authorities whose actions may be inspired by terrorist groups via social media.
"You should be especially vigilant at this time and follow the advice of the Tunisian security authorities and your tour operator, if you have one."
1/24
Gallery: Victims Of Tunisia Gun Attack
Carly Lovett, 24, recently became engaged and was from Gainsborough, Lincolnshire. She worked as a beauty blogger and was a former student at the University of Lincoln
Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said: "Since the attack in Sousse the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably, leading us to the view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely.
"The Tunisian investigation into those behind the Sousse attack and that on the Bardo museum earlier this year is ongoing and the Tunisians have made clear they want to track down further individuals who they suspect may have links to this attack.
"While we are working with the Tunisian authorities to further strengthen those measures, we judge that more work is needed to effectively protect tourists from the terrorist threat.
"Taking all these factors together we judge it is right and prudent to make this change. We have not taken this decision lightly but our first priority will always be the safety of our citizens.
"In the days and weeks ahead, we will continue to keep the situation under close review and to work with the Tunisians to further understand the threat and to strengthen their security response to it."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:27:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top Tibetan Monk On Money Laundering Charge</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515983</Link>
        <Description>Karmapa Urgyen Trinley is charged in connection with a 2011 raid on a monastery where hundreds of thousands of pounds was found.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Top Tibetan Monk On Money Laundering Charge
Karmapa Urgyen Trinley is charged in connection with a 2011 raid on a monastery where hundreds of thousands of pounds was found.
13:27, UK, Thursday 09 July 2015
Lama Trinley, pictured in 2008
Share by email
A Tibetan monk seen as a possible successor to the Dalai Lama is to be prosecuted for money laundering.
The decision to prosecute Karmapa Urgyen Trinley comes after an Indian court overturned a decision to drop charges.
A judge at the Himachal Pradesh High Court issued an order for authorities to open criminal proceedings over the recovery of around $1m (650,000) in foreign currency during a raid on his Buddhist monastery four years ago.
Criminal conspiracy charges were filed after the raid but a district court in 2012 dismissed the case but the latest appeal means Trinley now faces judicial proceedings.
The case dates back to a raid in January 2011 on a monastery in the Himalayan town of Dharamshala in which investigators say stacks of bank notes in 26 different currencies were recovered, including the equivalent of 65,000 in Chinese yuan.
Play video "Obama: Dalai Lama A 'Good Friend'"
Video: Obama: Dalai Lama A 'Good Friend'
The raid came after police stopped two people driving a car that was full of cash - the pair said the money was intended for a land deal involving a trust run by Trinley.
The 30-year-old has denied any wrongdoing, saying the bank notes were donations from devotees gathered over the years and he was not involved in any land deals.
The monk, who fled Tibet at the age of 14, is recognised by both China and the Dalai Lama as the reincarnation of the Karmapa Lama, the 17th incarnation of the head of the Karma Kagyu lineage, one of the four major schools of Tibetan Buddhism.
Since fleeing Tibet and reaching India after an eight-day journey on foot and horseback, Trinley has lived mainly at the Gyuto Monastery in Dharamshala, the northern Indian hill station that is the seat of the Tibetan government in exile.
Play video "Obama-Dalai Lama Talks Anger China"
Video: Obama-Dalai Lama Talks Anger China
He is seen as having the highest profile of an array of young lamas who could succeed the 80-year-old Dalai Lama.
Their appearances together have increased speculation he is being groomed as the Nobel peace laureate's spiritual successor.
Trinley's spokesman, Kunzang Chungyalpa, said the lama had great faith in India's judicial system.
"He strongly believes truth will prevail at the end."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
