<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:28:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inside Mexico's Infamous Meth 'Super Labs'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515628</Link>
        <Description>One of Mexico's most infamous cartels gives Sky News unprecedented access to one of its industrial-scale methamphetamine labs.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Inside Mexico's Infamous Meth 'Super Labs'
One of Mexico's most infamous cartels gives Sky News unprecedented access to one of its industrial-scale methamphetamine labs.
23:28, UK, Wednesday 08 July 2015
Play video "Narco State II: Industrial Meth Lab"
Video: Narco State II: Industrial Meth Lab
Share by email
By Stuart Ramsay, Chief Correspondent
In the central mountains of Mexico lies the city of Culiacan. By rights it should be a sleepy backwater, a one-donkey rural nowheresville, but it is not.
Alongside manicured parks and pristine government buildings it boasts shopping malls, designer clothes shops, five star hotels,shi-shi restaurants and nightclubs.
What makes Culiacan so different to other rural cities is that it is the home of one of the country's most powerful and ruthless gangs, the Sinaloa Cartel. Where there are cartels, there is money - lots of it.
The Sinaloa deal exclusively in drugs, vast quantities of them.
It's a multi-million dollar business that takes place under the nose of the country's anti-narcotics units which patrol the ganglands of the city day and night.
Play video "Narco State II: Meeting The Cartel"
Video: Narco State II: Meeting The Cartel
In recent years the profitability of their business has soared.
The reasons are twofold, firstly they are focusing on the production and export of methamphetamine or crystal meth, rather than cocaine and heroin, and secondly they have developed ways to produce the drug on an industrial scale.
The cartels generally, but the Sinaloa obsessively, maintain incredibly high levels of security. It's why they have lasted and indeed thrived for so long.
After eight months of negotiation they agreed to allow us to see their meth production process and with it see a 'super lab' at work. It has never been allowed before.
Inside a heavily-guarded factory, men in overalls and wearing gloves and face masks mix together a series of chemicals into huge drums.
Play video "Narco State II: Packing Meth"
Video: Narco State II: Packing Meth
There is an instant reaction, sending clouds of foul smelling, toxic and highly explosive gas into the air.
They barely speak to avoid identification and they are wary of the chemicals.
They move back and forth as the ingredients react. The reaction process only takes 15 minutes or so but to get to the point where they have created the meth will take a few days.
The reason why meth is so popular with the cartels is that it is completely synthetic and can be made cheaply at home.
The cartels control ports that allow them to bring in some of the most important ingredients in bulk from India and China. Their distribution network to markets in the United States, Europe and further afield have been in place for years.
Play video "Narco State II: Small Meth Lab"
Video: Narco State II: Small Meth Lab
But the ability to produce huge amounts of the drug marked something of a 'narco revolution' for the Mexican cartels.
They were so confident of the purity and quality of their meth that initially they used to include batches of the "product" with cocaine and marijuana shipments that had already been ordered - they sent it for free.
They were convinced the foreigners would be hooked; they were right.
The production of the drug is one aspect of the process but making money from it means preparation, packing and shipping.
The 'super lab' is made up of a number of different locations.
Play video "Narco State II: Inside A Crack Lab"
Video: Narco State II: Inside A Crack Lab
We crossed town to another secret building where we found 10 men in masks and gloves sitting around tables laden with crystal meth.
For the next 48 hours they will pack the powder into tiny capsules before it is shipped abroad.
There is a quarter of a million pounds-worth of drugs on the table and the gang leader told me he can produce that amount once a week.
"We are making 12m a year profit and we are a medium-sized operation," he told me.
"It all goes to the US because it sells for more, the product goes directly to the United States," he said, adding that the value of the drugs increases nine times by the time they get to Europe.
1/9
Gallery: Warring Factions: Mexcio's Powerful Drugs Cartels
"The majority of it is taken in trailers - that's how they take it from here," he said.
This huge, highly-organised business is not actually about making drugs, it is quite simply about making money.
Most experts who study the cartels believe it is unlikely that given their reach across society they will ever be beaten, well not any time soon.
"They become a form of an alternative justice system or alternative police and that is very worrying for the country," Mexico-based British journalist and author Ioan Grillo told me.
"And that leads you to understand how the conflict has led to more than 84,000 cartel-related murders in the last seven years.
1/3
Gallery: The Dark Side Of Mexico
"Corruption is extremely bad to the point where you have police officers who are not simply turning a blind eye to organised crime, they're full on assassins for organised crime, they are full on cartel members," he said.
The Mexican authorities and the United States drug enforcement agencies are struggling to even remotely control the trafficking of drugs across Mexico's borders.
Like a multinational company it is driven by the market. For now the demand is high. So the supply keeps coming.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:05:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Keeps Banks Closed After Reform Offer</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515412</Link>
        <Description>Restrictions on banks remain after Athens is told to prepare a rescue plan before a summit on Sunday if it is to stay in the euro.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Greece Keeps Banks Closed After Reform Offer
Restrictions on banks remain after Athens is told to prepare a rescue plan before a summit on Sunday if it is to stay in the euro.
21:05, UK, Wednesday 08 July 2015
Play video "Greece Promises Reform Proposals"
Video: Greece Promises Reform Proposals
Share by email
Banks in Greece will stay closed for the rest of the week as the country makes a last-ditch attempt to head off a European crisis.
The 60 (42) daily limit on cash machine withdrawals will also remain in place until next Monday, state television reported.
The restrictions on banks were extended after Greece offered to start reforming its pension and tax systems next week.
Athens promised the economic reforms as it announced a new bid for funds from the European Stability Mechanism (ESM), the EU organisation that provides financial assistance for eurozone members.
Greek finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos carried hand-written notes
A letter to the ESM from Greece's finance minister said: "We propose to immediately implement a set of measures as early as the beginning of next week including: tax reform related measures; pension related measures."
The three-year loan would enable Greece to cover its debt obligations, the ministry said, preventing it from defaulting and ensuring it does not have to drop out of the euro.
Play video "We're An 'Austerity Laboratory'"
Video: We're An 'Austerity Laboratory'
It came as EU President Donald Tusk warned that Athens has one last chance to obtain a rescue deal if it wants to remain in the single currency.
Earlier Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras accused creditors of transforming Greece into an "austerity laboratory".
Eurozone leaders decided at an emergency meeting overnight that Greece should have one more chance to present a credible rescue plan.
The heads of all 28 EU member states will discuss any proposal at a "decisive" summit on Sunday.
It is understood the submission to the ESM is just part of what will be required.
Play video "Merkel: Candid Discussion On Greece"
Video: Merkel: Candid Discussion On Greece
When Mr Tsipras spoke to the EU parliament in Strasbourg on Wednesday morning, he said he was calling for negotiations on the "sustainability of (Greek) public debt".
But he said any "restructuring" of the debt would not "provide an extra burden" on European people.
Mr Tsipras said: "In many European countries, austerity programmes have been put into effect.
"However, nowhere have those programmes been so harsh and so long lasting as in Greece and it is no exaggeration to say that my country has over the past five years been transformed into an austerity laboratory.
"This experiment, I think all of us have to accept, has not been a success. Over these five years we have seen a sky rocketing of poverty, unemployment has soared ... as has debt.
Play video "What Next For Athens?"
Video: What Next For Athens?
"Today, the majority of the Greek people ... feel that they have no other choice other than to demand that they be given a way out of this dead end and they have expressed this in the most direct way possible and we have to implement that decision."
Greece's new finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos arrived at Tuesdays meeting with handwritten notes scrawled on hotel notepaper.
A close-up photograph showed they included the phrase "no triumphalism".
Spain's Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy welcomed the latest Greek proposals as a "positive" change in tone.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 11:39:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece May Have Finally Run Out Of Deadlines</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515196</Link>
        <Description>It is clear that EU leaders have lost their patience and a Grexit may be impossible to stop, writes Sky's Sophy Ridge.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Greece May Have Finally Run Out Of Deadlines
It is clear that EU leaders have lost their patience and a Grexit may be impossible to stop, writes Sky's Sophy Ridge.
09:39, UK, Wednesday 08 July 2015
Greek Prime Minster Alexis Tsipras leaves the emergency eurozone summit
Follow Sophy
Greece has until Sunday to present a plan for reform - or it faces leaving the euro.
I know you're probably rolling your eyes already - and I understand why. It's easy to have deadline fatigue.
Eurozone leaders have thrown around deadlines at emergency summits like confetti, and happily fail to stick to them.
This time, though, something is different.
As the night wound on , during which eurozone leaders held an emergency summit, it became clear that this was not a happy meeting.
1/2
Gallery: Photographer Captures 'No Triumphalism' Note
A zoomed-in version of Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos' note to self, including the words: "No triumphalism."
Greece's new finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos - the man billed as a bridge-builder with the rest of the eurozone - failed to turn up on Tuesday with any written, concrete proposals.
Instead he arrived clutching a scrap of paper from his hotel with handwritten notes scrawled on them. One of them simply stated: "No triumphalism."
If this was a reminder not to seem too smug about the Greek referendum rejecting austerity, then it was a spectacular misreading of the situation.
Rather than strengthening their negotiating hand, the No vote steeled the resolve of the leaders determined not to give Greece special treatment.
Play video "Eurozone's Ultimatum To Greece"
Video: Eurozone's Ultimatum To Greece
"The basis is not there" for negotiations, Angela Merkel seethed after the summit.
Does she think Greece will come up with the goods? "I am not very optimistic," she said.
Donald Tusk - president of the EU Council - added: "I have no doubt that this is the most critical moment in the history of the EU."
Jean-Claude Juncker - president of the EU Commission - said: "We have a Grexit scenario prepared in detail  I am strongly against Grexit but I cannot prevent it if the Greek government is not doing what we expected."
Play video "We're An 'Austerity Laboratory'"
Video: We're An 'Austerity Laboratory'
These are men whose entire careers are built on the EU project openly discussing the idea of Greece leaving its single currency.
The bad blood between the Greek negotiators and other eurozone leaders was clear.
Mr Juncker actually started banging the podium while rejecting the accusation by the former Greek finance minister that EU bigwigs were acting like a form of terrorism.
"Who are they? And who do they think I am?" he railed, in between fist bangs.
Play video "Merkel: Candid Discussion On Greece"
Video: Merkel: Candid Discussion On Greece
Yes, we have heard the threat of looming deadlines before.
But the eurozone leaders will find it difficult - even impossible - to climb down from Tuesday night's rhetoric if Greece fails to come up with the goods.
By the end of the week, we should have an answer.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:33:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>All US United Flights Temporarily Grounded</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515405</Link>
        <Description>The ground halt marked the second time in two months the Chicago-based airline has been hit by major technical issues.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
All US United Flights Temporarily Grounded
The ground halt marked the second time in two months the Chicago-based airline has been hit by major technical issues.
16:33, UK, Wednesday 08 July 2015
Long lines formed at United counters across the country
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
United Airlines has resumed operations after all US flights were temporarily grounded due to the company's latest computer systems glitch.
The ground halt, which lasted less than two hours, was related to "network connectivity", the airline said.
Passengers began tweeting images of long lines at United counters at airports across the country on Wednesday morning.
Passengers await updates in San Francisco. Pic: William Allison/Twitter
"We're being told the United systems issue is affecting all flights, nobody is going anywhere," wrote William Allison, who was briefly stranded at San Francisco International Airport.
Flight screens went blank. Pic: William Allison/Twitter
Other images showed flight information screens that had gone blank.
"We are working to resolve and apologise for any inconvenience," United said in a statement.
The line in Boise stretched across the terminal. Pic: Jeralyn Novak/Twitter
The Chicago-based airline suffered a similar technical issue on 2 June that prompted a temporary halt to all takeoffs nationwide.
United also suffered a series of problems in 2012 when it switched to a passenger information system previously used by merger partner Continental Airlines.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:39:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Microsoft Axes 7,800 Jobs As Phone Sales Lag</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515445</Link>
        <Description>The restructure is in addition to 18,000 job cuts announced last year as the company struggles to take on Apple and Google.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Microsoft Axes 7,800 Jobs As Phone Sales Lag
The restructure is in addition to 18,000 job cuts announced last year as the company struggles to take on Apple and Google.
21:39, UK, Wednesday 08 July 2015
The company said last year it would shed another 18,000 jobs
By Sky News US Team
Microsoft is cutting 7,800 jobs as it seeks to charge up its sluggish phone hardware business.
It is also writing off $7.6bn (4.9bn) relating to its purchase ofNokia's phone business last year.
The restructure is in addition to 18,000 job cuts the company announced last year.
Microsoft currently has more than 118,000 employees.
CEO Satya Nadella promised 'fundamental restructuring' of its phone unit
Chief executiveSatya Nadellasaid a "fundamental restructuring" of its phone business lay ahead.
"I am committed to our first-party devices including phones," MrNadella said in an email to staff .
"However, we need to focus our phone efforts in the near term while driving reinvention."
The company paid $7.3bn (4.7bn) in April 2014 for Nokia's handset unit, but the deal left it with just 3% of the smartphone market.
Ex-Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer made the Nokia deal
Now Microsoft is writing off more than the entire cost of the Finnish acquisition in what is known as an "impairment charge".
In addition, it is absorbing a $750m (490m) to $850m (550m) restructuring charge.
Microsoft's Windows Phone system has struggled to take on Apple's iOSand Google's Android system.
The Nokia deal was sealed by Mr Nadella's predecessor Steve Ballmer, who wanted to take on the iPhone.
Mr Ballmer famously laughed at Apple's handset before its 2007 release.
"There's no chance that the iPhone is going to get any significant market share," he remarked at the time. "No chance."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 08:11:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Army 'To Cut 40,000 Troops In Next Two Years'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515106</Link>
        <Description>America is set to reduce its Army to its smallest size since the Second World War, according to US media reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
US Army 'To Cut 40,000 Troops In Next Two Years'
America is set to reduce its Army to its smallest size since the Second World War, according to US media reports.
06:11, UK, Wednesday 08 July 2015
As many as 40,000 soldiers and 17,000 civilian employees could be cut
Share by email
The US Army is reportedly planning to cut 40,000 soldiers from its ranks over the next two years.
The losses would see it reduced from its current size of around 490,000 to 450,000 by the end of the budget year in September 2017, according to US media.
That would make it the smallest it has been since just before it entered the Second World War.
It is also said to be planning a further 17,000 civilian job cuts as part of the cost-saving initiative.
A US defence official speaking to the AFP news agency confirmed the reports.
The losses, tipped to affect almost all of the Army's foreign and domestic posts, are expected to be confirmed this week.
USA Today says the cuts are revealed in a document it has obtained.
The plans have raised concerns over the country's defence capabilities.
According to USA Today, it was argued in budget documents in 2013 that going below 450,000 troops could mean the US could not win a war.
At the peak of fighting in Iraq and Afghanistan, the US Army had some 570,000 soldiers, the publication said.
The report was published just a day after US President Barack Obama said the US should step up its campaign against Islamic State in Syria and Iraq, warning that a long battle lay ahead.
He said: "This will not be quick. This is a long-term campaign. It will take time to root them out, and doing so must be the job of local forces on the ground with training and air support from our coalition."
Last month the Pentagon announced it was sending a further 450 US troops to act as advisors to Iraqi troops attempting to seize back the western city of Ramadi from IS militants.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:00:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant Found Dead In Channel Tunnel</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514615</Link>
        <Description>The incident comes days after around 150 migrants tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant Found Dead In Channel Tunnel
The incident comes days after around 150 migrants tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
11:00, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Both passenger and freight services have been disrupted
A migrant has died trying to reach Britain through the Channel Tunnel on a freight train.
Operator Eurotunnelsaid the incident happened near Calais at around 5amBST (6am local time).
A section of the tunnel was closed for investigation and both freight and passenger services have been disrupted.
"Following the discovery of migrants on a freight shuttle, early this morning, the shuttle was immediately stopped," said a French official.
"During an investigation by border police, a deceased migrant was found in the tunnel," he added.
Play video "Tunnel Travel Chaos After Strike"
Video: Tunnel Travel Chaos After Strike
Authorities have yet to say how the migrant died.
It is the second migrant fatality in as many weeks following the death of an Eritrean while trying to get on a train at Coquelles last month.
A Eurotunnel spokesman said freight services were affected more than passenger trains, which were"running with slight delays".
He added: "We are working very hard to restore full services as soon as possible."
Play video "Migrants Try To Get On To Lorries"
Video: Migrants Try To Get On To Lorries
The incident comes days after around 150 migrants caused delays and cancellations when they tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
There have been increased calls for a resolution to the migrant crisis in Calais, which has escalated in recent months.
Around 3,000 people displaced from countries including Eritrea, Syria and Afghanistan have set up camp near the port.
Last week more than 3,000 truckers had to queue for several days in high temperatures on the M20 following a wildcat strike by ferry workers in France.
Play video "Inside Asylum-Seeker Camp (Archive)"
Video: Inside Asylum-Seeker Camp (Archive)
Hauliers have also faced problems with migrants desperately trying to clamber on board theirHGVs to the UK.
French authorities have faced claims they are not doing enough to safeguard lorry drivers from intimidation and violence.
The Road Haulage Association (RHA) has suggested deployment of the French military to boost security in Calais amid growing fears that a death could occur.
Port of Dover officials said last week's ferry strike cost the UK economy 1bn.
Play video "Queues At St Pancras And Kent"
Video: Queues At St Pancras And Kent
They have joined calls for "robust contingency plans" to be introduced to ensure the port - a 100bntrade route - can operate unimpeded.
Home Secretary Theresa May and her French counterpart Bernard Cazeneuve last week agreed to increase the joint intervention fund to improve security in and around the Channel Tunnel.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:25:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian Bombers Intercepted Off US Coast</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514728</Link>
        <Description>Fighter jets are scrambled after four long-range Tu-95 "Bear" bombers fly close to Alaska and California on Independence Day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Russian Bombers Intercepted Off US Coast
Fighter jets are scrambled after four long-range Tu-95 "Bear" bombers fly close to Alaska and California on Independence Day.
12:25, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Four TU-95 "Bear" bombers flew close to the US on Independence Day
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
Four Russian bombers caused the US Air Force to scramble fighter jets after they flew close to the US coast, according to reports.
Two Russian Tu-95 "Bear" bombers were intercepted off Alaska at around 10.30am Eastern Time on Independence Day by two F-22 Raptor jets.
Just half an hour later another pair of Tu-95s were detected off the central coast of California and two F-15 Eagles were scrambled to intercept.
A spokeswoman for the North American Aerospace Defense Command (NORAD) did not confirm if either of the long-range bombers was armed, Fox News reported.
None of the Russian aircraft entered US airspace, which is 12 nautical miles off the coast, but defence officials have not revealed how close they were to US soil.
Michael Kucharek, a spokesman for NORAD, told Fox News: "These are not unprecedented flights, but we are postured to respond whether Alaska or California.
"At no time did the bombers enter North American sovereign airspace."
Russian bombers also flew close to US coastlines on 4 July 2013.
Last year, two more long-range bombers flew within 50 miles of California .
There have been at least 50 reported incidents of Russian aircraft being intercepted by US Air Force jets since 2006, the Washington Times reported.
The incident occurred on the same day that Russian President Vladimir Putin sent a congratulatory message to US President Barack Obama to mark Independence Day.
In 2014, Russian defence officials announced long-range bombers would expand their regular patrols to the Arctic, the Caribbean and the Gulf of Mexico.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:07:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Officer Describes Finding Britons Dead On Beach</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515031</Link>
        <Description>Hannah Witheridge and David Miller were found nearly naked and several metres apart, the police officer tells a Thai court.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Officer Describes Finding Britons Dead On Beach
Hannah Witheridge and David Miller were found nearly naked and several metres apart, the police officer tells a Thai court.
13:07, UK, Wednesday 08 July 2015
David Miller and Hannah Witheridge were killed in September last year
Share by email
By Jonathan Samuels, News Correspondent, on Koh Samui
A policeman has described finding the bodies of British backpackers Hannah Witheridge and David Miller, as the trial of the two men accused of their murder begins in Thailand.
The pair were killed last September shortly after meeting on the holiday island of Koh Tao.
Their bodies were found on the beach. Prosecutors say Miss Witheridge, 23, from Norfolk, had been raped and beaten.
Mr Miller, 24, from Jersey, drowned in the sea after receiving head injuries.
The first witness in the trial on Koh Samui told the court he found a gruesome sight as he arrived on the scene shortly after getting a 6.30am call.
Win Zaw Htun (L) and Zaw Lin (R) arrived at court on Wednesday morning
Lt Jakkapan Kaewkao said: "I found a man's body lying on the beach with seawater lapping his body. Then I found the woman's body behind the rocks."
Spots of blood were on the rocks, he added, and the two bodies were 12 metres apart and nearly naked. Mr Miller was face down.
1/11
Gallery: Accused At Crime Scene, October '14
Two workers from Burma suspected of killing two British tourists on the island of Koh Tao, stand near the crime scene during an October 2014 reconstruction
Both bodies showed signs of physical assault and Miss Witheridge appeared to have been sexually assaulted, he told the court.
The two Burmese men accused of the murders, 22-year-olds Win Zaw Htun and Zaw Lin, sat in court wearing orange prison uniforms with their legs shackled. Both men have pleaded not guilty to murder.
The defendants' lawyers criticised police handling of the case during cross examination, accusing officers of failing to secure the crime scene and call in experts quickly enough.
They asked the lieutenant why Mr Miller's body was moved before medics or a forensic team had arrived and whether police on Koh Tao knew how to test for DNA.
Lt Jakkapan said he moved Mr Miller's body to stop it being washed away.
The doctor who visited them after their detention, Chasit Yoohat, told the court the defendants confessed to him as he examined them.
The families of both victims have flown to Thailand to attend the trial and were seen arriving at the courthouse on Wednesday.
During the session, they saw photos of the backpackers' bodies as they were shown to the court.
A verdict is not expected until October.
The case has thrown a spotlight on Thailand's justice system after a chaotic police investigation and questions over the arrest of the alleged killers.
Police have previously said DNA found at the scene matches that of the defendants who were working illegally on Koh Tao and confessed to the murders after being arrested.
However, a short time after being detained the pair retracted their confessions, claiming they were abused and threatened by interrogators.
The court is expected to rule on the defence team's request to have DNA evidence from the scene re-tested by an independent laboratory.
Thai police deny any wrongdoing.
Both of the victims' families have said they are hopeful for a fair and transparent trial.
The family of David Miller said in a statement: "Over the coming weeks we hope to gain a better understanding as to how such awonderful young man lost his life in such idyllic surroundings in such a horrible way.
"We have borne our thoughts in silence as we have not wanted to influence any court proceedings, but simply want to see justice done fairly and openly."
Ms Witheridge'sfamily said: "Speculation, rumour and theory have been incredibly hurtful to our family and Hannah's friends, making an already unthinkable time harder to bear.
"We of course want to see those responsible for the brutal murder of our precious girl brought to justice."
The start of the trial will last three days and the prosecution is expected to continue calling witnesses who were the first on the murder scene.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 12:08:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teen Guilty Of Hacking PlayStation Network</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1515242</Link>
        <Description>The Lizard Squad Twitter account boasts about the lenient sentence given to a 17-year-old who committed 50,000 cybercrimes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
Teen Guilty Of Hacking PlayStation Network
The Lizard Squad Twitter account boasts about the lenient sentence given to a 17-year-old who committed 50,000 cybercrimes.
10:08, UK, Wednesday 08 July 2015
Lizard Squad - a group of hackers - claimed responsibility for the attack
Share by email
A teenager who helped to ruin Christmas for millions of children by shutting down the PlayStation and Xbox networks has been convicted of 50,700 offences.
But despite being part of the Lizard Squad network that has taken credit for major hacking attacks over the last few years, the 17-year-old user - known as "zeekill" - was let off with a slap on the wrist.
He was given a two-year suspended sentenced by a court in Finland - where he has not been named by local media due because he is a minor - and ordered to fight cybercrime as part of his rehabilitation.
The identities of Lizard Squad's members were shrouded in mystery until security analyst Brian Krebspublished a blog post naming some of the suspects, including zeekill, earlier this year.
Lizard Squad's attacks on PlayStation and Xbox saw the consoles' online gaming networks knocked offline for several days in late December.
In April zeekillwas also implicated in an online harassmentcampaign against a 20-year-old.
Thousands of people ending up calling the victim's home after an online hoax said his telephone number was the hotline for a Tesla car competition.
Espoo District Court also found him guilty of tampering with servers at MIT and Harvard University, as well as money laundering.
The Lizard Squad Twitter account gleefully boasted about the sentence, which surprised many for its leniency.
One tweet read: "Zeekill got a suspended sentence for 2 years. 0 time spent in prison."
Another said: "Basically he'll be monitored for 2 years by the local police. Gotta love Finland :)."
A final message read: "All the people that said we would rot in prison don't want to comprehend what we've been saying since the beginning, we have free passes."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
