<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="SMH">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Mon Aug 17 17:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant find 'hot spots' warming faster</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/climate-change/university-of-nsw-climate-researchers-steven-sherwood-and-nidhi-nishant-find-hot-spots-warming-faster-20150618-ghhlxd.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant find 'hot spots' warming faster
Date
Climate researcher Steven Sherwood has found data issues are to blame for not detecting hot spots.
Photo: James Brickwood
This article is part ofClimate for Change,aFairfax Media series on global warming. Full coverage can be found here .Follow our coverage on Facebook .
It's the hole in the science that global warming sceptics have long exploited  the apparent lack of "hot spots" high in the atmosphere over the tropics that should be there if climate models were accurate.
We found the global warming signal is stronger than we thought it would be.
Climate researcher Steven Sherwood
After years of debate, University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant have resolved data issues that not only reveal those "hot spots" to be there  but they are in fact warming some 10 per cent faster than modelling has predicted.
"[We found] the global warming signal is stronger than we thought it would be," Professor Sherwood said.
Advertisement
For Professor Sherwood, it's just another example  along with the "global warming hiatus" that has been deemed this month by US scientists to be a data error  of how so-called climate sceptics can divert or distort debate.
"The models predict that if, and only if, man is the cause of warming, the tropical upper air, six miles above the ground, should warm up to thrice as fast as the surface, but this tropical uppertroposphere "hotspot" has not been observed in 50 years of measurement," Christopher Monckton, a prominent Britishsceptic, wrote in 2010.
That the upper troposphere hadn't warmed compared with the surface would be a major surprise for science, Professor Sherwood said.
Surfacetemperatures have been rising at about 0.15 degrees per decade. As air rises over the tropics, a lot of water vapour condenses, releasing latent heat, that warms up the air.
"It would have been truly astonishing if the temperatures in the upper troposphere hadn't been going up faster than at the surface," Professor Sherwood said.
"If it didn't appear, it would have nothing to do with whether humans are causing climate change, but it would mean there is something about the way air mixes in the atmosphere that we didn't know," he said. "And the ramifications for climate change could go either way."
Professor Sherwood's paper found data issues were to blame for not detecting the hot spot that really was there.
One source of the bad data was the result of weather balloons becoming more accurate by making the monitors less susceptible to warming by the sun.
"Over time, it has happened less, so it has made the temperatures appear not to rise when they really did rise," he said.
Professor Sherwood said he hadn't bothered to follow how sceptics had responded to his paper, saying that scientist had merely identified a problem and worked to resolve it.
He is more critical, though, of the role played by the sceptics in proclaiming an apparent slowdown in surface temperature warming over the past decade or so.
Even this so-called hiatus is now being viewedby the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as largely the result of instrument misreadings.
"A lot of scientific effort went into the hiatus although none of us believed it was very significant just because the sceptics were making so much hay out of it," he said "It's an example of where the sceptics are succeeding to some extent in distracting scientists away from perhaps more important work that they could be doing."
Sceptics' interest in "hot spots" they believed weren't there and the fact they couldn'taccount for the additional heat being trapped by the Earth from its increased greenhouse gases, pointedto a contrast in approaches, he said.
"They're not aiming for a self-consistent and reasonably comprehensive description of the world. What they are aiming at is to discredit something," he said.
Resolving issues such as the hot spot removedone more data dispute for sceptics to pick over, he said, adding,"the inconsistencies don't go on forever".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:40:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Some All Blacks not up to it: Hansen</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/some-all-blacks-not-up-to-it-hansen-20150709-3z04y.html</Link>
        <Description>All Blacks coach Steve Hansen says some players' inability to handle the Apia pressure cooker in NZ's 25-16 win over Samoa has been noted.</Description>
        <MainBody>Some All Blacks not up to it: Hansen
Sport World Union News Breaking News Sport
Date
Print
The All Blacks will prepare for one of the great adjustments in Test rugby with words of warning ringing in their ears from Steve Hansen.
The coach was unimpressed with elements of their season-opening 25-16 win over Samoa in Apia, even when taking into consideration the heat, the rustiness of the players and the absence of Highlanders and Hurricanes players involved in the Super Rugby final last weekend.
He is demanding considerable improvement for the opening Rugby Championship Test against Argentina on Friday next week in wintry Christchurch, where a temperature drop of about 25C must be factored in.
Several unnamed players have plenty to prove after Hansen delivered his verdict on how the team struggled to cope with the intensity of the world No.9 ranked Samoans on Wednesday.
Advertisement
"Some guys coped with it and others didn't, so we got answers there," he said.
"We're nowhere near where we need to be. It wasn't as good a performance as we were hoping for but there were a number of factors."
More than two-thirds of his team hadn't played for the previous three weeks, while the draining humidity was something they were never going to be prepared for, given they arrived in Samoa less 48 hours before kick-off.
The challenging nature of the Test was a positive because of the lessons learned and the realisation they have a long way to go in the Rugby Championship.
"There's no point us panicking. We've got a base camp and now we can keep working and keep going up.
"We know we've got to go a long way up if we're going to be really competitive."
Hansen faces a selection juggle next week, with the 17 players involved in the Super Rugby final becoming available again.
They will arrive in Christchurch on Friday, one day before the Samoan returnees.
Changes are likely but Hansen is giving few clues about how many.
He will farewell the six players who were additions to his original squad: Seta Tamanivalu, Tom Taylor and Ofa Tu'ungafasi, plus three who made their debuts in Apia - George Moala, Brad Weber and Charlie Ngatai.
Another to make his debut, prop Nepo Laulala, remains as injury cover for the injured Charlie Faumuina while halfback Andy Ellis does the same for Tawera Kerr-Barlow.
Kerr-Barlow makes his international return from a long-term knee injury for the Maori All Blacks against Fiji in Suva on Saturday.
Maori captain Ngatai was to join them from Apia.
Hansen was relieved the bruising Samoan Test hadn't resulted in any major injuries.
Luke Romano had suffered a gruesome facial injury but was cleared of any break by x-rays.
The lock was to undergo a further scan in New Zealand to confirm there was no fine crack to his cheekbone.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:10:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Promise seen in an inexpensive cholera vaccine</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/promise-seen-in-an-inexpensive-cholera-vaccine-20150709-gi8dkv.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Promise seen in an inexpensive cholera vaccine
Date
A patient with cholera symptoms taken to to the Doctors Without Borders (MSF) cholera treatment centre in the slum neighbourhood of Cite Soleil  in Port-au-Prince in 2010.
Photo: Getty
UN peacekeepers linked to Haiti's cholera outbreak
New York: An inexpensive, little-known cholera vaccine appears to work so well that it can protect entire communities and perhaps head off explosive epidemics like the one that killed nearly 10,000 Haitians in 2010.
A major study published on Wednesday in The Lancet found that the vaccine gave individuals more than 50 percent protection against cholera and reduced life-threatening episodes of the infection by about 40 percent in Bangladesh, where the disease has persisted for centuries.
Cholera patient Onel Cadet in Port-au-Prince in 2010.
Photo: Getty
In a result that surprised researchers, the vaccine worked far better than supplying families with chlorine for their water and soap for hand-washing.
Advertisement
The study is "really very important, and testing it in 270,000 people is phenomenal," said DrLouiseIvers, a health policy adviser at Partners in Health, a medical charity that fightscholera in Haiti.
"In the last five years, the conversation has switched from 'we shouldn't use vaccine' to 'How can we use it best?'"
Haiti struggled to contain the cholera epidemic in 2010.
Photo: Getty
DrEric Mintz, a cholera expert at the Centresfor Disease Control and Prevention, said the study "shows that the vaccine is feasible for government medical care".
Cholera, which causes severe diarrhoea, kills about 91,000 people a year, most of them children. It is endemic in more than 50 countries, mostly in Asia and Africa.
When the infection unexpectedly spreads to a new country where no one has immunity - as it did after Haiti's 2010 earthquake, and in Zimbabwe in 2008 - it can overwhelm health systems and kill thousands within months.
The surprisingly effective vaccine, called Shanchol, has been slow to gain acceptance.
It is based on a vaccine first made in Vietnam, then improved in the 1990s at the International Vaccine Institute in Seoul, South Korea. Shanchol has been made by Shantha Biotechnics in India since 2009.
The vaccine's protection lasts at least five years and perhaps longer, although that has not been proven yet.
It contains two killed disease-causing strains of cholera bacteria, is taken orally, and comes in a bottle about the size of a typical "energy shot". The two-dose regimen costs $5.The Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, which paid for much of the research, hopes to get the price below $2.70 as production increases.
New York Times
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:49:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sodhi earns Black Caps ODI call-up</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/sodhi-earns-black-caps-odi-callup-20150709-3yzyq.html</Link>
        <Description>Ish Sodhi has been selected for Zimbabwe leg of the Blacks Caps' August tour, but will be replaced by seamer Doug Bracewell in South Africa.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sodhi earns Black Caps ODI call-up
World Sport Breaking News Sport Cricket
Date
Print
New Zealand leg-spinner Ish Sodhi has been included in a 16-strong one-day squad named on Thursday to tour Zimbabwe next month, but will miss the South African leg.
Injured players Trent Boult and Corey Anderson will miss the tour, as will skipper Brendon McCullum and paceman Tim Southee, who are both being rested.
Kane Williamson will captain the side in McCullum's absence.
Sodhi, who previously represented New Zealand at Test and Twenty20 level, is in line to make his ODI debut for the Black Caps.
Advertisement
He was one of three players to miss out when New Zealand Cricket last week named its 20-strong list of contracted players.
Batsman Colin Munro, another to miss out on a contract, has also been included in the team which will play six ODIs and three Twenty20 matches over 25 days beginning in Harare on August 2.
Sodhi will be replaced by seamer Doug Bracewell for the South African leg of the tour, which begins in Durban on August 14.
Black Caps coach and selector Mike Hesson says the choice of Sodhi for Zimbabwe and Bracewell for South Africa was very much a matter of picking horses for courses.
"We think Ish will be useful on pitches which tend to be slow and take turn, and against a Zimbabwe team stacked with right-handers," he said.
"But we're unlikely to need a third spinner in South Africa, which is why we've opted for another seamer in Doug."
Hesson said the absence of injured and rested players provided plenty of opportunity for a host of returning players to further their international credentials.
Batsmen Tom Latham and Munro are joined by pace bowler Adam Milne and allrounder James Neesham, who return to the fray following layoffs due to injury.
"There are chances there for batsmen such as Tom and Colin, for Ish and for a handful of bowlers," Hesson said.
"And, not least, it's another good opportunity for (stand-in captain) Kane Williamson to continue upskilling in terms of leadership."
New Zealand: Kane Williamson (captain), Doug Bracewell (South Africa series), Grant Elliott, Matt Henry, Martin Guptill, Tom Latham, Mitchell McClenaghan, Nathan McCullum, Adam Milne, Colin Munro, James Neesham, Luke Ronchi, Mitchell Santner, Ish Sodhi (Zimbabwe series), Ross Taylor, Ben Wheeler.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:39:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Yemen government tells UN it agrees to conditional truce</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/yemen-government-tells-un-it-agrees-to-conditional-truce-20150709-gi88i0.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Yemen government tells UN it agrees to conditional truce
Date
Houthi militants man a checkpoint on a street leading to the site of a car bomb attack near a mosque in Sanaa on Tuesday.
Photo: Reuters
Dubai: Yemen's government has told the United Nationsit would agree to a truce to end more than three months of fighting provided key "guarantees" were met, a spokesman said.
Selling black market fuel during an acute shortage in Sanaa earlier this month.
Photo: Reuters
"The Yemeni authorities have informed the Secretary General of the United Nations Ban Ki-moon of its agreement to implement a truce in the coming days," spokesman Rajeh Badi saidfrom the government's seat of exile in Saudi Arabia.
Advertisement
Yemen's president had on Wednesday "set guarantees for the success of the truce", Mr Badi said.
These included the release of prisoners by Yemen's dominant Houthi group, including the loyalist defence minister, as well as the Houthis' withdrawal from four southern and eastern provinces where they are fighting local militias.
A girl looks from the roof of her house, which is located next to the building of the Houthi movement's politburo that was hit by a Saudi-led air strike on Tuesday.
Photo: Reuters
The UNhas received a letter from the Yemeni government and was "seeking clarification from the parties", said Mr Ban's spokesman Stephane Dujarric.
Saudi Arabia and an Arab coalition have been bombing the Iran-allied Houthis and their allies in Yemen's army in an effort to back armed opponents of the Houthis and restore Mr Hadi.
There was no immediate comment from the Houthi movement, which views its takeover of the capital Sanaa last September, and of much of the country since, as a revolution against a corrupt government backed by the West.
The Houthi movement's politburo after it was hit by a Saudi-led air strike in Sanaa on Tuesday.
Photo: Reuters
The Houthis have not yet accepted a UNSecurity Council Resolution passed in April which recognises Mr Hadi as the legitimate president and calls on them to quit seized land.
Aid agencies say the fighting and a near-blockade imposed by an alliance of Arab states aimed at weapons deliveries to the Houthis has caused a humanitarian catastrophe, with most people needing some kind of aid.
More than 3,000 people have been killed in the conflict and over a million displaced, and the UNhas been urgently pushing for a pause to help impoverished people.
"We're optimistic (the Houthis) will agree, because this will guarantee the sending of aid to Yemenis," Mr Badi said.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:32:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sheffield Shield game to be played in NZ</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/sheffield-shield-game-to-be-played-in-nz-20150709-3yzwa.html</Link>
        <Description>NSW will face Western Australia in Lincoln this summer in the first Sheffield Shield fixture to be played overseas.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sheffield Shield game to be played in NZ
Sport World Breaking News Sport Cricket
Date
Print
Cricket Australia will take the unprecedented step of playing a Sheffield Shield game overseas to help the Test side prepare for a series in New Zealand.
The South Island town of Lincoln - just outside of Christchurch - will host a first-class match between NSW and Western Australia next year, starting on February 3, according to the full 2015-16 schedule released on Thursday.
CA shifted the fixture overseas instead of scheduling a tour game prior to the two-Test series in New Zealand, which starts on February 12.
The majority of Test players not involved in the one-day series against the Black Caps are likely to feature in the Shield game.
Advertisement
"If we were to schedule a warm-up game, it would have to happen in parallel with the Chappell-Hadlee (one-day series) ... and Sheffield Shield," high-performance manager Pat Howard said.
"That would obviously have a negative impact on the Shield because we'd have to pull extra players out of that competition.
"Therefore we thought bringing a Shield match, involving a number of international players, to New Zealand was a different option that gives us some strong preparation in local conditions."
The other two Shield games in round six will be played on the east coast of Australia.
"Obviously we can't cater for everyone in that scenario, and a number of our Test players will be playing in the Chappell-Hadlee series," Howard said.
The Shield has been running since 1892-93 and there has never been a fixture played outside Australia.
Meanwhile, Australia Day cricket will return to Adelaide Oval next year after it lost the fixture to Sydney in 2015.
One of three Twenty20 clashes with India will be played in the South Australian capital on January 26.
It follows the announcement that Adelaide Oval will host the first-ever international day/night Test later this year.
T20 international cricket also returns to the SCG for the first time since 2010 as part of a new deal with the historic venue, adding to the Test and any ODI matches already scheduled.
It means there will be no more international fixtures at ANZ Stadium for at least the next seven years.
HIGHLIGHTS OF THE 2015-2016 SUMMER SCHEDULE
* Australia Day fixture returns Adelaide Oval, which will also host the first ever day-night Test match - against New Zealand - from Nov 27-Dec 1
* There'll be a day-night round of Sheffield Shield with matches in Adelaide, Melbourne and Hobart from Oct 27-30 ahead of first international day-night Test
* Lincoln in NZ and Coffs Harbour to host Sheffield Shield matches
* Domestic One-Day Cup to be hosted exclusively in Sydney from Oct 5-26
* Big Bash League starts Thursday Dec 17
* Inaugural Women's Big Bash League to start Dec 5
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:28:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Australian couple caught having sex on park bench in Florence</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/australian-couple-caught-having-sex-on-park-bench-in-florence-20150709-gi8dnl.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Australian couple caught having sex on park bench in Florence
Date
An Australian couple are in hot water after being detained for having sex near Florence's famous Ponte Vecchio bridge.
Photo: Vince Caligiuri
In yet another case of Australians behaving badly overseas,two travellers have been detained by Italian police for allegedly having sex on a park bench in Florence.
The 20-year-old woman and 23-year-old man, bothAustralian tourists, are accused of committing obscene acts in a public place.
Passers-by rang Italian police after seeing them at 11.45pm on Monday, July 7, ona bench in the LungarnoTorrigiani public gardens, local news site Ansa reported.
The gardens are a popular riverside spot close to Florence's famous Ponte Vecchio bridge.
Advertisement
Local media reported that the smattering of shockedonlookers didn't perturb the couple and they only stopped when police officers arrived.
Such incidents have prompted the city's residents to start a Facebook page, Firenze Degrado , outing the bad behaviour of visitors.
Last year, an American couple were photographed having sex on the doorstep of a Chanel boutique and an American girl was caught urinating between two cars in the middle of the city.
Australian travellersare well-versed at getting into hot water while abroad.
Last year, footage emerged of two touristsstreaking through Peru's famous Machu Pichu. The country's Ministry of Culture released a statement identifying them as 18year-oldLiam Timothy from Sydney and30 year-old Topp Mathew Jared from New Zealand.
In March, drunk Australian Jacob Saveisberg was arrested for stealing two raw prawns from a Patong restaurant, stuffing them in his pockets and refusing to give them back when caught.
The Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade has been contacted for comment.
Fairfax Media
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:36:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd sentenced to home detention in New Zealand</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/ls-celebrity-news/former-acdc-drummer-phil-rudd-sentenced-to-home-detention-in-new-zealand-20150709-gi8dnc.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Former AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd sentenced to home detention in New Zealand
Date
Beat it: Phil Rudd is one of a long list of notable drummers.
Photo: Redferns
Phil Rudd wants to rejoin AC/DC: A Current Affair interview
As the judge dressed Phil Rudd down, perhaps the most stinging rebuke was that the former AC/DC drummer's playing wasn't anything special.
Rudd was sentenced in the Tauranga District Court on Thursday to eight months home detention on drugs and threatening to kill charges .
Rocky ride: Malcolm Young, Bon Scott, Cliff Williams, Angus Young and Phil Rudd back in the AC/DC heyday.
Photo: Redferns
Rudd appeared in front of Judge Thomas Ingram for sentencing after pleading guilty to possession of cannabis and methamphetamine and one charge of threatening to kill. He has been on bail the whole time.
Advertisement
The judge warned Rudd he would go to prison if he breached the terms ofhis sentence.
"I stone cold guarantee that's where you'll end up. I'm not yourheadmaster, I'm not your father, I'm a judge."
Phil Rudd pleaded guity in Tauranga District Court in New Zealand to drug charges and threatening to kill.
Photo: Rebekah Parsons-King/Fairfax NZ
He said Rudd would be monitored 24 hours a day during his homedetention, to be served at his waterfront Tauranga mansion.
"There is simply no place to hide"
Earlier, the court was told Rudd's actions were the result ofmethamphetamine psychosis and he was addicted to the drug.
Affidavits to the court said Rudd would lose tens of millions ofdollars if he was convicted because he couldn't tour to certaincountries with AC/DC.
Judge Ingram said there was no evidence he had an offer from the bandand he was not convinced that Rudd's drumming was integral to theAC/DC sound.
"Queen replaced Freddie Mercury," he said.
RUDD'S OFFENDING
It was revealed in November last year that Rudd had been arrested and charged with drugs offences and attempting to procure a murder, a charge that was dropped 24 hours later.
In April, when Rudd pleaded guilty to possessing drugs and threatening to kill, the court heard he'd made a call to an associate asking him to "take out" a former security guard turned personal assistant after becoming angry when his solo album launch in August last year flopped.
He fired a number of employees, including his victim.
On September 25 at 8.12pm Rudd phoned an associate in Australia saying he wanted the victim "taken out", and "taken care of because they were a bunch of f***en c****.
Rudd then offered the associate $200,000, one of his cars, a motorbike or a house, which the associate believed was payment for the request.
The next day at 8.27am, Rudd called the victim and asked if he was "on today", the victim said yes at which point Rudd said "I'm going to come over and kill you".
Rudd made two further calls to the same victim, who hung up after realising it was Rudd.
Police then obtained a warrant to search Rudd's Bureta home in Tauranga on November 6.
When police arrived Rudd was in the lounge and attempted to conceal a container of crumbs, which after testing was found to be 6gms of cannabis.
Rudd then pulled out a bag of cannabis from the couch, the court was told.
ESR testing found the bag contained a further 20.2gms of cannabis.
When police arrived at the home Rudd was wearing jeans and no shirt. In his front jeans pocket police discovered a white powder, which turned out to be 0.273gms of methamphetamine.
Police searched the home where they found 0.205g of methamphetamine in the master bedroom, 47.2gms of cannabis in the hallway cupboard, and a further 17.9gms of cannabis in the pool room bedroom.
A total of 0.478gms of methamphetamine and 91gms of cannabis was found.
ADRIFT FROM THE BAND
Previously Rudd has said he's seen the error of his ways and wished he was touring with AC/DC again.
Rudd told an Australian TV station in May his former bandmates, including guitarist Angus Young, weren't talking to him.
"They haven't called me. I wrote them a letter and I tried to get in touch with Angus but I've had no contact from anybody," Rudd told A Current Affair. "I'm very disappointed, but that's life."
Rudd said he was "fit and ready to go" and wished he was touring with AC/DC.
"I've seen the error of my ways and it's onward and upward from here."
Angus Young said last year that Rudd was not himself and needed help.
Last year, Rudd was ordered to pay more than $72,000 after kicking a door in and sacking workers during a tantrum at his restaurant, Phil's Place.
AC/DC are due to play concerts in Wellington and Auckland in December, the last gigs of a world tour.
Stuff
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:41:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia plans anti-terrorism wall along border with Libya</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/tunisia-plans-antiterrorism-wall-along-border-with-libya-20150709-gi8882.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tunisia plans anti-terrorism wall along border with Libya
Date
Tunisian soldiers and police patrol the area of Mount Salloum near Algeria's border earlier this month.
Photo: Reuters
Tunis: Tunisia is building a 160-kilometre-long wall along its border with Libya as part of a plan to protect the country from Islamist militants operating in Libya, Prime Minister Habib Essid has told local news organisations.
The wall is one of several new security measures announced by the government in the aftermath of two attacks by Islamist extremists against foreign tourists that have shaken the country and threatened its economy. A gunman killed 38 tourists at a beach hotel in Sousse tendays ago, and in March two men shot dead 21 tourists at the national museum in Tunis.
The plan to build a fence dates back to 2012 but the authorities now see it as a matter of urgency after the beach attack last month, which was inspired by the jihadist group Islamic State.
Patrolling Tunisia's borders earlier this month.
Photo: Reuters
Links between jihadist movements in Tunisia and Libyadate back to the 1980s. Suggestions that Tunisian militants may be training in Libya began in early 2012, after a civil war opened security vacuum in which Islamist militancy flourished.
Advertisement
The president, Beji Caid Essebsi, has declared a 30-day state of emergency, saying the country is "not safe".
Addressing parliament on Wednesday, Mr Essebsi said terrorist plots aimed at massive deaths and destruction of the country's economy remained an issue.
Tunisian President Beji Caid Essebsi earlier this week.
Photo: AP
Tunisia has exported more fighters to wars in Syria and Iraq than any other country, and Islamic State has often featured Tunisians in propaganda material.
After the latest attack the government fired the governor of Sousse and 16 police officials for failings in intelligence gathering and their slow response to the emergency. President Beji Caid Essebsi declared a state of emergency on Saturday, and 1,300 armed guards have been deployed to protect hotels and tourist sites.
The attacks have also focused concerns about the lawlessness in Libya and the growing presence of the Islamic State group and other extreme Islamist organisations there. All three gunmen involved in the two attacks were trained in a militant camp near the town of Sabratha in western Libya, officials have said. Tunisia's border with Libya runs for 480 kilometres through the desert, and militants and smugglers easily evade border controls.
A tourist takes pictures of his partner in Sidi Bou Said, a popular tourist destination near Tunis, earlier this week.
Photo: Reuters
The new wall, or berm, will run for 160 kilometresbetween the major border crossings at Ras Jedir on the coast and Dhehiba. It will serve as a temporary barrier until a more expensive electric fence can be built, Mr Essid told the newspaper La Presse.
Tunisian officials have said they are looking for international assistance and equipment to help control their long desert border with Libya, including helicopters and radar systems.
In a national television address on Saturday, Mr Essebsi warned Tunisians that they were in a state of war against terrorism. Among the threats, he said, were instability in Libya and the porous desert border.
"We have 500 kilometres of borders with Libya, most of them are desert and we need special technical equipment to control those borders that we do not have," he said.
"Unfortunately, Libya is not doing its role in fighting terrorism," he added. "There are many armed organisations within Libya that are like states within a state, there are two governments, one recognised internationally and one that is not, plus there is foreign interference from different countries with different agendas. Libya's borders are long and they neighbor different countries and we don't have a common organized system to protect these borders."
New York Times, Telegraph
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:59:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Italian PM Silvio Berlusconi found guilty of bribing Italian senator</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/former-italian-pm-silvio-berlusconi-found-guilty-of-bribing-italian-senator-20150709-gi88k8.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Former Italian PM Silvio Berlusconi found guilty of bribing Italian senator
Date
Judge Serena Corleto reads the sentence in the Naples court on Wednesday.
Photo: AP
Woman tells of sex with Berlusconi
Naples:Italy's former prime minister Silvio Berlusconi has beenfound guiltyof bribing a senator to switch factions in a move which helped topple the then government in 2008.
The court in southern Italy on Wednesday sentenced Berlusconi to three years in jail and banned him from holding any public office for five years, a judge said in a ruling shown live on television.
Nicolo Ghedini, lawyer of Silvio Berlusconi, leaves the Naples court on Wednesday.
Photo: AP
The four-times prime minister denied the charges. However, he will not have to serve his sentence because a statute of limitations kicks in later this year before any appeal can be held, preventing the courts from pursuing the case further.
Advertisement
Berlusconi lost his parliamentary immunity when he was ejected from the Senate in 2013 following a conviction for tax fraud. Despite remaining head of his once-triumphant Forza Italia party, he is struggling to revive his political fortunes.
Prosecutors accused Berlusconi, 78, of bribing Sergio De Gregorio, a former senator in the small Italy of Values party, to switch allegiance in 2006 in a move that eventually helped topple the government of Berlusconi's arch rival, Romano Prodi.
Silvio Berlusconi photographed last year.
Photo: AP
De Gregorio admitted receiving 3 million euros ($4.47 million) from Berlusconi and attempting to persuade other senators to change sides. He was separately sentenced to 20 months in jail after a plea bargaining deal.
Berlusconi said he gave De Gregorio the money to help finance a new political movement. "This is a desperately unjust and unjustifiable ruling," said his lawyer, Niccolo Ghedini.
Berlusconi finished in March a community service sentence tied to the tax fraud case, but fresh judicial woes are lapping at his feet.
A court in the southern city of Bari has ordered him to appear as a witness on Friday in the trial of seven defendants who are accused of procuring prostitutes for the ex-premier's alleged sex parties between 2008 and 2009.
Earlier this year, Berlusconi was acquitted of having sex with an under-aged prostitute at the parties when the judge ruled it could not be proved that he knew the woman was just 17.
Last week, magistrates in Milan completed an investigation into suspicions key witnesses in the case were bribed, saying they believed Berlusconi gave 10 million euros to persuade various women to keep quiet.
Berlusconi has denied the accusations and a court will rule later this year whether to press further charges.
He was ousted as prime minister in 2011 in the midst of the euro zone financial crisis. He has repeatedly said he was forced from office as a result of a plot by European Union officials.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:44:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lee tees up US Women's Open assault</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/lee-tees-up-us-womens-open-assault-20150709-3yzjv.html</Link>
        <Description>Australia's highest-ranked women's golfer Minjee Lee is ready to take on the challenging par-70 Lancaster Country Club course at the US Women's Open.</Description>
        <MainBody>Lee tees up US Women's Open assault
Breaking News Sport Golf Sport World
Date
Print
Teen star Minjee Lee will spearhead Australia's charge at the US Women's Open starting on Friday (AEST) at the Lancaster Country Club in Pennsylvania.
The 19-year-old from Perth, who recently replaced veteran Karrie Webb as the highest-ranking women's golfer in Australia, says she is looking forward to taking on the challenging 6,483-yard, par-70 course.
"I am really excited to be Aussie No 1. To represent Australia is such a great honour and I want to work even harder to keep my ranking as long as Webby did," said Lee.
"The course is in great condition, the rough is growing out and especially with the undulating greens I think the tournament will shape up to be very challenging and a great test for us all.
Advertisement
"I really like the look of the course and we all love a challenge so I'm really looking forward to getting started."
Asked about her chances, she responded: "You never know when it's going to be your week so I'm going to take one shot at a time and play smart golf.
"I want to enjoy the atmosphere and most of all have fun."
Fellow compatriots joining Lee in the field are Webb, who won back-to-back Open championships in 2000 and 2001, fellow Queenslanders Katherine Kirk and Sarah Jane Smith, Victorian Breanna Elliott and RACV Ladies Masters Champion Su Oh.
Elliott and Oh made it through qualifying.
Elliott will be the first player to tee off at the Open. She will be joined in the morning groups by Smith, Oh and Webb.
Kirk and Lee will tee-off in the afternoon.
Local newspapers have reported they were expecting over 10,000 spectators to attend the event and the interest has been evident with great crowds during the practice rounds.
"I was surprised how many people were out spectating already just for the practice rounds," said Lee.
In total 156 players are vying for the Open title and their share of the $US4.5 million ($A6.06 million) purse with the winner taking home a cheque for $US810,000 ($A1.09 million).
American Michelle Wie is the defending champion.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:55:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Torrential rains increased 12 per cent in three decades as world warmed: study</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/climate-change/torrential-rains-increased-12-per-cent-in-three-decades-as-world-warmed-study-20150709-gi87ne.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Torrential rains increased 12 per cent in three decades as world warmed: study
Date
Heavy rain events are on the increase, climate researchers say.
Photo: Andy Zakeli
Torrential rains have become more frequent worldwide since 1980, with Southeast Asia getting the biggest increase in downpours, a scientific study said on Tuesday.
The report adds to evidence that rising man-made greenhouse gas emissions are stoking extremes from heatwaves to precipitation. Warmer air absorbs more moisture, which then can be dumped in downpours.
"We find a clear overall upward trend for these unprecedented hazards," lead author Jascha Lehmann of the Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research said in a statement.
Overall, there were 12 per cent more downpours which broke local records from 1981 to 2010 than would be expected in an unchanged climate, according to an analysis of rainfall statistics from thousands of weather stations since 1900.
Advertisement
South-east Asia had the biggest increase with 56 per cent, while Europe saw a 31 per cent rise.
The study said 2010 was the year with most records broken, from Texas to Pakistan. Flooding in Pakistan was the worst in its history, killing more than 2,000 people and affecting 18 million.
The findings may help guide investment in flood prevention, from reinforcing riverbanks to building storm drains in cities.
Dim Coumou, one of the authors, said natural climate shifts could explain the frequency of downpours until about 1980.
"After that we clearly go out of that range and see many more record-breaking events," he told Reuters. "I would expect this to continue over coming decades - it depends of course on how much humanity will emit."
The U.N. panel of climate scientists concluded last year there had been "an increase in the number of heavy precipitation events in a number of regions" since about 1950 due to rising temperatures.
In April, a Swiss-led study said global warming was to blame for most extremely hot days and almost a fifth of heavy downpours.
Officials from almost 200 countries will meet in Paris in late 2015 to try to work out a U.N. deal to curb greenhouse gas emissions.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:41:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Angela Merkel can't escape Greece's geopolitical pull as she tours Balkans</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/angela-merkel-cant-escape-greeces-geopolitical-pull-as-she-tours-balkans-20150709-gi87hu.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Angela Merkel can't escape Greece's geopolitical pull as she tours Balkans
Date
German Chancellor Angela Merkel looks up before a summit over the Greek crisis in Brussels on Tuesday. Now on a tour of the Balkans, she cannot forget Greece's problems affect the whole region.
Photo: Virginia Mayo
Berlin:As a student in East Germany, Angela Merkel would travel by train south through the Balkans and gaze over to Greece, wondering when she might be able to visit.
Now she can't escape its pull.
As the German chancellor began a three-country tour of the western Balkans on Wednesday, she would never be far from the spillover effects of the five-year-long Greek crisis. From regional economic malaise to creeping Russian influence and a growing refugee crisis, all can be traced back to Greece.
The fact isn't lost on Mrs Merkel, who knows well that further political instability in Greece would risk more turbulence across the Balkans, according to a government official with knowledge of her strategy. That's one argument in favour of a deal to bind it to the euro, the official said, asking not to be named because those negotiations are private.
Advertisement
"Stability in the Balkans definitely feeds into Merkel's more general worries about the potential geopolitical consequences of a Grexit," said Famke Krumbmueller, a London- based analyst at political risk consultancy Eurasia Group. "Having a failed state on the border of Europe could spill over into the already unstable Balkans."
She travelled to Albania, then to Serbia, where she's staying overnight in Belgrade, before heading on to Bosnia and Herzegovina, where a bloody civil war ended only 20 years ago.
Greece's problem
On arrival at the Serbian capital, Mrs Merkel made a pointed comparison between Greece, whose ongoing membership in the euro is at risk, and its Balkan neighbour, which is vying to enter the European Union.
"Right now we are seeing that things in Greece are not going that well," she told reporters in Belgrade on Wednesday. Serbia, by contrast is "a totally different situation where a government has chosen out of conviction a difficult path".
Building on a visit to Croatia in July last year, the tour is a demonstration of her engagement with a region that has become a testing ground for Germany's ambitions for a more active foreign policy.
"We need to move things forward step by step" in the Balkans, Mrs Merkel said in Tirana, the Albanian capital, on Wednesday alongside Prime Minister Edi Rama. "This can only happen if we give a European perspective to countries in the western Balkans not just on paper, but also make it a reality."
Putin signal
By attempting to anchor the Balkans in a Western orbit, the chancellor is sending a signal to Russian President Vladimir Putin, who has made his own play to reassert Russian influence in what were communist allies until the fall of the Berlin Wall.
Mr Putin hosted Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras for talks in St Petersburg last month, raising concern in some European capitals about the orientation of a country that was kept out of the Soviet grip by Allied intervention after World War II.
"Greece is an anchor of stability in the Balkans," former German foreign minister Joschka Fischer said in an interview with the weekly Die Zeit. "If it falls, it could have wide-ranging consequences for the entire region  and that's been noted in Moscow."
Remembering Srebrenica
Greek banks have the potential to amplify the crisis across the Balkans after using euro adoption to expand abroad. At particular risk are Romania and Bulgaria, where Greek lenders control more than a quarter of banking assets, while units also operate in Serbia and Macedonia.
It's a part of Europe Mrs Merkel knows from her trips south to the Bulgarian-Greek border  as related in a 2012 speech  and which was later convulsed by the Balkan wars of the 1990s that splintered the constituent parts of Yugoslavia into seven states. Her trip will wind up in Sarajevo, where she'll meet with representatives of the Mothers of Srebrenica group whose family members died in the July 1995 massacre of the same name.
Two of those states, Slovenia and Croatia, are now members of the European Union and Mrs Merkel is keen to show that Germany cares about the rest of the western Balkans, and regards them as potential EU members, the official said.
There's a lot of catching up to do. Croatia, the EU's newest member after joining in 2013, has an economy smaller than that of Luxembourg despite having almost nine times the population. Albania generated a gross domestic product of 10 billion ($14.9 billion) last year, a fifth of Croatia's.
Greek effect
Here too, the ripples of Greece's economic woes are being felt, as a source of employment for many across the western Balkans evaporates. In addition, the region has become a main corridor for refugees fleeing across the eastern Mediterranean, many of them heading for Germany.
For all those reasons, the Greek crisis is being watched very closely in Serbia, according to Jan Techau, the Brussels-based director of Carnegie Europe. Any rupture to Greece's membership in the euro or the EU might cause Serbia to reconsider its pro-western course, he said.
"Merkel will consider all these geopolitical factors very carefully in her handling of the Greek crisis," Mr Techau said in an interview from Brussels. "The timing of her Balkan trip is perfect."
Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
