<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="SMH">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Mon Aug 17 17:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant find 'hot spots' warming faster</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/climate-change/university-of-nsw-climate-researchers-steven-sherwood-and-nidhi-nishant-find-hot-spots-warming-faster-20150618-ghhlxd.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant find 'hot spots' warming faster
Date
Climate researcher Steven Sherwood has found data issues are to blame for not detecting hot spots.
Photo: James Brickwood
This article is part ofClimate for Change,aFairfax Media series on global warming. Full coverage can be found here .Follow our coverage on Facebook .
It's the hole in the science that global warming sceptics have long exploited  the apparent lack of "hot spots" high in the atmosphere over the tropics that should be there if climate models were accurate.
We found the global warming signal is stronger than we thought it would be.
Climate researcher Steven Sherwood
After years of debate, University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant have resolved data issues that not only reveal those "hot spots" to be there  but they are in fact warming some 10 per cent faster than modelling has predicted.
"[We found] the global warming signal is stronger than we thought it would be," Professor Sherwood said.
Advertisement
For Professor Sherwood, it's just another example  along with the "global warming hiatus" that has been deemed this month by US scientists to be a data error  of how so-called climate sceptics can divert or distort debate.
"The models predict that if, and only if, man is the cause of warming, the tropical upper air, six miles above the ground, should warm up to thrice as fast as the surface, but this tropical uppertroposphere "hotspot" has not been observed in 50 years of measurement," Christopher Monckton, a prominent Britishsceptic, wrote in 2010.
That the upper troposphere hadn't warmed compared with the surface would be a major surprise for science, Professor Sherwood said.
Surfacetemperatures have been rising at about 0.15 degrees per decade. As air rises over the tropics, a lot of water vapour condenses, releasing latent heat, that warms up the air.
"It would have been truly astonishing if the temperatures in the upper troposphere hadn't been going up faster than at the surface," Professor Sherwood said.
"If it didn't appear, it would have nothing to do with whether humans are causing climate change, but it would mean there is something about the way air mixes in the atmosphere that we didn't know," he said. "And the ramifications for climate change could go either way."
Professor Sherwood's paper found data issues were to blame for not detecting the hot spot that really was there.
One source of the bad data was the result of weather balloons becoming more accurate by making the monitors less susceptible to warming by the sun.
"Over time, it has happened less, so it has made the temperatures appear not to rise when they really did rise," he said.
Professor Sherwood said he hadn't bothered to follow how sceptics had responded to his paper, saying that scientist had merely identified a problem and worked to resolve it.
He is more critical, though, of the role played by the sceptics in proclaiming an apparent slowdown in surface temperature warming over the past decade or so.
Even this so-called hiatus is now being viewedby the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as largely the result of instrument misreadings.
"A lot of scientific effort went into the hiatus although none of us believed it was very significant just because the sceptics were making so much hay out of it," he said "It's an example of where the sceptics are succeeding to some extent in distracting scientists away from perhaps more important work that they could be doing."
Sceptics' interest in "hot spots" they believed weren't there and the fact they couldn'taccount for the additional heat being trapped by the Earth from its increased greenhouse gases, pointedto a contrast in approaches, he said.
"They're not aiming for a self-consistent and reasonably comprehensive description of the world. What they are aiming at is to discredit something," he said.
Resolving issues such as the hot spot removedone more data dispute for sceptics to pick over, he said, adding,"the inconsistencies don't go on forever".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:48:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World News Update, What you need to know</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-world/world-news-update-what-you-need-to-know-20150710-3z1tx.html</Link>
        <Description>World News Update, What you need to know</Description>
        <MainBody>World News Update, What you need to know
Breaking News World World
A Serbian war crimes suspect nicknamed "Captain Dragan" has arrived in Zagreb from Australia to face allegations of torture and murder after battling extradition for a decade.
ELSEWHERE:
BRUSSELS - Less than two hours ahead of a midnight deadline the eurozone has received new bail-out reform plans from Greece.
WASHINGTON - Hackers who breached US government databases stole personal information of 21.5 million people, officials say following an investigation into the attack widely blamed on China.
Advertisement
LONDON - A 16-year-old girl has been charged with two terror offences in northern England in a case linked to a 15-year-old boy accused of inciting a man to commit a terror attack at an Anzac event in Melbourne.
PARIS - Paris, the city of light, love, and tourists, has released a new mobile app called "Yes I speak touriste" to help foreigners struggling with their French find some respite.
LONDON - Touching family photographs have been released to mark the christening of Princess Charlotte.
LONDON - A young woman who was critically injured in a car crash in Scotland spent three days waiting with the dead body of her boyfriend for help to arrive.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:44:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Do other countries have Donald Trumps? Of course they do</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/do-other-countries-have-donald-trumps-of-course-they-do-20150710-gi96gm.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Do other countries have Donald Trumps? Of course they do
Date
It's not just the US, a lot of nations have their own Donald Trump.
Photo: Reuters
As America stumbles its way through the early stages of Donald Trump's unlikely and uncomfortable bid for the presidency, some here are wondering what exactly Trump says about the nation.
"Do other national cultures create men like Donald Trump?" Atlantic writer Jeffrey Goldberg asked on Twitter. "Asking for the United States."
Do other national cultures create men like Donald Trump? Asking for the United States.
 Jeffrey Goldberg (@JeffreyGoldberg) July 8, 2015
Goldberg probably asked that question in jest, but there may be real concern behind it. To many, Trump's political career seems to combine three ugly undercurrents of USpolitics: the outsize role of money, the never-ending campaign season, and America's embrace of reactionary celebrity figures.
Advertisement
So do other countries really have their own Donald Trumps? Well, yes, of course they do. When Goldberg asked his question, there was a flood of responses from foreign readers, who pointed to their own rich and rude political figures. Some comparisons don't quite seem fair (you may dislike Dominique Strauss-Kahn or Nigel Farage, but their faults and virtues are different from Trump's), many, many other suggestions did seem apt.
Trump is a product of American society, but he's not unique. His mixture of murky wealth, extreme arrogance and vulgar chauvinism can be found all over the world, albeit with local spins. Here are just a handful of the world's other Donald Trumps.
Silvio Berlusconi
Silvio Berlusconi.
Photo:Remo Casilli
One of the best-known examples of a foreign Trump might be Silvio Berlusconi, the business magnate who was Italy's prime minister for about nine years in total. Berlusconi, like Trump, espoused an entrepreneurial spirit but soon became better known for his misdemeanours and odd behaviour: One time, he hid behind a monument and jumped out to scare German leader Angela Merkel, shouting, "Coo-coo" ("She enjoyed it," Berlusconi later said). Like Trump, he even has an intriguing hairstyle.
Is Berlusconi a true Trump? Perhaps, but there are certainly a number of important differences. Berlusconi was a real world leader for a considerable amount of time, and he does appear to have - on limited occasions - displayed the grace and gravitas that comes from that position. "I met Berlusconi once," Goldberg tweeted when someone suggested him. "He didn't seem quite so ridiculous. Ridiculous, but not at that level."
Berlusconi's fall from grace was worsened by the pressures created by allegations of corruption and sexual misdeeds during his notorious "bunga bunga" parties: These factors have led him to face a number of charges after leaving office in 2011. Trump's business dealings may be murky, but they appear to fall short of outright corruption - and it seems he gets more pleasure from outraging sections of the American public than he does from any sordid soirees.
Clive Palmer
Clive Palmer. 
Photo:Glenn Hunt
Clive Palmer, an Australian billionaire, certainly creates Trump-size headlines. He has plans to construct a replica of the Titanic. He wants to open his own "Jurassic Park." He has accused his political opponents of being funded by the CIA. He has called Chinese officials "mongrels" (and later apologised).
The similarities between the two go beyond headlines and money, however. For years, Palmer has been accused of using his wealth to influence politics in Australia. In 2013, he established a political party and became a member of parliament.
Some in Australia wonder whether Trump is following Palmer's playbook, but there are also differences between the two: Palmer seems genuinely intent on gaining political power, not just attention.
"Imagine if Donald Trump had his own party, and that party controlled the balance of power in the Senate," is how one Australian academic summed it up last year.
Vladimir Zhirinovsky.
Chinese billionaire Chen Guangbiao.
Photo:LUCAS JACKSON
China is a country full of very rich people, and often these very rich people have deep political ambitions. However, it's possible that Chen Guangbiao is the only one who can match Trump for sheer arrogance.
There are numerous examples of how big Chen's ego is, including his audacious and doomed attempt to buy The New York Times and his insistence on singing at media events. Perhaps the best example of Chen's ego, however, is a business card he handed to me in 2013.
Despite his Trump-like qualities, Chen is a very much a product of the modern Chinese world. He made his fortune in the recycling business, and his high profile comes from a combination of his charitable endeavours and his ultranationalist foreign policy messages.
While not a politician, Chen appears to be intertwined with the government, which is said to have issued decrees to state media banning negative coverage about him.
Vladimir Zhirinovsky
Vladimir Zhirinovsky. Photo: AP.
While Vladimir Zhirinovsky, the loud-mouthed Russian politician who founded the Liberal Democratic Party in 1990, may lack the business credentials of Trump (his background is in the military), he has a habit of making statements that suggest a kinship with the American businessman.
For example, he suggests arming every single person in Russia so they can kill birds. He threatened to carpet-bomb Poland and the Baltic states. He rode a donkey in an infamous 2012 election video. In fact, he has probably gone further than even Trump would: A few years ago, he punched a political rival in the face after a televised election debate.
Despite his antics, Zhirinovsky is a political force in Russia. His ill-named political party, actually a far-right populist entity, gained 11 percent of the vote in the 2011 Duma election. It seems that Zhirinovsky is a product of the chaos of the post-Communist period in Russia. As The New York Times wrote in 1994: "Mr. Zhirinovsky can be racist, cruel, endlessly strident. But he knows how to draw a crowd and how to hold it."
Tomio Okamura
In many parts of Central and Eastern Europe, business success and political populism mingle, creating fertile grounds for local variants of Trumps.
The Czech Republic's Tomio Okamura seems especially appropriate for this list, however. Like Trump, he has not only parlayed entrepreneurial success into a spot on a reality television show, he has also been able to gain political momentum and a seat in the Czech senate. At one point, polls suggested that he was the third most popular politician in the country.
The similarities go further, however. Like Trump, Okamura has espoused anti-immigrant views: He recently told Czechs that they should walk pigs near mosques and suggested sending the Roma to India. And, like Trump, he comes from an immigrant background. Trump's mother is Scottish; Okamura was born in Tokyo to a Japanese-Korean father and a Czech mother.
TheWashington Post
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:36:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OPM hack affected 21.5 million people, US says</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/opm-hack-affected-215-million-people-us-says-20150710-gi9614.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>OPM hack affected 21.5 million people, US says
Date
Hackers have stolen security clearance information of 21.5 million people from the Office of Personnel Management's system.
Photo: Daniel Acker
Cyberwar explained in 11 pictures
WASHINGTON: The massive hack last year of the Office of Personnel Management's system containing security clearance information affected 21.5 million people, including current and former employees, contractors and their families and friends, officials said on Thursday.
That is in addition to a separate hack  also last year  of OPM's personnel database that affected 4.2 million people. That number was previously announced.
Together, the breaches arguably comprise the most consequential cyber intrusion in US government history. Administration officials have privately said they were traced to the Chinese government and appear to be for purposes of traditional espionage.
Advertisement
The 21.5 million figure includes 19.7 million individuals who applied for a background investigation, and 1.8 million non-applicants, predominantly spouses or people who live with the applicants. Some records also include findings from interviews conducted by background investigators, and about 1.1 million include fingerprints, officials said.
Individuals who underwent a background investigation through OPM in 2000 or afterwards are "highly likely" affected, officials said. Background checks before 2000 are less likely to have been affected, they said.
The lapse enabled hackers to gain access not only to personnel files but also personal details about millions of individuals with government security clearances  information a foreign intelligence service could potentially use to recruit spies.
Because the exposed records included information on individuals who served as references on security clearance applications, US official said that stolen data includes details on certain employees' relatives and friends.
The announcement seemed only to strengthen Republican calls on Capitol Hill for OPM director Katherine Archuleta and her chief information officer, Donna Seymour, to resign.
"Since at least 2007, OPM leadership has been on notice about the vulnerabilities to its network and cybersecurity policies and practices," Utah Republican RepresentativeJason Chaffetz, chairman of the House oversight and government reform committee, said in a statement.
"Their negligence has now put the personal and sensitive information of 21.5 million Americans into the hands of our adversaries," MrChaffetz said. "Such incompetence is inexcusable. Again, I call upon President Obama to remove director Archuleta and Ms Seymour immediately."
The intrusion of OPM's system containing security clearance data took place in June or early July 2014, officials said. In December, a separate OPM database containing personnel records was also hacked, affecting 4.2 million current and former employees.
In both cases, officials said, the hackers worked for the Chinese government, although the Obama administration has not formally accused Beijing. "It is an enormous breach, and a huge amount of data that is personal and sensitive was available to adversaries," FBI director James Comey said at a Senate intelligence committee hearing on Wednesday.
"We're talking about millions and millions of people affected by this," he said. "I'm sure the adversary has my SF86 now," referring to the Standard Form 86, which all applicants for security clearances must fill out.
He noted it lists "every place I've lived since I was 18, every foreign trip I've taken, all of my family and their addressesI've got siblings. I've got five kids. All of that is in there."
"It is a huge deal," Mr Comey said
At a roundtable with reporters on Thursday, MrComey called the heist a "treasure trove of information".
Just imagine, he said, "if you were a foreign intelligence service and you had that data  how it would be useful".
Not every spy's data is in the system. The CIA conducts its own security clearance investigations and keeps that data to itself. Even so, some US officials have said that a foreign spy service might be able to identify US intelligence operatives by comparing stolen OPM records with rosters of US personnel at embassies overseas.
Names that appear on US embassy lists but are missing from the OPM files might enable a foreign intelligence service with sophisticated computer capabilities to identify CIA operatives serving overseas under diplomatic cover.
"That's not conclusive that the person might be undercover CIA," said one official, who requested anonymity to discuss a sensitive topic."But it's certainly worth taking a look at." Such are the concerns that some officials have about the lack of security over the government's data systems. "This is something that we must do better at defending against, because you can't really blame our adversaries for trying to get this information," the official said. "It's really about how do we defend against it." OPM has been under fire for the breaches.
OPM officials have defended the agency, saying that it was only because of a strategic plan put in place by MsArchuleta shortly after she became director in November 2014 that the breaches were discovered.
"There are certainly some people I would like to see given the boot for not paying attention to cybersecurity, but Katherine Archuleta is not one of them," said one administration official, requesting anonymity to discuss personnel issues. Maybe they didn't move as fast as they should have but they were at least moving in the right direction and were prioritising it in an agency that didn't think of itself as having a security mission."
It has taken weeks for the agency to come up with the number, in large part because of the difficulty, officials say, of reviewing data contained in numerous computers that make up the background check system. Many of the computers are antiquated. There were many instances of names being duplicated  sometimes because someone was listed as a reference in several background checks as well as having their own clearance.
Employees are angry and two class-action lawsuits have been filed against the agency and MsArchuleta.
The White House has been discussing possible response options, to include covert actions that would not be publicly announced. Among the options, officials said, are economic sanctions. MrObama recently signed an executive order creating a sanctions tool to punish cyber attacks and cyber economic espionage.
However, some US officials caution against taking actions against foreign states when the cyber theft is conducted for traditional spying motives. The United States has not officially named China or the motive, but privately officials say it appears China was conducting a form of traditional espionage. The data taken does not appear to fall into the category of intellectual property or commercial secrets that can be used to benefit another country's industry.
"I think we have to be careful about the importance of continuing to draw a line between theft for economic advantage and traditional foreign intelligence activities, which may look untraditional now that they're in the cyber realm," said Democratic CaliforniaRepresentativeAdam Schiff, a member of the House intelligence committee. "We want to draw a bright line" that hacking for economic benefit "is a violation of international norms".
If the United States blurs the line between economic spying and foreign intelligence spying, "we risk undermining the fight against economic theft".
The government has already begun taking steps to mitigate the damage in the intelligence and counterintelligence arena, MrSchiff said. "We're going to be doing that for years, in terms of the whole range of steps that we'll have to take to protect our people and our sources and methods."
He added: "The consequences will be very far-reaching."

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:28:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Finance News Update, what you need to know</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-world/finance-news-update-what-you-need-to-know-20150710-3z1t9.html</Link>
        <Description>Finance News Update, what you need to know</Description>
        <MainBody>Finance News Update, what you need to know
World Breaking News World
WORLD FINANCE UPDATE:
The Australian dollar is weaker against the greenback, which bounced overnight despite disappointing US jobless figures.
At 0630 AEST on Friday, the Aussie was trading at 74.56 US cents, down from 74.77 cents on Thursday.
And the Australian share market looks set to open lower, after Wall Street rose following strong gains in Asian and European equity markets.
Advertisement
At 0645 AEST on Friday, the September share price index futures contract was down 20 points at 5,388.
ELSEWHERE:
BRUSSELS - Less than two hours ahead of a midnight deadline the eurozone has received new bail-out reform plans from Greece.
LONDON - The Bank of England has voted to leave its main interest rate at a record-low 0.50 per cent in the face of low inflation and steady growth.
WASHINGTON - The number of people seeking unemployment benefits in the US rose last week to the highest level since late February. But the increase likely reflected temporary auto plant shutdowns rather than any underlying labor market weakness.
MOSCOW - A summit of the BRICS countries has concluded with a declaration calling on the five member states to intensify their industrial development.
KIEV - Ukraine says it will offer nearly 350 state firms for sale to foreign investors at an upcoming US conference aimed at saving the war-shattered country's imploding economy.
PURCHASE, New Jersey - PepsiCo is using pricier products to help drive up sales.
NEW YORK - Coty is buying 43 beauty brands from Procter &amp; Gamble Co, including Miss Clairol, Covergirl and Max Factor.
NEW YORK - Ford plans to move production of two of its smallest cars from its assembly plant in Michigan to a plant abroad by 2018 to maintain competitiveness.
DETROIT - Honda has added 4.5 million vehicles in countries outside the U.S. to the growing list of cars and trucks recalled for Takata air bags that could explode with too much force and spew shrapnel at drivers and passengers.
NEW YORK - IBM has unveiled a powerful new chip which the company says could boost computing power of "everything from smartphones to spacecraft."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:33:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Communist crucifix' puts Pope Francis on the spot</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/communist-crucifix-puts-pope-francis-on-the-spot-20150710-gi95l0.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>'Communist crucifix' puts Pope Francis on the spot
Date
Please Log in to update your video settings
Video will begin in 5 seconds.
Please Log in to update your video settings
First the Pope, next Obama
Following a visit from the Pope to Bolivia, President Evo Morales seeks to reestablish diplomatic ties with the US.
PT2M7S 620 349
Video settings
La Paz: The Vatican is seeking to explain a "Communist crucifix" given to Pope Francis by Bolivian President Evo Morales, saying it's a symbol of dialogue and not an offensive melding of faith and ideology.
Mr Morales gave the crucifix carved into a hammer and sickle to Francis when they met on Wednesday upon the Pope's arrival in Bolivia.
The Vatican wasn't expecting the unusual gift and it immediately raised eyebrows.
Pope Francis is presented a gift of a crucifix carved into a wooden hammer and sickle, the Communist symbol uniting labour and peasants, by Bolivian President Evo Morales in La Paz, Bolivia.
Photo: AP
It turns out the crucifix was designed by Jesuit activist Luis Espinal, who was assassinated in 1980 by suspected paramilitaries during the months that preceded a military coup. Francis is a fellow Jesuit and he stopped to pray at the site where Espinal's body was dumped.
Advertisement
Vatican spokesmanFatherFederico Lombardisaid onThursday the Pope had hadno idea that Espinal had designed such a crucifix.
Father Lombardi said Espinal's fellow priests said he had designed the crucifix as a symbol of dialogue and commitment to freedom for Bolivia during a turbulent time.
Many church theologians have bitterly denounced the Marxist influences on Liberation Theology, but Francis has tried to rehabilitate the movement  without the Marxism.
AP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:58:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confederate flag to be removed from South Carolina state house</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/confederate-flag-to-be-removed-from-south-carolina-state-house-20150710-gi95ii.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Confederate flag to be removed from South Carolina state house
Date
Please Log in to update your video settings
Video will begin in 5 seconds.
Please Log in to update your video settings
Republican's tearful plea to remove the Confederate Flag
In the wake of the Charleston shootings, South Carolina Republican Jenny Anderson Horne pleads for 'the symbol of hate' to be removed from state Capitol grounds.
PT1M53S 620 349
Why not stop selling guns?
Washington:The Confederate flag will be removed from the grounds of the South Carolina state house less than a month after a white racist allegedly murdered nine African-Americans - including a state senator - in a Bible class in the hope of provoking a race war.
The vote to remove the flag came on Thursday morning in the state capital, Columbia, after 15 hours of debate. It included a tearful pleafrom a white Republican politician who is a descendant ofConfederate leader Jefferson Davis.The flag's removalwas approved 94 to 20.
A protester against the Confederate flag, Theron Foster, of Columbia, gives a clear message outside the South Carolina state house.
Photo: John Bazemore
Shortly after 4pm local time Governor NikkiHaley spoke on the state house floor, saying that South Carolina was following the example of the dead  who had invited the gunman into their church to pray, and their families, who had forgiven him.
Advertisement
As family members watched on she signed the bill into law using nine pens, which were to be presented to the families.
The flag will be removed from the grounds at 10am on Friday.
The Confederate battle flag flutters in the breeze in front of the South Carolina state house.
Photo: John Bazemore
"South Carolina can remove the stain from our lives," said Representative Joe Neal, a 64-year-old black Democrat. "I never thought in my lifetime I would see this."
The flag, which many opponents liken to the swastika, was not raised above the South Carolina state house until 1962, when the southern states were in revolt against federally enforced desegregation.
After an earlier debate it was removed from the dome of the capitol building in 2000 and moved to a Confederate war memorial, where it remained flying at full mast after last month's murders even while other official flags were lowered to half.
The Confederate battle flag flies next to a Civil War memorial outside the South Carolina state house.
Photo: AP
The flag has long been the focus of controversy across the South, where its defenders view it as symbol of their heritage rather than of slavery and oppression.
During the debate some representatives tried to stall the process by moving amendments, one which would have seen a similar flag raised in the battle flag's place.
At a crucial point the Republican representative of Charleston, Jenny Anderson Horne, a descendant of the Confederate leader Jefferson Davis, wept as she called for the flag to be immediately removed.
"I cannot believe that we do not have the heart in this body to do something meaningful  such as take a symbol of hate off these grounds on Friday  and if any of you vote to amend, you are ensuring that this flag will fly beyond Friday. And for the widow of Senator [Clementa]Pinckney and his two young daughters, that would be adding insult to injury  and I will not be a part of it," she said.
"And for all of these reasons, I will not vote to amend this bill today. We may visit this another session, another year. But if we amend this bill, we are telling the people of Charleston: We don't care about you. We do not care that someone used this symbol of hate to slay [nine] innocent people who were worshiping their God."
She concluded by saying, "We need to follow the example of the Senate: Remove this flag  and do it today, because this issue is not getting any better with age."
She left the dais to an ovation and hugs from colleagues.
Many Americans have been shocked at how quickly the Confederate battle flag has been abandoned since the shooting.
Within days, Governor Haley, who in the past has supported the flag's presence on the memorial, spoke out against it.
In his eulogy to Senator Pinckney, the pastor of Mother Emmanuel, President Barack Obama addressed the flag directly for the first time.
"It's true a flag did not cause these murders. But as people from all walks of life, Republicans and Democrats, now acknowledge, including Governor Haley, whose recent eloquence on the subject is worthy of praise as we all have to acknowledge, the flag has always represented more than just ancestral pride," he said.
"For many, black and white, that flag was a reminder of systemic oppression and racial subjugation. We see that now," he said.
Since then major retailers, both bricks-and-mortar and online, have pulled memorabilia bearing a likeness of the flag from sale and many public institutions are removing the flag.
The debate has stirred significant anger, with politicians on both sides of the debate in South Carolina reported to have received death threats.
Next week the Ku Klux Klan is planning a rally in defence of the flag at the state house.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:33:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moeen hails Bayliss influence</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/moeen-hails-bayliss-influence-20150710-3z1p0.html</Link>
        <Description>England's Moeen Ali says the influence of Trevor Bayliss was key to him dismissing Steve Smith and Michael Clarke on day two of the Ashes opener.</Description>
        <MainBody>Print
England all-rounder Moeen Ali claims inside knowledge from new coach Trevor Bayliss was key to his dismissals of Australian batting king-pins Michael Clarke and Steve Smith.
Moeen helped his side reach 434 after resuming day two on 343-7 with a breezy 77 from 88 balls.
He then starred with the ball by taking the scalps of the tourists' two most dangerous players as Australia slipped to 5-264 at stumps - a deficit of 166 runs.
Moeen's spot in the side had been questioned ahead of the series after he struggled against the West Indies in May, but he revealed a few quiet words from the former NSW coach, who only took on the England job three weeks ago, had worked wonders.
Advertisement
"He knows a lot of the (Australian) guys quite well," he said.
"He's had an input, but a lot of the guys have played against them already.
"Input has come from everybody. Trevor's more of a motivator ... telling us to enjoy and play our best cricket."
Smith looked well set for big score and showed his class with three boundaries off a Moeen over.
However, the world's No.1-ranked player, whose technique as a No.3 batsman has been questioned by former England spinner Graeme Swann, got himself into a terrible tangle facing a fairly harmless looking delivery when on 33.
With his arms and legs all over the place, Smith attempted to shovel the ball over the top of Moeen's head, but only succeeded in lobbing it straight to Cook at short mid-on.
Clarke also got a start and, although he lacked fluency early on, was beginning to find his range with a classy drive through extra cover from a Moeen delivery that pitched too short.
But from the off-spinner's very next over, Clarke was back in the dressing room for 38 after trying to dance down the pitch to a full delivery, only to hammer the ball straight back at the bowler who took a sharp catch at waist height.
"Smith kept using his feet to me and I almost went a little bit one-day mode, trying to bowl at his hip or fire it down the leg side," Moeen said.
"He got himself into a bit of a mess really, but I'm obviously happy to get him.
"They were two big wickets ... but it's more in the context of the game - two very good players."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:08:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ignominous record for unlucky Rogers</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/ignominous-record-for-unlucky-rogers-20150710-3z1on.html</Link>
        <Description>Chris Rogers made history at Cardiff by becoming the first player in Test history to score seven successive 50s without reaching a century.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ignominous record for unlucky Rogers
Cricket Breaking News Sport World Sport
Date
Print
Chris Rogers etched his name in the Test cricket record books in Cardiff, but not for reasons befitting an excellent innings of 95 on day two of the Ashes series.
The veteran opener again demonstrated his prowess in British conditions as he joined Zimbabwe's Andy Flower, Sri Lanka great Kumar Sangakkara and West Indies pair Everton Weekes and Shivnarine Chanderpaul as players to have passed 50 in seven successive Test innings.
However, he is now the only man in that group to fail to cash in and make a century after being dismissed in the 90s for the second time in his last three visits to the crease.
Aside from a reviewed lbw appeal from Stuart Broad that showed he'd got the thinnest of edges into his pad, Rogers was largely untroubled as he approached what would be a fifth Test century.
Advertisement
But fully aware of his recent nerves in the 90s, his mindset appeared to change.
An awkward top-edge off Broad only just eluded Moeen Ali on the long leg boundary to give him a first six in Test cricket was as out of character as it gets for a player renowned for grit not glitz.
And five overs later he was back in the pavilion. Undone by an angled delivery from Mark Wood that found the edge of his bat and nestled in the gloves of Jos Buttler.
His anguished reaction was evidence of his frustration at a glorious chance gone begging.
Rogers insisted his new 'record' is not something to be upset about, but was frustrated he couldn't go on and post a big score on a pitch that's still good for batting.
"It's a nice stat. Shame none of them were hundreds," he said.
"As an opener it's so important to be consistent and by doing that you're doing a job for the team, so I can be quite proud of that I think."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:45:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aussies add four medals at UIni Games</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/aussies-add-four-medals-at-uini-games-20150710-3z1o9.html</Link>
        <Description>Australia sit tenth on the medal table at the World University Games in Korea after winning four medals on day six.</Description>
        <MainBody>Aussies add four medals at UIni Games
Breaking News Sport Sport World
Date
Print
Golds in athletics and swimming were part of a four-medal haul for the Australian team on day six of the World University Games in Korea.
Swimmer Holly Barratt put in a personal-best effort to take gold in the 50m backstroke, her second medal of the games in Gwangju.
The West Australian, who won a bronze in the 50m butterfly earlier in the week, won Thursday's race with a personal best of 28.04 seconds.
"I wasn't expecting that. It was quite a big (personal best) and I thought if I do a good race I might come in second, but the best thing for me was the time," Barratt said.
Advertisement
Queensland's Dane Bird-Smith, meanwhile, raced through persistent rain to win the 20km walk in the morning.
The 22-year-old beat out Canada's Benjamin Thorne to win by just three seconds.
Other Australian success came from the men's 4x200m freestyle relay side, who won silver, and Queensland long jumper Naa Anang, who produced a personal best to win bronze.
At the end of day six, the Uniroos sit tenth on the medal table with thirteen medals - three gold, two silver and eight bronze.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:58:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Indian judge lets rapist out of jail so he can 'mediate' with his victim</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/indian-judge-lets-rapist-out-of-jail-so-he-can-mediate-with-his-victim-20150710-gi94xh.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Indian judge lets rapist out of jail so he can 'mediate' with his victim
Date
Protest after the rape of a a women in New Delhi in 2014.
Photo: Reuters
Chennai:In a country still struggling to deal with widespread violence against women, an Indian judge has touched off a firestorm by suggesting that a rape victim and her attacker heal their rift in the hope of a happy ending.
When Madras High Court Judge P. Devadass recently let a rapist out of jail on bail so he could "mediate" with his victim, it caused an uproar among legal scholars and women's rights activists.
The move was deemed "retrograde," "misogynistic" and simply bad jurisprudence. Lawyers who work in the courthouse's mediation centre wrote a letter to the chief justice, demanding that Devadass'order be rescinded. India's Supreme Court, weighing in on a different case, said last week that any compromise between a rape victim and a perpetrator would be a "spectacular error".
Candle light vigil for a woman raped in a New Delhi convent school in March.
Photo: Reuters
Devadass, a former family court judge, declined through staff members to discuss his order. But critics say it provides a glimpse of the patriarchal attitudes still prevalent in the male-dominated Indian judiciary.
Advertisement
More thantwo years after the fatal gang-rapeof a student brought protesters to the streets and a clarion call for change, judges in India continue to court controversy with their comments in rape cases. One judge asserted that child prostitution is not rape, and another suggested that women who have premarital sex are prone to cry rape or kidnapping later.
The lawyers in the Madras High Court mediation centre, an alternative to the overburdened court system, arbitrate mostly civil cases and have called Devadass'order "highly inappropriate". They said it reinforces centuries-old Indian cultural stereotypes  that a woman who is the victim of sexual violence should marry the perpetrator to protect her honour, especially if a child is born from the assault.
"The thinking is if there has been a rape, there has been sexual contact and, therefore, the best solution for her would be to marry the man," said Geeta Ramaseshan, a Madras High Court lawyer and mediator. "It's a very patriarchal mind-set."
The victim, now 22, remembers vividly what happened to her in 2008. The aunt who raised her was at a funeral in a nearby town, she said, leaving her to babysit children in the home of her neighbour.
Her neighbour's son, V. Mohan, a universitystudent, had been nasty to her in the past but was friendly this time, offering her a cold drink. She soon became dizzy and passed out. When she came to, she was lying on the floor. Mohan beckoned her over to show her his mobilephone. He hadphotographed his assaultand threatened to use the images to blackmail her, she said.
"To this day, I do not know the reason why he raped me," the woman said quietly on recently.
A week after the rape, she broke down and told a friend. Word spread in the village, a cluster of just three lanes in the southern state of Tamil Nadu. Her father, an alcoholic who was an itinerant presence in her life, beat her. "Why did you not tell us?" relatives demanded.
Her family went to the police to file a report. The situation worsened when it became clear that she was pregnant. A DNA test later confirmed Mohan's paternity. He and his parents offered to pay a $US3000 settlement if she got an abortion. Even the village elders weighed in, also urging abortion.
Mohan was arrested and convicted in 2009, sentenced to seven years in prison. Last year, he filed an appeal.
In his recent order, Devadass ruminated that women were often the "soft targets of male lust" and lamented that there were two victims in this case  the woman as well as the child born as a result of the rape.
"Now, [the victim] has become mother of a child," the judge wrote. "But as on date, she is nobody's wife. So, she is an unwed mother. Now there is a big question mark looming large before [the victim] as well as her child, who is completely innocent."
The judge deemed that mediation was the best option in this case, noting that he had recommended it on another occasion earlier this year, with the rapist agreeing to marry the victim, a case now heading toward a "happy conclusion".
Sriram Panchu, a senior lawyer, said the judge's order is being protested partly because mediation is normally used to resolve marital or commercial disputes, not violent crimes.
The victim said that the judge's directive caught her by surprise and that she has been living in fear that her attacker would find and harm her.
"If I meet the judge, I would ask him, 'Do you know the pain I suffered as a child and was raped, and raising this child?' " she said. "You are sitting in an air-conditioned hall writing your judgment. Have you ever thought of me? How I have suffered? The scar still remains."
Mohan said in a telephone interview that he wants to pursue mediation, and his attorney, C. Arunkumar, said they would participate. Neither discussed the case in detail, although Mohan had earlier said that the sex was consensual.
Karuna Nundy, a Supreme Court lawyer, said there had been a slow attitudinal shift within the judiciary as gender-sensitivity training increases and awareness grows. But advocates say more is needed, including gender equity on the bench. Only a small percentage of judges in India's high courts are women, and there is only one female Supreme Court judge.
"The habits of patriarchy die hard  in any country," Nundy said.
Since the mediation order, the victim and her daughter, now seven, have taken refuge in a women's shelter. Over the weekend, they watched cartoons together as evening drew in.
The woman, soft-spoken and dressed in the traditional shalwar kameez suit, said she was shunned after the birth of her daughter and struggled to find employment, working briefly in a knitting mill and doing other odd jobs. Both the victim, who left school in year10, and her daughter are now in school.
A mediation hearing in her case has been set for Monday, and women's groups are planning to protest. Ramaseshan says the victim should simply not show up, because mediation requires both parties to be willing. And she is not.
"I do not want to see him at any cost, for any reason," the victim said. "Even if it is mandatory, I will not go."
Washington Post
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:05:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rainbow Warrior bombing, 30 years on</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-world/rainbow-warrior-bombing-30-years-on-20150710-3z1mo.html</Link>
        <Description>Friday marks 30 years since the Rainbow Warrior was bombed in New Zealand and Greenpeace is using the anniversary to celebrate acts of courage and protest.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rainbow Warrior bombing, 30 years on
Breaking News World World
Sometimes Bunny McDiarmid can remember everything about the bombing of the Rainbow Warrior in vivid detail.
Other times it can seem a very long time ago.
Ms McDiarmid had been a deckhand on the Greenpeace vessel before two French agents slipped into Auckland's Waitemata Harbour under the cover of darkness on July 10, 1985 to attach two bombs to its hull.
The blast left Portuguese-Dutch photographer Fernando Pereira dead and the New Zealand government and public reeling.
Advertisement
Ms McDiarmid - now the outgoing head of Greenpeace New Zealand - was among the tight-knit group of activists who had embarked on campaigns in the Pacific to protest against French nuclear testing and draw attention to the terrible legacy it left on the people, the land and the ocean.
When she thinks back to the bombing 30 years ago, she recalls just how shocking it was.
"It was very, very hard to comprehend that it had happened, particularly because we lost Fernando," Ms McDiarmid told AAP.
"It was shocking, not only for Greenpeace - it was shocking for New Zealand, it was shocking for New Zealanders."
That shock did not fade in the months that followed as the extent of the French government's involvement was revealed.
While much attention is always focused on the bombing and its political fallout, Ms McDiarmid says Greenpeace wants to use this anniversary as a chance to celebrate acts of courage and protest.
"Much of New Zealand has been defined by our activism, whether it was women getting the vote, or Bastion Point, or a nuclear free New Zealand," she said.
It is that activist streak - and the need for people to continue to have the courage to speak out to effect social change - that connects the events of 30 years ago with today.
Ms McDiarmid thinks the Rainbow Warrior is a symbol that inspires hope in that sense.
"Sometimes just raising your voice is a big thing," she said.
"It can be a really incredible act of courage, depending on where you are, or who you are, or what the context is.
"Just opening your mouth can be incredibly significant - you can risk your life, it can change the course of history."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:03:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd to appeal sentence</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-world/acdc-drummer-phil-rudd-to-appeal-sentence-20150710-3z1lq.html</Link>
        <Description>Craig Tuck, the lawyer for AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd, says he's filed an appeal against his client's home detention sentence in New Zealand.</Description>
        <MainBody>AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd to appeal sentence
World Breaking News World
Print
AC/DC's estranged drummer Phil Rudd is appealing his home detention sentence in New Zealand.
The 61-year-old drummer was sentenced at Tauranga District Court on Thursday to eight months' home detention, after he earlier admitted charges of threatening to kill and possessing methamphetamine and cannabis.
Rudd will be electronically monitored at his Tauranga waterside mansion and must also complete a rehabilitation programme.
Judge Thomas Ingram told Rudd there "was nowhere to hide" and he would be jailed if he was found with any traces of drugs or alcohol in his system.
Advertisement
But Rudd's lawyer Craig Tuck confirmed to AAP on Thursday evening that he's filed an appeal against the sentence.
Mr Tuck had argued for a discharge without conviction, saying a conviction would leave Rudd unable to travel to Japan, Canada and the US with the band resulting in the loss of tens of millions of dollars.
Mr Tuck said Rudd's actions were the result of methamphetamine psychosis.
But Judge Ingram said Rudd had been discharged twice before, on assault and cannabis charges, and there was no evidence to suggest he was with the band anymore.
The judge was not convinced Rudd's drumming was integral to the AC/DC sound.
"Queen replaced Freddie Mercury," Judge Ingram said.
AC/DC's global Rock or Bust tour continues without Rudd, with the band confirming Chris Slade will be in the drummer's seat when it plays in Australia and New Zealand later this year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
