<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:18:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Air Force leader sees Russia as 'biggest threat'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f598a6/sc/23/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1172810A90CUS0EAir0EForce0Eleader0Esees0ERussia0Eas0Ebiggest0Ethreat0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The US must increase its presence in Europe, says Deborah James, to deal with danger from Moscow</Description>
        <MainBody>US Air Force leader sees Russia as 'biggest threat'
The US must increase its presence in Europe, says Deborah James, to deal with    danger from Moscow
Moscow's military machine on display earlier this year commemorating the Second World WarPhoto: EPA/SERGEI CHIRIKOV
By Reuters
2:18AM BST 09 Jul 2015
Russia is the biggest threat to US national security and America must boost its military presence throughout Europe even as Nato allies face budget challenges and scale back spending, Deborah James, US Air Force Secretary, said on Wednesday.
"I do consider Russia to be the biggest threat," Ms James told Reuters in an interview after a series of visits and meetings with American allies across Europe, including Poland.
She said Washington was responding to Russia's recent "worrisome" actions by boosting its presence across Europe, and would continue rotational assignments of F-16 fighter squadrons.
"This is no time to in any way signal a lack of resolve in the face of these Russian actions," she said.
 Fighter jet pilot rescued after planes collide in US
Ms James said she was disappointed that only four of Nato's 28 members had thus far met the target of spending 2 per cent of gross domestic product on defence.
"This is not something that came up out of thin air. This is something that we as Nato members agreed to do. All of us need to be advocates," she said.
The top air force civilian leader acknowledged that Europe was facing difficult immigration and economic challenges, but said the Nato military alliance and associated commitments should be a clear priority.
Britain on Wednesday said it would commit to the 2 per cent spending pledge for the next five years, which will raise the number of Nato allies meeting the spending goal to five in 2015.
A Russian Federation Air Force Su-27 Sukhoi fighter aircraft during a training exercise
Given the tensions, the air force is continuing its effort to reduce US reliance on Russian RD-180 rocket engines for military and intelligence satellite launches, said Ms James.
She said there were huge demands on US air force assets now, given the tensions with Russia and the fight against the Islamic State in Iraq and the Levant , but the air force was also working hard to defend its weapons systems and networks against growing cyber attacks.
Ms James said her records were among those involved in a massive breach of personnel records held by the Office of Personnel Management that some US officials have blamed on China. China denies any involvement in hacking the databases.
 US training just 60 Syrian fighters to combat Islamic State
She added that the air force took a hard look at its cyber security immediately after the revelations and decided to redouble its efforts, although no new actions were needed.
She said the service was cataloguing weapons and IT systems to detect any possible vulnerabilities, while also working to set up 39 cyber security teams around the country.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:40:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge orders Time Warner Cable to pay $229,500 to woman "harassed by" robocalls</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f598a8/sc/23/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1172810A30CJudge0Eorders0ETime0EWarner0ECable0Eto0Epay0E22950A0A0Eto0Ewoman0Eharassed0Eby0Erobocalls0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Araceli King received 153 automated telephone calls in a year, even though she told company it was using an out-of-date number</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Judge orders Time Warner Cable to pay $229,500 to woman "harassed by" robocalls
Araceli King received 153 automated telephone calls in a year, even though she    told company it was using an out-of-date number
Judge orders cable TV company to pay $229,500 for 153 robocalls it made to Araceli KingPhoto: Getty
By Rob Crilly , New York, and Reuters
1:40AM BST 09 Jul 2015
Follow
Nobody likes being on the receiving end of automated phone calls or robocalls  especially when they are meant for someone else.
So pity the American woman who received 153 of them from a single company in less than a year, all intended for a customer who previously used her mobile phone number
Now though the offending company, Time Warner Cable , has been ordered to pay damages of $229,500 (150,000) or $1,500 per phone call to Araceli King, an insurance claims specialist from Texas.
Sergei Lemberg, her lawyer, told Reuters: "Companies are using computers to dial phone numbers.
"They benefit from efficiency, but there is a cost when they make people's lives miserable. This was one such case."
The calls were made through an "interactive voice response" system meant for customers who were late paying bills.
They were intended for Luis Perez who had once owned the mobile phone number now used by Ms King.
However, the calls continued even after Ms King spent seven minutes explaining the misunderstanding to a company representative.
In making the award, Alvin Hellerstein, Manhattan federal judge, said a responsible business would have tried harder to find Mr Perez and solve the problem.
He added that 74 of the calls had been placed even after Ms King resorted to legal action in March 2014, and that it was "incredible" to believe Time Warner Cable when it said it still did not know she objected.
"Defendant harassed plaintiff with robocalls until she had to resort to a lawsuit to make the calls stop, and even then TWC could not be bothered to update the information in its [interactive voice response] system," he wrote.
He was so insensed that he tripled the normal level of damages.
The company insisted that it had not breached the Telephone Consumer Protection Act, a law meant to curb robo-call and telemarketing abuses, because it believed it was contacting Mr Perez, who had consented to being phoned.
A spokeswoman said the company was reviewing the decision.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:49:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Homeless boy using McDonald's light to do homework proves inspirational</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f4e4fb/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cphilippines0C117280A990CHomeless0Eboy0Eusing0EMcDonalds0Elight0Eto0Edo0Ehomework0Eproves0Einspirational0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Picture of homeless boy forced to do his homework on a pavement in the Philippines goes viral</Description>
        <MainBody>Homeless boy using McDonalds light to do homework proves inspirational
Picture of homeless boy forced to do his homework on a pavement in the    Philippines goes viral
Daniel Cabrera, 9, a homeless boy who uses light from fast food restaurant to do his school homework Photo: Facebook
By Our Foreign Staff
Comments
An image of a homeless boy who used light from a McDonalds restaurant in the Philippines to do his homework has gone viral on social media with many saying he had inspired them.
Daniel Cabrera was spotted by Joyce Torrefranca, a medical student, as he worked away on the pavement in Manilla.
She posted the image to Facebook, saying Daniel had inspired her to work harder.
No chair, no table, no problem--Daniel Cabrera is determined to study: http://t.co/bzHIiFskAx #inspiring #motivation pic.twitter.com/HR4jc70HMI
 TeleDevelopmentPH (@TeledevPH) June 30, 2015
The picture was soon being shared thousands of times, with people reflecting how often even basic living standards are taken for granted.
Daniels home was burnt down and his father died. He is often seen begging with his mother in the same area, but shows a determination to get an education.
"As a student, it gave me an inspiration to work harder. I'm fortunate my parents were able to send me to school. I seldom go to coffee shops to study, but this kid just hit me, Torrefranca told Rappler.
I applaud #kmjs10 for its relevance. This kid is Daniel Cabrera who teaches usna aral muna over everything. pic.twitter.com/u46EguVrq0
You really don't need much, you just have to be determined and focused on the things that you want to achieve."
One of Daniels teachers, Rosalina Detuya, described him as a happy child.
He is also intelligent and actually answers during class discussion, he really participates, she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Paris to allow cyclists to skip red lights</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f4e4fc/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C117280A980CParis0Eto0Eallow0Ecyclists0Eto0Eskip0Ered0Elights0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Cyclists in Paris to be allowed to skip some red lights after tests show it will not increase accidents</Description>
        <MainBody>France
Paris to allow cyclists to skip red lights
Cyclists in Paris to be allowed to skip some red lights after tests show it    will not increase accidents
A man rides his bicycle during a protest against cars, gas emission and agressive driver in Paris, September 2014Photo: DOMINIQUE FAGET/AFP/GETTY
By Our Foreign Staff
Comments
Cyclists in Paris are to be allowed to ride through some red lights in a bid by the mayors office to get more people on their bikes.
At several junctions there will be separate signals for cars and bikes, and while cars will be held by a red light, cyclists will be permitted to turn right or go straight ahead.
In such scenarios, they would have to give way to pedestrians and other road users where necessary.
The new road rules will be rolled out from the end of July, the mayors office said, adding in a statement that the new rules will "help improve the flow of cycle traffic".
A survey was held in 2012 apparently proving that letting cyclists move more freely actually reduced the chances of accidents.
Paris has been battling a smog problem for several years, and the mayors office is keen to get more people riding bikes.
In December, Anne Hidalgo, the mayor of Paris, said she wanted the city's historic centre to become "semi-pedestrianised" as she laid out a plan to tackle traffic and pollution in the French capital.
"In the four central districts, apart from bikes, buses and taxis, the only vehicles allowed will be residents' cars, delivery vehicles and emergency vehicles," Anne Hidalgo said in an interview with the Journal du Dimanche weekly.
Ms Hidalgo said the proposed scheme would start at weekends but could be "quickly" rolled out for the rest of the week.
The mayor also said that the amount of cycle lanes would be "doubled by 2020" as part of a 100-million-euro bike development plan.
She said she also wanted to roll out a system of electric-powered bikes along the same lines as the city's popular velib temporary bike hire network.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:12:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Men really will accept unfair deals from attractive women</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f5014b/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C117280A870CMen0Ereally0Ewill0Eaccept0Eunfair0Edeals0Efrom0Eattractive0Ewomen0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Chinese study finds what many have suspected all along - that men are influenced by a woman's looks even in a financial deal</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Men really will accept unfair deals from attractive women
Chinese study finds what many have suspected all along - that men are    influenced by a woman's looks even in a financial deal
A sales assistant in a shopPhoto: Alamy
By Rob Crilly , New York
12:12AM BST 09 Jul 2015
Follow
Beautiful women really do get away with more, according to a new scientific study that looked at how men responded to financial offers associated with a range of female faces.
Chinese psychologists found that men were more likely to accept an unfair offer if it came from a beautiful woman, according to the paper published in Frontiers of Neuroscience .
It adds to growing evidence of a beauty premium , suggesting that better-looking people are frequently rated higher in factors such as intelligence and potential for success.
To study the question, the team at Zhejiang University in Hangzhou recruited 21 men aged between 18 and 26.
It took the form of a computer game, in which they were presented by a photograph of a Chinese woman - previously rated as attractive or unattractive by another group of men  along with her offer to split a small sum of money (10 yuan or about 1).
The subjects - monitored for brain activity and reaction time - were asked to decide whether to accept an offer from each woman.
Results showed that the men were more likely to accept unfair offers when the woman was attractive than when she was unattractive, wrote the researchers, led by Qingguo Ma.
They were also quicker to respond to fair offers and slower to respond to unfair offers when the woman was attractive.
Meanwhile, the men's brains showed more activity when they were dealing with an attractive woman.
Which is perhaps strange, given the subjects' tendency to accept less advantageous offers without even the chance of a date.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:56:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Briton arrested after BA flight diverted to Boston</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f4d6a3/sc/10/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C117280A110CBriton0Earrested0Eafter0EBA0Eflight0Ediverted0Eto0EBoston0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police meet Houston-bound 747 to arrest Darren Halliwell, of Greater Manchester, who is charged with interfering with a flight crew</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Briton arrested after BA flight diverted to Boston
Police meet Houston-bound 747 to arrest Darren Halliwell, of Greater    Manchester, who is charged with interfering with a flight crew
A British Airways 747 planePhoto: Getty Images
By Our Foreign Staff
10:56PM BST 08 Jul 2015
A British Airways flight bound for Houston had to be diverted on Wednesday after a British man allegedly assaulted a woman.
The 747 landed at Boston Logan International Airport where Massachusetts state troopers were waiting to arrest Darren Halliwell, 48, of Aspull, Wigan, Manchester.
"State Police had been notified that the flight was being diverted to Logan after Halliwell allegedly assaulted a woman he was travelling with and became disruptive," said a police statement.
"Out of respect for her privacy we are not naming her or commenting on her relationship to the defendant."
Sources say #BritishAirways incident involves alleged domestic assault -4 passengers restrained man. Was a London to Houston flight #7News
 Cheryl Fiandaca (@CherylFiandaca) July 8, 2015
Local television stations said he had been restrined by four other passengers before the plane landed.
He was charged with interfering with a flight crew and is due to appear in East Boston District Court on Thursday.
Authorities said more charges could be filed.
A Foreign Office statement said: "We are aware of reports of the arrest of a British national at Boston Logan International Airport and stand ready to offer consular assistance as necessary."
Authorities say the flight, BA 195, continued to Houston after his arrest.
 Airline passenger's erratic behaviour 'and demand for nuts' caused flight diversion
A British Airways spokesman said: "Our customers and crews deserve to enjoy their flights, and not to suffer any form of abuse.
"This sort of behaviour will not be tolerated, and the captain took the decision to divert the aircraft to Boston as a precaution.
"The matter will now be handled by the police."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:38:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ricky Gervais backs Canada official who refused to kill bear cubs</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f4d6a6/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Ccanada0C117279790CRicky0EGervais0Ebacks0ECanada0Eofficial0Ewho0Erefused0Eto0Ekill0Ebear0Ecubs0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Thousands joins camapign to reinstate Canadian conservation officer who was suspended for refusing to put down two black bear cubs</Description>
        <MainBody>Canada
Ricky Gervais backs Canada official who refused to kill bear cubs
Thousands joins camapign to reinstate Canadian conservation officer who was    suspended for refusing to put down two black bear cubs
Actor and comedian Ricky GervaisPhoto: Getty Images
By AFP
Comments
Thousands of people including British actor-comedian Ricky Gervais demanded the reinstatement Wednesday of a Canadian conservation officer who was suspended for refusing to put down two black bear cubs.
The bears were believed to be just two months old and were found in a tree near their mother, who was captured and destroyed Sunday after she was discovered eating salmon in the freezer of a home in Port Hardy, British Columbia.
Bryce Casavant, conservation officer, suspended for refusing to kill bear cubs http://t.co/E6AKvu6Kyd Reinstate this honourable man.
 Ricky Gervais (@rickygervais) July 8, 2015
Rather than put the pair to death, Bryce Casavant entrusted them to a shelter, the North Island Wildlife Recovery Association, triggering his suspension without pay after he had been told by his superiors to euthanize them.
"After investigating, he decided there was no need to euthanize the cubs. They were never in the house or trailer, and the owner of the property told me that too," director Robin Campbell said.
"Be Kind to Animals"- Derek pic.twitter.com/StireETQuK
 Ricky Gervais (@rickygervais) July 8, 2015
A petition for Casavant to be reinstated has garnered over 42,000 signatures in a day and support from Gervais, who tweeted to his nine million followers: "Reinstate this honourable man."
Mary Polak, British Columbia environment minister, said an internal investigation was under way.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:34:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore's police chief is fired after riots</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f4d6a8/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C117279590CBaltimores0Epolice0Echief0Eis0Efired0Eafter0Eriots0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mayor says city needs a change to bring down high levels of violence since Freddie Gray died after suffering criticial injuries in police custody</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Baltimore's police chief is fired after riots
Mayor says city needs a change to bring down high levels of violence since    Freddie Gray died after suffering criticial injuries in police custody
Stephanie Rawlings-Blake, of Baltimore, MarylandPhoto: AFP
By Rob Crilly, New York, and agencies
10:34PM BST 08 Jul 2015
The mayor of Baltimore fired the city's police commissioner on Wednesday, two and half months after riots erupted in the wake of a black man's death in custody and amid a spike in violent crime.
Stephanie Rawlings-Blake announced her decision in a brief statement, saying that Anthony Batts would be replaced by his deputy, Kevin Davis.
He decision came just hours after the police union issued a report critical of the departments response to the riots in April.
She later set out her reasons at a news conference.
We need a change. This was not an easy decision, but it is one that is in the best interest of the people of Baltimore, she said.
We cannot continue to have the level of violence that weve seen.
Demonstrators climb on a destroyed Baltimore Police car in the street near the corner of Pennsylvania and North avenues during violent protests following the funeral of Freddie Gray (Getty Images)
Mr Batts and his department have been under intense scrutiny since Freddie Gray died one week after suffering a critical spinal injury in police custody.
Six police officers have been criminally charged in his death.
During the riots, Mr Batts and his commanders told officers to "hold the line" with troublemakers rather than risk escalating the confrontation by tackling people people causing damage. Almost 400 buildings were damaged and the National Guard was deployed to help restore order.
Since the rioting stopped, the city has seen a sharp increase in violence, with 155 homicides this year, a 48 per cent increase over the same period last year.
 Police brutality and racial tensions in the US - in 90 seconds
The US Justice Department is conducting a civil rights review of the department, and Batts has been criticized by the Baltimore police union. Its report accused the chief and his lieutenants of taking a passive approach to criminals, leading to the recent increase in violence.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:01:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Children of the Gaza War, BBC Two, review: 'melancholy'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f4672f/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cculture0Ctvandradio0Ctv0Eand0Eradio0Ereviews0C1172720A80CChildren0Eof0Ethe0EGaza0EWar0EBBC0ETwo0Ereview0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The words of the children of the Israel-Gaza conflict in this documentary were haunting, says Harry Mount</Description>
        <MainBody>TV and Radio reviews
Children of the Gaza War, BBC Two, review: 'melancholy'
The affecting words of the children living on both sides of the Israel-Gaza    conflict in this documentary were haunting
4
Abdulrahman (front right) lost his father and 17 other family members in the war of summer 2014Photo: BBC
By Harry Mount
Comments
The BBC Two documentary, Children of the Gaza War, entered an arena in which even the television coverage divides opinion. I was on red alert for some Israel-bashing.
But Lyse Doucet, the BBCs Chief International Correspondent, is more on the ball than that. She was even-handed in her interviews with Palestinian and Israeli children caught up in last summers 51-day war  when rockets were fired from Gaza into Israel, and Israel responded with massive force. More than 500 children were killed in those 51 days, and thousands more traumatised. One 12-year-old boy saw his brother and three cousins killed on a Gaza beach by a rocket from an Israeli gunboat. His 1,000-yard stare, and husky voice  old beyond its years  were haunting.
The simple words of children were all the more affecting. We didnt know the beach was dangerous, he said. Those poor souls murdered on a Tunisia beach last month must have thought much the same.
The Israeli children in Sderot  only a mile from Gaza, and regularly hit by rocket attacks  had a harrowing time of it, too. At any one time during the conflict, they couldnt be more than 14 seconds from the safe room in their house  which we saw them racing to, when the rocket alarm went off. One family, who fled for northern Israel during the war, came back to find their house perforated by shrapnel.
Agam and Eilon live in Sderot, one of the most bombed places on earth. Photo: BBC
For all the shared experiences, you couldnt help but see a gulf in living standards between the two sets of children. The Israeli children spoke in fluent, American-accented English, as well as Hebrew. Their kindergartens had been depressingly but efficiently armoured with concrete walls. One13-year-old boy had his bar mitzvah in a bombproof hall.
Meanwhile, Gaza almost lives up to the war clich of being bombed back to the Stone Age. The children played on carts led by donkeys. Their parents cooked off open fires in wrecked tower blocks. It isnt hard to work out who has the better life prospects.
Nor is it hard to work out that these childhood traumas, on both sides, have sown the seeds of adult hatred. When we grow up, were going to kill them, said one little Palestinian girl.
An admirable, if melancholy, programme with one fault: the terrible soundtrack. When things are this sad, you dont need to pump up the gloom with discordant gongs, arrhythmic thuds and screeching violins.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:58:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Donald Trump: 'I'll win the Latino vote'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f46735/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C117278970CDonald0ETrump0EIll0Ewin0Ethe0ELatino0Evote0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Republican candidate says he has a 'great relationship with Mexican people' despite saying many Mexican immigrants were criminals</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Donald Trump: 'I'll win the Latino vote'
Republican candidate says he has a great relationship with Mexican people despite saying many Mexican immigrants were criminals
Republican presidential candidate Donald TrumpPhoto: Reuters
By Reuters
Comments
Republican Donald Trump on Wednesday said he would win the Latino vote if he gets his party's nomination for president and claimed a "great relationship with the Mexican people," despite recent comments about immigrants that have cost him business .
"I'll win the Latino vote. I will win it," Trump said in an excerpt of an interview with NBC News released on Wednesday. He said he would be better able to create jobs as president than fellow Republican Jeb Bush or Democrat Hillary Clinton .
"I will create jobs, and the Latinos will have jobs that they don't have right now, and I will win that vote," Trump said.
What about the undocumented immigrant with a record who killed the beautiful young women (in front of her father) in San Fran. Get smart!
 Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) July 4, 2015
A steady stream of Trump's business partners have broken ties with him since his June 16 announcement that he would seek the Republican nomination for the November 2016 election.
During his speech, Trump vented about illegal immigrants, saying that many of the people crossing the border from Mexico are criminals. Republicans and Democrats alike have criticised his remarks.
Meanwhile, the Comcast Corp-owned NBC television network , Macy's Inc department store chain and others have ended relationships with Trump.
The PGA of America on Tuesday said it was moving a golfing event away from a Trump-owned course and was considering options for another event planned for the same venue.
On Wednesday, well-known chef Jose Andres said he was scrapping plans for a restaurant at a new hotel Trump is opening in Washington in light of the candidate's recent comments.
"I believe that every human being deserves respect, regardless of immigration status," Andres, who was born in Spain, said in a statement.
Trump said in the NBC interview that many of the people who work for him, including workers at the site of the planned hotel in Washington, are legal immigrants from Mexico.
"They love me, I love them," Trump told NBC.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:15:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hillary Clinton accused of making false claim over Benghazi emails</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f2c5bf/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Chillary0Eclinton0C1172720A0A0CRepublicans0Econtradict0EHillary0EClintons0Eaccount0Eof0EBenghazi0Eemails0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Democratic frontrunner said she was never subpoenaed for her emails but Republicans release documents showing she was</Description>
        <MainBody>Hillary Clinton accused of making false claim over Benghazi emails
Democratic frontrunner said she was never subpoenaed for her emails but    Republicans release documents showing she was
Democratic president candidate Hillary Clinton speaks at an organising event at a private home in Glen, New HampshirePhoto: Darren McCollester/Getty Images
Follow
Hillary Clinton is facing fresh questions about her honesty after it emerged that she made a false claim about the personal email account she used for official business while secretary of state.
The Democratic frontrunner said on Tuesday that she had voluntarily handed over thousands of emails to a congressional committee investigating the 2012 attack on the US consulate in Benghazi, Libya.
She insisted that she had never been served with a subpoena, a legal document compelling her to hand over the emails. "I've never had a subpoena," she told CNN.
But Republicans who control the Benghazi committee released documents showing that she had in fact been served with a subpoena on March 4, once it became clear that she had used a private email account.
"After Secretary Clinton falsely claimed the committee did not subpoena her, I have no choice in order to correct the inaccuracy," said Trey Gowdy, the Republican chairman of the Benghazi committee.
A spokesman for Mrs Clinton said she meant that she was not facing a subpoena at the time she deleted around 30,000 emails she said were not related to her work.
"She was asked about her decision to not to retain her personal emails after providing all those that were work-related, and the suggestion was made that a subpoena was pending at the time. That was not accurate," he said.
Although few Americans have followed the legal back-and-forth over the subpoena, Mrs Clinton's claim is likely to reinforce the impression held by many voters that she is not honest.
A CNN/ORC poll last month found that 57 per cent of respondents said they did not believe Mrs Clinton is "honest and trustworthy".
In her interview with CNN, her first major interview in the three months since she launched her campaign, Mrs Clinton said: "People should and do trust me."
She blamed Republicans for sowing doubts about her honesty and said she had been subjected to a "constant barrage of attacks that are largely fomented by and coming from the Right".
Other senior US officials, including Barack Obama and John Kerry, use official email accounts and Mrs Clinton has been criticised for the private account, which was based on a server in her New York home.
She also deleted more than 30,000 emails from the account, which she said were not related to State Department work. "People delete their personal emails, their work-related emails, whatever emails they have on a regular basis," she said.
"The committee does not know why or when she chose to wipe clean her personal server, but we do know her way of doing things provided an incomplete public record, said Mr Gowdy, the Benghazi committee chairman.
Documents released by the Benghazi committee show that the subpoena was sent to Mrs Clinton's lawyer on March 4, 2015.
The subpoena ordered her to turn over all emails sent between January 1, 2011 and December 31, 2012 that were related to Libya or the Benghazi attack.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:35:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How radical Left-wing US presidential candidates have fared</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f3f9e3/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cus0Epolitics0C117210A970CHow0Eradical0ELeft0Ewing0EUS0Epresidential0Ecandidates0Ehave0Efared0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Bernie Sanders threatens to derail Hillary Clinton's procession to the Democratic nomination, the historical precedent suggests that US voters are unlikely to back a radical candidate</Description>
        <MainBody>US Politics
How radical Left-wing US presidential candidates have fared
As Bernie Sanders threatens to derail Hillary Clintons procession to the    Democratic nomination, the historical precedent suggests that US voters are    unlikely to back a radical candidate
Mr Sanders proudly describes himself as a socialistPhoto: Michael Dwyer/AP
By David Millward, US Correspondent
8:35PM BST 08 Jul 2015
Bernie Sanders populist left-wing campaign has breathed life into what had been a dull procession towards a Hillary Clinton coronation as the Democrats nominee for the White House.
Mr Sanders, who proudly describes himself as a socialist, follows a long tradition of radicals who have surfed a tidal wave of support.
But while the 73-year-old Vermont senator is packing vast halls across the country, the historical precedent suggests that the chances of a radical actually moving into the Oval Office are rather slim.
Supporters hold up signs at a campaign rally for Senator Bernie Sanders, in Madison, Wisconsin (Bloomberg)
Candidates from William Jennings Bryan to George McGovern have generated excitement among their supporters only for their campaigns to end in heroic failure.
For more than a century left-wing tilts at the White House have not only ended in disappointment, but at times done considerable damage to others on the Liberal wing of American politics.
William Jennings Bryan
A Nebraska congressman who electrified the 1896 Democratic convention with his Cross of Gold" speech which, by favouring what was known as free silver, would have increased the amount of money in circulation and aided the poor and debt-ridden farmers.
He attacked the supporters of the Gold Standard as crucifiers of Christ and hailed advocates of free silver as true Christians. But while securing the Democratic nomination, he was defeated by William McKinley.
He served as Secretary of State and had two other tilts at the White House in 1900 and 1908, losing both times. In his later years he campaigned for peace, prohibition and womens suffrage.
Henry Wallace
Henry Wallace served as Franklin Roosevelts vice president during FDRs third term, much to the distaste of the conservative wing of the Democratic party which had little time for the former agriculture secretary.
He was dropped from the ticket at the 1944 Democratic convention and replaced by Harry Truman, who became president on FDRs death.
Wallace ran as the Progressive Partys candidate in 1948 on a platform which included a US equivalent of the National Health Service which was being established in Britain.
He was also endorsed by the Communist party, which was hardly a blessing at the time. The election ended in humiliating failure with Wallace coming in fourth not only behind Harry Truman and his Republican opponent, Thomas Dewey, but also Strom Thurmond a southern Dixiecrat who opposed integration.
Eugene McCarthy
With the Vietnam war at its height Eugene McCarthy, a poet, professor and Minnesota senator, captured the imagination of young voters who were opposed to the conflict and being drafted to fight in south east Asia.
While other Democrats also opposed the war, it was McCarthy who stuck his head over the parapet and took on the increasingly unpopular president Lyndon Johnson while others, notably Robert Kennedy, watched from the sidelines.
Backed by thousands of students who knocked on doors, distributed badges and leaflets, McCarthy won 42 per cent of votes to Johnsons 49 per cent in the New Hampshire Primary.
With private polling showing that McCarthy was set to win in Wisconsin and the charismatic Kennedy entering the race, Johnson pulled out.
Kennedy was assassinated and Hubert Humphrey, who won the nomination, failed to catch the imagination of voters in the election which was won by Richard Nixon.
George McGovern
An outspoken opponent of the Vietnam war, the South Dakota senator rebuffed approaches to run against Johnson in 1968 before throwing his hat into the ring just ahead of the 1968 Democratic convention.
Selected as the partys candidate four years later, he swept to the nomination with the backing of liberals and anti-war activists.
Arguably the most radical Democrat presidential candidate of the modern era, his platform included pulling out of Vietnam and cutting defence spending.
He was crushed by Nixon in the election, even losing his home state. McGovern only won in Massachusetts and Washington DC. It was the second biggest landslide in American political history with the incumbent taking 520 seats in the electoral college to McGoverns 17.
Ralph Nader
A veteran consumer advocate who made his name in the 1960s attacking the safety record of the US car industry, his main target was General Motors which he accused of underhand tactics in trying to discredit him.
Nader settled his dispute with the car giant for $425,000.
His advocacy for car safety helped pave the way for the establishment of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.
But his political career was rather less successful running repeatedly as an independent candidate for the White House.
Normally he made little impact. The exception was in 2000 when Nader took 2.74 per cent of the vote. In Florida, where George W Bush defeated Al Gore by 537 votes, Nader was backed by more than 97,000 voters - leading to critics accusing him of handing the contest to the Republicans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:31:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berlusconi found guilty of bribing Italian senator</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f3f9e4/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Citaly0C117277840CBerlusconi0Efound0Eguilty0Eof0Ebribing0EItalian0Esenator0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Naples court sentences former Italian premier Silvio Berlusconi to three years in prison for bribing a senator</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy
Berlusconi found guilty of bribing Italian senator
Naples court sentences former Italian premier Silvio Berlusconi to three years    in prison for bribing a senator, but media tycoon not likely to serve the    sentence
Italy's flamboyant former Prime Minister Silvio BerlusconiPhoto: EPA/GABRIELE PUTZU
Follow
Silvio Berlusconi has been sentenced to three years in prison for bribing a senator in 2006 as part of a plot to topple the then-centre-left government.
But Berlusconi, 78, will not have to serve the sentence because the statute of limitations in the corruption case will lapse in the autumn, before appeals can be completed.
The Italian justice system dictates that two levels of appeals must be exhausted before a defendant begins a sentence.
Judge Serena Corleto reads Berlusconi's sentence (AP)
"It was a good trial, passionate, but in terms of consequences the imminent expiration date takes all the pathos out of the verdict," said prosecutor Henry John Woodcock.
The former Italian premier was found guilty of bribing Sergio De Gregorio, a member of the Italy of Values party, to switch sides.
The move brought about the downfall of the then-prime minister Romano Prodi in 2007.
The verdict comes months after Berlusconi completed a community service order for tax fraud.
He would have gone to prison for the crime if he had been younger. Instead, he was allowed to serve the time by helping out at an old people's home .
Nicolo Ghedini, Berlusconi's lawyer, leaves the Naples court after the verdict (AP)
Prosecutor Vincenzo Piscitelli told the court in Naples that the 3 million paid to the senator were "a colossal economic investment made with the aim of achieving the sole goal that interested Berlusconi, who was obsessed by his desire to kick Prodi out and take his post".
Berlusconi has also been banned from serving in public office for five years, but, again, it will not apply due to the expiry of the statute of limitations.
Mr De Gregorio has acknowledged accepting the money.
Berlusconi denied the charge, with the defence claiming that shifting alliances are a normal part of Italian politics.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:09:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tom Selleck of Magnum P.I. accused of California water theft</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f3f9e5/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C117277760CShawshank0Eprison0Eescape0E10A0A0A0A0A0Ereward0Eoffered0Eas0Efocus0Eturns0Eto0Eaccomplices0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Tom Selleck, star of the 1980s detective series, sued and "drought shamed" for allegedly swiping water to feed his avocado farm</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Tom Selleck of Magnum P.I. accused of California water theft
The case of the thirsty avocado farmer: Selleck, star of the 1980s detective    series, sued and "drought shamed" for allegedly swiping water to    feed his avocado farm
Magnum P.I. star Tom Selleck is accused of stealing water to grow his avocadosPhoto: Rex/Alamy
By Nick Allen, Los Angeles
8:09PM BST 08 Jul 2015
Tom Selleck, the star of Magnum P.I., was pursued for two years by a real-life private investigator over accusations he swiped truck loads of water from the drought-plagued state of California to use on his avocado farm.
It is not known whether the detective hired by a water authority drove a red Ferrari and sported an impressive moustache, or if he was accompanied during his work by a thumping theme tune.
But as he doggedly tracked the missing liquid, taken from a public hydrant, all roads led to Mr Selleck's sprawling $10 million ranch, which includes 20 acres of avocados.
The 70-year-old actor is now being sued by the water authority.
Selleck is most famous for playing the glamorous Hawaii private eye (Rex)
Those refusing to save water, including celebrities, are increasingly being shamed by neighbours who post pictures of still-verdant gardens on social media.
Mr Selleck's ranch (Getty Images)
In a complaint filed at Ventura Superior Court the Calleguas Municipal Water District accused Mr Selleck, 70, and his wife Jillie, 57, of persistently using water from the public hydrant near a construction site since 2013.
According to the complaint the Sellecks are not permitted to use the hydrant because their property is in a different water district, the Hidden Valley Municipal Water District.
Selleck faces alleged water theft charges (AP)
On Nov 26, 2013 Calleguas sent cease-and-desist letters to the Selleck ranch, and an address associated with the actor on The Avenue of the Stars in Los Angeles.
Less than a month later the truck was filling up again.
The Calleguas water authority said it hired a private investigator, at a cost of $22,000, to gather evidence of the alleged water theft.
Selleck also starred as Monica's love interest in hit 90's comedy Friends (NBC)
It claimed to have documented a white truck filling up at the hydrant, then heading to the Selleck ranch, more than a dozen times.
In late Spring, when avocados are harvested, the truck was said to have been spotted taking water on four consecutive days.
Mr Selleck has previously spoken abut the difficulty of making a profit from the crop.
His ranch also includes an eight-bedroom Spanish colonial ranch house built in 1926, horse stables, a tennis court, swimming pool, heliport, and three hole golf course.
However, aerial photographs on a property website appeared to show large areas of brown, water-starved grass.
The Calleguas water authority is seeking an injunction to stop use of its water by Mr Selleck, financial damages, legal fees and the cost of the private investigator.
A representative for Mr Selleck did not respond to a request for comment.
It is unclear if the actor was aware of where the water, which Calleguas says was going to his property, was coming from.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:00:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Europeans told to bring Greece back from the brink and avoid descent into 'uncontrolled' Grexit</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f3f9e6/sc/25/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cfinance0Ceconomics0C1172760A70CEuropes0Ecreditors0Etold0Eto0Eavoid0Edescent0Einto0Euncontrolled0EGrexit0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>White House escalates warnings about geopolitical and financial dangers of letting Greece go as future of 'riots and chaos' face Athens</Description>
        <MainBody>Economics
Europeans told to bring Greece back from the brink and avoid descent into 'uncontrolled' Grexit
White House escalates warnings about geopolitical and financial dangers of    letting Greece go as future of 'riots and chaos' face Athens
Tsipras: "My country has been transformed into an experimental austerity laboratory for the last five years"Photo: Reuters
By Mehreen Khan , Matthew Holehouse, Brussels
8:00PM BST 08 Jul 2015
Comments
Europes creditor powers have been warned against igniting an uncontrolled financial and geopolitical crisis in Greece by letting the country fall out of the eurozone at the end of the week.
US Treasury Secretary Jacob Lew waded into the crisis on Tuesday, as Athens was preparing to make its final attempt to secure its future in the single currency. The Greeks have been told they have three days to prevent a fatal eurozone exit.
 Greece news live
Mr Lew said lenders risked making a mistake for Europe, the European economy and the global economy, to take the risks that are involved with an uncontrolled crisis in Greece.
Washington has become increasingly exasperated by the mishandling of Greeces woes, which they fear could destabilise Europe's fragile Mediterranean periphery.
President Barack Obama made his first personal intervention for months on Tuesday , urging German chancellor Angela Merkel to find a solution to Greeces crippling debts , which are set to reach 180pc of GDP this year.
Alexis the Saviour: Mr Tsipras is under pressure to save his country from the abyss Photo: Rex Features
Mr Lew said it was no longer clear that there will be a solution to Greeces turmoil. He said both parties were gambling with the stability of the global economy in entertaining the prospect of a Grexit.
Before things broke down and they went to a referendum, they were within a couple of billions of euros of closing the gap, Mr Lew told the Brookings Institute .
For anyone who has participated in fiscal policy discussions, you wouldn't usually buy hundreds of billions of dollars of risk for a few billion.
He added ultimately it was a matter for the Europeans to decide, but the White House would "try to help the parties understand the options they have".
Athens made a fresh request for a three-year rescue programme to lenders on Tuesday morning.
The government is set to lay out a comprehensive package of economic reforms it intends to carry out in return for cash from Europes joint rescue fund  the European Stability Mechanism.
Greece's application for a new ESM loan
Without a deal, "riots and chaos will ensue, said Christian Noyer, the governor of the Bank of France and a member of the ECB governing council.
"The Greek economy is on the brink of catastrophe. A deal absolutely must be reached on Sunday because it will be too late after that and the consequences will be grave," he told Europe 1 radio.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras is under intense international and domestic pressure to finally capitulate and order an overhaul of his country's controversial pensions system and abolish tax exemptions for its tourist islands.
I am warning the prime minister that we have reached our limit of trust in him, said the interim leader of Greece's opposition New Democracy party, Evangelos Meimarakis.
 AEP: Europe is tearing itself apart over Greece
Athens' bail-out letter said the government would now "immediately implement" unspecified tax and pension reforms "as early as the beginning of next week".
Greece is rushing to secure an immediate release of up to 3.3bn of funds owed to the country from the European Central Bank on Monday, in order to stave off a default to the ECB on July 20.
ECB liquidity for Greek banks (ELA) frozen at 89bn. Makes no difference. BoG cash is getting into those ATMs by pure magic from reserves
 A Evans-Pritchard (@AmbroseEP) July 8, 2015
The country's financing needs amount to more than 70bn over the next three years, according to the International Monetary Fund .
Europes finance ministers are set to discuss Greece's request during a phone conference on Thursday, in order to lay the groundwork for another extraordinary summit of all 28 European leaders on Sunday.
Should Greece fail to satisfy its lenders demands, politicians and lawyers are set to thrash out a legal mechanism for Greece to be ejected from the eurozone and food and medical supplies to be sent to the country.
"Is that the image of Europe we want to give to the world?"
France's Valls on the prospect of Grexit
Greek tourism groups warned of an explosion of unemployment if no deal is struck.
There has been surge in sales of fridges, televisions and top-of-the-range computers as Greeks attempt to turn their remaining cash into tradable assets.
The European Central Bank decided to maintain its freeze on emergency funding for Greek banks at 89bn. The stance will continue to add to the liquidity squeeze on the financial system. Banks will now continue to be closed until the end of the week at least.
French president Manuel Valls urged the eurozone's creditor bloc, led by Germany, to seriously consider the new Greek plan in order to bring the European project back from the abyss.
It shows a real willingness to move forward and reform," Mr Valls said of Greece's proposals, which promise to carry out tax and pension reforms as early as next week.
Manuel Valls Photo: AFP
Paris has become the leading voice of compromise, urging its fellow 18 eurozone members to avoid a catastrophic miscalculation over Greece.
Keeping Greece in the euro is a "geopolitical issue of the highest importance", Mr Valls told his parliament.
"An exit would definitely cause a drop in revenues, exploding import costs, including for basic goods, social and political consequences that none of us are able to predict. Is that what we want for the Greek people?
"Is that the image of Europe we want to give to the world?, he said.
Au peuple grec, je dis : ? ?????? ????? ? ?????? ! MV
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:41:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British mother reunited with newborn in Spain after DNA tests</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f3ebb7/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C117274620CBritish0Emother0Ereunited0Ewith0Enewborn0Ein0ESpain0Eafter0EDNA0Etests0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Stacie Cottle reunited with newborn girl after having to undergo DNA tests in Spain to prove parentage</Description>
        <MainBody>British mother reunited with newborn in Spain after DNA tests
Stacie Cottle reunited with newborn girl after having to undergo DNA tests in    Spain to prove parentage
Stacie Cottle reunited with her daughter, AnzelikaPhoto: Olive Press Spain
By Guy Hedgecoe in Madrid
7:41PM BST 08 Jul 2015
A British woman has been given custody of her newborn baby in Spain , after a three-week wait for a DNA test to prove that the child was hers.
Stacie Cottle, 27, gave birth on June 16 at her mothers house in Velez-Malaga, southern Spain.
When she took the newborn to the local hospital in Axarquia the following day, staff alerted the authorities because they suspected that the child was older than the mother said  and therefore possibly not hers.
Police visited Ms Cottle at her mothers rented home and told her that the baby would be taken into care pending a DNA test.
They treated me as if I was a thief and Id kidnapped my daughter, when what I did was go to the doctor in order to certify the birth and be able to go back to my country, Ms Cottle told local newspaper Diario Sur.
It took three weeks for the test results to come through, during which time Ms Cottle stayed in the hospital to breastfeed her daughter.
On Tuesday, the DNA results came through, showing that Ms Cottle was indeed the mother and she and her baby checked out of the hospital that afternoon, along with her other daughter, aged three.
I cant understand how they could take so long to give me the DNA results, when I brought all the pregnancy documentation, scans and even the afterbirth and my daughter still had the umbilical cord uncut, she said.
A Spanish medical official told the local media: This is the normal procedure in this kind of case, because the baby wasnt born in the hospital and we had to confirm that the mother was who she really said she was.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:17:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia blocks UN resolution condemning Srebrenica massacre as genocide</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f36aa5/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cbosnia0C117276130CRussia0Eblocks0EUN0Eresolution0Econdemning0ESrebrenica0Emassacre0Eas0Egenocide0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Britain leads condemnation as Russia deploys veto power to thwart recognition at UN that massacre of 8,000 Bosnian Muslim men and boys 20 years ago was act of genocide</Description>
        <MainBody>Bosnia
Russia blocks UN resolution condemning Srebrenica massacre as genocide
Britain leads condemnation as Russia deploys veto power to thwart recognition    at UN that massacre of 8,000 Bosnian Muslim men and boys 20 years ago was    act of genocide
Nura Mustafic visits the graves of her husband and sons alongside thousands of other victims of the 1995 massacrePhoto: Paul Grover
By Philip Sherwell , New York
7:17PM BST 08 Jul 2015
Follow
Russia has vetoed a British-drafted United Nations resolution condemning the 1995 Srebrenica massacre as a crime of genocide amid acrimonious exchanges on the eve of the 20th anniversary of the slaughter of 8,000 Bosnian Muslim men and boys.
Philip Hammond, the Foreign Secretary, led condemnation of the Russian vote to block the first formal recognition by the UN Security Council that the worst atrocity in Europe since 1945 was an act of genocide.
The victims were gunned down and buried in mass graves after Bosnian Serb forces overran a supposedly safe haven run by Dutch UN peacekeepers in the final months of the three-year Bosnian war.
It was one of the darkest chapters in UN history and Western powers were widely condemned for abandoning the Muslim victims to their fate.
 Meet the US government historian who tracks down Bosnian war criminals in America
"The failure to adopt this resolution is a snub to the families of the victims and the survivors of Srebrenica, Mr Hammond said. True reconciliation requires facing up to the realities of the past by all sides and determination to learn the lessons for the future.
President Vladimir Putin instructed his ambassador to exercise Russias veto power at the Security Council after he was lobbied by Serbian and Bosnian Serb leaders , Moscows traditional Balkan allies.
Russia was the sole country among the 15 Security Council members to vote against the resolution at a meeting that began with a minutes silence to remember the victims. Ten members supported the resolution and four abstained, including China.
Vitaly Churkin, Moscows ambassador, criticised the British wording as "confrontational and politically-motivated", arguing that it unfairly singled out Bosnian Serbs for committing war crimes in a conflict in which all three ethnic groups were the victims of atrocities.
But Peter Wilson, the deputy British ambassador, delivered a stinging rebuke of the Russian vote. The United Kingdom is outraged that Russia has vetoed this resolution today, he told the chamber. Russias actions tarnishes the memory of all those who died in the Srebrenica genocide.
UK outraged that Russia vetoed @UN SC resolution on #Srebrenica today. Russias actions tarnishes memory of those who died in the genocide.
 UKUN_NewYork (@UKUN_NewYork) July 8, 2015
This draft resolution did not point fingers of blame, score political points nor seek to reopen painful divisions. It did not link the crimes of Srebrenica to the Serb people. It recognised that there were victims on all sides.
But reconciliation must be based on a shared acceptance of the facts; that genocide occurred at Srebrenica. This is a legal fact, not a political judgement. On this there is no compromise.
But Mr Churkin insisted: "The draft that we have in front of us will not help peace in the Balkans but rather doom this region to tension.
British and American diplomats had been locked in tense negotiations with their Russian counterparts for 24 hours after a vote was delayed on Tuesday, but Moscow refused to drop its insistence that references to the killings as an act of genocide be scrapped.
Two international courts have already called the slaughter genocide, but the world body has never reached that conclusion.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:09:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police seize 1.2 billion in assets from five Sicilian pensioners in anti-mafia haul</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f36aad/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Citaly0C117268890CPolice0Eseize0E10B20Ebillion0Ein0Eassets0Efrom0Efive0ESicilian0Epensioners0Ein0Eanti0Emafia0Ehaul0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Businesses, property and bank accounts seized from three brothers and two sisters in one of Italy's largest sweeps of its kind</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow
More than 1.6 billion (1.2bn) worth of assets have been seized from a family of five Sicilian pensioners in one of Italy's largest ever anti-mafia hauls, police said on Wednesday.
The three brothers and two sisters, described as businesspeople from the area outside Palermo, the Sicilian capital, allegedly received help from the islands Cosa Nostra mafia to win construction contracts related to public works.
The businesses, property and bank accounts seized belong to Carmelo Virga, 66, his brothers Vincenzo, 78, and 71-year-old Francesco, and their sisters Anna, 76, and Rosa, 68.
The siblings, originally from the small town of Marineo in the suburbs of Palermo, are believed to have worked as labourers in the 1980s before allegedly amassing millions under the protection of Cosa Nostra.
The Palermo division of the Anti-Mafia Department (DIA) said they had seized some 800 buildings including houses and factories, motor vehicles and dozens of bank accounts.
"Today's seizure is certainly one of the biggest the DIA has carried out in its 20-year history," Adelmo, Lusi, vice chief of DIA operations, said.
"The (1.6 billion) sum is enormous for a family unit that until 30 years ago was made up of carpenters, manual labourers and housewives."
The seizure is the first stage in the investigation process by the DIA. No arrests have yet been made.
Carmelos son, Gaetano, who has collaborated with several anti-mafia organisations in the past and has given evidence against extortion rackets on the island, told police that he and his family were consistently threatened by the mafia between May and November 2010.
He told investigators that he was approached by a member of the mafia, who told him: "Remember that you have children.
He said one of the alleged extortionists subsequently came to the familys office on one of their construction sites to demand protection money.
My uncle sent him away telling him he would not get a penny, he told investigators. But he came back again and again.
The operation by the Palermo-based court was aimed at "known entrepreneurs from the Palermo area who belong to the Marineo mafia family, linked to the Corleone clan," the DIA said.
The Corleone clan are a faction within Cosa Nostra that dominated the organisation during the 1980s and 1990s.
"Complex investigations have uncovered how the Virgas have benefited from the backing of the Cosa Nostra in the bidding for works and public tenders in the construction sector," the DIA added.
News of the investigation came as 10 people were arrested for mafia association in southern Germany in a joint operation by Italian and German police.
Police in Reggio Calabria, a city at Italys southern tip, believe the suspects have cloned the mafia model used by the Ndrangheta , now considered the most powerful crime syndicate in Italy.
Organised crime networks typically seen in Calabria, the homeland of the Ndrangheta, were set up in the small German towns of Frauenfeld, Singen, Rielasingen, Engen and Ravensburg.
A previous operation by Calabrian police found evidence the Ndrangheta were operating in Switzerland.
However, the 'Ndrangheta have also spread tentacles outside Europe.
Last month, a major investigation by the Australian Broadcasting Corporation and Fairfax Media found Australian politics had been infiltrated at high levels by the feared Italian clan.
The group allegedly used a number of well-known donors to political parties to legitimise its activities. The investigation also claimed the son of an alleged mafia boss did work experience at the Australian embassy in Rome in 2010.
Italian investigators say the 'Ndrangheta now ranks as the biggest cocaine trafficking organisation in Europe. Through the international drug trade, it has developed links with the Zetas, a powerful and violent crime syndicate in Mexico that has turned itself into the main suppliers of the Ndrangheta by shipping cocaine through the US and into Europe.
The 'Ndrangheta is now considered more powerful than Cosa Nostra, which has long plagued Italy.
Three years of recession have helped deep-rooted corruption and mafia networks to flourish, with the country ranking 69th of 177 countries in Transparency International's 2014 Corruption Perceptions Index, joint last in the European Union.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:49:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI searches for teenage victims of 'sextortion' in UK, US and Canada</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47ef3c09/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C117257220CFBI0Esearches0Efor0Eteenage0Evictims0Eof0Esextortion0Ein0EUK0EUS0Eand0ECanada0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>FBI appealing for help to track down hundreds of victims of Florida man who tried to blackmail teenage victims into sending him explict photographs online</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
FBI searches for teenage victims of 'sextortion' in UK, US and Canada
FBI appealing for help to track down hundreds of victims of Florida man who    tried to blackmail teenage victims into sending him explict photographs    online
Lucas Michael Chansler has been sentenced to 105 years in prisonPhoto: AP
By Philip Sherwell , New York
6:49PM BST 08 Jul 2015
Follow
A British teenage girl was among hundreds of child sextortion victims of an American man convicted of using online threats to try to extort sexually explicit images from his targets.
The Federal Bureau of Investigations (FBI) has so far tracked down more than 100 victims of Lucas Michael Chansler, who has been jailed for 105 years for the growing Internet crime of sextortion .
But FBI agents are trying to locate around 240 still-unidentified victims to tell them that their predator has been jailed in an attempt to end the torment that many have suffered for years.
The only identified British victim was a then 15-year-old girl from the outskirts of Birmingham who was targeted by Chansler in 2008. But there may be more British victims as the FBI often only have now-defunct social media accounts for his targets.
We want to contact his victims so that we can tell them that this man has been convicted and put behind bars said Larry Meyer, the FBI special agent who led the investigation.
 Philippines police and Interpol smash cyber-extortion network
Many of them have been tormented for years by what he did to them and threats he made. We are trying to inform his victims that this dark chapter in their lives has closed in the hope that it brings some relief after the years of suffering.
Chansler, 31, from Florida, admitted exploiting the youth and vulnerability of his targets to demand that they send him sexually explicit photographs. He would befriend his victims using online aliases on social media sites and then persuade them to expose themselves or engage in sexually explicit conduct on video chats that he secretly recorded.
Chansler then threatened to post the images online or to send them to the girls' parents unless they agreed to provide more graphic images.
He told that authorities that he targeted girls aged between 13 and 18 as adults were "too smart" to be tricked by him. His victims, some of whom tried to commit suicide because of the shame, came from 26 US states, three Canadian provinces and Britain.
"With the expansion of the Internet, online profiles, social media and the ability to anonymise somebody, sextortion has really escalated in the United States and around the world," said Peter Kowenhoven, an FBI investigator. "Because the Internet is global and cuts across state lines, the victims can be found anywhere."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:43:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beyonc-inspired skyscraper to be built in Australia</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f36aae/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Caustralia0C117275710CBeyonce0Einspired0Eskyscraper0Eto0Ebe0Ebuilt0Ein0EAustralia0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Yet another reason why Beyonc rules the world: her body is the inspiration for a skyscraper in Australia</Description>
        <MainBody>Australia
Beyonc-inspired skyscraper to be built in Australia
Yet another reason why Beyonc rules the world: her body is the inspiration    for a skyscraper in Australia
By Charlotte Krol, video source ITN
6:43PM BST 08 Jul 2015
An Australian company is to build a skyscraper featuring curvaceous structures inspired by pop star Beyonc.
The 78-storey skyscraper will be near Melbournes Southern Cross railway station where it will house apartments, retail space and hotel rooms.
The Premier Tower (l) and Beyonce (r) (ITN)
The Premier Towers curves were inspired by one of the pop star's music video Ghost, in which she waves a billowing piece of black fabric in front of a wind machine.
Elenberg Fraser, the firm behind the skyscraper, estimate that it will take 14 months to construct.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
