<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:53:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Senior Pakistani Taliban leader killed drone strike</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fca97c/sc/40/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cpakistan0C117298680CSenior0EPakistani0ETaliban0Eleader0Ekilled0Edrone0Estrike0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Shahidullah Shahid, a former member of the Pakistani Taliban who defected to Islamic State and was operating in Afghanistan, killed in drone strike, official says</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistan
Senior Pakistani Taliban leader killed drone strike
Shahidullah Shahid, a former member of the Pakistani Taliban who defected to    Islamic State and was operating in Afghanistan, killed in drone strike,    official says
Shahidullah Shahid's death has been confirmed by the Afghan intelligence agency, the National Directorate of SecurityPhoto: Ishtiaq Mahsud/AP
By Ashfaq Yusufzai, Peshawar
8:53PM BST 09 Jul 2015
A senior Pakistani Taliban leader who defected to Isil has been killed in a drone strike with other senior militants, a local security official said.
Sheikh Maqbool, who operated under the nom de guerre Shahidullah Shahid and had been chief spokesman of the Tehreek-i-Taliban Pakistan (TTP), was killed in neighbouring Afghanistan along with Gul Zaman, a military commander from Pakistans Orakzai tribal region.
Gul Zaman had been appointed deputy leader of the Khorasan Province, the fast-growing Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant branch in Afghanistan.
The total death toll from the strike remains unclear, and there are no reports whether the leader of the group, Hafiz Mohammed Saeed, was at the meeting which was targeted.
According to at least one Pakistani official, the toll was 11 dead and four injured, all defectors from the Pakistan to Isil and all from Orakzai. However, other reports put the death toll at 49 militants, attending a shura or council meeting.
The Afghan intelligence agency, National Directorate of Security, confirmed Shahids killing in a statement.
The Pentagon confirmed there had been a series of strikes in the Achin district of Nangarhar on Monday and Tuesday. "All of these strikes were conducted against individuals threatening U.S. and coalition forces," a spokesman said.
A Pakistani official said: There was an Isil shura meeting when the missiles hit them.
It was a pretty massive hit. So many Isil fighters and commanders have been killed in one go.
 Islamic State claims Pakistan and Afghanistan for its 'caliphate'
Shahidullah Shahid had left TTP to join Isil after Pakistans military operation in June last year that evicted the Pakistani militant group from its stronghold of North Waziristan.
This was another example of military action against an al-Qaeda associated or allied group backfiring when the defeated or targeted elements turned to Isils more successful brand for protection.
Both the TTP and the local Isil branch, announced last year, had their bases in Pakistans Khyber tribal regions mountainous Tirah Valley.
After the Pakistan army advanced there too, they abandoned their sanctuary and moved to Afghanistans Nangrahar province.
 Afghan Taliban warns jihadists to avoid Islamic State extremism
The official said the Afghan Taliban quickly moved to the area and seized the charred bodies. Isil has now requested the TTA to return the bodies, the official said, referring to the acronym of the Afghan Taliban.
That request was despite a battle between the Taliban and Isil in both Nangrahar and Kunar provinces of Afghanistan.
Officials said that Isil had seized control of some areas in Afghanistan close to the Pakistani border after evicting TTA fighters.
The TTA has called for reinforcements and they are moving back to reclaim the area, the official said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:35:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks: John Kerry 'prepared to walk away' from negotiations</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fca97d/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Ciran0C11730A1610CIran0Enuclear0Etalks0EJohn0EKerry0Eprepared0Eto0Ewalk0Eaway0Efrom0Enegotiations0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>John Kerry says major world powers will not "rush" into a nuclear deal with Iran, adding he was "absolutely prepared" to walk away</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow
John Kerry claimed on Thursday that America was absolutely prepared to stop negotiating over Iran s nuclear ambitions, but announced that talks would nonetheless continue beyond their latest deadline.
On the thirteenth day of the Vienna meeting, the US secretary of state made clear that no agreement would be reached in time for a deadline laid down by Congress.
The US Administration has undertaken to give both Houses 30 days to review any nuclear deal with Iran achieved by midnight on July 9  and 60 days if an agreement comes later.
Mr Kerry announced that the deadline for a 30-day review period would be broken and the Vienna talks extended for a third time. Let me assure you, we would not be here continuing to negotiate just for the sake of negotiating. Were here because we believe were making real progress towards a comprehensive deal, he said.
We are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever. We also recognise that we shouldnt get up and leave simply because the clock strikes midnight.
The aim of the talks is to settle the confrontation over Irans nuclear programme . However, one round of negotiations after another has failed to solve a multitude of complex problems.
The latest obstacle is believed to concern an arms embargo currently imposed on Iran by two United Nations Resolutions. Iran wants this restriction to be lifted as part of a general easing of sanctions under a final deal.
To make matters more difficult, Russia has openly supported Irans demand. Sergei Lavrov, the Russian foreign minister, said on Thursday: We are in favour of lifting the embargo as soon as possible and will support a decision made by Irans negotiators.
But Russia is supposed to be America's negotiating partner when it comes to talks with Iran. The two countries both sit in the P5 plus 1 contact group, consisting of the Security Councils five permanent members plus Germany, which deals with Iran on the nuclear issue. This public split within the ranks of the P5 plus 1 has eased the pressure on Iran to made any concessions over the arms embargo.
Mr Kerry stressed how the stakes for a final nuclear agreement were very high, adding: We will not rush and we will not be rushed. All that we are focused on is the quality of the agreement and that is what will continue to define our work.
But Mr Kerry delivered an implicit warning to Iran, saying: We know that difficult decisions dont become easier over time. One way or the other, those decisions must be taken very soon.
On Wednesday, Mr Kerry held a conference call with President Barack Obama and the US national security team. President Obama made it very clear to me last night: we cant wait forever for the decision to be made, said Mr Kerry. We know that. If the tough decisions dont get made, we are absolutely prepared to call an end to this process.
The secretary of state insisted that the talks were not open-ended. But after 13 days and three extensions  the latter with no mention of a new deadline  there is no sign of when the Vienna negotiations might end.
But the recriminations over the failure to conclude a deal have already begun. Western diplomatic sources say that Iran has tried to reinterpret a framework agreement reached in the Swiss town of Lausanne in April. They say the reason for the deadlock is that other countries around the increasingly tense negotiating table have been forced to resist this attempt.
On Thursday night, a senior Iranian official argued that, on the contrary, other countries had backtracked from the Lausanne terms. The official accused Iran's negotiating partners of changing their positions on the "full range" of issues when "it's not even the 11th hour, it's the 13th hour".
Alluding to the divisions within the "P5 plus 1", the official said that Iran's counterparts spent more time "coordinating" their own positions than "coordinating with us".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:07:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sarkozy signs petition against proposal to turn unused French churches into mosques</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fca981/sc/13/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C117298220CSarkozy0Esigns0Epetition0Eagainst0Eproposal0Eto0Eturn0Eunused0EFrench0Echurches0Einto0Emosques0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy joins string of Right-wing intellectuals to sign petition following a proposal by Paris mosque head that unused churches could be turned into mosques</Description>
        <MainBody>France
Sarkozy signs petition against proposal to turn unused French churches into mosques
Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy joins string of Right-wing    intellectuals to sign petition following a proposal by Paris mosque head    that unused churches could be turned into mosques
Nicolas Sarkozy is against the proposalsPhoto: ANNE-CHRISTINE POUJOULAT/AFP
Follow
Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy signed a petition on Thursday criticising a proposal to turn empty churches into mosques, as a poll suggested that more than two thirds of French people are vehemently against the idea.
Other signatures on the petition, called Dont Touch My Church, included controversial writer and political journalist ric Zemmour and philosopher Alain Finkielkraut, as well as Jeannette Bougrab , the former partner of Stphane Charbonnier, Charlie Hebdo's slain editor.
The petition, published in the Right-wing magazine Valeurs Actuelles, comes after Dalil Boubakeur, the rector of the Grand Mosque in Paris, said he was in favour of repurposing unused churches due to the serious dearth of places of worship for Muslims.
"This is a delicate issue, but why not," he told Europe 1 radio last month. "Its the same God, the rites are similar, fraternal and I think that Muslims and Christians can coexist and live together, he said.
The petition said the French would never tolerate the prospect of a religious practice other than Catholic in their churches.
A church is not a mosque, and to claim that the rites are the same is a scandalous denial of reality, it went on.
Valry Giscard d'Estaing, another former French president, and Edouard Balladur, a former prime minister, also responded to Mr Boubakeur's proposal in the magazine's appeal to "preserve these sentinels of the French soul".
"The French Catholic churches have been part of the historical heritage of the French population for ten centuries," Mr Giscard d'Estaing wrote, while Mr Balladur stressed the need to save "the traditions that are largely the image and culture of our nation."
France is home to around 40,000 churches for a population of around four million practicing Catholics.
The country currently has around 2,500 mosques, while another 300 are under construction. But with more than five million Muslims in France  the largest population in Europe  Mr Boubakeur and other imams suggested last month that the number of mosques should be doubled by 2017.
Calls for more mosques have been supported by France's Christian leaders as a legitimate demand.
Muslims should, like Christians and Jews, be able to practise their religion, Monseigneur Ribadeau-Dumas, spokesperson for the Bishops Conference of France, told French radio station Europe 1.
However, more than 67 per cent of French are opposed to the suggestion, and are two and a half times more likely to say "totally opposed" than "somewhat opposed", according to a survey by the French Institute of Public Opinion, Ifop.
"Even if France is deeply de-Christianised since the 1960s, there is a real commitment  to the Christian roots and their symbols," Jerome Fourquet, Ifops director of opinion and strategy, told the magazine.
In April, Thierry Mandon, the Socialist minister of simplification, said that the lack of "decent" places of worship for French Muslims was partly to blame for some believers turning to radical Islam.
His words came as France struggles to calm community tensions in the wake of the January Islamist attacks in Paris.
"There aren't enough mosques in France," he told iTele. "The more you let the Muslims of France pray in cellars and garages, the more you hold a mirror up to discrimination that is the basis of anger and fertile ground for radicalisation," he said.
Mr Sarkozy, who hopes to lead his conservative The Republicans party to the 2017 presidential race, has toughened his stance on Islam. He recently called for France's ban on the Islamic headscarf to be extended from schools to universities and for halal meals in schools to be scrapped.
Since a 1905 law separating the church and state, France does not fund the construction of religious buildings.
This has led to complaints that many new mosques in France are funded by foreign Muslim states with sometimes radical religious views.
Anouar Kbibech, new head of the French Council of the Muslim Faith, said that it was "up to French Muslims to take themselves in hand".
The solution, he said, was to build "local human-sized projects, that can be funded by believers themselves" rather than vast "mosque cathedrals". These should "fit into French architectural heritage" in a harmonious way, he told Metronews.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:04:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syria army battles Islamic State outside Palmyra</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fca98a/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Csyria0C11730A0A740CSyria0Earmy0Ebattles0EIslamic0EState0Eoutside0EPalmyra0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Syrian army troops backed by war planes advance to within several kilometres of Palmyra, according to monitor</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria army battles Islamic State outside Palmyra
Syrian army troops backed by war planes advance to within several kilometres    of Palmyra, according to monitor
A file photo of a Syrian army soldier fires artillery shells towards ISIL jihadists in northeastern PalmyraPhoto: AFP
By Louisa Loveluck in Cairo
8:04PM BST 09 Jul 2015
Forces loyal to Syria s Bashar al-Assad on Thursday edged to within several kilometres of the Islamic State -held ancient city of Palmyra.
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a monitoring group, said ground troops had reached some three miles west of the city and were engaged in fierce clashes with the jihadist militants.
"Regime forces could enter the city at any moment, they are not far away and the area between them and the city is desert," Observatory director Rami Abdel Rahman said.
The ancient city of Palmyra and its modern town of the same name, known in Arabic as Tadmur, fell under the control of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (Isil) in May . The militants have used its Roman theatre as a stage for ceremonial executions, and mined the surrounding site in an attempt to deter the expected government fightback.
Heavy regime airstrikes have backed the ground offensive to retake Palmyra, causing dozens of residents to flee Tadmur earlier this week. Although most have focused on the town itself, at least one has damaged parts of the Unesco-listed ruins.
Nestled along a strategically important highway between the cities of Homs and Deiz Ezzor, the towns capture cut an important supply line for Mr Assads government, underscoring the troubles it is starting to face as Syrias war continues through its fifth year.
As the country moves towards de facto partition, regime forces are retrenching around the core strategic areas of Damascus and the Mediterranean coast. Mr Assads overstretched army increasingly relies on manpower provided by foreign allies Iran or the Lebanese group Hezbollah.
The regime has been hesitant to commit significant resources to fight renewed rebel offensives in Deraa in the south or Aleppo in the North.
The death of the Assad familys longest standing confidant, Mohammed Nasif Kheirbek, has also left the presidents inner circle shrunken and riven by infighting over the role played by Iran in Syrias war.
Tehran's financial assistance has been seen as pivotal to the Syrian government and economy, which has shrunk by more than a half since the conflict in 2011 erupted. Syrias state news agency said on Wednesday that Mr Assad had signed a law ratifying a $1 billion credit line from Iran.
According to the United Nations, more than four million Syrians have now fled abroad, the largest number from any crisis in almost 25 years. The agency said on Thursday that an additional 7.6 million people have been displaced from their homes within Syria as a result of the fighting.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:22:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Parisians will be swimming in the Seine by 2024, promises French capital's mayor</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fca98b/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C11730A0A750CParisians0Ewill0Ebe0Eswimming0Ein0Ethe0ESeine0Eby0E20A240Epromises0EFrench0Ecapitals0Emayor0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Anne Hidalgo pledges to end swimming ban for Parisians in time for 2024 Olympic Games that she hopes will be held in the city</Description>
        <MainBody>France
Parisians will be swimming in the Seine by 2024, promises French capital's mayor
Anne Hidalgo pledges to end a swimming ban for Parisians in place since 1923    by having residents of the French capital bathing in the river after the    2024 Olympic Games she hopes will be held in the city
Swimming in Paris' river used to be a popular pastimePhoto: Keystone-France
Follow
Paris Socialist mayor on Thursday pledged to have resident of the French capital swimming in the Seine river by 2024, in her latest bid to clean up the city .
Anne Hidalgo made the promise days after kicking off Paris bid to host the 2024 Olympic Games, after the city lost out to London in 2012 .
She said it was her dearest wish that the swimming phase of the Games triathlon should take place in the Seine. Contestants for the event in London took to Hyde Parks Serpentine.
Mayor Hidalgo (AFP)
The Seine has already been used for sporting events  notably for Frances triathlon championships in 2011  but not for private individuals. Ms Hidalgo went further by adding: Parisians will be able to bathe in the Seine after 2024.
The pledge will ring bells for longstanding residents of the French capital as Jacques Chirac, mayor of Paris from 1977 to 1995, insisted in 1988 that Parisians would be frolicking in the Seine by 1994.
Today, one can only say that Parisians had to leave their bathing suits in the wardrobe, noted Le Parisien. The river has been off limits since 1923, with bathers risking a 15-euro fine for jumping in.
The possibility for everyone to swim in the Seine will form part of the precious legacy that this collective Olympic adventure must leave us, said Ms Hidalgo.
Political observers said the pledge to clean up the Seine was clearly a nod to Ms Hidalgos Green allies who voted against Paris Olympic bid. Clia Blauel, Green mayoral deputy in charge of water, tweeted: If organising the triathlon enables us to re-conquer the water quality of the Seine, it will be worth its weight in gold medals.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:08:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britons told to leave Tunisia amid fears of a fresh terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc6536/sc/40/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1172990A50CBritons0Etold0Eto0Eleave0ETunisia0Eamid0Efears0Eof0Ea0Efresh0Eterror0Eattack0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Foreign Office has changed its travel advice for Tunisia warning against all but essential travel amid fears gunman Selfeddine Rezgui's cell could be ready to strike again</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
Britons told to leave Tunisia amid fears of a fresh terror attack
Foreign Office has changed its travel advice for Tunisia warning against all    but essential travel amid fears gunman Selfeddine Rezgui's cell could be    ready to strike again
By Tom Whitehead , Security Editor, video source UK POOL
7:08PM BST 09 Jul 2015
Britons have been told to leave Tunisia as soon as possible amid fears it is highly likely they will be targeted in a fresh terror attack.
The Foreign Office changed its travel advice for the country warning against all but essential travel.
Holiday operators were urgently arranging additional flights to bring Britons currently travelling in the country home, the FCO said.
 Tunisia appeals for information on two suspected accomplices
There are up to 3,000 Britons currently in Tunisia, it is understood, and they have been told to contact their tour operator or airline to plan their return.
The change came two weeks after Isil-backed gunman Selfeddine Rezgui slaughtered 38 people in the beach town of Sousse, including 30 Britons.
Foreign Office sources said it had become apparent that Rezgui was not working alone and his cell had clearly targeted British nationals.
It is also feared the Tunisian authorities cannot adequately protect tourists from another attack.
Philip Hammond, the Foreign Secretary, said: Since the attack in Sousse the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably, leading us to the view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely.
"The Tunisian investigation into those behind the Sousse attack and that on the Bardo museum earlier this year is ongoing and the Tunisians have made clear they want to track down further individuals who they suspect may have links to this attack.
"While we are working with the Tunisian authorities to further strengthen those measures, we judge that more work is needed to effectively protect tourists from the terrorist threat.
"Taking all these factors together we judge it is right and prudent to make this change. We have not taken this decision lightly but our first priority will always be the safety of our citizens.
"In the days and weeks ahead, we will continue to keep the situation under close review and to work with the Tunisians to further understand the threat and to strengthen their security response to it.
Flowers on an upturned sun lounger on the beach where 38 died (Warren Allott)
It came as it emerged that RAF bombers have killed more than 240 Isil terrorists in Iraq since raids began in October 2014,
The success of the raids is likely to increase calls for Britain to intervene in Syria, which is expected to be put to a vote in Parliament later this year.
Michael Fallon, the Defence Secretary, said that the raids are justified because Isil is an "evil" organisation which murders innocent civilians and poses a serious threat to Britain.
He said: "ISIL is an evil and barbaric organisation. It is murdering innocent civilians on a huge scale in the Middle East and it poses an extremely serious terrorist threat to our country. Thats why the action our armed forces are taking to combat it is so important."
Seifeddine Rezgui was photographed on the beach where he killed 38 people
On its website, the FCO said the advice had been changed due to the evolving security situationreinforcing our view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely.
The advice said that on balance there was no adequate protection in place in Tunisia for British tourists.
It added: If youre in Tunisia and you dont have an essential need to remain you should leave by commercial means.
Tour operators are arranging additional flights and will be organising departures for their customers.
Those travelling independently need to make their own arrangements, it said.
Those who need help are told to contact the British embassy in Tunis.
It said: Further terrorist attacks are highly likely, including in tourist resorts, and by individuals unknown to the authorities whose actions may be inspired by terrorist groups via social media.
You should be especially vigilant at this time and follow the advice of the Tunisian security authorities and your tour operator, if you have one.
The Foreign Office had faced questions over why it had not changed its travel advice in the immediate aftermath of the Sousse atrocity.
 Tunisia building wall to prevent travel to Libyan jihad camps
Sources said the decision was taken after a series of arrests in the investigation in Tunisia made it clear it was not a lone wolf attack and a larger group was behind it.
The Association of British Travel Agents (Abta) urged people due to travel to Tunisia to contact the company they booked through.
It said: "For anyone due to travel, you should be aware that travelling out to Tunisia at this time is likely to invalidate your travel insurance policies. Most insurance policies will still provide cover for travellers in a country at the time of Foreign Office advice change.
"Those with holidays booked within the next 48 hours to Tunisia are advised to contact your travel company to discuss available options. If you have booked a package you will be entitled to a refund or alternative holiday."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:08:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CNN investigates star correspondent 'life-saving surgery' report after Nepal earthquake</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc653a/sc/17/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cnepal0C117299890CCNN0Einvestigates0Estar0Ecorrespondent0Elife0Esaving0Esurgery0Ereport0Eafter0ENepal0Eearthquake0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dual on-screen role of Sanjay Gupta as CNN chief medical correspondent and neurosurgeon put under microscope amid scrutiny of his coverage of brain operation in Nepal</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal
CNN investigates star correspondent 'life-saving surgery' report after Nepal earthquake
Dual on-screen role of Sanjay Gupta as CNN chief medical correspondent and    neurosurgeon put under microscope amid scrutiny of his coverage of brain    operation in Nepal
Sanjay Gupta said he was asked by a Nepalese medical team to assist with the surgery on an 8-year-old girlPhoto: Getty Images
By Philip Sherwell , New York
7:08PM BST 09 Jul 2015
It was one of those moments that seem broadcasting gold for US television news networks  a dramatic video report that made headlines around the world .
Sanjay Gupta, CNNs star chief medical correspondent who is also a highly-rated neurosurgeon, declares Salina will live after donning doctors scrubs in a Kathmandu hospital operating room.
Dr Gupta reported how he had just helped perform life-saving brain surgery on a girl identified by the network as Salina Dahal , an eight-year-old seriously injured in Aprils devastating Nepal earthquake, after local doctors requested his assistance.
But CNN has now launched an inquiry into reports that its correspondent misled viewers after an investigative website established that Salina did not receive surgery for any injuries that day and was only treated for a broken wrist and some minor head wounds.
The accuracy of his coverage was challenged by an investigation by the Global Press Institute , a news website that trains and employs female journalists in the developing world and that tracked down patients and doctors involved that day.
The institutes Global Press Journal reported that Dr Gupta actually operated on another girl, Sandhya Chalise, who is aged 14. She looks quite different from Salina and the CNN footage had shown Gupta inspection scans that were said to show the patients fractured skull and blood clot in Bir hospital in Kathmandu.
The controversy has raised fresh questions about the role of celebrity television news presenters just months after NBCs chief anchor Brian Williams was suspended after he admitted exaggerating his coverage of the 2003 Iraq war.
And is has focused attention again on Dr Guptas dual role and tendency to become involved in the stories that he is covering after he was previously filmed giving medical treatment during reporting trips to Haiti and Iraq.
The journalist-surgeon has now appeared on CNN to try to clarify his reporting, acknowledging that he may indeed have operated not on the girl identified in his report but on the 14-year-old tracked down by Global Press Journal.
He described the scenes at the hospital as completely chaotic in the days after the devastating aftermath and said that the details may have been confused in the process.
These facts are important to us, he said. We are trying to independently verify which child it was who got that operation at the time. There were many children, many people in the hospital.
When you report on these kinds of situations you take lots of different bits of information and you consolidate it and in the end you tell the story.
But adding to the controversy, it has emerged that an earlier text story on the CNN website correctly reported the girls injuries, but it was later updated to reflect the disputed details in the video report.
CNN released a statement saying that it was investigating the report but insisting that the names and ages of patients were provided to Gupta and his team by the hospital.
Cristi Hegranes, the founder and executive director of the Global Press Institute and the publisher of Global Press Journal, said that the chaos did not excuse the inaccurate reporting and that the incident was more than a simple question of a factual mistake.
What we do know is that the culture of celebrity reporting and the discipline of foreign correspondence in todays news media is deeply problematic, she wrote in a comment piece on the website: This story demonstrates that the world needs new models for international reporting. We believe trained local reporters is, at least, part of the solution.
In a statement, CNN said: Journalism is not brain surgery. But brain surgery is brain surgery. We are so proud that Sanjay was one of the few reporters in Nepal to cover the earthquake, and while there was asked to help save a young victims life.
As we reported he assisted the surgeons at Bir Hospital by performing a craniotomy on a young victim. Some reporting has suggested it was not the young girl we, at the time of our own reporting in the midst of the crisis, believed her to be. We will try to verify that. Regardless, Sanjay spent a week in Nepal, helped save a young life in the operating room, and we couldnt be prouder of him. He has our full and unequivocal support.
In a separate development, Dr Rajiv Jha, the senior neurosurgeon at Bir Hospital who conducted the operation, told the Guardian that it was Dr Gupta who had repeatedly asked to take part in an operation, rather than his help being requested by medical staff.
But both Dr Gupta and CNN insisted that he only put on his scrubs and staged his medical intervention after he was asked to assist
Critics have previously criticised the networks portrayal of Dr Gupta as a medical hero who helped treat patients on camera during reporting trips to Iraq and to Haiti after the 2010 earthquake.
"If you're there as a medical professional and you feel, for reasons of humanity, that you have to serve as a medical professional, turn the camera off. It's not that complicated," Philip Kennicott, a cultural critic for the Washington Post, told NPR's Michel Martin in 2010.
Kelly McBride, a senior scholar on media ethics with the Poynter Institute, a journalism college, told NPR that it was exploitative to serve both as physician and reporter.
"If they're treating patients, they have an obligation to treat that patient with dignity," she said. "Clearly those patients have no capability of consenting to having their medical situation becoming part of a news story."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:58:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French campaign against sexual harassment on public transport launched</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc653b/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C117299610CFrench0Ecampaign0Eagainst0Esexual0Eharassment0Eon0Epublic0Etransport0Elaunched0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Twelve-point plan including stops on demand for female passengers using night buses drawn up after survey finds all female passengers have suffered some sexual or sexist treatment</Description>
        <MainBody>France
French campaign against sexual harassment on public transport launched
Twelve-point plan including stops on demand for female passengers using night    buses drawn up after survey finds all female passengers have suffered some    sexual or sexist treatment
A survey for the French goverment suggested all female passengers had suffered some kind of sexual or sexist treatmentPhoto: Alamy (Posed by models)
 Pascale Boistard (@Pascaleboistard) July 9, 2015
It will experiment with stops on demand for female passengers using night buses to help them get closer to their final destination without having to walk alone.
After a certain hour, its quite difficult for women to get home. Stops on demand will bring them closer to home. It works in Canada, Pascale Boistard, womens rights minister, told RMC radio.
To help victims or a witnesses signal any abuse, a text message alert system has been created.
When you witness a reprehensible act, one can be scared to intervene. Here, you can discreetly send a text alert to the (national rail operator) SNCF security centre, who can dispatch agents, said the secretary of state. The SNCF number is 3117 and Paris bus and metro alert is 3249.
The government is also working on a geo-localisation application to quickly locate where an incident took place.
It also vowed to remove any advertising deemed sexist or liable to create a hostile environment for women in public transport.
Public transport spaces mustnt be dedicated to feeding sexist harassment through degrading images of women, said Ms Boistard.
Her comments came as a department store Galeries Lafayettes current billboard campaign featuring a nude woman reclining with a bikini bottom dangling from her foot sparked anger among feminist groups.
You cant sell bikinis if you dont even put the bikini on the woman, said Ms Boistard.
This autumn, an awareness campaign will also be launched on how to react to such harassment and what the punishment is for offenders, which will be relayed in schools.
The campaign following a shock survey that found that "every female user of mass transit has been a victim" of "gender harassment or sexual assault"  even though some are "unaware" of this because they have been conditioned to accept low-level abuse.
Harassment can range from "insults to other intimidating behaviour (insistent flirting, whistling, comments on appearance), to sex attacks or rape," it said. The problem meant that six out of ten women were afraid of being attacked on public transport compared to three out of ten men.
In 2013, some 207 sex attacks were registered in Paris public transport, with 152 of them ending in an arrest.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:46:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cheetah surprises tourist by leaping into safari jeep</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc653c/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Csafariandwildlifeholidays0C117299840CCheetah0Esurprises0Etourist0Eby0Eleaping0Einto0Esafari0Ejeep0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mickey McCaldin got a close look at the big cat on safari in the Maasai Mara</Description>
        <MainBody>Cheetah surprises tourist by leaping into safari jeep
Mickey McCaldin got a close look at the big cat on safari in the Maasai Mara
"I've been living in Kenya all my life and I've never seen anything like this" Photo: Barcroft
6:46PM BST 09 Jul 2015
Comments
An Irish tourist got the shock of his life on safari in Kenya's Maasai Mara when a cheeky cheetah leapt into his jeep.
The bold creature got up close and personal with Mickey McCaldin, bareing its teeth just inches from his face. Family friend David Horsey captured the tense standoff between the pair.
David, 62, from Mombasa, Kenya, said: "I've been living in Kenya all my life and I've never seen anything like this.
 The best photobombing animals
"At first Mickey was really relaxed but I think he was quite concerned it might try and sit in his lap. Unlike a domestic cat, you certainly don't want that."
David captured the pictures last month as the group tracked a well-known family of cheetahs, whose mother is called Malaika.
Having followed them for a couple of days previously, they observed that the family hadn't had a kill for a few days.
David and Mickey were on safari in the Maasai Mara Photo: AP/FOTOLIA
David said: "The family had been looking for a gazelle for a few days with no luck.
"As we'd been around for a couple of days, I think they were used to the jeep so the mum jumped on top to get a better view.
"I think the other cheetah tried to follow her up but went a different way.
"Once it had got bored of Mickey it turned away and looked out of the vehicle for a few minutes.
"It just jumped out afterwards."
The big cat eventually hopped out Photo: AP/FOTOLIA
Mickey was out on holiday with his wife and sister, who are friends of David and his wife Vicky.
David said: "Me and Vicky have lived in Kenya all our lives but we never feel the urge to leave.
"People always ask us where we're going on holiday and it's always around the game reserves.
"You never know what you're going to come across - just like this."
The animal was a little braver than the cheetah captured by newlyweds Edgar and Stacie Cobos in the Serengeti last year .
It stopped short of entering their vehicle, preferring to gaze in through the sunroof.
Edgar Cobos cautiously looks up as the cheetah peers below Photo: Serengeti Safari Camp
Telegraph Travel columnists Richard and Sarah Madden, meanwhile, had their own extraordinary encounter , captured in the video below.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:38:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope rebukes Bolivia's President Evo Morales for gift of crucifix mounted on hammer and sickle</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc653d/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Csouthamerica0Cbolivia0C117298340CPope0Erebukes0EBolivias0EPresident0EEvo0EMorales0Efor0Egift0Eof0Ecrucifix0Emounted0Eon0Ehammer0Eand0Esickle0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis makes clear he is not amused as Evo Morales, Bolivia's left-wing leader, presents gift that mixes the symbols of Christianity and communism</Description>
        <MainBody>Bolivia
Pope rebukes Bolivia's President Evo Morales for gift of crucifix mounted on hammer and sickle
Pope Francis makes clear he is not amused as Evo Morales, Bolivia's left-wing    leader, presents gift that mixes the symbols of Christianity and communism
Evo Morales presents Pope Francis with a gift of a crucifix carved into a wooden hammer and sicklePhoto: AP
By Philip Sherwell , New York
6:38PM BST 09 Jul 2015
Follow
Pope Francis has rebuked his host Evo Morales, the Bolivian president, after the left-wing South American leader presented him with a crucifix mounted on a hammer and sickle  the international symbol of the avowedly atheist creed of communism.
The disapproving look on the pontiffs face made abundantly clear that he was not impressed by the provocative greeting gift handed to him Mr Morales when he paid a courtesy call after arriving in the country.
Thats not right, the Pope noted. The slight was all the more notable as the Argentine pontiff praised the social and economic reforms of Mr Morales when he arrived from Ecuador on the second leg of a three-country tour of his native South America.
Pope Francis is framed by a feather headdress worn by a child as he walks with several children wearing traditional costumes after he was greated by Bolivian President Evo Morales (AP)
But Bolivian officials explained that the gift was a replica of a crucifix made by Father Luis Espinal, a human-rights activist who was killed by a paramilitary death squad in 1980. The Pope had earlier prayed at the site of the murder of his fellow Jesuit en route to the presidential palace.
On his arrival, Pope Francis stressed the role of the Church in Bolivian society, saying the faith has continued to shed its light upon society, contributing to the development of the nation and shaping its culture.
Those words were a clear message to his host. After his election in 2006, Mr Morales, an indigenous Indian, adopted a confrontational approach towards the Roman Catholic Church to which he once referred as his main enemy.
Flying the flag; Evo Morales (Reuters)
He has frequently criticised its role in the colonisation of the continent, ordered the Bible and cross to be removed from the presidential palace and made the country a secular state.
Indeed, all official ceremonies in Bolivia are now preceded by rituals venerating the Andean earth goddess Pachamana. "I remain convinced that we Bolivians have a double religion, double faith," the president said in January. "We are Catholics, but at the same time we have rituals of our own."
But his attitude toward the Church changed radically when Francis became pope. He has been keen to cultivate good relations with a religious leader who is widely perceived as a champion of the poor and oppressed and indeed Mr Morales has twice visited him at the Vatican.
The gift ceremony was not his first awkward encounter with a pope. When he met in 2010 with Francis' predecessor, Benedict XVI, he gave him a letter suggesting the church abolish celibacy and allow women to be priests.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:46:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Muslim groups raise $50,000 to repair US black churches after fires</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc0062/sc/38/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C117296520CMuslim0Egroups0Eraise0E50A0A0A0A0Eto0Erepair0EUS0Eblack0Echurches0Eafter0Efires0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Arson is suspected at several African-American churches in the wake of the Charleston bible class massacre.</Description>
        <MainBody>Muslim groups raise $50,000 to repair US black churches after fires
Arson is suspected at several African-American churches in the wake of the Charleston    bible class massacre.
Elisha Walker, 9, and his mother Bonita Walker look at the charred remains of the back left wing of Briar Creek Road Baptist Church, Charlotte, N.C.Photo: AP
By Nick Allen
5:46PM BST 09 Jul 2015
Muslim groups have raised $50,000 (32,500) to help rebuild black churches hit by arson attacks in the wake of the Charleston bible class massacre .
Fires have struck at least six historically African-American houses of worship since white supremacist Dylann Roof killed nine people at the Emanuel church in Charleston last month.
The fundraising was started by groups including the Muslim Anti-Racism Collaborative and the Arab-American Association of New York.
On the fundraising page they said: "We must always keep in mind that the Muslim community and the black community are not different communities. We are profoundly integrated in many ways, in our overlapping identities and in our relationship to this great and complicated country.
"Too often cowards inflict us with a crippling fear, but with encouragement and support from likely and unlikely places fear cannot stop us."
The FBI and the US Bureau of Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives are investigating the church fires in North Carolina, Tennessee, South Carolina, Georgia and Florida.
Arson is suspected in at least three of the fires.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:43:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italian woman who revealed affair to lover's wife fined for harassment</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc0063/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Citaly0C117290A930CItalian0Ewoman0Ewho0Erevealed0Eaffair0Eto0Elovers0Ewife0Efined0Efor0Eharassment0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Conviction of harassment upheld, as Italian judges rule that making an anonymous call to reveal an affair is a reprehensible act regardless of whether the claim is true</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy
Italian woman who revealed affair to lover's wife fined for harassment
Conviction of harassment upheld, as Italian judges rule that making an    anonymous call to reveal an affair is a reprehensible act regardless of    whether the claim is true
The mistress called her lovers wife twice from her mobile phonePhoto: Alamy
Follow
An Italian woman who made anonymous calls to her lovers wife to tell her of their affair has been told she must pay a 400 (287) fine for harassment.
The woman, named locally as Annamaria D.R., also told her lovers wife about other affairs her husband had allegedly been having in Bari and Potenza, southern Italy .
She argued in court during an appeal hearing that because her lovers wife did not hang up on her calls immediately, it was clear she was interested in what was being said.
The mistress tried to overturn a conviction of harassment originally issued by the Court of Potenza in 2013.
However, Italys Supreme Court in Rome ruled that the fact the wife did not interrupt the calls "cannot be seen as acquiescence on the wife's part, given the serious nature of what was being revealed."
"The petulant and disturbing nature of the calls is shown in the anonymous forms they took," said the ruling.
The court upheld the original conviction of harassment, with judges saying that an anonymous call to reveal an affair is a reprehensible act regardless of whether the claim is true.
The mistress called her lovers wife a total of three times, once from her office phone and twice from her mobile, to tell her that her husband had betrayed her many times and continued to do so. One call lasted 28 minutes, another 11 minutes.
The wife, who cannot be named due to privacy laws, later decided to file a complaint and requested the examination of her phone records to trace the call.
According to a 2010 survey, half of Italians have extramarital affairs. The study by the Italian Association for Family Lawyers found that 55 per cent of men and 45 per cent of women cheat on their wives or husbands.
In around half of cases, cheating partners are found out through indiscreet mobile phone text messages, emails betray one in five and a further one in 10 are given away by anonymous letters.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:36:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Train tour to reveal North Korea's 'undiscovered cities'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc0065/sc/10/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Ctravelnews0C1172920A70CTrain0Etour0Eto0Ereveal0ENorth0EKoreas0Eundiscovered0Ecities0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A pioneering train journey through North Korea aims to offer a rare glimpse of places beyond Pyongyang</Description>
        <MainBody>Train tour to reveal North Korea's 'undiscovered cities'
A pioneering train journey through North Korea aims to offer a rare glimpse of    places beyond Pyongyang
Mount Myohyang, North KoreaPhoto: Koryo Tours
Comments
Travelling in vintage 1970s train carriages with dining cars and beds, visitors on a pioneering rail journey through North Korea will travel to places very rarely seen by foreigners.
Passengers on the Eastern Adventure by Rail trip, run by Koryo Tours, a Beijing-based operator that specialises in holidays to North Korea, will venture to "as yet undiscovered cities including Sinpho and Kimchaek, while seeing remote beaches.
 In pictures: a fascinating view of everyday life in North Korea
Visitors will take the inaugural train ride to Mount Myohyang, known for its fresh air, from Pyongyang, and visit the areas main attraction, the International Friendship Exhibition, which houses all the gifts presented to the countrys former leaders Kim Il Sung and Kim Jong Il through the years by various world figures.
The train on which tourists to North Korea will travel (Photo: Koryo Tours)
Travellers on the tour will be the first foreigners to experience a local tram ride in Chongjin, North Koreas third largest city, where the tour includes a visit to the Foodstuffs Factory, said to provide "fascinating insight into the production of consumer goods. Guests then before board an overnight charter train for Wonsan, a coastal city that is "frozen in time" and home to socialist buildings and public spaces from the 1970s and 1980s.
 Incredible timelapse video of Pyongyang
The tour of Wonsan includes visits to the small hotel where Kim Il Sung once stayed and the Old Railway Station from where he departed on his return to Pyongyang after the countrys liberation from Japanese rule in 1945. The journey back to the capital from Wonsan will pass waterfalls, lakes and "quiet local settlements", while glimpsing the towns of Yangdok and Sinyang.
A local village outside Pyongyang (Photo: Koryo Tours)
The 11-day rail tour, which runs from October 2 at 2,890 per person, will be the second time foreign tourists have been allowed to travel on this itinerary in North Korea, after the operator's first trip last year. This followed several years of requests made to the North Korean government for permission to operate the tour. A train service between Pyongyang and Beijing has already been available to tourists for several years.
"But this year's tour will include more unseen places," Simon Cockerell, general manager of Koryo Tours, told CNN .
Chongjn, North Korea (photo: Koryo Tours)
"Pyongyang has been developing in recent years, with lots of shiny new buildings [being built]," Mr Cockerell said.
"Chongjin plans to do the same too, but it hasn't so it's more like what lots of tourists would expect Pyongyang, or North Korea, to be like," he added.
A bus outside a railway station in Pyongyang (Photo: Koryo Tours)
The notoriously reclusive nation lifted a four-month ban this March preventing foreign tourists from crossing its borders over fears that the Ebola virus might enter the country.
The Beijing-based tour operator Young Pioneer Tours is running the first dedicated beach holidays to stretches of sand at Wonsan, Kumgang and Hamhung , which the tour operator described as stunning and gorgeous. The trip, which also takes in Pyongyang and the Korean Demilitarised Zone (DMZ), is recommended for North Korea veterans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:24:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Son says father was tricked into going to Syria with Islamic State</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fc0066/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Csyria0C117294720CSon0Esays0Efather0Ewas0Etricked0Einto0Egoing0Eto0ESyria0Ewith0EIslamic0EState0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Shalim Hussain, whose father is in Syria with IS along with his family, says Muhammed Abdul Mannan was tricked into going and doesn't want to be there</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria
Son says father was tricked into going to Syria with Islamic State
Shalim Hussain, whose father is in Syria with IS along with his family, says    Muhammed Abdul Mannan was tricked into going and doesn't want to be there
By Charlotte Krol, video source ITN / ITV    News
5:24PM BST 09 Jul 2015
The son of man "tricked" into joining the Islamic State in Syria has revealed he is being held against his will.
In an exclusive interview with ITV News , Shalim Hussain said his father, Muhammed Abdul Mannan, 75, had been forced to get into a van by a group of men in Istanbul, later finding himself in Syria.
Mr Mannan was also with his wife and 10 other members of their family, who are from Luton. They have not been seen since leaving for a trip to Bangladesh in May.
Mr Hussain said his father had been crying down the phone from Syria.
"My Dad is confused, sad, crying every day - [he's] not in peace", he said.
A picture purporting to show Mr Mannan in Syria emerged on social media last week.
Shalim Hussain speaking to ITV News
IS claimed the family were "safer than ever" now they had joined the terror group.
Mr Hussain explained the family were in Istanbul when a group of men came to their hotel room to check their passports before taking them downstairs one by one.
The men then told the grandfather and his wife to leave their children and grandchildren behind and go home to Britain , but when they refused to leave Mr Hussain claimed the men threw the pair into two cars.
A police-issued photo of the family (back row left - right) Rajia Khanom, 21, Mohammed Toufique Hussain, 19, Mohammed Saleh Hussain, 26, Roshanara Begum, 24, Sheida Khanam, 27, (front row left -right) Muhammed Abdul Mannan, 75, and Minera Khatun, 53 (Bedfordshire Police)
Insisting that no one from his family has become radicalised or had plans to flee to Syria, Mr Hussain made an emotional appeal for their return.
"Please come back. We're missing you badly, all of you.
"It's such a bad feeling, I can't describe, it's like something empty in the heart...something really missing.
"We all miss them, we're all lost without them."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:18:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Israeli 'Pop Idol' jailed for hacking Madonna emails and selling demo tracks</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fb2610/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Cisrael0C117294870CFormer0EIsraeli0EPop0EIdol0Ejailed0Efor0Ehacking0EMadonna0Eemails0Eand0Eselling0Edemo0Etracks0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Adi Lederman also fined 15,000 shekels (2,600) after confessing to hacking and selling demo tracks from Madonna's album "Rebel Heart"</Description>
        <MainBody>Israel
Former Israeli 'Pop Idol' jailed for hacking Madonna emails and selling demo tracks
Adi Lederman also fined 15,000 shekels (2,600) after confessing to hacking    and selling demo tracks from Madonna's album "Rebel Heart"
The demo tracks were stolen from global star Madonna
By Nick Allen , Los Angeles
5:18PM BST 09 Jul 2015
Follow
A former reality talent show contestant has been jailed for 14 months after hacking into computers to steal songs from Madonna 's latest album before it was released.
Adi Lederman, 39, who appeared on A Star Is Born on Israeli television, appeared in a Tel Aviv court and admitted charges of computer trespassing, and infringement of privacy and property rights.
According to the charges he "shared various files and music files copyrighted by Madonna Esther Louise Ciccone".
Lederman hacked into email servers used by Madonna's musical director Kevin Antunes, and her talent manager Guy Oseary.
That allowed him to obtain passwords which were then used to copy files from cloud accounts, according to court papers..
Adi Lederman
He then sold tracks from the album Rebel Heart to two buyers for $300 each before it was released.
Lederman was also able to obtained parts of Madonna's work diary.
He was arrested in January following an investigation by the FBI. The album was released to the public in March.
In a statement Tel Aviv Magistrates Court said: "The ease with which crimes such as this can be committed by those who have skills in the field, such as the accused, require an appropriate punitive response that has a deterrent and uncompromising message."
A lawyer for Lederman told the court he was "not someone with a criminal mentality, but rather, a very fired-up and impassioned collector who went too far".
Unfinished tracks from Rebel Heart had also leaked online a month before Lederman was arrested.
Madonna has previously described the crime as an "invasion into my life creatively, professionally and personally".
She said it "remains a deeply devastating and hurtful experience".
Speaking earlier this year, she said: "I am profoundly grateful to the FBI, the Israeli police investigators and anyone else who helped lead to the arrest of this hacker."
Lederman was also fined 15,000 shekels ($4,000) and admitted the crime as part of a plea deal with prosecutors.
A Star Is Born is the Israeli version of American Idol and Lederman made a brief appearance before being voted off.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:07:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Isil militants 'kill four children' during destruction of historic Iraq church</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fb2616/sc/6/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Ciraq0C11729410A0CIsil0Emilitants0Ekill0Efour0Echildren0Eduring0Edestruction0Eof0Ehistoric0EIraq0Echurch0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Isil militants reportedly kill four children during destruction of an ancient Christian church in the Iraqi city of Mosul</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraq
Isil militants 'kill four children' during destruction of historic Iraq church
Isil militants reportedly kill four children during destruction of an ancient    Christian church in the Iraqi city of Mosul
A file photo of a member of ISIL dismantling a cross on the top of a church in Mosul, IraqPhoto: AP
By Louisa Loveluck in Cairo
5:07PM BST 09 Jul 2015
Militants from the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (Isil) reportedly killed four children this week when they destroyed an ancient Christian church in the Iraqi city of Mosul.
A spokesman for the Mosul arm of the Kurdistan Democratic Party, Saeed Mamuzini, told news website Rudaw on Thursday that the Mother of Aid church, part of the Caldean Catholic Church which stretches across Iraq and Syria, was thousands of years old.
It was not immediately clear how the children died.
The extremist groups lightning assault on Mosul last year forced many of the 60,000-strong Christian population - once one of several minorities in Sunni-majority Mosul - to flee in fear of their lives.
Their empty homes have been confiscated with the letter N for nasrani, or Christian, daubed on each gate.
Isil has also destroyed Sunni and Shia mosques, reducing huge structures to smashed rubble. The jihadists have destroyed shrines and other ancient sites across the region, labelling them as idolatrous.
Irina Bokova, head of the UN cultural agency Unesco, said last week that one fifth of Iraq's estimated 10,000 official sites had been heavily looted under Isil control. She described the damage as cultural cleansing.
As Isil consolidates its reign of fear over residents in cities across northern Iraq, forces aligned against the militants are divided over how to dislodge them.
The United States had initially urged the Iraqis to focus on reclaiming Mosul, but later changed tack, arguing for a focus on the Isil-held city of Ramadi, the capital of Sunni-majority Anbar province which extremists overran two months ago.
But Hashed al-Sha'abi, a coalition of mostly Shia militias, has been calling the shots in Anbar and have moved instead on the nearby city of Fallujah, an offensive which continued on Thursday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:07:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Republican Party tells Donald Trump to 'tone down' rhetoric on immigrants</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fb2626/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cus0Eelection0C117293850CRepublican0EParty0Etells0EDonald0ETrump0Eto0Etone0Edown0Erhetoric0Eon0Eimmigrants0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Republican leaders fear the billionaire's claim that many Mexican immigrants are rapists will hurt the party in 2016 election</Description>
        <MainBody>US Election
Republican Party tells Donald Trump to 'tone down' rhetoric on immigrants
Republican leaders fear the billionaire's claim that many Mexican immigrants    are rapists will hurt the party in 2016 election
Republican presidential candidate Donald TrumpPhoto: Reuters
Follow
The head of the Republican Party has asked Donald Trump to "tone it down" amid fears that the billionaire's claim that many Mexican immigrants are rapists will damage the party's hopes of taking back the White House.
Reince Preibus, the chair of the Republican National Committee, called Mr Trump this week and cautioned him that his outbursts were enraging Hispanic voters and could hurt the party's other candidates, according to the Washington Post .
The business mogul seems to have largely ignored the message and continued to insist in interviews that illegal immigrants "are causing tremendous problems in terms of crime, in terms of murder, in terms of rape".
He also denied Mr Preibus asked him to rein in his rhetoric. "He called me, ten minutes, said I hit a 'nerve', doing well, end!" he said on Twitter.
Totally false reporting on my call with @Reince Priebus. He called me, ten minutes, said I hit a nerve", doing well, end!
 Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) July 9, 2015
While Mr Trump's immigration comments are not hurting him in the polls  some surveys put him second only to Jeb Bush  they have alienated many of his business partners who no longer wish to be associated with him.
The latest to cut ties is Jos Andrs, a Spanish-born celebrity chef who has backed out of an agreement to open a restaurant in Mr Trump's new hotel down the street from the White House.
"Donald Trumps recent statements disparaging immigrants make it impossible for my company and I to move forward," Mr Andrs said.
The Trump business empire responded to the decision the same way it has to other business partners: with threats of a lawsuit.
Mr Trump is already suing Univision , the Spanish-language television network, after it dropped its coverage of his Miss Universe beauty pageant. He has also threatened to sue NBC for the same reason .
While the 69-year-old has angered many fellow Republicans with his outbursts, he seems to be enjoying his time in the spotlight and is regularly summoning US television networks to his Trump Tower headquarters in New York for interviews.
In an interview with NBC, he insisted he has "a great relationship with the Mexican people".
"They love me, I love them," Mr Trump said, before insisting that Latinos would vote for him despite his comments. "I'll tell you something, if I get the nomination, I'll win the Latino vote," he said.
There are around 11 million illegal immigrants, also known as undocumented migrants, in the US and they pose a policy quandary for both Democrats and Republicans.
They are too many to be deported and some have been in the US for decades, working in jobs, paying taxes and raising American children.
Many legal Latino immigrants have family members who are in the US illegally and would use their votes to punish candidates who demonise their community.
Hillary Clinton and most Democrats support a "pathway to citizenship" under which illegal immigrants could come out of the shadows and begin a process to eventually become US citizens.
Republicans are divided on the question of citizenship and most emphasise a massive deployment of resources to stop new immigrants coming across the 2,000 mile US-Mexico border.
Mr Trump's own solution is to build a wall, which he says he would force the Mexican government to pay for, but he has not said what he would do with people already in the US.
"I would do something very, very strong," he told CNN. "We have to build a wall, a real wall. Not a wall that people walk through."
While he is determined to keep illegal immigrants out of the US, he appears to have failed to keep them out of his own construction sites.
Several workers building Mr Trump's new hotel told the Washington Post they were in the country illegally.
He also settled a lawsuit in 1999 which accused him of hiring undocumented Polish workers to help build his headquarters. The workers claimed they were paid $5 (3.24 an hour) and forced to work 12-hour shifts, seven days a week.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:01:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Foreign rabbit furs for Australia's famous Akubra hats</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fb262f/sc/32/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Caustralia0C117294210CForeign0Erabbit0Efurs0Efor0EAustralias0Efamous0EAkubra0Ehats0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Akubra decision to only use foreign rabbit skins to create hats leads Australian MP to declare himself "hopping mad"</Description>
        <MainBody>Australia
Foreign rabbit furs for Australia's famous Akubra hats
Akubra decision to only use foreign rabbit skins to create hats leads    Australian MP to declare himself "hopping mad"
Distinctive Australian MP Bob Katter is said to be "hopping mad" at the decisionPhoto: AP
By Flynn Murphy, Sydney
5:01PM BST 09 Jul 2015
An Australian politician has threatened to ditch his trademark Akubra hat after the company announced it would only use foreign rabbit skins.
Bob Katter, a longstanding Queensland country MP who has previously labelled himself an "economic nationalist", said he was "hopping mad over Akubra's decision" in a press statement on Thursday.
Were going to be a bunch of bunnies if we keep voting for people that are enforcing this paradigm upon us where we buy everything from overseas," Mr Katter said, lamenting the high value of the Australian dollar and "interest rates 1000 per cent higher than the rest of the world".
We are having discussions with Akubra and Ive made it quite clear to them, that of course you can get some rabbit fur in Australia."
"If you cant find them in Australia, Ill eat my hat."
Akubra chief financial officer Roy Wilkinson said the company had to cut its rabbit skin processing operation and import processed furs in order to stay in business.
"When your operation is losing money, you have to make a decision in the best interests of your total operation," he told the ABC.
The iconic Australian hat-maker will now only use imported European rabbit skins.
"We dont want to change hat brands, but we are not going to be wearing hats made out of foreign product, Mr Katter said.
Mr Katter is no stranger to stunts. In 2009 he wheeled a barrow full of bananas into Australia's Parliament House to protest the government's decision to import the fruit from the Philippines. Mr Katter's staff dressed as bananas for the occasion.
And in 2011 Mr Katter auctioned one of his Akubras for almost $3000 in support of his "longstanding and unwavering support for marriage between a man and a woman".
"We can't get the heteros to marry these days and now you are telling us you are going to let the other mob to marry -- not likely," Mr Katter said then, arguing gay marriage would contribute to what he called the "collapse of the 'pair bond'" in western societies.
In 2004 Mr Katter sensationally revealed that he was one of the men who pelted the Beatles with eggs during their 1964 Australian tour, ending a 40 year mystery.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:57:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Srebrenica 20 years on: What have been the successes and failures of UN peacekeeping missions?</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47fb2630/sc/6/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cbosnia0C117294360CSrebrenica0E20A0Eyears0Eon0EWhat0Ehave0Ebeen0Ethe0Esuccesses0Eand0Efailures0Eof0EUN0Epeacekeeping0Emissions0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>1995 massacre of more than 8,000 Bosnian Muslim men in Srebrenica was a notable failure of the UN peacekeeping operation</Description>
        <MainBody>Bosnia
Srebrenica 20 years on: What have been the successes and failures of UN peacekeeping missions?
1995 massacre of more than 8,000 Bosnian Muslim men in Srebrenica was a    notable failure of the UN peacekeeping operation
By Barney Henderson , New York and graphic by Sam Dodge
4:57PM BST 09 Jul 2015
Follow
United Nations peacekeeping operations began in 1948 and the light blue helmets and berets have been deployed to many of the world's trouble spot from Papua New Guinea to Haiti ever since, with varying levels of effectiveness.
An internal UN study last year found that UN peacekeeping missions routinely avoid using force to protect civilians who are under attack, intervening in only 20 per cent of cases despite being authorised to do so by the UN Security Council.
While some peacekeeping missions perform adequately, others have failed to protect civilians  notably at Srebrenica, where Dutch peacekeepers watched on powerless as thousands of men were murdered.
Of the 69 UN peacekeeping missions over the past 68 years, there have been some notable failures  and cases of successful intervention.
Where peacekeepers have succeeded - and failed
Srebrenica
On July 11, 1995, towards the end of Bosnia's 1992-95 war, Bosnian Serb forces swept into the eastern Srebrenica enclave and executed 8,000 Muslim men and boys in the days that followed, dumping their bodies into pits. It was the worst massacre in post-Second World War European history. The UN had previously declared the town one of the safe areas, to be "free from any armed attack or any other hostile act". 600 Dutch infantry were supposed to be protecting thousands of civilians who had taken refuge from earlier Serb offensives in north-eastern Bosnia.
As Serb forces began shelling Srebrenica, Bosnian Muslim fighters in the town asked for the return of weapons they had surrendered to the UN peacekeepers but their request was refused. The Dutch peacekeepers were obliged to watch as the killings began. The failure led in part to the creation of the United Nations Peacebuilding Commission and set the West on a new course of 'liberal interventionism'.
Potocari memorial, Srebrenica, Bosnia and Hercegovina
Rwanda
Another major failing of the UN peacekeeping organisation was not doing more to prevent the 1994 Rwandan genocide that left up to one million people dead. A 1999 inquiry found that the UN ignored evidence that the genocide was planned and refused to act once it had started. More than 2,500 UN peacekeepers were withdrawn after the murder of ten Belgian soldiers. In one case, the peacekeeping forces deserted a school where Tutsis were taking shelter  hundreds of people inside were immediately massacred.
Kofi Annan, who was then head of UN peacekeeping forces was accused of failing to pass on warnings of the massacre. UN soldiers did not return to Rwanda until June, by which time hundreds of thousands of people were dead. The UN was accused of leaving Rwanda to its fate.
Somalia
The UN operation was the first time the peacekeeping force had been used for humanitarian intervention. However, the peacekeepers were met with a hostile reception in Mogadishu. Several of them were killed and the bodies of dead US soldiers were paraded through the streets on the orders of the Somali warlords.
When an American Black Hawk helicopter was shot down as part of the Battle of Mogadishu, the US withdrew its troops. In 1995 the UN withdrew all peacekeeping troops. It was described at the time by one UN official as "the greatest failure of the UN in our lifetime".
Sierra Leone
The UN peacekeeping force that operated in Sierra Leone from 1999 to 2005 is hailed as a success. It was created to help implement a peace agreement after the countrys devastating civil war.
Mr Ban officially closed the UN offices in Freetown in 2014, declaring a successful conclusion to the organisations work in helping to bring peace to the country, calling it a triumph for the people of Sierra Leone after what had been a decade of warfare. Our blue helmets disarmed more than 75 000 ex-fighters, including hundreds of child soldiers. The UN destroyed more than 42,000 weapons and 1.2 million rounds of ammunition  a potentially deadly arsenal that is now itself dead, Mr Ban declared.
Burundi
Burundi is also frequently cited as a success story for the UN peacekeeping operation, helping it recover from decades of ethnic war. Ban Ki-moon, UN secretary-general, hailed Burundi's substantial progress, overcoming formidable challenges since the end of the civil war. But in 2014 he extended the peacekeeping mission for a year to help the country through elections, that took place earlier in July, and cautioned that the gains made under the UNs watch were not irreversible.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:47:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictures of the day: 9 July 2015</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47f69126/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cpicturesoftheday0C117275440CPictures0Eof0Ethe0Eday0E90EJuly0E20A150Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Underwater basil, a gull stealing a fish and the Pope in South America</Description>
        <MainBody>These elephants knew exactly how to cool off in the hot weather. Splashing around in the water together, the young elephants, Bala and Hari, both 2 years old, enjoyed a bath at Chester Zoo.Picture: Caters

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
