<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>FBI says it thwarted Islamic State-inspired July 4 attacks</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/FBI-says-arrested-10-in-July-4-plots-inspired-by-Islamic-State</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. authorities foiled attacks planned around the Fourth of July, arresting more than 10 people in the month before the holiday who were inspired by Islamic State online recruitment, FBI Director James Comey said on Thursday. </Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. authorities foiled attacks planned around the Fourth of July, arresting more than 10 people in the month before the holiday who were inspired by Islamic State online recruitment, FBI Director James Comey said on Thursday.
"I do believe our work disrupted efforts to kill people likely in connection with July 4th," Comey told reporters at the headquarters of the Federal Bureau of Investigation. He did not detail the number of plots uncovered or their targets.
Separately, a national security source said multiple overseas plots by Islamic State sympathizers had also been halted in recent days.
The FBI and the U.S. Department of Homeland Security had warned local law enforcement to be on alert for attacks around the July 4 holiday celebrating the 1776 U.S. Declaration of Independence. No such attacks occurred.
Authorities' concern heightened around the holiday as Islamic State leaders called for followers to do what they could wherever they could to carry out violence on behalf of the militant group.
Comey described the tactic as "crowdsourcing terrorism" and said the FBI had accepted the heightened state as the "new normal."
Some of those arrested were communicating with Islamic State via encrypted data, a second U.S. security source said.
The FBI has pressured tech companies to remove encryption that gives users privacy protections that cannot be broken by law enforcement.
Comey estimated that dozens of people influenced by Islamic State have "gone dark" and disappeared from the FBI's watch because of encrypted data.
The United States is engaged in a military campaign with allies in the Middle East to fight Islamic State militants who have taken over parts of Iraq and Syria and created cells in other countries racked by conflict in the region.
(Reporting by Julia Edwards and Mark Hosenball; Writing by Julia Edwards; Editing by Doina Chiacu and Howard Goller)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>France urges Greek &amp;#34;responsibility&amp;#34; in return for EU solidarity</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/Merkel-again-rules-out-haircut-on-Greek-debt</Link>
        <Description>(Reuters) - Following is the latest news on Greece&amp;#39;s debt crisis after euro zone leaders set Athens a deadline of the end of the week to come up with convincing reform proposals. All times are in GMT.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:40:05 AM
Updated:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:40:05 AM
France urges Greek "responsibility" in return for EU solidarity
to win cash or gadget!
(Reuters) - Following is the latest news on Greece's debt crisis after euro zone leaders set Athens a deadline of the end of the week to come up with convincing reform proposals. All times are in GMT.
1420 - Political talks over Greece must produce strong outcome on Sunday for the European Central Bank to provide continued support, ECB's Ewald Novotny says.
1404 - Only "very low" leeway to reprofile Greece's debt, German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble says.
1351 - French Finance Minister Michel Sapin says Greece leaving the euro zone would damage the credibility of the currency bloc but so too would Greece staying while it continuously violates its financial obligations.
1316 - Germany's Schaeuble says Greece needs to deliver on concrete prior actions to gain European financial support, adding that it is difficult to see such steps being taken before Sunday.
1304 - The IMF's chief economist, Olivier Blanchard, says Greece is a small part of the world economy and its possible exit from the euro zone should have limited impact on the rest of the world. However, he warns that similar crises could happen in other countries.
1301 - Europe must build common tools to fight crises and needs to strike a balance between fiscal discipline and growth to reduce the risk of future turmoil, French Finance Minister Michel Sapin says.
1203 - German Chancellor Angela Merkel reiterates that a so-called "haircut" on Europe's loans to Greece is out of the question.
1152 - The chances of Greece leaving the euro zone this year have fallen, according to the betting odds of bookmakers Paddy Power and William Hill, three days before the deadline for a comprehensive deal.
1014 - European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker will meet members of Greece's opposition parties on Thursday and Friday in Brussels as all sides seek a weekend deal to avert a Greek bankruptcy, a Commission spokesman says.
1009 - The head of the European Council, Donald Tusk, says the EU's national parliaments have to be persuaded to vote in favour of helping Greece if European leaders reach a good agreement on Sunday. Tusk says a deal on debt should be part of the agreement.
1005 - Bulgarian Economy Minister Bozhidar Lukarski is quoted as saying Greek-owned banks in the Balkan country are "under controls" to prevent funds being sent to Greece. More than a fifth of Bulgaria's banks are Greek-owned.
0944 - Irish Finance Minister Michael Noonan says he sees a better than 50 percent chance of Greece reaching a deal with its creditors by a weekend deadline following a "distinct change of mood"
0830 - The chief executive officer of Greece's natural gas company, DEPA, says the utility can guarantee the unobstructed supply of gas supplies in the country
0745 - Greek Energy Minister Panagiotis Lafazanis, leader of the far-left flank of the ruling Syriza party, says he expects an aid deal with creditors "soon" but he opposes a third bailout with tough austerity measures that would stifle growth
0733 - ECB is ready to implement a range of "non-standard" monetary policy measures if Greece leaves the euro zone, Governing Council member Ardo Hansson tells an Estonian newspaper
0714 - Greece's stock exchange will remain closed until July 13, the country's Capital Markets Commission says, after authorities decide to extend a bank holiday and capital controls
0700 - The head of Germany's Bundesbank, Jens Weidmann, says capital controls in Greece should remain in place until a new bailout programme has been agreed. He also says no further central bank liquidity support should be given to its banks
0634 - Greece is planning a reform package worth 12 billion euros over two years, more than previously planned, to offset a return to recession after months of difficult negotiations with creditors, the Greek daily Kathimerini reports.
0549 - ECB President Mario Draghi says will be "really difficult" to end the Greek crisis and save the country from bankruptcy, in comments made to Italian financial daily Il Sole 24 Ore.
0535 - Greek government spokesman Gabriel Sakellaridis says Athens is confident it can clinch a deal with international creditors which can be approved by the country's parliament.
0519 - The head of the Greek bank association, Louka Katselii, says Greek banks have enough liquidity in cash machines to serve the public until Monday.
0042 - Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe says will work with Group of Seven countries and other Asian countries to ensure economic and finance market stability as the euro zone grapples with Greece's debt crisis
2044 - Some large Greek banks may have to be shut and taken over by stronger rivals as part of a restructuring of the sector that would follow any bailout of the country, European officials tell Reuters
1908 - IMF chief Christine Lagarde reiterates Greece's massive debt will need restructuring, something Germany is resisting
1903 -  Greek banks will remain closed for the rest of the week and a 60-euro per day ATM withdrawal limit will remain in force, Greek state television reported
1841 - Greece's government will be encouraged to deliver a "precise plan" for its finances to inspire confidence among euro zone currency partners, says French President Francois Hollande
1800 - Fed officials need more signs of strengthening U.S. economy before raising interest rates, according to minutes of June Fed meeting, cite Greece's debt crisis as serious concern
1610 - The European Stability Mechanism asks EU experts and the IMF to review Greece's request for a loan
1607 - Luxembourg Finance Minister Pierre Gramegna tells parliament that euro zone finance ministers would ask the European Commission and European Central Bank to review Greece's bailout request
1553 - European Central Bank policy setters keep the level of emergency assistance to Greek banks steady, a person familiar with the matter says
1436 - French Prime Minister Manuel Valls says basics of a Greek deal have been laid out, a deal is within grasp
1334 - Reuters polling shows for first time economists saying Greece's exit from euro zone is more likely than not
(Compiled by Gareth Jones)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Bolivian &amp;#39;communist crucifix&amp;#39; gift to Pope surprises Vatican</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/Bolivian-communist-crucifix-gift-to-Pope-surprises-Vatican</Link>
        <Description>SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia (Reuters) - The Vatican acknowledged it was taken by surprise to discover that a wooden hammer and sickle sculpture with a figure of a crucified Christ gifted to the Pope in Bolivia was not commissioned by leftist president Evo Morales but designed by a priest killed in 1980.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:32 AM
Updated:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:32 AM
Bolivian 'communist crucifix' gift to Pope surprises Vatican
to win cash or gadget!
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia (Reuters) - The Vatican acknowledged it was taken by surprise to discover that a wooden hammer and sickle sculpture with a figure of a crucified Christ gifted to the Pope in Bolivia was not commissioned by leftist president Evo Morales but designed by a priest killed in 1980.
The blending of the symbol of communism, under which many Christians were persecuted in the former Soviet bloc and still are in some communist countries, provoked outrage among Catholic officials.
Pope Francis looked bemused when Morales, at a meeting on Wednesday night, handed him the unusual gift, a replica of the priest's sculpture. The Argentine-born pontiff is on the second stop of his tour of three of the poorest South American countries.
The general interpretation was that Morales had commissioned the design of the wooden sculpture.
"The culmination of arrogance is to manipulate God for the service of atheist ideologies," wrote Spanish bishop Jose Ignacio Munilla on Twitter, posting a photo of Francis receiving the gift.
Other Church officials and some Bolivian opposition politicians accused Morales, the country's first indigenous leader, of using the occasion to push his anti-Western views and provoke the pope.
But as the controversy flared on Wednesday night, Bolivian reporters said they recalled that the original author of the sculpture was Jesuit Father Luis Espinal Camps, a strong supporter of the rights of miners who was killed by a right-wing paramilitary squad 35 years ago.
Shortly after his arrival in La Paz, Francis stopped to pray at the site where the priest's body was dumped along a road.
"It's true. This is something Espinal did. The pope didn't know about it. I did not know about it. A lot of people didn't know about it," Vatican spokesman Father Federico Lombardi said at an unscheduled briefing on Thursday.
Lombardi, a Jesuit himself as is the pope, said Francis had not "expressed any judgement" on the sculpture, the original of which was made in a period when many Catholic priests were involved in Liberation Theology movements in defence of the poor.
Representatives of the president and the government could not be reached for comment on Thursday.
Lombardi said Bolivian Jesuits had told him the sculpture was "not a Marxist interpretation of religion but an opening to dialogue with others who were looking for justice and liberation."
"I don't think I would put this symbol on an altar in a church however," Lombardi said.
One irony of the situation was that Francis' fellow countryman, the revolutionary Ernesto "Che" Guevera, was executed by CIA-backed Bolivian troops in Bolivia in 1967.
The late Pope John Paul took a dim view of Liberation Theology, saying it was influenced by the Marxist concept of the class struggle.
During his 27-year pontificate, which ended with his death in 2005, the Vatican disciplined a number of prominent Liberation Theologians, including Brazil's Leonardo Boff.
Under Francis, Latin America's first pope, they have been somewhat rehabilitated.
Morales' strained relations with the Catholic Church have begun thawing under Francis, and he warmly embraced the pope seven years after denouncing the Church as "an instrument of domination".
(Additional reporting by Sarah Marsh and Diego Ore; Editing by Richard Lough and Grant McCool)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>New Yemeni al Qaeda leader calls for attacks on United States</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/New-Yemeni-al-Qaeda-leader-calls-for-attacks-on-United-States</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - The new leader of al Qaeda&amp;#39;s Yemen branch has called for attacks on the United States in his first speech since taking command, the U.S.-based SITE monitoring group reported on Thursday, citing an audio recording.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:30 AM
Updated:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:31 AM
New Yemeni al Qaeda leader calls for attacks on United States
to win cash or gadget!
DUBAI (Reuters) - The new leader of al Qaeda's Yemen branch has called for attacks on the United States in his first speech since taking command, the U.S.-based SITE monitoring group reported on Thursday, citing an audio recording.
Qassim al-Raymi succeeded Nasser al-Wuhayshi as military commander of Al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula (AQAP) after Wuhayshi was killed in a U.S. drone strike in Yemen's south-eastern city of Mukalla last month.
In the speech, Raymi eulogized Wuhayshi, pledged allegiance to al Qaeda leader Ayman al-Zawahri, and called for attacks on the United States, SITE said.
"All of you must direct and gather your arrows and swords against it," SITE quoted Raymi as telling Muslims in general in the 14 minute and 9 second recording.
"God has helped you against this enemy, for not only did you reach its home, but with praise to God and His grace, you have reached the depths of its heart," he added.
The authenticity of the recording, produced by AQAP's al-Malahem Media Foundation, could not immediately be verified.
Wuhayshis death was seen as a major blow to AQAP, regarded by the United States as al-Qaedas most dangerous affiliate, and to al-Qaeda more broadly.
Addressing Zawahri, he said: "I pledge allegiance to you, to listen and obey, in times of difficulty and prosperity, in hardship and in ease, to endure being discriminated against and not to dispute about rule with those in power, and to wage jihad in the cause of God the Almighty, with the Book of Allah and the Sunnah [traditions] of His Messenger, Allah's peace and blessings be upon him, as much I am able."
Raymi also congratulated a coalition of jihadi factions in Syria that include the Nusra Front for its recent success in Idlib province, and the Afghan Taliban for victories in its Azm spring offensive, SITE said.
(Reporting by Sami Aboudi; Editing by Catherine Evans)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>U.N. says Yemen&amp;#39;s warring factions agree to humanitarian truce</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/Yemen-ceasefire-announcement-within-24-hours--Houthirun-Saba-news-agency</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI/SANAA (Reuters) - Yemen&amp;#39;s warring factions confirmed their agreement on Thursday to a temporary humanitarian ceasefire set to begin on Friday night, United Nations envoy Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:27 AM
Updated:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:29 AM
U.N. says Yemen's warring factions agree to humanitarian truce
to win cash or gadget!
DUBAI/SANAA (Reuters) - Yemen's warring factions confirmed their agreement on Thursday to a temporary humanitarian ceasefire set to begin on Friday night, United Nations envoy Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed said.
The pause in the fighting will last about a week until the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan and aims to allow the delivery of assistance to some of the 21 million Yemenis in need.
The U.N. has worked intensively to broker a ceasefire to halt more than three months of many-sided fighting inside the country and Saudi-led air strikes against the Houthis and their army allies that have killed more than 3,000 people.
"For the humanitarian pause, we are going to start tomorrow evening and we have assurances from all the parties, and we are quite optimistic it will be respected," Ould Cheikh Ahmed told Reuters by phone from Ethiopia, after finishing discussions in the Houthi-held Yemeni capital Sanaa.
"We have agreed to go ahead, based on two major points. The first is the commitment of all parties not to violate this ceasefire, this humanitarian pause. The second is that humanitarian assistance can reach all parts of Yemen," he added.
Relief agencies say the fighting and a near-blockade imposed by an alliance of Arab states, aimed at stopping weapons deliveries to the Houthis, have caused a humanitarian disaster in Yemen, with over 80 percent of its 25 million people now needing some form of emergency aid.
Rights groups have also condemned local blockades by armed groups on supplies headed for war-torn civilian areas.
CHALLENGE
Yemen's president Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi, in exile in Saudi Arabia, has asked the U.N. for "guarantees" to help the truce succeed, which include prisoner releases by the Houthis and withdrawals from vast areas where it is battling local fighters.
Implementing more thorny political points, the envoy said, would not happen immediately and required more discussion, but the Houthis have released a top pro-Hadi politician in Sanaa and allowed the shipment of 50 aid trucks to the embattled southern city of Aden to buttress the truce.
A senior Western diplomat said the intensity of battles raging nationwide would render a swift calm difficult.
"It is still going to be a challenge to have this call heeded within the next 24 hours because of the entrenched fighting on the ground," the diplomat told Reuters.
News of the expected truce helped lift the Saudi stock market. The index closed 2.5 percent higher.
Saudi Arabia and an Arab coalition have been bombing the  Houthis and their allies in Yemen's army in an effort to restore Hadi and bolster armed opponents of the Iran-allied Houthis.
The Houthis, who took over the capital Sanaa last September, deny Saudi accusations that they are an Iranian proxy and describe their armed advance throughout Yemen as a revolution against a corrupt government backed by the West.
The group has previously said it welcomed any ceasefire but has yet to accept a U.N. Security Council Resolution passed in April which recognises Hadi as the legitimate president and calls on them to quit seized land.
The United States fears the turmoil will strengthen al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula, the deadliest branch of the global militant group.
AQAP's new leader Qassim al-Raymi, appointed after his predecessor was killed in U.S. drone strike last month, called for attacks on the United States in a taped speech released on Thursday.
(Additional reporting by Angus McDowall in Riyadh and Michelle Nichols at the United Nations; Editing by Andrew Roche)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Taiwan&amp;#39;s China-friendly KMT mimics Chiang Kai-shek&amp;#39;s fall from pedestal</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/Taiwans-Chinafriendly-KMT-mimics-Chiang-Kaisheks-fall-from-pedestal</Link>
        <Description>TAOYUAN, Taiwan (Reuters) - Dumped outside Chiang Kai-shek&amp;#39;s mausoleum in Taiwan are nearly 200 unwanted statues of the Nationalist Party hero, a suggestion of the punishment his party faces in January elections for pushing the self-ruled island too close to political foe China.</Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
TAOYUAN, Taiwan (Reuters) - Dumped outside Chiang Kai-shek's mausoleum in Taiwan are nearly 200 unwanted statues of the Nationalist Party hero, a suggestion of the punishment his party faces in January elections for pushing the self-ruled island too close to political foe China.
Cast in bronze and in different shades of red, brown, grey and blue, the generalissimo is saluting, holding a book, leaning on a cane, sitting regally or perched on a plinth - a peaceful if surreal gathering that belies the disarray of the party it represents.
Some statues still standing elsewhere around the island have been decapitated or defaced.
The Nationalist Party, or Kuomintang (KMT) in Chinese, is expected to be dealt a thrashing in the presidential poll by the pro-independence Democratic Progressive Party (DPP), a result likely to irritate giant neighbour China which claims the island as its own, though no one expects close economic ties to unravel.
"The KMT is in freezing winter. It will get worse before it gets better," said a party member, who spoke on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the issue.
The party has been in crisis mode since November when it lost power in local elections. The defeat paved the way for Hung Hsiu-chu to step up as its only prospective presidential candidate. But her stated intention of signing a peace treaty with China and appearing to move closer to Beijing's position of "one China", including Taiwan, has rubbed a lot of party cadres the wrong way.
In short, KMT supporters are bailing out. Campaign jockeying and factional infighting are pushing members away from a party that numbered well over a million in 2000 but is now down to about 890,000, with only about a third of them active.
Mainstream public opinion on the island is in favour of maintaining the status quo with China, which is a key campaign message from DPP presidential hopeful Tsai Ing-wen. Economic ties, while seen as imbalanced in favour of China, won't be rolled back however distant the prospect of political talks.
Beijing, for instance, insists Taiwan can be ruled under the "one country, two systems" formula under which Hong Kong, a former British colony, returned to Chinese rule in 1997. Both the DPP and KMT reject this model, which prompted unprecedented pro-democracy protests in Hong Kong last year, blocking streets for months.
SLOWING GROWTH, STAGNANT WAGES
Chiang remains a hero for some in Taiwan, and even in China he is looked upon with increasing favour in certain quarters, despite his forced flight to Taiwan in 1949 with the remains of his Republic of China government after the Communists won the Chinese civil war.
Chiang died in 1975. China continues to claim Taiwan as its territory, and has never renounced the use of force to bring the now proudly democratic island under its control.
Late last month, legislator Chang Sho-wen publicly quit the KMT. Another member, Hsu Hsin-ying, left the party after last year's local election loss which forced President Ma Ying-jeou to resign as party chief.
The election result was seen as a vote against Ma's China-friendly policies. Democratically minded young and middle-class Taiwanese, unhappy with slowing economic growth and stagnant wages, remain suspicious of China's intentions and see only big business prospering from closer ties.
"The history of the KMT, of Chiang, has been diluted," said Hsu Wen-long, 50, whose father, a KMT soldier, fled to Taiwan with the generalissimo. When Hsu was young, children were taught it was a fight for survival between the KMT and the Communists. That is not the case with the younger generation.
"What you learn in your early years stays with you for a lifetime," Hsu said.
The hundreds of twenty-somethings who occupied parliament last year to stop a trade pact that would bring the island even closer to China were at primary school under the last DPP rule.
But some Nationalists argue that stronger ties with China will help prevent Beijing from taking control any way it wants.
"If the KMT should become weak or split up, there will be no checks and balances against the DPP," said Nationalist Justin Chen. "If in Taiwan society there doesn't exist a voice of unification, then China's Communist Party will reach its hand directly into this island. That is a different stage of confrontation."
As for those busts and statues, the DPP's Chen Shui-bian ordered them to be taken down from public display and sent to the wooded, lakeside park in Taoyuan when he was president between 2000 and 2008.
As late as last year, they were still being delivered.
(Editing by Nick Macfie)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Moniz to leave Iran talks temporarily, returns Friday evening</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/Moniz-to-leave-Iran-talks-temporarily-returns-Friday-evening</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. Energy Secretary Ernest Moniz will temporarily leave the Iran nuclear talks to accept an honour in Portugal and will return to the negotiations on Friday evening, a senior U.S. official said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:12 AM
Updated:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:13 AM
Moniz to leave Iran talks temporarily, returns Friday evening
to win cash or gadget!
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. Energy Secretary Ernest Moniz will temporarily leave the Iran nuclear talks to accept an honour in Portugal and will return to the negotiations on Friday evening, a senior U.S. official said on Thursday.
The official said Moniz would leave Vienna on Friday for  Lisbon where he will receive the Grand Cross of the Order of Prince Henry, meet his Portuguese counterpart to talk about energy and climate change and give a keynote address at a green growth conference. He will return to Vienna the same evening.
(Reporting By Arshad Mohammed; editing by John Irish)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Austria to send hundreds of homeless asylum seekers to Slovakia</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/Austria-to-send-hundreds-of-homeless-seekers-to-Slovakia</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - Austria is sending around 500 asylum seekers to Slovakia to relieve pressure on its Vienna refugee arrival centre, where 1,200 people are having to sleep outside, Austria&amp;#39;s interior ministry spokesman said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:08 AM
Updated:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:08 AM
Austria to send hundreds of homeless asylum seekers to Slovakia
to win cash or gadget!
VIENNA (Reuters) - Austria is sending around 500 asylum seekers to Slovakia to relieve pressure on its Vienna refugee arrival centre, where 1,200 people are having to sleep outside, Austria's interior ministry spokesman said.
The number of migrants seeking protection in the EU soared by 68 percent in the first five months of 2015 from a year earlier, the bloc said this month.
Many heading further north get stuck in countries like Italy or Austria and Vienna has demanded strict quotas to distribute migrants across a wider range of European Union states. It has been battling with its own provinces which for months have refused to fulfil domestic quotas for hosting refugees.
Austria's interior ministry said up to 500 asylum seekers would move in gradual stages to a former university building in the Slovak town of Gabcikovo by the end of September. Their asylum requests will continue to be processed in Austria, a spokesman for the interior ministry in Vienna said on Thursday.
Slovak Interior minister Robert Kalinak told public broadcaster ORF that pressure on Austria's asylum system was high and Slovakia stood ready to help.
Pictures of migrants wrapped in blankets sleeping on the grass outside Vienna's Traiskirchen asylum processing centre in Austrian media have caused an outcry on social media and human rights groups. (This version of the story was updated to add dropped word 'asylum' to headline)
(Reporting by Shadia Nasralla; Editing by Ruth Pitchford)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Iranian official accuses big powers of changing their stance</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/Iranian-official-accuses-big-powers-of-changing-their-stance</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - A senior Iranian official on Thursday accused the United States and other major powers of changing their positions in the nuclear talks with Tehran aimed at ending over a decade-old standoff with the country over its disputed nuclear programme.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:08 AM
Updated:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:11 AM
Iranian official accuses big powers of changing their stance
to win cash or gadget!
VIENNA (Reuters) - A senior Iranian official on Thursday accused the United States and other major powers of changing their positions in the nuclear talks with Tehran aimed at ending over a decade-old standoff with the country over its disputed nuclear programme.
The official, who spoke to reporters on condition of anonymity, also said some in the talks are walking back from an interim agreement that was made in April in the Swiss city of Lausanne between Iran and the major powers.
The official said Iran was looking forward to seeing whether the United States was prepared to abandon its "obsession with sanctions", reiterating the need for removal of the U.N. arms embargo on Iran.
(Reporting By Arshad Mohammed)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>EU sets July 20 deadline to reach deal on migration</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/10/EU-sets-July-20-deadline-to-reach-deal-on-migration</Link>
        <Description>LUXEMBOURG (Reuters) - The European Union failed on Thursday to reach a deal to resolve a migration crisis in the Mediterranean, and instead set a deadline of July 20 to reach an agreement on how to redistribute 40,000 asylum seekers currently in Italy and Greece.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:06 AM
Updated:                 Friday July 10, 2015 MYT 5:30:06 AM
EU sets July 20 deadline to reach deal on migration
to win cash or gadget!
LUXEMBOURG (Reuters) - The European Union failed on Thursday to reach a deal to resolve a migration crisis in the Mediterranean, and instead set a deadline of July 20 to reach an agreement on how to redistribute 40,000 asylum seekers currently in Italy and Greece.
"We made progress but we are not there yet," Dimitris Avramopoulos, the European Commissioner responsible for migration, told reporters after a meeting of European interior ministers in Luxembourg.
The European Commission, the EU's executive arm, proposed in May to relocate 60,000 refugees over the next two years. Two-thirds of them would be sent from Italy and Greece to other EU states, while the remaining 20,000 would be resettled directly from their countries of origin or transit.
Germany and France announced on Thursday that they would jointly take in more than 20,000 refugees in the next two years.
Poland said it would take 2,000.
Several other EU countries made commitments, diplomats said, but did not disclose figures, while Austria, Slovakia and Spain refused to make formal pledges.
"We made progress, but some countries will only give precise numbers in the coming days," France's Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said on the sidelines of the meeting.
Another ministerial meeting has been called for July 20 in Brussels to seek a definitive deal, Luxembourg Foreign and Immigration Minister Jean Asselborn told reporters.
National pledges are already "more than enough" to cover the proposed figure of 20,000 refugees to be resettled from their original countries, Asselborn said.
The difficulty is in sharing out the 40,000 asylum seekers from Italy and Greece.
Britain and Denmark have declined to participate in the relocation plan for these people, although they are taking part in the resettlement of the 20,000.
More than 135,000 migrants arrived in Europe by sea in the first half of 2015, mostly landing in the two Mediterranean countries of Italy and Greece, according to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees.
The EU envisages stricter controls on arriving migrants to identify them and return them to their countries of origin if they cannot claim asylum in Europe.
A new EU-monitored facility to register migrants will be set up in Italy next week to improve the identification process and prevent migrants from moving to other EU countries to claim asylum.
(Editing by Barbara Lewis, Catherine Evans, Toni Reinhold)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
