<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Times of India">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:37:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK stunned by scale of child sex abuse: Judge</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fc2a88/sc/3/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CUK0Estunned0Eby0Escale0Eof0Echild0Esex0Eabuse0EJudge0Carticleshow0C480A0A94560Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A judge says Britain has been stunned by revelations about child sexual abuse, warning that the true scale of the crime has been underestimated and one in 20 children may have been a victim.</Description>
        <MainBody>A judge says Britain has been stunned by revelations about child sexual abuse. (An undated handout file photo of Justice Lowell Goddard/AP photo)
RELATED
LONDON: A judge says Britain has been stunned by revelations about child sexual abuse , warning that the true scale of the crime has been underestimated and one in 20 children may have been a victim.
Justice Lowell Goddard opened a public inquiry into decades of abuse on Thursday, vowing that "no one, no matter how apparently powerful, will be allowed to obstruct our inquiries."
READ ALSO: UK probing who's who for child abuse
In the past few years, revelations of abuse have implicated taxi drivers, entertainers, clergy, senior politicians and others. There have been claims that police failed to investigate allegations of abuse for decades.
Goddard, a New Zealand judge, was appointed earlier this year to head an inquiry into how public agencies  including government bodies, police, hospitals, churches and the BBC  handled child-abuse allegations.
READ ALSO: Singer's daughter jailed in UK for sex with minor
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=UK sex abuse,UK,Justice Lowell Goddard,child sex abuse in UK,child sex abuse
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:54:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protests in Ghana over increasing cost of living</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fbd744/sc/24/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CProtests0Ein0EGhana0Eover0Eincreasing0Ecost0Eof0Eliving0Carticleshow0C480A0A88530Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of workers took to the streets in Ghana on Thursday to protest against the increased cost of living as union leaders warned the country's economic woes were reaching a crisis point.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
Protests in Ghana over increasing cost of living
AFP | Jul 9, 2015, 10.24 PM IST
Hundreds of workers took to the streets in Ghana on Thursday to protest against the increased cost of living as union leaders warned the country's economic woes were reaching a crisis point. (Picture source: Twitter)
RELATED
TEMA, GHANA: Hundreds of workers took to the streets in Ghana on Thursday to protest against the increased cost of living as union leaders warned the country's economic woes were reaching a crisis point.
Protesters in the industrial city of Tema, 25 kilometres (16 miles) east of Accra, demonstrated over rising prices of goods and services which they said were not being matched by wage increases.
A yawning public sector deficit, a falling local currency and high inflation have heaped pressure on Ghana, which until recent years was seen as a promising emerging economy.
In February, the government in Accra turned to the International Monetary Fund for a $918 million loan package to stabilise the economy and ease debt pressure.
"The economic meltdown began way back three years ago. Gradually it's getting to a crescendo," Solomon Kotei, general secretary of the Industrial and Commercial Union of Ghana, told AFP.
Among the protestors complaints was the removal of subsidies on fuel and increased taxation, forcing belts to be tightened and complaints about poor service in return.
Lack of electricity has been a growing problem, with power cuts lasting sometimes up to a day at a time and hitting economic activity.
"Ghanaians are paying the full brunt of these things. However, our salaries are not actually getting commensurate with all these things, so pressure is coming on the meagre salaries," said Kotei.
Ghana has been seen as the rising star in West Africa, with a strong democratic record as well as solid exports in gold, cocoa and, since 2010, oil.
But President John Dramani Mahama has been accused of not doing enough to sustain economic growth and the cedi slumped against the US dollar in the last year.
Mahama has been urged to cut wasteful public spending, including "ghost workers" in the public sector, lower deficits and pay down debts.
On June 30, the IMF said the fund's financial and economic programme was largely "on track" and growth was expected to remain about 3.5 per cent this year.
Increasing electricity production would be critical to improve growth in 2016, it added.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Industrial and Commercial Union of Ghana,increasing cost of living in Ghana,demonstration in Ghana
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:27:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canada's Bellegarde calls for recognition of native languages</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fbd746/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CCanadas0EBellegarde0Ecalls0Efor0Erecognition0Eof0Enative0Elanguages0Carticleshow0C480A0A83550Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Canadian First Nations national chief Perry Bellegarde called Thursday for the government to recognize more than 60 indigenous languages he dubbed "national treasures," alongside the country's official French and English.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
Canada's Bellegarde calls for recognition of native languages
AFP | Jul 9, 2015, 09.57 PM IST
Canadian First Nations national chief PerryBellegarde. (Picture source: Twitter)
RELATED
MONTREAL: Canadian First Nations national chief Perry Bellegarde called Thursday for the government to recognize more than 60 indigenous languages he dubbed "national treasures," alongside the country's official French and English.
Bellegarde heads Canada's assembly of First Nations, which advocates for the array of indigenous people in the country.
There are 1.4 million aboriginal people, some 4.3 per cent of the Canadian population, but their languages are not officially recognized by the federal government.
"There has basically been a killing of the languages in Canada," by compulsory education in French and English in native communities, Bellegarde said in an interview with The Globe and Mail newspaper.
"Our languages should be looked upon as national jewels, national treasures," he said.
A 2011 census found more than 60 indigenous languages in 12 major language families.
Bellegarde called for the government to set aside funding for the preservation of the languages of the country's first inhabitants.
Bellegarde suggested the funding could create a national institute to help preserve and teach the languages, many of which are only spoken by a small number of older people.
Bellegarde said the "ultimate goal" would be for the languages to be printed alongside French and English.
"But let's do small steps to get there."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Perry Bellegarde,Canadian languages
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:27:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canada chief calls for recognition of native languages</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fb6f8a/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CCanada0Echief0Ecalls0Efor0Erecognition0Eof0Enative0Elanguages0Carticleshow0C480A0A83550Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Canadian First Nations national chief Perry Bellegarde called Thursday for the government to recognize more than 60 indigenous languages he dubbed "national treasures," alongside the country's official French and English.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
Canada's Bellegarde calls for recognition of native languages
AFP | Jul 9, 2015, 09.57 PM IST
Canadian First Nations national chief PerryBellegarde. (Picture source: Twitter)
RELATED
MONTREAL: Canadian First Nations national chief Perry Bellegarde called Thursday for the government to recognize more than 60 indigenous languages he dubbed "national treasures," alongside the country's official French and English.
Bellegarde heads Canada's assembly of First Nations, which advocates for the array of indigenous people in the country.
There are 1.4 million aboriginal people, some 4.3 per cent of the Canadian population, but their languages are not officially recognized by the federal government.
"There has basically been a killing of the languages in Canada," by compulsory education in French and English in native communities, Bellegarde said in an interview with The Globe and Mail newspaper.
"Our languages should be looked upon as national jewels, national treasures," he said.
A 2011 census found more than 60 indigenous languages in 12 major language families.
Bellegarde called for the government to set aside funding for the preservation of the languages of the country's first inhabitants.
Bellegarde suggested the funding could create a national institute to help preserve and teach the languages, many of which are only spoken by a small number of older people.
Bellegarde said the "ultimate goal" would be for the languages to be printed alongside French and English.
"But let's do small steps to get there."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Perry Bellegarde,Canadian languages
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:01:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina House approves removal of Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fb8e7a/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CSouth0ECarolina0EHouse0Eapproves0Eremoval0Eof0EConfederate0Eflag0Carticleshow0C480A0A7810A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Lawmakers in South Carolina's House of Representatives voted on Thursday to remove the Confederate flag from the grounds of the state legislature following last month's shooting massacre at a black church.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World US
Breaking News:
South Carolina House approves removal of Confederate flag
AFP | Jul 9, 2015, 09.31 PM IST
Thursday's vote came after a full day of heated debate a day earlier in the South Carolina House, as lawmakers opposed to removing the flag introduced a raft of amendments to slow down passage of the measure.
RELATED
CHARLESTON: Lawmakers in South Carolina's House of Representatives voted on Thursday to remove the Confederate flag from the grounds of the state legislature following last month's shooting massacre at a black church.
The bill which was passed earlier this week in the state Senate now goes to the desk of South Carolina's governor Nikki Haley, who had urged lawmakers to pass the measure, following the June 17 massacre of nine African Americans.
Haley, in a post on her Facebook page, praised lawmakers for voting to remove the flag from the grounds of the state capital building, a move which just a few weeks ago would have been unthinkable.
"Today, as the Senate did before them, the House of Representatives has served the State of South Carolina and her people with great dignity," Haley wrote.
"I am grateful for their service and their compassion. It is a new day in South Carolina, a day we can all be proud of, a day that truly brings us all together as we continue to heal, as one people and one state", she added
Thursday's vote came after a full day of heated debate a day earlier in the South Carolina House, as lawmakers opposed to removing the flag introduced a raft of amendments to slow down passage of the measure.
It passed by a vote of 94-20, more than the two-thirds vote needed for approval.
"It's been a long time coming but I always felt this day would come," tweeted James Clyburn, a longtime member of the US House from South Carolina, who is African American.
"I look forward to governer Haley expeditiously signing this bill and finally removing the Confederate Battle Flag from the Statehouse grounds", he added
Officials said once removed, the flag will be taken to a museum where it will be displayed as an artifact of Southern history.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Nikki Haley,Confederate flag,black church,African Americans
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:39:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suburban Detroit police hope squirrel mugshot helps crack nut theft case</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fb5086/sc/21/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmad0Emad0Eworld0CSuburban0EDetroit0Epolice0Ehope0Esquirrel0Emugshot0Ehelps0Ecrack0Enut0Etheft0Ecase0Carticleshow0C480A0A73690Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police in the Detroit suburb of Shelby Township are hoping a social media post about a felonious squirrel will help authorities locate some 28,000 pounds of stolen snack nuts.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Mad, Mad World
Breaking News:
Suburban Detroit police hope squirrel mugshot helps crack nut theft case
Reuters | Jul 9, 2015, 09.09 PM IST
My Saved articles
RELATED
DETROIT: Police in the Detroit suburb of Shelby Township are hoping a social media post about a felonious squirrel will help authorities locate some 28,000 pounds of stolen snack nuts.
Alas, the mock mugshot of the rodent, posted on the department's Facebook page on Tuesday, has not produced any leads on the actual culprit, Detective Lieutenant Jason Schmittler said. (here)
The nuts, which were on a parked tractor trailer, went missing sometime during the weekend of June 27. Authorities found the rig abandoned in Detroit on July 1 but about 28,000 pounds of packaged walnuts and other snack nuts - worth an estimated $128,000 - were missing.
Police officials hoped that through the power of social media and cute animals, the squirrel wanted poster would result in leads that would help crack the case. It attracted a rush of media attention and was shared more than 400 times on Facebook, it did not produce any credible leads.
"Obviously the squirrel attracted some attention but not the types of calls that we were hoping for," Schmittler said.
Shelby Township is about 30 miles north of Detroit.
Deputy chief Mark Coil told Reuters the squirrel wanted poster is the latest example of the department's efforts to increase its social media presence. It follows a trend in policing throughout the United States to use social media platforms to be more approachable to a public that in recent months has been inundated with stories and video images of police brutality.
"At the end of the day, this is just a new spin on how we do an old business," Coil said.
The department emphasized in its Facebook post that the squirrel is not a suspect and it was just a picture used to draw attention. "Please do not call in squirrel sightings," the police said in the posting.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:28:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Over 4 million refugees have now fled Syria: UN</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fb5081/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0COver0E40Emillion0Erefugees0Ehave0Enow0Efled0ESyria0EUN0Carticleshow0C480A0A71690Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>More than 4 million Syrians have fled abroad since the 2011 outbreak of civil war, the largest number from any crisis in almost 25 years, the United Nations said Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syrian refugee children, who have been living in Jordan with their family for 2.5 years after fleeing the violence in their Syrian hometown of Idlib, sit in front of their family residence in Madaba city. (Reuters photo)
RELATED
ISTANBUL: More than 4 million Syrians have fled abroad since the 2011 outbreak of civil war, the largest number from any crisis in almost 25 years, the United Nations said Thursday.
A recent wave of people leaving Syria and an update of Turkish statistics confirmed the tragic milestone, according to the UN refugee agency, UNHCR. The agency said 7.6 million additional people have been displaced from their homes within Syria by the fighting.
The 4 million refugees are the most to flee a conflict since the Afghan civil war forced 4.6 million out of their country beginning in 1992.
"This is the biggest refugee population from a single conflict in a generation," UN high commissioner for refugees Antonio Guterres said. "It is a population that needs the support of the world but is instead living in dire conditions and sinking deeper into poverty."
The flow of refugees is accelerating only 10 months after the agency said more than 3 million Syrians had fled their country.
Turkey has borne much of the impact. In June alone, according to UNHCR, more than 24,000 people arrived from northern Syria amid fighting between the Islamic State group and Kurdish militants. The more than 1.8 million Syrians in Turkey have made it the biggest host of refugees in the world, an expensive undertaking that Turkey is bearing mostly on its own.
"What are we going to be facing in another year's time?" Andrew Harper, the UNHCR chief in Jordan, asked in an interview with The Associated Press.
Syrian refugees who had fled Tal Abyad, re-enter with their belongings in Syria from Turkey on June 22, 2015. (AFP photo)
Harper emphasized that countries involved had to figure out ways to keep the Syrian refugees productive.
"We should make sure that the people who are here, the skills, the work, the ability, are not wasted," Harper said. "We do not want to warehouse the refugee population of four million. Just imagine the amount of productivity they could contribute to an economy."
In the village Hashemite, near the Jordanian capital of Amman, refugee Nada Fareed said her husband had been out of work for about half a year and her family was getting deeper into debt.
"We depend on the vouchers to buy milk and we pay the rent to the landlord with just debt and more debt," the mother of five who left Al Houl, in northeastern Syria in 2011, told the AP. "The situation is very, very critical."
"life in al-Houl was terrifying. How could we not leave?" she added.
Syrian refugees re-enter in Syria from Turkey on June 22, 2015. (AFP photo)
Yusra Fahid Al-Masry, a single mother with three children, living in Amman's Ashrafiyeh neighborhood said "the hardest part is paying for water, the children's expenses, to buy things to drink and eat."
The dire situation is pushing a wave of Syrian refugees to escape to Western Europe, taking increasingly risky paths across the Mediterranean as European countries resist the flow of migrants and refugees.
"We cannot afford to let them (the refugees) and the communities hosting them slide further into desperation," Guterres said.
Syrian refugees stand in a building on June 27, 2015 in Syrian Kurdish city of Amuda, after running away from clashes between regime forces and the Islamic State group. (AFP photo)
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Syrian refugees,Antonio Guterres
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:24:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Last surviving leader of Turkey's 1980 coup dies</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fa5ec7/sc/11/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CLast0Esurviving0Eleader0Eof0ETurkeys0E1980A0Ecoup0Edies0Carticleshow0C480A0A62410Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Turkish former air force general Tahsin Sahinkaya, the last surviving leader of the 1980 coup which led to military rule and left lasting scars on the country, died on Thursday. He was 90.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Last surviving leader of Turkey's 1980 coup dies
AFP | Jul 9, 2015, 07.54 PM IST
Turkish coup era general Tahsin Sahinkaya dies at age 90. (Photo: Getty Images)
RELATED
ISTANBUL: Turkish former air force general Tahsin Sahinkaya, the last surviving leader of the 1980 coup which led to military rule and left lasting scars on the country, died on Thursday. He was 90.
The putsch on September 12, 1980 was the bloodiest in Turkey's coup-ridden history, overthrowing a civilian government and putting in place a military junta that ruled Turkey for three years.
Sahinkaya was the last remaining survivor of the coup leaders after the death in May aged 97 of Kenan Evren, the army general who led the junta and served as president from 1980 to 1989.
Sahinkaya died at a military hospital in Istanbul, the official Anatolia news agency said. He passed away after three days on a life support machine.
With the powers of the military, which ardently defended Turkey's secular order, clipped under the Islamic-rooted Justice and Development Party (AKP) which came to power in 2002, prosecutors began investigating the coup leaders on charges of acting against the state.
But only Evren and Sahinkaya were still alive when the case was judged in June 2014. Both were given life sentences but never went to prison because of their poor health.
The 1980 coup was justified by the military as bringing order to Turkey after a period of social and political chaos.
It was the bloodiest in Turkey's modern history, with 50 people executed while dozens died from torture. Some 600,000 were arrested and many others went missing.
Sahinkaya and Evren escaped prosecution until Ankara stripped them of their immunity in 2010 in legislation adopted exactly 30 years after the coup.
Sahinkaya's death also comes less than one month after the passing of former Turkish prime minister and president Suleyman Demirel, the premier at the time who was ousted by the September 12 coup.
Born in 1925 in the central Anatolian region of Merzifon, Sahinkaya entered a military training college and had been promoted to general by 1977 and was made head of the air force in 1978.
He was one of the most prominent figures on the five-person National Security Council  the military junta that took power in the wake of the coup.
With the return of civilian rule, he retired in December 1983. In a sign of how the ex-coup leaders are regarded in today's Turkey under the AKP's co-founder President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, there was official silence on Sahinkaya's death.
The mastermind of the coup, Evren, was accorded a low-key state funeral on May 12, which was attended by the military but boycotted by the AKP.
Demirel, by contrast, was laid to rest in a grandiose public ceremony with leaders including Erdogan paying tribute to his achievements.
Evren remained unrepentant in the years after the coup, defending the hanging of a 17-year-old convicted of killing a soldier in the unrest, declaring his "hands didn't tremble" as he signed death sentences under his junta.
Including Evren and Sahinkaya, the military junta had five members, all of whom are now dead. Naval commander Nejat Tumer died in 2011, ground forces chief Nurettin Ersin died in 2005 and gendarmerie commander Sedat Celasun in 1998.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Turkey's 1980 coup,Tahsin Sahinkaya
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:43:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>1,000-year-old corn cobs, kernels found at US site</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47fa5b09/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0C10A0A0A0Eyear0Eold0Ecorn0Ecobs0Ekernels0Efound0Eat0EUS0Esite0Carticleshow0C480A0A57580Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Archaeologists in the northwestern state of South Dakota have uncovered corn cobs, corn kernels and sunflower kernels that are over 1,000 years old.</Description>
        <MainBody>The prehistoric Indian village in Mitchell is an active archaeological site and open to the public. Students work every year at the site. (Photo credit: Chris Maddaloni / Getty Images)
RELATED
MITCHELL (South Dakota): Archaeologists in the northwestern state of South Dakota have uncovered corn cobs, corn kernels and sunflower kernels that are over 1,000 years old.
Officials say the discoveries at the prehistoric Indian village in Mitchell show that people who lived in the region at the time farmed and had a diverse diet.
The village is an active archaeological site and open to the public. Students from the University of Exeter in England and Augustana College in Sioux Falls work every year at the site that holds dual status as a National Register and National Historic Landmark site.
Augustana archaeology professor Adrien Hannus told The Daily Republic (http://bit.ly/1MhusfG ) that the new discoveries indicate the village dwellers weren't exactly primitive. He says it was a successful village of farmers, hunters and foragers.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=South Dakota,prehistoric Indian village in Mitchell
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:35:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lebanese anti-government protesters scuffle with army</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f9e933/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CLebanese0Eanti0Egovernment0Eprotesters0Escuffle0Ewith0Earmy0Carticleshow0C480A0A56470Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of Lebanese supporters of a Christian politician scuffled on Thursday with troops who blocked them from reaching the government building in downtown Beirut where a Cabinet session was underway.</Description>
        <MainBody>Supporters of Christian leader Michel Aoun chant slogans as they hold Free Patriotic Movement flags, during a demonstration near the government headquarters in downtown Beirut, Lebanon. (AP photo)
RELATED
BEIRUT: Dozens of Lebanese supporters of a Christian politician scuffled on Thursday with troops who blocked them from reaching the government building in downtown Beirut where a cabinet session was underway.
Leader of the Free Patriotic Movement Michel Aoun had called for the demonstrations following a dispute over security appointments in the government.
Aoun, a former army commander, insists that the government should make the appointments a priority while government officials have said only regular items would be on the agenda. The meeting ended later with an agreement to postpone the discussion until July 23.
Earlier, Lebanese soldiers beat back dozens of protesters with batons as they tried to break a security barrier, triggering hours-long skirmishes at the entrance to the posh Beirut souks in the downtown. The army said seven soldiers were being treated for various injuries while the FPM, Aoun's party, said that around 17 protesters were hurt.
Lebanon has been without a president since May 2014 and Aoun has accused Prime Minister Tammam Salam of taking advantage of the presidential vacuum and running the country as if he were president.
Lebanon is the only country in the Arab world with a unique power-sharing system under which the president must be a Maronite Christian, the prime minister a Sunni Muslim and the parliament speaker a Shia Muslim.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=shia,Maronite Christian,Lebanese,Christian,Aoun
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:35:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israel says citizen being held by Hamas in Gaza Strip</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f95996/sc/11/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CIsrael0Esays0Ecitizen0Ebeing0Eheld0Eby0EHamas0Ein0EGaza0EStrip0Carticleshow0C480A0A38720Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An Israeli civilian is being held against his will by the Islamist group Hamas in the Gaza Strip, Israel said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
Israel says citizen being held by Hamas in Gaza Strip
Reuters | Jul 9, 2015, 05.05 PM IST
The brother and the mother of Avraham Mengistu, 29, an Israeli of Ethiopian descent who is reportedly held captive in the Gaza Strip, gives a press conference in the southern city of Ashkelon. (AFP photo)
RELATED
JERUSALEM: An Israeli civilian is being held against his will by the Islamist group Hamas in the Gaza Strip, Israel said on Thursday.
Hamas, the Palestinian enclave's dominant faction, declined to comment.
Israel suspects militants in Gaza would use its citizens to bargain for the release of Palestinians held in Israeli jails.
Israel's Defence Ministry said there was "credible intelligence" that Avraham Mangisto, 26, a resident of Ashkelon, the nearest Israeli city to the Gaza Strip, "is being held against his will by Hamas in Gaza". It said he had crossed the border on foot on Sept. 7, 2014.
The statement also said: "The defence establishment is also dealing with an additional case of an Israeli Arab who is being held in Gaza." It did not give details.
Reporting the cases had been barred until Thursday.
Mangisto's brother, Ilan, speaking on behalf of the family said they were placing their trust in the Israeli government to bring Avraham, who was unwell, home.
"This is a distressing humanitarian case because my brother is not well... I ask the Israeli government to bring him home safely and call on the international community to intervene and to bring its influence to bear for his release."
In an emotional plea made outside the family's run-down Ashkelon apartment, Ilan Mangisto also called on Hamas to consider his brother's medical state and to "release him immediately".
Israel's president, Reuven Rivlin, said the family had feared for Mangisto's safety before he crossed to Gaza, adding he should not be considered an asset.
"Without discussing (medical) details, his family was very worried about him before he left ... he cannot be considered to hold tactical or strategic value in the struggle between us and Hamas or any other foes," Rivlin told reporters.
Israeli media said Mangisto, who is of Ethiopian origin, crossed of his own volition into the Gaza Strip, circumventing the border along the beach.
Gilad Shalit, an Israeli soldier who was abducted by militants in a cross-border raid in 2006, was released after more than five years in captivity in exchange for over 1,000 Palestinians in Israeli jails.
Israeli Defence Minister Moshe Yaalon said this week Israel was seeking the return of the remains of two soldiers killed during last year's Gaza war.
The Defence Ministry said Israel had "appealed to international and regional interlocutors to demand (Mangisto's) immediate release and verify his well-being" and would "continue to pursue the release and return of the citizen to Israel".
In the 50-day war that ended last August, more than 2,100 Palestinians were killed, mostly civilians. Israel put the number of its dead at 67 soldiers and six civilians.
Israeli air strikes and shelling hammered the densely populated Gaza Strip causing widespread destruction of homes and schools. Hamas and other militant groups launched thousands of rockets and mortar bombs out of the enclave into Israel.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Hamas,Gaza Strip
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 13:40:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Australian businessman promises to give money to distraught pensionerater photgraph goes viral</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f8e6ce/sc/3/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CAustralian0Ebusinessman0Epromises0Eto0Egive0Emoney0Eto0Edistraught0Epensionerater0Ephotgraph0Egoes0Eviral0Carticleshow0C480A0A30A0A30Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Greek man pictured weeping outside a bank as he tried to withdraw his pension but was turned away became the human face of the Greek crisis, but now that man is set to receive a personal bailout from an Australian businessman.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Australian businessman promises to give money to distraught pensionerater photgraph goes viral
Alexander SehmerAlexander Sehmer,The Independent | Jul 9, 2015, 04.10 PM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
Chatzifotiadis had waited in line at four banks across his city, but was turned away without being able to withdraw his money.
RELATED
A Greek man pictured weeping outside a bank as he tried to withdraw his pension but was turned away became the human face of the Greek crisis, but now that man is set to receive a personal bailout from an Australian businessman.
Images of the elderly Giorgos Chatzifotiadis collapsing outside a bank in Thessaloniki and being helped away by a policeman and another man in a suit after he was unable to withdraw his EUR 120-a-week pension were seen around the world in the international media.
Over the last few weeks Greek banks have remained closed and withdrawals have been limited after Greek negotiators failed to reach a deal with the country's international creditors.
Chatzifotiadis had waited in line at four banks across his city, but was turned away without being able to withdraw his money.
In Australia, James Koufos, the CEO of a Sydney-based financial services company, was moved by the images of Chatzifotiadis and when it emerged that elderly Greek was an old family friend, he went into action.
READ ALSO: Crying Greek pensioner  The story behind the poignant photo
Koufos took to Facebook, writing in a post "I urge all my Facebook friends to please help us track this man", and promising to pay Chatzifotiadis's pension for "as long as it takes".
Chatzifotiadis, he said in the post, was a friend of his late father. The two were at school together in the same village in Greece.
Koufos's mother, who still lives in Greece, told him of the family connection and Koufous has promised to fly to Greece to pay Chatzifotiadis's pension.
Speaking to The Daily Mail in Australia, Koufos said he had been told where Chatzifotiadis was living.
"It's an amazing and rare chance to really help someone," he was quoted in an article on the MailOnline as saying.
He is quoted as saying he will use some of the inheritance left to him by his father, and that he has received "four or five thousand" euros in donations from other people moved by Chatzifotiadis's plight.
Greeks voted against the terms of a bailout deal in a referendum over the weekend and a new bailout deal has yet to be agreed.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 13:22:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Londoners suffer as strike shuts Tube</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f917d4/sc/6/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CLondoners0Esuffer0Eas0Estrike0Eshuts0ETube0Carticleshow0C480A0A26610Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A 24-hour strike by staff and drivers brought the British capital's underground rail network to a halt and left millions of Londoners struggling to get to work on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
Londoners suffer as strike shuts Tube
Reuters | Jul 9, 2015, 03.52 PM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
Early morning commuters walk past a closed underground gate at Victoria station during a tube strike in London. (AFP photo)
RELATED
LONDON: A 24-hour strike by staff and drivers brought the British capital's underground rail network to a halt and left millions of Londoners struggling to get to work on Thursday.
London Underground's bosses said no trains would run all day on the Tube, as the world's oldest underground passenger railway is known, because of the stoppage. The strike follows a dispute over plans for new night services.
Commuters who usually use the underground network walked, cycled, battled to find taxis, or crammed onto crowded buses. Many simply stayed at home.
Tony Clark, a radio producer who usually uses the rail network, turned to a boat service on the River Thames for his commute from Greenwich in east London.
"This (the boat) is the only way I can do it," he told Reuters. "The buses aren't feasible. I got up early to get in on time and now I think I'm going to be late."
The Tube usually handles up to 4 million passengers a day, with more than 535 trains in operation at peak times. Transport bosses said they had put on extra river services and 200 more buses to cope with extra demand.
But massive queues waiting for buses snaked down streets by the capital's main rail stations. Taxi-hailing app Hailo said it had seen a 500 per cent increase in pre-booked cabs, with demand more than double than they saw on New Year's Eve.
Members of four rail unions representing staff from managers to drivers have joined the walkout, unhappy with the pay and terms offered by London Underground to implement 24-hour service at weekends on some lines, which is due to begin in September.
"They should stop playing games and start talking to us in good faith to get a sensible solution to this dispute," said Manuel Cortes, leader of the TSSA union.
London Underground has said it has hired extra night drivers, offered a fair pay deal and said most staff would be unaffected by the changes. No one would have to work more hours, it said.
London mayor Boris Johnson said the action was political, accusing the unions of having no interest in doing a deal. He told BBC radio that union leaders should "cut the cackle, stop the misery for Londoners and allow the Tube workforce to get on with their job".
Compounding the problem for some commuters, staff on First Great Western, which provides services between London and western England, were also on strike.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Tube,staff and drivers,London Underground,left millions of Londoners struggling,British capital's underground rail network
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:41:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia wants Iran arms embargo ended as soon as possible</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f82c1f/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CRussia0Ewants0EIran0Earms0Eembargo0Eended0Eas0Esoon0Eas0Epossible0Carticleshow0C480A0A20A70A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Russia called on Thursday for a UN weapons embargo on Iran to be lifted as soon as possible, saying it would help Tehran contribute to the fight against terrorism.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Russia wants Iran arms embargo ended as soon as possible
Reuters | Jul 9, 2015, 03.11 PM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
A final deal on Iran's nuclear programme is within reach, Lavrov said on Thursday, adding that he is ready to return to Vienna for talks between Tehran and six major world powers to work on the agreement. (Reuters photo)
RELATED
UFA, Russia: Russia called on Thursday for a UN weapons embargo on Iran to be lifted as soon as possible, saying it would help Tehran contribute to the fight against terrorism.
The arms embargo is among stumbling blocks at talks in Vienna between Iran and six major powers, including Russia, on curbing Tehran's nuclear programme in exchange for relief from economic sanctions.
"We are calling for lifting the embargo as soon as possible and we will support the choices that Iran's negotiators make," Russian foreign minister Sergei Lavrov said during a summit of the BRICS emerging economies in the Russian city of Ufa.
"Iran is a consistent supporter of the struggle against ISIS and lifting the arms embargo would help Iran to advance its efficiency in fighting terrorism," he told reporters.
Lavrov said a deal was "within reach," and that he was ready to return to Vienna when required, but the quality of the agreement was more important than the timing.
In Vienna, a senior Western diplomat said there was nothing new in the Russian position on the weapons embargo.
"That said, we are working collectively on a way forward on this difficult issue," the senior Western official said.
The deadline for the deal has been extended until Friday, but Russian deputy foreign minister Sergei Ryabkov said the talks had reached their most difficult phase.
"These talks are like alpinists claiming a peak: 95 percent of the way has been completed but there are still several steps, the last few metres (are) the most difficult," Ryabkov said.
President Vladimir Putin was due to meet Iranian President Hassan Rouhani later on Thursday in Ufa. Rouhani will be attending a security summit in the city on Friday.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=weapons embargo on Iran to be lifted,UN weapons embargo,Tehran contribute to the fight against terrorism,Russia called on Thursday,exchange for relief from economic sanctions
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:25:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Amid violence and hunger, South Sudan marks 4th birthday</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f882bb/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CAmid0Eviolence0Eand0Ehunger0ESouth0ESudan0Emarks0E4th0Ebirthday0Carticleshow0C480A0A17940Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Amid ongoing violence and the threat of famine, South Sudan is marking four years of independence from Sudan.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
Amid violence and hunger, South Sudan marks 4th birthday
AP | Jul 9, 2015, 02.55 PM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
READ MORE threat of famine | South Sudan is marking four years of independence | Amid ongoing violence | a vote to secede
RELATED
JUBA, South Sudan: Amid ongoing violence and the threat of famine, South Sudan is marking four years of independence from Sudan.
South Sudan became the world's newest nation in 2011 following a vote to secede from northern neighbor Sudan.
But the young country fell into war after just 18 months as a result of a political dispute between President Salva Kiir and his former deputy Riek Machar.
The prominent South Sudanese activist Edmund Yakani said that there is "nothing that we can celebrate" about the independence anniversary.
Aimee Ansari of CARE International said that as South Sudan's conflict continues, "the malnutrition numbers that we're seeing now make me profoundly concerned that too many children in this country won't reach their fifth birthday."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=threat of famine,South Sudan is marking four years of independence,Amid ongoing violence,a vote to secede
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:15:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Don't merge Gilgit-Baltistan into Pakistan'</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f87dd9/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cpakistan0CDont0Emerge0EGilgit0EBaltistan0Einto0EPakistan0Carticleshow0C480A0A16510Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (PoK) Prime Minister Chaudhry Abdul Majeed has warned Islamabad against any attempt to convert Gilgit-Baltistan into a federal province.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gilgit-Baltistan is part and parcel of the state of Jammu and Kashmir. Any attempt to merge it into Pakistan will deal a fatal blow to our stand in the light of UN resolutions.
RELATED
ISLAMABAD: Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (PoK) Prime Minister Chaudhry Abdul Majeed has warned Islamabad against any attempt to convert Gilgit-Baltistan into a federal province.
"Gilgit-Baltistan is part and parcel of the state of Jammu and Kashmir. Any attempt to merge it into Pakistan will deal a fatal blow to our stand in the light of UN resolutions envisaging right to self-determination for the Kashmiris," Dawn quoted Majeed as saying in at a press conference in Muzffarabad.
Earlier, some Kashmiri leaders have expressed concern over alleged moves to convert Gilgit-Baltistan into the fifth province of Pakistan.
On Tuesday, PoK President Sardar Mohammad Yaqoob Khan warned that such a step would be more damaging than the dismemberment of the country in 1971.
"I call upon the prime minister of Pakistan to avoid (taking) any decision that does not fall in his jurisdiction. He cannot take this decision unless we, the people of Jammu and Kashmir, take it," Majeed said.
Recalling that Gilgit-Baltistan had been given in the administrative control of Pakistan on a temporary basis, he advised Islamabad not to think beyond that.
"On behalf of over 17.5 million Kashmiris, I warn you (Islamabad) to change your thoughts. Or else, there will be severe reaction," he said.
Answering a question, he said it was the responsibility of the PoK parliamentary committee to seek the consent of the prime minister of Pakistan and the minister for Kashmir affairs in order to carry out constitutional amendments "smoothly and amicably".
Majeed said the role and responsibilities of the government of Pakistan under the United Nations Commission for India and Pakistan (Uncip) resolutions should not be negated. "With this in mind, there is no harm in talking to them," he said.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Prime Minister Chaudhry Abdul Majeed,Pakistan-occupied Kashmir,Islamabad,Gilgit-Baltistan
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 11:38:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thailand deports scores of Uighur Muslims to China</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f7b7aa/sc/28/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Csouth0Easia0CThailand0Edeports0Escores0Eof0EUighur0EMuslims0Eto0EChina0Carticleshow0C480A0A11840Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Thailand today said it had deported around 100 Uighur Muslims detained in the kingdom since last year to China, in a move sparking fears for the safety of the asylum-seekers.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World South Asia
Breaking News:
Thailand deports scores of Uighur Muslims to China
AFP | Jul 9, 2015, 02.08 PM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
Turkish nationalists step on a Chinese flag, during a protest to denounce China's treatment of ethnic Uighur Muslims, in front of the Chinese consulate in Istanbul. (AFP photo)
RELATED
BANGKOK: Thailand today said it had deported around 100 Uighur Muslims detained in the kingdom since last year to China, in a move sparking fears for the safety of the asylum-seekers.
The fate of scores of suspected Uighurs  a Turkic  speaking, largely Muslim minority in China's northwestern Xinjiang region who have long chafed under Chinese control  has hung in the balance since they illegally entered the kingdom in March 2014.
The asylum-seekers, who presented themselves to police as Turkish, had been held in detention as Thai authorities determined their nationalities amid a tussle between Turkey and China over where they should be moved.
Today, Thai government spokesman Werachon Sukhondapatipak told reporters that "some 100" Uighurs were deported to China on Wednesday after finding "clear evidence they are Chinese nationals".
He also revealed that an earlier group of around "170 Uighurs" were repatriated to Turkey in late June  the first public announcement by Thai authorities of both deportations.
The legal wrangle between Turkey and China over the group came to the fore in March when both countries sought the repatriation of a family of 17 that claimed they were Turkish.
Worasit Piriyawiboon, a human rights lawyer that was representing the Teklimakan family, said that 15 had been deported to Turkey in June. He did not know the fate of the other two members.
Uighurs in Xinjiang, who number around 10 million, say they face cultural and religious restrictions.
China has recently launched a wide-ranging crackdown in the region in the face of rising violence which authorities blame on Islamist separatists.
Under pressure from Beijing, countries including Cambodia, Malaysia and Pakistan have all in recent years forcibly returned fleeing Uighurs to China.
In Bangkok on Thursday, Werachon said that Thailand had expressed its concerns over the safety of the group to China.
"China agreed to take care of their safety and will now put them through the judicial process. It has reassured Thailand about its humanitarian principles," he said.
But rights groups lambasted the move by Thailand's generals, who have ruled the country since seizing power in a coup last May, as a "violation of international law".
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Thailand today,safety of the asylum-seekers,Muslim minority in China,move sparking fears,deported around 100 Uighur Muslims
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 08:16:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 4 million refugees have now fled Syria, UN says</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f69575/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CMore0Ethan0E40Emillion0Erefugees0Ehave0Enow0Efled0ESyria0EUN0Esays0Carticleshow0C479984960Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A recent wave of people leaving Syria and an update of Turkish statistics confirm the tragic milestone, according to the UN refugee agency, UNHCR.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
More than 4 million refugees have now fled Syria, UN says
AFP | Jul 9, 2015, 10.46 AM IST
READ MORE UNHCR | UN High Commissioner for Refugees
RELATED
ISTANBUL: The number of Syrians who have fled abroad since the outbreak of civil war in their country has risen to more than 4 million, the largest number from any crisis in almost 25 years, the United Nations said Thursday.
A recent wave of people leaving Syria and an update of Turkish statistics confirm the tragic milestone, according to the UN refugee agency, UNHCR. The agency said in a statement that 7.6 million additional people are displaced from their homes within Syria.
"This is the biggest refugee population from a single conflict in a generation," said UN High Commissioner for Refugees Antonio Guterres in a statement. "It is a population that needs the support of the world but is instead living in dire conditions and sinking deeper into poverty."
The new figure shows that the flow of refugees is accelerating only 10 months after the agency recorded more than 3 million Syrians fleeing their country.
Turkey has seen much of the recent flow. In June alone, according to UNHCR, more than 24,000 people arrived from northern Syria amid fighting between the Islamic State group and Kurdish militants. The more than 1.8 million Syrians in Turkey have made it the biggest host of refugees in the world, an expensive undertaking that the country is bearing mostly out of its own treasury.
The dire situation in the region is pushing a wave of refugees to seek escape in Western Europe, taking increasingly risky paths as European countries resist the flow.
"We cannot afford to let them and the communities hosting them slide further into desperation," Guterres said.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=UNHCR,UN High Commissioner for Refugees
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:50:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lagarde: A new Greece programme needs debt restructure</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f61e32/sc/25/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CLagarde0EA0Enew0EGreece0Eprogramme0Eneeds0Edebt0Erestructure0Carticleshow0C47997270A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>International Monetary Fund managing director Christine Lagarde has said that a new program to prop up Greece's finances would require creditors to restructure debt.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece is in a situation of acute crisis which needs to be addressed,IMF MD ChristineLagarde said.
RELATED
WASHINGTON: International Monetary Fund managing director Christine Lagarde has said that a new program to prop up Greece's finances would require creditors to restructure debt.
In addition to the reforms Athens needs to undertake, she said, "the other leg is debt restructuring, which we believe is needed in the case of Greece for it to have debt sustainability."
"Greece is in a situation of acute crisis which needs to be addressed," she told a conference in Washington on Wednesday.
Despite the fact that Greece defaulted on its debt to the IMF on June 30, Lagarde assured that the institution "remains fully engaged in order to help find a solution."
In a report last week the IMF said Greece's official EU creditors should double the payback period for Greece's debts and stump up another 36 billion euros (US $ 40 billion) to ensure the country's finances remain sustainable.
But the European Commission and the European Central Bank are pressing the country hard to accept a package of austere fiscal and policy adjustments that Athens has so far refused to accept.
Lagarde said the numbers themselves "will have to be revisited," but added that Greece, which no longer has access to IMF resources since its default, should not benefit from any special treatment.
"It is certainly my view that the IMF has to follow its rules, should not bend its rules and should be always even-handed."
She justified the Fund's continued participation in new aid talks for Greece even if Athens has been a severe critic of the institution.
"I have heard talk here and there in France saying, 'but what is the IMF doing in this situation? It should be handled by the Europeans,'" she told reporters.
"At the time when I was (France's) finance minister I also supported this viewpoint."
But, she said, the IMF is involved "because the IMF was asked by Greece to be involved."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=INTERNATIONAL MONETARY FUND,greece,Christine Lagarde
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:44:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek banks to stay closed until Monday: Finance ministry</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f69b54/sc/25/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CGreek0Ebanks0Eto0Estay0Eclosed0Euntil0EMonday0EFinance0Eministry0Carticleshow0C479972260Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Greek banks will remain closed until Monday, the finance ministry said as the government raced to come up with a new proposal to present to creditors in a last-minute drive to avert a eurozone exit.</Description>
        <MainBody>The referendum turned out a 61-percent result against the creditors' latest bailout proposals, souring relations between Athens and many of its European peers.
READ ALSO
No plans to issue parallel currency, Greece says
Speaking before the European Parliament earlier on Thursday, Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras vowed to present "credible" reform plans before a Thursday deadline set by exasperated European leaders.
The Greek government has promised to start pension and tax reforms next week, as demanded by creditors, in return for a three-year loan to drag its financial system back from the brink of collapse.
"Tomorrow we will openly submit our proposals with reliable reforms in order to reach what we have called an honest compromise," Tsipras told Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos upon returning from Strasbourg.
In return, Tsipras said he sought "clear pledges" on funding and a reduction of Greece's crushing public debt.
The capital controls have kept Greek banks going but authorities have struggled to keep ATMs supplied with cash, and additional obstacles to imports have led to fears of shortages in goods and medicine.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Greek banks,Finance Ministry,Creditors
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
