<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="UPI">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:57:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea to introduce second cellular provider</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/North-Korea-to-introduce-second-cellular-provider/3971436405117/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>North Korea to introduce second cellular provider
A second provider, Byol, is expected to offer wireless services only to North Koreans.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 8, 2015 at 9:57 PM
Comments
SEOUL, July 8 (UPI) -- North Korea is making a dent in the country's wireless-service monopoly, by introducing a second cellular provider in its growing mobile phone market.
A source in Pyongyang told North Korea Tech , a U.S.-based news outlet, that the state has selected the firm Byol, meaning star in Korean, as an alternative domestic provider of wireless services.
Byol has already been in operation inside the reclusive country, offering cable-based Internet to Pyongyang's foreign residents, South Korean news agency Yonhap reported.
The differentiated Internet service for foreigners in North Korea was established so ordinary North Koreans would not be able to access websites outside the country or make international phone calls, South Korean television network SBS reported.
With the new changes, however, Star is expected to offer wireless services only to North Koreans.
Byol, compared to the existing network of Koryolink, also is expected to be easier to operate.
Radio Free Asia reported North Korea's decision reflects the state's wish to diminish Koryolink's powerful monopoly, and Martyn Williams of North Korea Tech said North Korea has selected Byol to reduce the exercise powers of its majority shareholder, the Egyptian firm Orascom.
Orascom holds a 75 percent share in Koryolink, but Byol is expected to merge with Koryolink, a move designed to lessen the percentage of Orascom's share of revenue in Koryolink's profits, estimated to be $540 million at the official exchange rate, according to North Korea Tech.
The mobile phone is becoming a central component of everyday life for many North Koreans, and more households own two mobile phones as a way around prohibitively expensive service plans.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:13:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin hosting summit of emerging economies</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Putin-hosting-summit-of-emerging-economies/3691436360125/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Putin hosting summit of emerging economies
By Jared M. Feldschreiber | July 8, 2015 at 3:13 PM
Comments
UFA, Russia, July 8 (UPI) -- Russian President Vladimir Putin arrived in Ufa on Wednesday as he prepares to host a summit of leaders from emerging economies interested in independence from the International Monetary Fund, among other issues.
The BRICS Summit will address billion-dollar initiatives aimed at advancing its five members: Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa.
"The BRICS Summit in Ufa is probably the most important and nerve-racking than even the year of its launch," Victoria V. Panova , the Strategy Planning adviser at the National Committee on BRICS Research, told UPI. "Expectations include supporting Russia's longstanding view of necessity to deepen BRICS' cooperation with practicalities of... enhancing ties in all areas of social, economic and political life through outreach with involvement of different stakeholders."
The members will also tackle solutions to social problems.
"Priority social issues on the agenda, like healthcare, education [and] labor would certainly take their proper place with a number of concrete proposals," Panova said. "Political problems of regional conflicts, combat against illegal drug trafficking and terrorism will be discussed to demonstrate a consensus."
In May, Russia's upper house of Parliament ratified a proposal to establish a $100 billion foreign currency reserve pool for BRICS countries. This would be devoted to protecting national currencies so members would no longer be dependent on the International Monetary Fund.
The creation of the development bank will serve as an alternative to the IMFO, a key initiative this week. The financial institution would be located in Shanghai and headed by K.V. Kamath, an Indian private banker for the first six years. Five-year terms each for Brazil and Russia would then follow.
Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi met with Putin on Monday, as India and Pakistan are set to become full members of the SCO. India applied to become a full member in 2014 while Pakistan's request has been pending for years. Both countries are currently observers. Besides Russia and China, SCO's members are the former Soviet republics of Tajikistan, Uzbekistan, Kazakhstan and Kyrgyzstan.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:55:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea's military shuffle means winners and losers</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/North-Koreas-military-shuffle-means-winners-and-losers/9601436378751/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
North Korea's military shuffle means winners and losers
A purge may have occurred after the execution of former Defense Minister Hyon Yong Chol, according to South Korea press.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 8, 2015 at 2:55 PM
Comments
SEOUL, July 8 (UPI) -- North Korea 's military has been reorganizing its top brass, and Kim Jong Un 's latest visit to Pyongyang's Kumsusan Palace of the Sun indicated changes have taken place in the bureaucracy.
South Korean news agency Yonhap reported during a memorial service on Wednesday, Kim performed a roll call of North Korean military officials.
The absence of Kim Chun Sam, who was appointed director of operations for North Korea's military in November, had analysts speculating about another purge related to the execution of former Defense Minister Hyon Yong Chol , South Korea press reported.
Kim Chun Sam was profiled for the first time in January when he attended an airborne assault weapons inspection.
The military official was last seen publicly at the 103rd birthday celebration of the late Kim Il Sung on April 15.
The order in which the names were called reflected the rank of the officials, according to South Korean television network SBS.
At the top of list was Hwang Pyong So, Kim Jong Un's top military aide, followed by Pak Yong Sik , who was promoted from a three-star to a four-star general in April. Pak's placement in the roll call indicates he is the North Korea defense chief, according to Yonhap.
Gen. No Kwang Chol, the former deputy chief of North Korea's military, was also promoted to operations chief, South Korea press reported.
No's profile has become more public since he accompanied Choe Ryong Hae, a top Kim aide, to Russia last November.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:43:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Parliament approves trade deal with U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/European-Parliament-approves-trade-deal-with-US/4921436375804/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
STRASBOURG, France, July 8 (UPI) -- The European Union's parliament approved a significant trade deal with the United States Wednesday.
The European Parliament gave initial backing to the Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TIP), which would create the world's largest free trade zone. The vote came with reservations, including demands the agreement will not allow large corporations to sue governments in secretive courts, and for transparency in investor-state disputes, among others.
The parliament members attached over 100 amendments to the deal, whose final document must be approved by the European Parliament. It could go into effect in 2016. The European Commission estimated the agreement could be worth 120 billion Euros ($132.6 billion), equal to one-half of one percent of the European Union's gross domestic product, by 2027.
Marlene Mizzi, representing Malta in the parliament, commented in a statement, "I think that this agreement, if and only if negotiated properly, could be of benefit to our economies and could open up new opportunities," she said.
"Having said that, however, EU needs to be extra cautious and to ensure that European values are properly defended in the talks and in the final agreement. Such values cover well-established precautionary principles, consumer protection, safeguarding EU food and healthy safety standards and high environmental standards, as well as providing strong protection of labor rights and of public services."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:40:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>15 arrested over Bogota bombings</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/15-arrested-over-Bogota-bombings/9051436371191/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
BOGOTA, July 8 (UPI) -- Colombia's National Police announced that 15 people have been arrested with potential links to the two small intimidatory bombings recently carried out in Bogota.
Three women, two university professors and two district administration officials were among those arrested. Some are accused of being members of the National Liberation Army (ELN) left-wing rebel group, which also carried out attacks in Bogota last year.
About eight people were injured, but not seriously, in Thursday's attack when two small bombs detonated in Bogota . Defense Secretary Luis Carlos Villegas said the explosions were meant to intimidate.
Created in 1964, the ELN was formed by intellectuals inspired by the Cuban revolution and Marxist ideology . The group was seen as more politically motivated than Colombia's largest rebel group, the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC).
The ELN initially abstained from participating in the drug trade, but since the decline from its highest power in the late 1990s, it formed alliances with criminal gangs and became involved drug trafficking.
Current ELN membership ranks are estimated to be as low 1,500 from a previous high of 4,000.
Colombian President Juan Manuel Santos took to Twitter to praise efforts in capturing the suspects.
Capturadas 11 personas del ELN responsables de petardos en Bogot. Felicitaciones a @PoliciaColombia y @FiscaliaCol -Pagarn por atentados!
 Juan Manuel Santos (@JuanManSantos) July 8, 2015
"Captured 11 ELN people responsible for firecrackers in Bogota. Congratulations to the Colombian Police and Attorney General's Office. They will pay for the attacks!" Santos said, later adding that operations will continue to capture all responsible for "terrorizing the capital."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:19:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Finnish teen convicted of hacking 50,700 computers</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Finnish-teen-convicted-of-hacking-50700-computers/5981436373963/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
ESPOO, Finland, July 8 (UPI) -- A Finnish teenager was convicted Wednesday for carrying out over 50,000 computer break-ins.
Julius Kivimaki, 17, was found guilty by the District Court of Espoo of 50,700 cases of aggravated hacking, disruption of telecommunications, theft and aggravated breaches of secrecy of communications. Using the nickname Zeekill, his actions included use of stolen credit card numbers to make online purchases, money laundering and pranks, which included the moving of network traffic from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology to the servers of Harvard University.
Kivimaki exploited vulnerabilities he discovered in an Adobe software program, ColdFusion, by installing "backdoors" on computers, allowing him to retrieve information.
The court noted he was 15 or 16 when the crimes occurred in 2012 and 2013, and issued a two-year suspended sentence. He is obliged, though, to repay 6,588 Euros ($7,282) for purchases he made.
Kivimaki had previously been linked to Lizard Squad, a notorious hacking ring involved in cyberattacks on Microsoft and Sony. Lizard Squad was not mentioned in Kivimaki's court documents.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:13:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi court sentences 24 to death in Tikrit massacre of military recruits</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Iraqi-court-sentences-24-to-death-in-Tikrit-massacre-of-military-recruits/8351436370048/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 5
| License Photo
BAGHDAD, July 8 (UPI) -- An Iraqi court sentenced 24 militants to death by hanging Wednesday for their role in the 2014 massacre of Iraqi military recruits at an air base formerly used by U.S. troops.
Hundreds of mostly Shi'ite Muslim recruits were shot to death in the northern Iraqi city of Tikrit in June 2014 after the Islamic State conquered Tikrit and seized the local Camp Speicher air base. Multimedia released by IS showed soldiers and recruits at Camp Speicher being assailed by gunmen.
The 24 men had joined more than 600 other militants who are believed to have taken part in the attack. Many are still at large. At the central court in Baghdad, the men pleaded not guilty, denying their involvement.
Human Rights Watch considers the killing at Camp Speicher to be the largest reported incident where
IS captured and subsequently executed soldiers.
In April, mass graves of Iraqi soldiers were found in Tikrit after the IS was driven out of the city. Forensic teams and experts dug up 12 grave sites. Some of the soldiers' hands were bound.
Information confirming the men's identities, whether they were affiliated with IS and where they were arrested was not released .
Four others were acquitted based on lack of evidence.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:55:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Website Voat rises as Reddit stumbles</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Website-Voat-rises-as-Reddit-stumbles/9941436371150/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
ZURICH, Switzerland, July 8 (UPI) -- The online service Voat surged in popularity this week after a backlash against its more established rival Reddit.
The website of the Swiss-based Voat was overloaded and crashed Wednesday. Though the smaller site frequently has issues, it's had even more difficulties in the last week as an influx of Redditors fleeing that site after the controversial firing of a popular administrator, Victoria Taylor . Taylor's responsibilities included hosting the popular "Ask Me Anything" (AMA) feature, which involves questions-and-answer sessions with famous and interesting people.
The reason for Taylor's departure was not specified, but a hectic AMA session last week in which Rev. Jesse Jackson discussed race relations, was not the cause, Reddit said.
"We screwed up. Not just on July 2, but also over the past several years," Reddit CEO Ellen Pao said in a post on the website. 'We haven't communicated well, and we have surprised moderators and the community with big changes. We have apologized and made promises to you, the moderators and the community, over many years, but time and again, we haven't delivered on them. When you've had feedback or requests, we haven't always been responsive. The mods and the community have lost trust in me and in us, the administrators of Reddit."
While Reddit stumbled and lost some its 163 million patrons, Voat enjoyed a surge of interest . Voat founders, students at the university of Zurich, have promised never to censor or ban any group on their site; a topic of criticism at Reddit under Pao's leadership.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:34:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trading resumes at New York Stock Exchange after technical glitch</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Trading-resumes-at-New-York-Stock-Exchange-after-technical-glitch/3871436372294/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 8
| License Photo
NEW YORK , July 8 (UPI) -- Trading resumed at the New York Stock Exchange around 3:10 p.m. local time Wednesday, after a technical issue took down the exchange for nearly four hours.
The exchange's website said they scheduled the NYSE MKT to resume orders at 3:05 p.m. and for the full exchange at 3:10 p.m.
Trading was halted around 11:32 p.m. due the technical glitch, around the same time the Wall Street Journal's website stopped working.
Nasdaq and other exchanges were operating normally.
Although the business day has been occupied with concern over Greece's financial position in Europe, a plunging stock market in China and the grounding of United Airlines planes, NYSE officials, while not offering much information, stressed the delay was caused by a technical issue.
"We're currently experiencing a technical issue that we're working to resolve as quickly as possible. We will be providing further updates as soon as we can, and are doing our utmost to produce a swift resolution, communicate thoroughly and transparently, and ensure a timely and orderly market reopen," a NYSE statement said earlier in the day.
The Department of Homeland Security noted "no sign of malicious activity" at the NYSE, a reference to any evidence of a cyberattack.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:28:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea to add Kim Jong Un's face to loyalty badges</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/North-Korea-to-add-Kim-Jong-Uns-face-to-loyalty-badges/1751436371901/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
North Korea to add Kim Jong Un's face to loyalty badges
The addition of Kim Jong Un is a sign the state is launching a full-scale idolization of the current leader.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 8, 2015 at 12:28 PM
Comments
SEOUL, July 8 (UPI) -- North Korean officials devoted to Kim Jong Un are to be awarded with a new loyalty badge that includes a portrait of the North Korean leader.
The badges currently feature North Korea founder Kim Il Sung and his son, the late Kim Jong Il, and are given exclusively to members of the North Korean elite, South Korean news outlet Newsis reported.
The addition of Kim Jong Un to the dual portraits of his father and biological grandfather is a sign the state is launching a full-scale idolization of the current leader.
An unidentified source familiar with the matter told South Korean newspaper Chosun Ilbo that Pyongyang's Mansudae Art Studio was working on the creation of a new loyalty badge in preparation for the Korean Workers' Party's 70th anniversary on Oct. 10.
Kim is planning to distribute the new badges to 3,000 priority members of the Workers' Party, as well as to youth members, the source said.
The general population is banned from wearing loyalty badges, as it denotes status. But the badges have reportedly been used as currency in impoverished North Korea.
The report follows announcements from North Korea state media that Kim paid his respects to Kim Il Sung at the founder's mausoleum, also known as the Kumsusan Palace of the Sun.
The former Kim died 21 years ago on July 8, 1994.
Kim attended the ceremony, with Pyongyang's military top brass in attendance.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:16:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>30 killed in Yemeni army mutiny</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/30-killed-in-Yemeni-army-mutiny/4861436367900/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
SANAA, Yemen, July 8 (UPI) -- At least 30 Yemeni soldiers were killed as they attempted a mutiny and defection to opposition rebels, military officials said.
Their deaths Tuesday came during clashes and airstrikes along Yemen's border with Saudi Arabia. Saudi airstrikes were called in after the soldiers attempted to defect to the side of Houthi rebels, backed by Iran and fighting troops loyal to ousted Yemeni President Abd Rabbu Mansour Hadi. In an unusual tactical move, Saudi fighter jets bombed Yemen's 23rd Mechanized Brigade, among the few Yemeni army bases which has not fallen into Houthi hands.
No official statement has been made by the pan-Arab coalition providing air support to Yemeni troops.
The Houthi forces were targets of a car bomb in Sanaa , Yemen's capital, Tuesday, which exploded at the historic al-Raoudh mosque. One person was killed, and the Islamic State took responsibility for the explosion. Four Houthis were also killed Tuesday by a car bomb at a police station in al-Baida province, an area in central Yemen with a strong al-Qaida presence.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:13:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kim Jong Un is paranoid about food safety, says source</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Kim-Jong-Un-is-paranoid-about-food-safety-says-source/8121436368705/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Kim Jong Un is paranoid about food safety, says source
North Koreas highest authorities now scrutinize fruits and vegetables cultivated in elite greenhouses.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 8, 2015 at 12:13 PM
Comments
SEOUL, July 8 (UPI) -- Every leaf of lettuce headed for North Korean leader Kim Jong Un 's dining table must pass meticulous inspection, and new food tests require the use of microscopes  signs Kim is paranoid about what he eats, according to a source.
North Korea's June 17 Farm in the Yongsong district of Pyongyang exclusively produces fruits and vegetables for Kim and North Korea's privileged class, South Korean news outlet Daily NK reported.
The farm was a gift from the late Kim Jong Il to his father Kim Il Sung in the 1980s. The greenhouses surrounded by mountains are known to grow North Korea's finest fruits and vegetables  as they are not cultivated for mass consumption.
Quality control, however, has never been as rigorous as it has become after Kim Jong Un fully assumed power in 2012.
North Korea's "highest authorities" now scrutinize fruits and vegetables cultivated in the greenhouses, the source told Daily NK.
"Produce headed for Kim Jong Un's table undergo a thorough cleaning. It then undergoes general, then specific inspections at a factory," the source said.
Food safety is a particular concern for Kim Jong Un and the farm only employs young, single North Koreans in their twenties of good class standing. Nearly all workers are graduates of elite universities in Pyongyang, and they are responsible for carefully inspecting the produce for "germs, toxins and health hazards," according to the source.
On Wednesday North Korea's state newspaper Rodong Sinmun ran an article of Kim's visit to the Pyongyang Vegetable Science Research Institute, where he said the facilities "were wonderful," while providing field guidance to workers.
Yonhap reported the work processes at the center were computer-automated and Kim had marveled at the innovations at the farm.
Kim's field guidance visits, however, have not always run so smoothly.
The manager of a terrapin farm was reportedly executed , after Kim expressed his displeasure with its condition.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:08:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>60 tourists rescued by Peruvian navy on Lake Titicaca</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/60-tourists-rescued-by-Peruvian-navy-on-Lake-Titicaca/8021436366886/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
TAQUILE, Peru, July 8 (UPI) -- About 60 tourists stranded on the Taquile Island in Lake Titicaca due to a storm were rescued by the Peruvian navy.
Foreign and Peruvian tourists were left stranded for several hours due to the nearly 40 miles per hour winds caused by the storm. The tourists were transported in patrol boats to the city of Puno near the Bolivian border, Peruvian officials announced Tuesday.
"We are frozen," Susan Fernndez, a tourist who called news outlet RPP Noticias after failing to communicate with proper authorities, said.
Naval commander Capt. Juan Jose Gonzalez said he regretted that the weather report, alarming the storm and recommended safety measures, were not communicated to the tourists beforehand. The navy prohibited ships returning from the Taquile Island to Puno due to the winds and high waves.
Gonzalez added that Taquile Island is safe and has tourist inns available for people who stay there.
At nearly 12,000 feet above sea level and about 3,300 square miles, Lake Titicaca, shared by Peru and Bolivia, is referred to as the highest navigable lake in the world.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:27:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10-foot floods recede in Venezuelan town allowing for recovery efforts</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/10-foot-floods-recede-in-Venezuelan-town-allowing-for-recovery-efforts/9561436360477/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
1 of 3
GUASDUALITO, Venezuela, July 8 (UPI) -- Flood waters up to 10 feet high have receded to at least three feet in the town of Guasdualito, Venezuela, allowing for recovery and aid efforts to help about 9,000 affected families.
There is no potable water or electricity and means of communication and access to food is limited in Guasdualito. The town in Venezuela's Apure state has been under state of emergency because of heavy rainfall last week that resulted in floods.
The town lies next to the Apure and Sarare rivers, which have risen due to the rain.
The town's residents are urging officials for water, food and medicine . Officials announced the distribution of 100 tons of food, personal hygiene materials, blankets, medicines and other aid on Tuesday.
Mobile emergency hospitals have been established with about 80 beds that can deal with 100 separate emergencies daily.
"Clinical towels, milk, diapers and other necessities were sent to supply those affected by the floods and we also have mobile clinics to help people in need," Legislative Council President Omaira Hernndez said.
The floods have affected about 200,000 hectares of productive agricultural land . The neighboring states of Mrida and Tchira have been alerted about possible flooding due to persistent heavy rains.
"The state has not been seriously affected, only have a state of alert in the city Rivas Davila," Mrida Director of Civil Protection Gerardo Rojas said.
Several municipalities in Tchira are under flood warning by Governor Jos Gregorio Vielma Mora.
About 40 Cuban doctors arrived to Guasdualito to render assistance in surgeries, hospitalizations and other means.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>$1.76 billion in assets seized in Italian anti-Mafia raid</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/176-billion-in-assets-seized-in-Italian-anti-Mafia-raid/2811436365871/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
PALERMO , Italy, July 8 (UPI) -- Over $1.76 billion in assets of Sicilian businessman Gaetano Virga and his family was seized Wednesday in an anti-Mafia raid, Italian police said.
Virga, a concrete magnate in Sicily , and his two brothers and two sisters, all in their 60s and 70s, are believed to have helped the Corleone family of the local Mafia in securing public construction contracts. Previously Virga was seen as a symbol of resistance to the Mafia, claiming extortion attempts in the past which led to the arrests of five people in the Sicilian town of Misilmeri.
The confiscation of assets totaled over 1.6 billion Euros ($1.76 billion) , Palermo police said, adding it was among the largest raids of its kind. Bank accounts, real estate and furniture were among the assets seized from the Virga family. The five members of the family worked as laborers in the 1980s but became billionaires through their involvement in the building trades and in criminal enterprises, Italian media reported.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:05:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Toy guns banned in Peshawar</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Toy-guns-banned-in-Peshawar/2101436360595/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Toy guns banned in Peshawar
By Tomas Monzon | July 8, 2015 at 11:05 AM
Comments
PESHAWAR, Pakistan, July 8 (UPI) -- The city of Peshawar, Pakistan prohibited Tuesday the sale of toy pellet guns that mimic real-life weapons used by extremist groups.
The toy guns are replicas of weapons such as the AK-47 automatic rifle but fire plastic or rubber pellets instead of bullets.
The city of Peshawar enacted a temporary ban on anyone selling or carrying these guns throughout the Muslim festival of Eid, which begins on July 18.
Under Section 144 , police have been instructed to deal strictly with those who do not comply. Parents have favored the ban.
The aim is to discourage children from mimicking the violent acts carried out by terrorist groups, such as the Taliban and al-Qaida, which ravaged the province of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa of which Peshawar is the regional capital. A December attack on a Peshawar school also left nearly 150 students and others dead.
Furthermore, injuries sustained by children that are hit by rubber pellets may also decline, although authorities do not keep figures on these incidents. Peshawar police said that while the ban will only last through the Eid festival, it may be extended if it proves popular with the public.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:52:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Africa's taxi drivers battle Uber for business</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/South-Africas-taxi-drivers-battle-Uber-for-business/4711436364651/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
JOHANNESBURG, South Africa, July 8 (UPI) -- Tensions in Johannesburg, South Africa, between taxi drivers and the ride-share service Uber have let to Uber requests for police protection.
The heavily-regulated taxi drivers, whose organization stems from South Africa's days of apartheid and black citizens' inability to find available taxis, object to Uber's capability , through its cellphone app, to undercut taxi fares in the city. Several Uber users last week reported harassment by taxi drivers, to the point they abandoned their Uber appointments and took taxis around the city.
"Recent intimidation...only underlines why people are increasingly choosing safe, reliable alternatives like Uber," the San Francisco-based company, which operates in 57 countries, wrote on its website.
At stake is the hard-earned patronage of taxi riders in a city which, for years, neglected the needs of the majority of its residents. The tense climate has become a battle between entrenched, certified taxi drivers and an upstart business model which typically undercuts the cost of a ride by two-thirds.
Uber customer Melinda Bason told of an incident in which a driver was frightened away from driving her and her husband, saying, "They (taxi drivers) grabbed the keys from the ignition, intimidating him. There was a gun involved and intimidation with that weapon."
Alon Lits, Uber executive in Johannesburg, said Uber drivers remain working, although "there have been isolated incidences. It's not widespread."
Uber has asked the Johannesburg police to protect its drivers, who do not carry weapons.
The backlash from taxi drivers is an indication of Uber's growth in South Africa; two million Uber fares were requested in the first half of 2015, compared to one million in all of 2014. It is also typical of cities around the world, where Uber's arrival has signaled fights with regulators and competition.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:31:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chile moves to legalize marijuana</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Chile-moves-to-legalize-marijuana/5921436364020/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Chile moves to legalize marijuana
By Tomas Monzon | July 8, 2015 at 10:31 AM
Comments
| License Photo
SANTIAGO, Chile, July 8 (UPI) -- Part of Chile's Congress has approved a law to decriminalize the growing and private consumption of marijuana for spiritual, medicinal and recreational use.
Were the bill to be approved by the Senate , Chilean individuals would be able to carry less than 10 grams of any cannabis variant, as well as be able to cultivate a maximum of six plants. Individuals who need marijuana for medicinal purposes must have prescriptions.
The bill passed the lower house of Congress by a wide margin of 68 in favor and 39 against. It will now be presented before a health commission and then the Senate for approval.
Planting, selling and transporting marijuana is currently punishable by up to 15 years in prison.
The changes would modify the country's Sanitary Code and law 20.000, which substitutes law 19.366 that prohibited the trafficking of cannabis and similar substances.
A member of Chilean President Michelle Bachelet 's coalition, Karol Cariola, said the vote was a big step forward for those who refuse to be persecuted for access to a medicine that they can grow themselves.
Were the bill to pass the Senate, Chile would join Uruguay, Jamaica, Colombia, Ecuador, Costa Rica and Mexico in featuring marijuana-friendly legislation. Uruguay created its legal market for cannabis in 2013.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:15:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Toyota executive Julie Hamp released with no charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Former-Toyota-executive-Julie-Hamp-released-with-no-charges/7271436355885/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Former Toyota executive Julie Hamp released with no charges
By Amy R. Connolly | July 8, 2015 at 10:15 AM
Comments
| License Photo
TOKYO, July 8 (UPI) -- Toyoto's highest ranking female executive was released from prison without charges Wednesday after allegations she imported painkillers into the country without permission.
Julie Hamp, head of public relations at the Japanese automaker, walked out of a Tokyo police building Wednesday, weeks after her June 18 arrest on suspicion of importing the narcotic painkiller oxycodone, a tightly controlled substance in Japan.
Suspects, in Japan, can be held for up to 23 days without charges or the possibility of bail.
Prosecutors said they had enough evidence to charge Hamp but felt justice had otherwise been served. They added that Hamp arranged with her father to have 57 oxycodone pills sent air mail from the United States to a Tokyo hotel in June, which is illegal in the country. Hamp, a 55-year-old American, resigned June 30 amid the allegations.
"She has already gone through a certain level of social punishment," an official from the Tokyo District Public Prosecutor's Office told the Wall Street Journal, adding prosecutors took her resignation into consideration.
Toyota President Akio Toyoda defended Hamp throughout the incident, calling her an important member of the Toyota team and a close friend. Hamp was appointed three months ago as head of public relations at the world's biggest automaker as the first non-Japanese Toyota executive to be based in Japan.
Toyota named Shigeru Hayakawa, a senior managing officer and board member, as Hamp's replacement. Hamp is free to return to the U.S. without a formal criminal record.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:58:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Analysts: China's stock market tumble cause for alarm</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Analysts-Chinas-stock-market-tumble-cause-for-alarm/1341436363024/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Analysts: China's stock market tumble cause for alarm
Government regulations against massive sell-offs had little impact on Wednesday.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 8, 2015 at 9:58 AM
Comments
| License Photo
BEIJING, July 8 (UPI) -- China's stock markets continued to fall precipitously on Wednesday in what regulators described as market "panic"  marked by irrational sell-offs  that one analyst has said could dwarf the crisis in Greece.
Beijing took aim at tumbling markets  a move that had little impact as the Shanghai Composite Index fell 5.9 percent and the Shenzhen Component Index was down nearly 3 percent, The Guardian reported . Within the first 10 minutes of trading on Wednesday, listed companies in both exchanges that had shed 10 percent, the daily limit, had their shares automatically suspended.
More than half the companies listed in Shanghai and Shenzhen exchanges, or 1,400, filed for a halt in trading to prevent further losses.
The vast majority, or 80 percent, of stock investors in China are small, retail speculators, some who have borrowed heavily to buy and sell equity.
South Korean news agency Yonhap reported ebullient but inexperienced brokers and investors are paying the price for the sudden downturn in China's markets.
Many were lured into quick investments after China relaxed restrictions and permitted individuals to open up to 20 accounts in their name.
Some who fell heavily into debt have committed suicide, according to Chinese press. One man in his 30s reportedly jumped from the 22nd floor of an apartment building after borrowing more than $1 million from a bank. After losing it all in a bad investment in a Chinese rail company, the man killed himself June 10 in Hunan province.
Trading on margin, or borrowed money, is expected to have extensive impact on China's falling stock markets, said Christopher Balding, a professor of economics at Peking University.
"It probably has a long way to go. Margin loans basically rose much faster, and they are not falling nearly as fast, margin debt is not falling nearly as fast as the market is falling. What that is telling us is that there is a lot of stock that needs to be sold that hasn't been sold yet," Balding told The Guardian.
China's debt now stands at $20 trillion, or 300 percent of GDP, and a downward spiral could make Greece "feel like a sideshow," said Ruchir Sharma, a financial analyst with Morgan Stanley Investment Management.
While China has been the greatest contributor to global growth this decade, Greece's economy is about the size of Bangladesh or Vietnam, Sharma said .
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:31:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece submits bailout request; PM Alexis Tsipras promises 'credible reform'</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/08/Greece-submits-bailout-request-PM-Alexis-Tsipras-promises-credible-reform/9231436351936/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 9
| License Photo
ATHENS, Greece, July 8 (UPI) -- Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras has urged Europe to stand together and called for a deal to be reached as the deadline for the country's financial reform proposals nears.
Tsipras spoke at a debate in the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France, on Wednesday, where he said Greece became a "laboratory for austerity " that "all of us have to accept, has not been a success," to both cheers and boos from the audience.
"Let's not let Europe be divided," he said, also promising to deliver "credible reforms."
Greece quietly submitted a formal request for a new bailout aid package during the European Parliament debate. The new amount for the bailout has not been requested, but it could easily be more than $55 billion.
The Greek Ministry of Economy, Infrastructures, Maritime Affairs and Tourism released a statement reassuring citizens and tourists "that there are adequate food supplies in the market" and that their prices would remain stable.
Greek people "stood up and were counted -- we have to listen to what they said," Tsipras said of Sunday's referendum. Voters were asked whether they accepted the terms of an international bailout submitted by the European Commission, the International Monetary Fund and the European Central Bank. Some 61 percent of Greek participants voted "no."
The country's government must present its new proposals by the end of Thursday ahead of a Sunday summit of all 28 members of the European Union that will decide Greece's fate.
"The stark reality is that we only have four days left to find an ultimate agreement," President of the European Council Donald Tusk told the European lawmakers.
Negotiations must reach an agreement over the country's $356 billion debt or Greece is threatened with expulsion from the Eurozone economic bloc.
European Union Economy Commissioner Pierre Moscovici told BBC News that Europe wanted to stop Greece from falling out of the euro.
"The commission does not want a Grexit... would be a terrible failure, and we are fighting to avoid it," Moscovici said, but added that proposals must come from Greece
"They know what they have to do, they know what we expect," he said.
Banks have been shut down since June 30 in Greece. People have only been able to withdraw up to $66 a day from ATMs due to capital controls.
Greece has a $3.3 billion payment due to the European Central Bank on July 20. On June 30, Greece became the first developed nation in history to default on a loan from the IMF.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 06:21:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Human Rights Watch: Kim Jong Un must stand trial for abuses</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/Human-Rights-Watch-Kim-Jong-Un-must-stand-trial-for-abuses/7261436324021/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
Human Rights Watch: Kim Jong Un must stand trial for abuses
The NGO said the North Korean leader has strengthened a rule of terror that was formed during his grandfathers time.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 7, 2015 at 11:21 PM
Comments
| License Photo
SEOUL, July 7 (UPI) -- North Korean leader Kim Jong Un must stand trial before an international tribunal for his crimes against humanity, a deputy director at Human Rights Watch said Wednesday.
Phil Robertson made the statement on the same day North Korea commemorates the 21st death anniversary of North Korea founder Kim Il Sung , Yonhap reported.
Robertson told Radio Free Asia that human rights violations against the North Korean people have been committed for three generations under the dynastic Kim regime and the present-day leader must stand trial for ongoing abuses.
According to Human Rights Watch, North Koreans continue to be arbitrarily detained, tortured and purged. Those who fall out of favor with the regime must endure hard labor and other forms of human rights violations, Voice of America reported.
Robertson said that while the late Kim Il Sung died without paying for his crimes, the living Kim Jong Un, who has committed the same crimes against humanity, must be taken to trial.
The Human Rights Watch deputy director said Kim Jong Un has strengthened a rule of terror that was formed during his grandfather's time. Secret police, concentration camps, unquestioned worship of the leader and public executions designed to instill fear are just some of the tools the North Korean leader employs to keep his position of power.
South Korea recently issued a report that states North Korea executed 1,382 people between 2000 and 2014 for a broad array of crimes that ranged from anti-state activities to viewing South Korean pornographic material.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:46:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Analysts: U.S. could do more for SKorea, Japan relations</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/Analysts-US-could-do-more-for-SKorea-Japan-relations/5071436310952/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Analysts: U.S. could do more for SKorea, Japan relations
By Elizabeth Shim | July 7, 2015 at 7:46 PM
Comments
| License Photo
WASHINGTON, July 7 (UPI) -- The United States could take a more active approach toward facilitating South Korea-Japan relations as Seoul and Tokyo struggle with disagreements over history and territory, a panel of analysts said on Tuesday.
In a panel co-hosted by the Global Peace Foundation at the Center for Strategic and International Studies in Washington, Michael Auslin of the American Enterprise Institute said the South Korea-Japan relationship is in a "perilous state."
"We're talking about things that shouldn't even be remarked upon," Auslin said, referring to a last-minute deal between the two neighbors that allowed Japan to register Meiji-era industrial buildings as UNESCO World Heritage sites on Sunday.
South Korea had initially opposed Japan's U.N. bid because the sites used Korean forced laborers who were recruited into Japan's wartime industry.
Seoul later came around when Tokyo agreed to recognize the employment of Korean forced laborers.
Relations between the two of the closest U.S. allies, however, were not always so frayed with bitter accusations, according to Sheila Smith, a senor fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations.
Smith said South Korean President Kim Dae-jung achieved a breakthrough beginning in 1998 when he spoke in Japan and delivered a message of reconciliation  referring to the 20th century as a "blip on the screen" of a longstanding relationship between the Japanese archipelago and the Korean peninsula that dates back to antiquity.
"There's not been a Korean leader since then who came close to that," said Smith.
Analysts agree a 2012 visit to the disputed islets of Dokdo, known as Takeshima in Japan, by then-President Lee Myung-bak has been responsible for a downturn in South Korea-Japan relations.
Smith said a change took hold among Japanese regarding South Korea after the presidential visit, and that public opinion has not recovered since Park Geun-hye assumed the presidency in 2013.
While North Korea remains the broader regional crisis that Seoul, Tokyo and Washington are quick to address through close coordination, Smith said South Korean political gestures have led to a feeling of "betrayal" in Japan, despite the brisk business and cultural exchanges that are ongoing between the two industrialized democracies.
"It's tapping into a broader anxiety in Japan about geostrategic change and isolation," Smith said.
"There's this kind of hurt attached to it."
The analysts agreed the U.S. should not mediate the difficult issues from history, but rather make efforts to bring about better relations between the allies by giving the conversation a higher public profile at home.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:14:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>President Obama, Vietnamese general secretary pledge deeper U.S.-Vietnam partnership</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/President-Obama-Vietnamese-general-secretary-pledge-deeper-US-Vietnam-partnership/6211436302375/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 8
| License Photo
WASHINGTON, July 7 (UPI) -- President Barack Obama and Vietnam's General Secretary Nguyen Phu Trong pledged a deeper partnership during an Oval Office meeting Tuesday.
The Hill quoted Trong, the 71-year old head of Vietnam's communist party, as saying he and Obama "agreed on the major directions for moving our relationship forward to make it more substantive, more positive, to build the mutual trust and cooperation between the two countries."
Obama agreed, saying the meeting was "an excellent opportunity for us to deepen our discussions around our vision for a comprehensive partnership."
Following the end of the Vietnam War in 1975, the United States normalized relations with Vietnam two decades ago and have since allied on recent issues, such as the Trans-Pacific Partnership (TPP) agreement and territorial disputes with China. Last year, the United States partially lifted a ban on weapons sales to Vietnam, allowing for weapons and weapon platforms for maritime security and surveillance capabilities.
During the meeting Obama reportedly told Trong he would visit Vietnam, and The Hill quoted Trong as saying he was glad the president accepted his invitation.
"Like in any relations between two countries in the world, Vietnam and the U.S. have differences on a number of issues such as perception on democracy, human rights and trade," NPR quoted Trong as saying in a written statement Friday. "To resolve differences, I believe the most effective way would be open and constructive dialogues to better understand each other so that differences won't become hurdles to the overall bilateral relations."
Vice President Joe Biden echoed that sentiment Tuesday. "We have different systems, but there's so much we can do together," The Hill quoted Biden as saying.
The meeting comes as Chinese media reports that officers in the People's Liberation Army Air Force are seeking a new long-range strategic bomber.
Citing a report by the Kanwa Defense Review, a Canada-based defense and weapons publication, China Daily reported PLA officers met and discussed creation of a long-range bomber capable of flying at least 8,000 kilometers, or 4,970 miles, without refueling.
Such a bomber would enable China to strike at two "island chains" that make up a layered maritime defensive perimeter, the first being islands stretching from Japan in the north and Taiwan and the Philippines in the south, and the second being farther east, stretching north from the Bonin Islands to the Marianas and the Caroline Islands to the south.
China last month announced it had almost completed a land reclamation project involving the creation of artificial islands in the South China Sea.
The masses are formed through the dredging of sand on top of coral reefs in the Spratly Islands, which the Philippines, Malaysia, Brunei, Taiwan and Vietnam claim as their own.
China claims the Spratly Islands as sovereign territory and says the project does not violate international law, while leaders from the Philippines, Malaysia and other countries with competing claims have condemned the project.
"We strongly oppose [China's] use of intimidation, coercion or force, as well as any unilateral actions that seek to change the status quo, such as large-scale land reclamation," the Group of Seven, or G7 nations, wrote in a statement last month.
While the United States has expressed concern over the issue, it has not formally sided with any one country that claims the islands.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 23:28:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Shabab militants suspected of attack killing 14 people in Kenya</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/Al-Shabab-militants-suspected-of-attack-killing-14-people-in-Kenya/5991436298105/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
1 of 4
SOKO MBUZI, Kenya, July 7 (UPI) -- Al-Shabab militants are suspected of attacking a village near Kenya's northeastern border with Somalia on Tuesday, killing 14 people and injuring 11 others, local officials said.
Mandera County Commissioner Alex Ole Nkoyo told Kenya's Standard Digital the gunmen opened fire around 1 a.m. in Soko Mbuzi village where mostly non-local quarry workers live near Mandera, Kenya.
He said the militants also used grenades to attack the victims.
"All indications are that they were Al-Shabaab militants. They destroyed metal grilled doors before they bombed the houses and opened fire on the innocent victims," Nkoyo said.
Witnesses said the attackers planted grenades at the entrance to tents, then threw gas bombs on the tents, causing the grenades to explode.
Kenya Red Cross officials told NDTV 11 people were taken for treatment at a local hospital, and some of those with more serious injuries were transferred by airplane to a hospital in Nairobi.
The al-Qaida-linked al-Shabab, which has been fighting to overthrow the government in Somalia, has increasingly expanded its attacks to neighboring Kenya.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
