<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="UPI">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:53:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia's list of 'undesirable' NGOs fuels fears of crackdown</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Russias-list-of-undesirable-NGOs-fuels-fears-of-crackdown/7431436445159/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Russia's list of 'undesirable' NGOs fuels fears of crackdown
By Jared M. Feldschreiber | July 9, 2015 at 3:53 PM
Comments
| License Photo
MOSCOW, July 9 (UPI) -- A list of "undesirable" civil rights organizations by the upper house of Russia's parliament is fueling perceptions of a crackdown on "foreign agents."
One non-governmental organization on the list, the Dynasty Foundation, which aided young and aspiring mathematicians and scientists, abruptly announced this week it was "liquidating its funds."
Soon after Vladimir Putin reassumed the presidency in 2012, he approved a law tightening controls on NGOs funded from abroad, forcing any that engage in "political activity" to register as a "foreign agent" -- a Cold War term.
In recent weeks, the Russian parliament's upper chamber called on authorities to blacklist 12 NGOs, including the Freedom House, the National Endowment for Democracy, George Soros ' Open Society and the Ukrainian World Congress -- all deemed "undesirable."
Putin signed the controversial bill into law in late May.
Dynasty's founder, Dmitry Zimin, who also started the mobile networking company Beeline, funded the foundation since its inception in 2002, with bank accounts that were kept abroad.
But this week, he announced the foundation's closing.
Putin's spokesman Dmitry Peskov told reporters on Wednesday that "no restrictions were placed on the Dynasty Fund. [The organization] could have continued its activity and we regret the fund's management decided to close it."
Meanwhile, an American businessman working as a professor at a Russian university was fired, then rehired in another position.
Kendrick White, who was teaching as vice rector at Lobachevsky State University of Nizhny Novgorod, was initially fired on June 30. The university said in a statement he was let go as part of a "restructuring of the management system."
But White had been criticized on a daily program by Sputnik News head Dmitry Kiselyov as playing a "harmful" role in Russia. Russian authorities say they are concerned that some of the country's best students will be hired by some of the most prestigious institutions and centers abroad.
"How it happened that such a position could be held by a U.S. citizen, a businessman from Washington, is still not clear," Kiselyov said in a report on White's career , which included setting up one of the first training young Russian entrepreneurs.
White denied such accusations in an interview with Kommersant .
"We we recently went to the U.S. with a group of Nizhny Novgorod students; they showed their projects and came back, no one stayed in the States," White said. "I have neither the authority nor the possibility to take one out of the country. But it is not necessary  we are against the brain drain. We want Nizhny Novgorod to develop, so that other regions of Russia take up this example, as well."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:47:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Saud al-Faisal dies at 75</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Former-Saudi-Foreign-Minister-Prince-Saud-al-Faisal-dies-at-75/7321436468905/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
RIYADH, Saudi Arabia, July 9 (UPI) -- Saudi Arabia's former foreign minister, Prince Saud al-Faisal died Thursday two months after he was replaced on the job, Saudi officials said. He was 75.
The cause of al-Faisal's death has not been revealed, though the Saudi information ministry said an official statement on the matter would be released later Thursday.
Al-Faisal was the longest-serving foreign minister in the world, spending 40 years in the position before he was replaced in April by Adel al-Jubeir, Al Arabiya reported. He served under four kings and was considered the be well-liked and respected within diplomatic circles, Al Jazeera reported.
The U.S. Embassy in Saudi Arabia tweeted a message from Secretary of State John Kerry saying, "Saud was not only the longest serving foreign minister, but was also one of the wisest."
Though the cause of his death is unknown, al-Faisal had a number of health complaints in recent years, including chronic back pain for which he had several surgeries.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:00:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia urges prompt lifting of Iran arms embargo in nuclear deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Russia-urges-prompt-lifting-of-Iran-arms-embargo-in-nuclear-deal/5931436458349/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Russia urges prompt lifting of Iran arms embargo in nuclear deal
By Jared M. Feldschreiber | July 9, 2015 at 3:00 PM
Comments
UFA, Russia, July 9 (UPI) -- Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov urged Thursday that the arms embargo on Iran be among the first sanctions lifted as a potential Iranian nuclear deal continues to take shape.
Speaking at the BRICS summit, Lavrov said there are no insurmountable problems left as the nuclear negotiations among the P5+1 group of world powers continue. In addition to Iran, the P5+1 is comprised of Britain, China, Russia, the United States and France.
"We state that arms embargo against Iran should be, in fact, lifted among the first sanctions restrictions," Lavrov said, according to Tass. "The second package of sanctions was adopted when Iran refused to hold talks and was motivated by the U.N. Security Council's wish to convince Iran, politically and economically, to sit down at the negotiating table."
Lavrov underscored that lifting the arms embargo would enable Iran "to increase its defense capability against terrorism," a reference to the Islamic State.
Meanwhile, Russian President Vladimir Putin met with Iranian President Hassan Rouhani on Thursday in Ufa as part of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, in which Iran has observers status. They discussed military and nuclear co-operation, as well as the fight against the IS.
While Tehran has contended from the outset of the talks that its nuclear program is for peaceful purposes, prominent members of Congress and Israel, the United States' most stalwart ally in the Mideast, have rejected that claim. U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry told reporters Thursday in Vienna that some of tough issues "remain unsolved."
"We will not rush, and we will not be rushed, [but] we are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever," Kerry said.
His comments came a few hours ahead of a soft deadline the Obama administration had set for the talks, Politico reported.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:02:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea may have capacity to produce anthrax, analyst says</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/North-Korea-may-have-capacity-to-produce-anthrax-analyst-says/5271436464375/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
North Korea may have capacity to produce anthrax, analyst says
An analysis of photos of Kim Jong Un from June indicated the leader was responding to news of anthrax shipments to U.S. bases in South Korea from a secretive biotech institute.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 9, 2015 at 2:02 PM
Comments
SEOUL, July 9 (UPI) -- A U.S. researcher said Thursday that North Korea has the capacity to produce military-size batches of anthrax through a pesticide research center.
Melissa Hanham of the James Martin Center for Nonproliferation Studies said Pyongyang Bio-technical Institute, dedicated to researching pest killers, was a dual-use facility that could produce biological weapons, South Korean news agency Yonhap reported.
The research institute operates under the supervision of Korean People's Army Unit 810, a key division of Pyongyang's military, highly regarded by North Korean leader Kim Jong Un .
Hanham said an analysis of photos of Kim, published in North Korea's state newspaper Rodong Sinmun in June, indicated the leader was responding to news of anthrax shipments to U.S. bases in South Korea from the biotech institute.
Her analysis revealed the state-of-the-art equipment appearing in the photographs also were weapon-making facilities, South Korean news network YTN reported.
In an update on 38 North , a Johns Hopkins University website dedicated to North Korea issues, Hanham said CABI, a Swiss group that runs agricultural aid programs around the world, helped North Korea establish a pilot facility for exploring pesticides in 2005.
Pesticide research in North Korea was established with funding from the Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation, and aid included Chinese equipment to Pyongyang.
"Unfortunately, this pilot facility could also be operated to produce anthrax and was possibly a training ground in preparation for the large-scale facility that Kim Jong Un recently toured," Hanham said.
Yonhap reported Kim Jong Un's visit to the research institute could be seen as a move to quietly threaten South Korea and the United States.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:00:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israel: two Israelis held hostage in Gaza</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Israel-two-Israelis-held-hostage-in-Gaza/1671436463207/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
TEL AVIV, Israel, July 9 (UPI) -- Two Israeli citizens are hostages in Gaza , the Israeli Defense Ministry announced Thursday.
The ministry said it had "credible evidence" Avraham Mangisto, 28, an Israeli citizen of Ethiopian descent, is being held "against his will" in Gaza, as well as another citizen, unidentified except that he is of Arab descent. Mangisto crossed from Israel to Gaza on Sept. 7, 2014; an Israeli court lifted media restrictions on reporting his disappearance Thursday. It added Israel had reached out to Hamas , Gaza's political leadership, for information on Mangisto, as well as to international mediators to assure his well-being.
Hamas officials offered no response to the announcement.
Israel has taken unusual precautions to ensure its citizens, especially its soldiers, are not apprehended by Hamas in Gaza and taken hostage, after the 50-day war between Gaza and Israel in 2014.
"We are making every possible effort to bring Mr. Mengisto back. It is Israel's moral obligation, even though the guy is not a soldier and passed of his own free will. Hamas has a responsibility to bring him back safely," commented Israeli Parliament member Yaacov Perry.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:55:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Susan Rice chides South Sudan leaders for 'self-inflicted disaster'</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Susan-Rice-chides-South-Sudan-leaders-for-self-inflicted-disaster/6111436461061/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
WASHINGTON, July 9 (UPI) -- U.S. National Security Adviser Susan Rice criticized South Sudan's leadership Thursday, saying it's directly responsible for the nation's civil war.
President Salva Kiir and rebel leader and former Vice President Riek Machar are responsible for South Sudan's return to war after its 2011 independence, she said.
In a statement acknowledging South Sudan's fourth anniversary as a country, Rice said the government has "abdicated its responsibilities, failed to protect its citizens and squandered its legitimacy. The government and rebels are committing appalling crimes against innocent women, children and the elderly. President Kiir and Riek Machar and their cronies are personally responsible for this new war and self-inflicted disaster. And only leaders on both sides can end this violence."
A civil war, between government troops and rebels loyal to Machar, has blighted South Sudan for the past 18 months. Earlier this week, the United Nations reported 1.5 million South Sudanese have been displaced by the conflict, with another 730,000 moved to neighboring countries.
The report noted a "new brutality and intensity" to the conflict beginning in April, when the army launched an offensive against opposition-held territory in the oil-rich Unity and Upper Nile states of the country. It cited the murder of women and children, rapes, looting and burning of homes as some of the consequences of the conflict.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:41:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thai consulate in Turkey attacked following deportation of Uighurs</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Thai-consulate-in-Turkey-attacked-following-deportation-of-Uighurs/7581436451240/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thai consulate in Turkey attacked following deportation of Uighurs
By Tomas Monzon | July 9, 2015 at 1:41 PM
1 of 2
| License Photo
ISTANBUL, Turkey, July 9 (UPI) -- Reports surfaced Thursday of an attack on the Thai consulate in Istanbul, Turkey following the deportation of 100 Uighurs from Thailand to China.
Nine protesters identifying themselves as the East Turkestan Education Association stormed the offices late on Wednesday night but did not injure anyone. They damaged the doors to the building, pulled down the consulate sign outside and damaged the interior furniture. The Thai flag was also removed as the building was ransacked, with stones being lodged at the exterior and files being littered on the street.
Security at the consulate was enhanced Thursday morning.
Through Facebook , The Royal Thai Embassy also urged local Thais to refrain from displays of nationality and avoid arguments with Turks on the subject of Uighurs.
On Thursday, Thailand confirmed and stood by its decision to deport the 100 individuals, claiming that it followed appropriate humanitarian procedures despite the disapproval of rights groups.
The Uighurs had presented themselves as Turkish upon entering Thailand. However, their Chinese nationality was confirmed, which formed the basis for Turkey's choice to deport them.
Human Rights Watch (HRW) says the Uighurs will probably face persecution, abuse and human rights violations in China. HRW has been critical of Thailand and Cambodia in the past for sending Uighurs to China given the way they are treated there.
The deportation led to a meeting between Turkish and Chinese officials on whether China imposed restrictions on Uighurs during Ramadan. Beijing claimed there were none, but protests still sparked over the debate and sullied the otherwise improving relationship between China and Turkey.
The indigenous Uighurs are ethnically Turkic Muslims that make up almost half of China's Xinjiang population. They used to be the majority , but ever since China abolished East Turkestan in 1949, the Uighurs have feared an erosion of their culture as droves of Han Chinese continue to immigrate. Forty percent of Xinjiang is now Chinese, which the Uighurs feel threatens their Islam-based lifestyle.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:06:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan closes stock market, offices in light of Typhoon</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Taiwan-closes-stock-market-offices-in-light-of-Typhoon/8521436459305/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
TAIPEI, Taiwan, July 9 (UPI) -- Taiwan prepared for the arrival of Typhoon Chan-hom Thursday by closing schools and offices and setting up command centers.
The typhoon is moving towards the northern part of the island, with maximum sustained winds of 155 kilometers per hour (96 mph) and gusts reaching 191 kilometers per hour (118 mph), the Central Weather Bureau said , adding ships should increase their alert. Although no mudslides have thus far been reported, torrential rain canceled flights at Taipei's Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport, and officials said more cancellations were expected.
Severe rain is expected in the southern part of the island, and mainland China, which is in the typhoon's path.
The Taiwan Stock Exchange will be closed Friday.
About 38,000 army personnel and rescue workers are on standby notice, the Ministry of National Defense said.
A 2009 typhoon killed at least 670 people in Taiwan, making it the deadliest in the country's history.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:06:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Firms call for resumption of tourism to North Korea</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Firms-call-for-resumption-of-tourism-to-North-Korea/8251436460201/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
Firms call for resumption of tourism to North Korea
South Korean corporations had incurred losses after the suspension of tourism that came after the May 24 sanctions.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 9, 2015 at 1:06 PM
Comments
SEOUL, July 9 (UPI) -- South Korean companies that have faced losses since the suspension of South Korea tourism to North Korea are urging programs to resume after a seven-year hiatus.
The tours of a panoramic mountain range in North Korea's Mount Kumgang Tourist Region stopped when a South Korean tourist was fatally shot in July 2008, but representatives from 49 South Korean firms called for a resolution on Tuesday, Voice of America reported .
"North and South Korea should resolve political differences that benefit neither and engage in a dialogue quickly with genuine interest," Lee Jong -heung, head of an association of the companies said at a press conference in Seoul.
Lee said South Korean corporations had incurred losses after the suspension of tourism that came after the May 24 sanctions, a South Korea measure against the North after the sinking of a South Korean navy warship in 2010.
The accident killed 46 South Korean seamen, and an international team of investigators concluded a North Korean torpedo was responsible for the attack.
South Korean newspaper Kyunghyang Shinmun reported Hyundai Asan, the construction arm of conglomerate Hyundai Group, had incurred a cumulative loss of $892.6 million.
In addition to its tour programs of the Kumgang Tourist Region, Hyundai Asan operates travel to and from Kaesong, near the Korean demilitarized zone
Due to South Korea sanctions, the Kumgang program has incurred a loss of $770.2 million and the lower-profile Kaesong program has suffered $122.4 million in lost revenue.
A Hyundai Asan spokesman told Kyunghyang the revenue lost was calculated using past statistics. Before tourism was suspended, 300,000 South Koreans visited Mount Kumgang on an annual basis, and Kaesong drew 100,000 tourists every year.
The firm also has had to drastically cut staff, and has laid off 75 percent of its workforce due to the North-South standoff, leaving 262 workers in a business that once employed 1,000.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:46:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia building anti-terrorism wall on Libyan border</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Tunisia-building-anti-terrorism-wall-on-Libyan-border/9361436457859/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
TUNIS, Tunisia, July 9 (UPI) -- A wall between Tunisia and Libya is under construction, Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essid said in an interview Wednesday.
The 100-mile wall on the border is one of the security measures Tunisia has taken to separate itself from Islamist militants harbored in Libya. Extremist acts, including the shooting of 21 people in March at a Tunis, Tunisia, museum, and July's killing of 38 at a resort beach at Sousse in June, have shaken Tunisia's security and economy.
A state of emergency was declared , and 1,300 armed guards are now patrolling Tunisia's beach resort communities.
The barrier is already under construction between Ras Jedir, on the Mediterranean coast, and the town of Dhehiba, and will be completed by the end of 2015, Essid said. He acknowledged, though, that securing the entire 310-miole border with Libya will be "difficult, very difficult." He told a national television audience Wednesday Tunisia was at war with terrorism, the porous border and Libya's political instability the country's major problems.
"We have 500 kilometers of borders with Libya, most of them are desert and we need special technical equipment to control those borders that we do not have. Unfortunately, Libya is not doing its role in fighting terrorism. There are many armed organizations within Libya that are like states within a state, there are two governments, one recognized internationally and one that is not, plus there is foreign interference from different countries with different agendas."
Tunisians comprise the largest percentage of foreigners who have gone to Iraq and Syria to fight for the Islamic State. Although Tunisia is hailed as an example of democracy in the Arab world, the government has not stopped excessive unemployment, reformed its oppressive system of state security or prevented rogue preachers from stirring animosities.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:41:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis to visit Bolivia's most dangerous prison</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Pope-Francis-to-visit-Bolivias-most-dangerous-prison/2771436448227/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 2
| License Photo
SANTA CRUZ, Bolivia, July 9 (UPI) -- Pope Francis will visit the Palmasola Rehabilitation Center, Bolivia's most violent prison where guards only secure the outside perimeter, as part of his three-nation South American tour.
The prison is notoriously crowded and violent . Francis will spend about an hour visiting the 5,000 inmates in Palmasola, located in Santa Cruz -- Bolivia's most populated city.
Accused drug dealers, rapists and murderers are being held in Palmasola, where there are no guards within its walls and where there is an apparent lucrative criminal economy. About 90 percent of Bolivia's 12,000 prisoners are awaiting trial .
There is a pavilion for women and children to visit inmates. Some families live within the prison's walls.
In 2013, violence between inmates in Palmasola left at least 31 dead, including a 2-year-old child. Inmates in Palmasola who do not have enough money sleep on the floor.
Visiting prisons is a tradition Francis has kept since he was Archbishop of Buenos Aires, Argentina. The pope arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday after visiting Ecuador.
The pope drank Trimate, a tea made of coca leaves, chamomile and anise seeds, on his plane ride to La Paz, Bolivia's capital, as to prevent altitude sickness .
La Paz sits about 13,000 feet above sea level and the air is about 30 percent thinner, which can cause fatigue, headaches and shortness of breath. The coca plant is illegal in the United States, but the use of its tea leaves is part of Bolivian tradition, acting as a mild stimulant, rather than for the illicit use of chemically creating cocaine.
The altitude of La Paz was especially worrying for the pope's visit, as Francis had part of his lung removed due to an infection as a child. The pope will head to Paraguay next.
Inmates have been preparing for the pope's visit by creating a walkway made of rocks, cleaning the prison walls and clearing huge piles of garbage. Prisoners have assured Francis will be safe.
Francis' South American tour is the first time the Argentine-born pope will visit three nations in a single trip.
Francis will visit Cuba in September and then the United States for nearly a week. He will tour and give speeches at stops in Washington, D.C., New York City and Philadelphia.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:22:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds of animals relocated in Mexico as circus show ban takes effect</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Hundreds-of-animals-relocated-in-Mexico-as-circus-show-ban-takes-effect/2771436445234/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
1 of 3
MEXICO CITY, July 9 (UPI) -- Nearly 1,100 wild animals, including elephants, bears and tigers, will be relocated from circuses throughout Mexico to zoos and conservation centers after a ban on public wild animal exhibitions took effect on Wednesday.
Of the 1,091 total animals to be relocated, 87 will be exported and 69 will remain under the supervision of circuses, according to Mexico's Federal Attorney for Environmental Protection (PROFEPA). The rest of the animals will be transported to 108 zoos and six conservation centers throughout the country .
In January, the Mexican government banned the circus use of wild animals in public shows under the General Wildlife Act, enforced with fines that can lead up to about $250,000 for circuses that break the law. The ban took effect on Wednesday.
Sunday was the last day animal shows took place nationwide, allowing time for circus owners to transport the animals.
PROFEPA asserted the law does not ban circuses having the animals , but prohibits the use of the animals as part of circus shows.
"Circuses can keep their animals as long as they are not presented in public performances," PROFEPA chief Guillermo Haro Blchez said in a press conference, adding that circuses must keep animals in respectful conditions or face fines.
Circuses that decide to keep the animals must also present plans on what they are planning to do with them to the government and what conditions the creatures will live in.
So far, 55 circuses reported their annual animal inventory -- 21 of which said they no longer have wild animals.
The accumulated inventory adds up to about 511 wild animals, far lower than the inventory of 1,091 reported by 60 circuses in 2014.
About 20 of Mexico's 75 circuses failed to produce annual animal inventories by the Wednesday deadline and now face administrative fines.
There are 200 animals native to Mexico and 891 exotic animals that have been or will be relocated, classified as:
Invertebrates, 1.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:53:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Output at joint Kaesong factory complex up, despite wage dispute</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Output-at-joint-Kaesong-factory-complex-up-despite-wage-dispute/4831436454829/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
Output at joint Kaesong factory complex up, despite wage dispute
Factory output in Kaesong was up from January to April, and 55,000 North and South Koreans are now working at the joint industrial complex.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 9, 2015 at 11:53 AM
Comments
SEOUL, July 9 (UPI) -- Despite a brewing dispute between North and South over the wages for North Korean workers at the Kaesong Industrial Complex, productivity at the factories has soared dramatically, according to South Korea's Unification Ministry.
The update from Seoul followed an announcement on Thursday that representatives from North and South Korea are to meet in Kaesong on July 16.
North Korea's chairman of a North-South joint committee agreed to a proposal for a sixth meeting between representatives of the two sides, Voice of America reported.
A Unification Ministry spokesman said the meeting in July is to be comprehensive in coverage, and details of issues such as the wage increase for North Korean workers in Kaesong are to be discussed through interoffice communication.
Seoul also said factory output in Kaesong was up from 2014. From January to April, when a sharp dispute over wages began to overshadow the joint North-South industrial project, production value was estimated to have reached $186 million, up 25 percent from $148 million from the same period in 2014.
Even during the height of the dispute in March and April, production value was up nearly 20 percent in each month from the year previous, Seoul said.
Kaesong has had its share of ups and downs, including a unilateral North Korea demand in February for an increase in North Korean workers' wages -- from a monthly minimum wage of $70.35 to $74. Seoul refused the request and tensions have ensued.
But long-term trends indicate the project has been enjoying a track record of strong growth since it began operations in 2005.
The number of North and South Koreans involved at Kaesong now stands at 55,000, up 2,000 from 2014, and the number of South Korean companies participating in the project has grown from 18 in 2005, to 124 at present.
An annual output value of $14.9 million in 2005 was up to $470 million in 2014, and cumulative production value since 2005 was up to $2.85 billion at the end of April.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:47:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IMF revises world economic growth; lowers global growth predictions</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/IMF-revises-world-economic-growth-lowers-global-growth-predictions/8321436454476/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
WASHINGTON, July 9 (UPI) -- The International Monetary Fund reduced its estimate of expected global growth in 2015 Thursday, citing financial market turbulence and slower U.S. expansion.
In revisions to its World Economic Outlook , released Thursday in Washington, the IMF said the world economy would grow by 3.3 percent, down from its April prediction of 3.5 percent. Its prediction for 2016, a 3.8 percent increase, was left unchanged.
The report singled out China and the Eurozone as areas of potential risk. China is currently in the midst of a stock market upheaval, with stock prices falling until a big increase Thursday; negotiations with creditors, if they fail, could push Greece from using the Euro as currency. Much of the IMF downgrade was caused by the United States' slower-than-expected growth in the first quarter of 2015, although it referred to the U.S. setback as "temporary."
"The projected pickup in global growth, while still expected, has not yet firmly materialized. Raising actual and potential output through a combination of demand support and structural reforms continues to be the economic policy priority."
It also noted the price of oil rebounded faster than expected in 2015's second quarter, reflecting higher demand.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:37:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Argentina Supreme Court gives relatives authority to cut life support</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Argentina-Supreme-Court-gives-relatives-authority-to-cut-life-support/6011436453572/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Argentina Supreme Court gives relatives authority to cut life support
By Tomas Monzon | July 9, 2015 at 11:37 AM
Comments
BUENOS AIRES, July 9 (UPI) -- Argentina's Supreme Court decided Wednesday that an individual's relatives have the right to request the end of life support for a terminally ill patient.
The decision comes after a suit by the family of a man identified as M.A.D., who has been bed-ridden in a hospital with serious brain injuries that have kept him from talking, making gestures, processing his surroundings or eating normally for 20 years.
The man told his family to keep him off life support and allow him to die should the need arise. That was an request that couldn't be fulfilled until now.
Judges Ricardo Lorenzetti, Elena Highton de Nolasco and Juan Carlos Maqueda voted for a change in this policy, following work with Cuerpo Medico Forense (Medical Body of Forensics) and the Instituto de Neurociencias de la Fundacion Favaloro (Institute of Neuroscience from the Favaloro Foundation).
The court ruled that although the man did not inform relatives of his life choice in writing, their claim that he did suffices.
The ruling will give patients the option for a "dignified death", which the court insists is not euthanasia but rather a form of therapeutic abstinence in the cases where the choice can be made. Euthanasia is defined by the World Health Organization as any action by the doctor that accelerates a suffering patient's death, with or without the patient's consent.
In May 2012, Argentina legalized a patient's right to declare his unwillingness to continue treatment when in a terminally ill state.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:28:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S., UAE launch social media center to counter IS propaganda efforts</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/US-UAE-launch-social-media-center-to-counter-IS-propaganda-efforts/4081436451283/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>U.S., UAE launch social media center to counter IS propaganda efforts
By Amy R. Connolly | July 9, 2015 at 11:28 AM
Comments
ABU DHABI, United Arab Emirates, July 9 (UPI) -- The United States and the United Arab Emirates launched a joint Middle East-based social media center to counter propaganda efforts by the Islamic State extremist group.
The Sawab Center will use "direct online engagement" to counter IS ideology and present "moderate and tolerant voices," the State Department said. Based in Abu Dhabi , the capital of the United Arab Emirates, the center issued a message on Twitter and YouTube saying the IS is spreading hate, fear and intolerance.
Richard Stengel, Under Secretary of State for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs, said the goal of the project is to dissuade people from joining the IS and to counter the IS social-media blitzes.
"One of the ideas of the Sawab Center and what we do in terms of messaging ourselves from Washington is to try to stem the flow of foreign fighters," Stengel said. "If somebody is debating whether to go, tell them that the mythology of what Daesh (the IS) is creating is false, you know, the caliphate isn't a paradise -- there's no plumbing, there's no electricity, there's no Internet access."
The Arabic word "sawab" means right or correct as in "the right path."
Make your voice heard, follow us and contribute to clear Islam from #Daesh barbaric actions #NoToDaesh pic.twitter.com/sEVyO6ensD
 Sawab Center (@sawabcenter) July 8, 2015
       #  #_ pic.twitter.com/VQ1wM3pfRq
 Sawab Center (@sawabcenter) July 8, 2015
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:05:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>London in chaos as subway workers strike gains momentum</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/London-in-chaos-as-subway-workers-strike-gains-momentum/4881436451562/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
LONDON, July 9 (UPI) -- A one-day strike Thursday by employees of London's train and subway employees has paralyzed the city and caused delays throughout the area.
Four million people rely on the London subway , known as the Underground or the Tube, daily, and a walkout over pay and working conditions by employees of First Great Western---the train-operating company---has snarled the flow of traffic. Two hundred additional buses are currently in service, and those who need not travel during peak times have been urged to stay home.
The strike began late Wednesday when members of the Rail, Maritime and Transport Union, the Transport Salaried Staffs Association and Unite walked out in a 24-hour action. The train drivers' union Aslef began its own 24-hour stoppage immediately afterward. The strike coincides with a two-day strike by First Great Western staff, which has reduced train service between London and western destinations in Britain.
Among the casualties of the job action is the annual tennis tournament in the London suburb of Wimbledon , which has reported fewer daily tickets sold.
All striking unions rejected a "final pay offer" Wednesday which included a two percent pay raise, and a bonus to weekend subway drivers.
London commuters relied on buses, bicycles, taxis, river boat services and simply walking to get to their destinations Thursday. During a radio interview Wednesday, London Mayor Boris Johnson called the pay offer rejected by workers "a very, very fair deal."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:29:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>USAF Secretary: Russia is biggest security threat to the U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/USAF-Secretary-Russia-is-biggest-security-threat-to-the-US/9691436449876/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
WASHINGTON, July 9 (UPI) -- The U.S. Secretary of the Air Force said she regards Russia as the primary threat to U.S. security.
Deborah Lee James spoke in Washington Wednesday after meeting with European allies, urging them to commit at least two percent of their gross domestic products to defense spending. Only five of NATO's 28 members  the United States, Greece, Estonia and most recently, the United Kingdom and Poland -- are at that benchmark.
Six other NATO countries are reducing their defense budgets, and in June NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg noted, "We need to redouble our efforts to reverse this trend. We are facing more challenges, and we cannot do more with less indefinitely."
The United States is responsible for about 75 percent of all NATO military spending, and for years U.S. leaders have urged other nations to increase their contributions.
Russia is seen as an increasingly hostile and destabilizing force in Europe, prompting James' tour of European capitals. It annexed Crimea and is involved in a rebellion in Ukraine; Russian President Vladimir Putin announced plans to upgrade the country's intercontinental ballistic missile program and a series of encounters between Russian military aircraft and NATO aircraft have recently been reported.
James acknowledged European economies face difficulties at the present time, most prominently the destabilization of the Euro because of Greece'as financial crisis.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:00:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea denies defection of top-ranking official</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/North-Korea-denies-defection-of-top-ranking-official/5041436448827/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>North Korea denies defection of top-ranking official
North Korea has called South Korea press reports "outright lies."
By Elizabeth Shim | July 9, 2015 at 10:00 AM
Comments
| License Photo
SEOUL, July 9 (UPI) -- North Korea denied South Korea press reports its top-level officials are defecting, and Seoul's Unification Ministry said Thursday the defection of one top-level official is unconfirmed.
Pyongyang's state media outlet KCNA denounced the South Korea reports, and said claims that former Deputy Chief of the General Staff of the Korean People's Army (KPA) Pak Sung Won had fled to Seoul are vicious rumors, South Korean news outlet Newsis reported.
An unidentified spokesman at South Korea's Unification Ministry said Seoul never confirmed the defection, South Korean newspaper Kyunghyang Sinmun reported.
When various South Korea press reports suggested Pak had either defected or been executed, North Korea's KCNA denounced the suggestions, and called them outright lies.
"The conservative South Korea press is viciously circulating rumors of 'instabilities in the North Korea system,'" KCNA said in statement.
"Even as South Korea's conservative press faction labels the top official a 'defector,' at this very moment he is providing guidance at Masikryong Ski Resort to ensure it becomes a place of happiness and laughter."
Masikryong Ski Resort is a multimillion-dollar construction project of Kim Jong Un that was launched to attract tourism to North Korea.
Pyongyang said it blames South Korean President Park Geun-hye's "clique" of conservatives for spreading negative perceptions of North Korea.
Pak was appointed deputy chief of the general staff of the KPA in 1995, according to Kyunghyang, and was recognized as a national hero in 2014 for his contribution to North Korea's only ski resort.
Kim's politics of fear is driving state officials stationed overseas to defect, and the recent purge of Defense Minister Hyon Yong Chol has shocked officials across all ranks.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:45:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UNHCR: Syria has worst refugee crisis in nearly 25 years</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/UNHCR-Syria-has-worst-refugee-crisis-in-nearly-25-years/1161436448486/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 4
| License Photo
GENEVA, Switzerland, July 9 (UPI) -- The UN Refugee Agency said Thursday that the situation in Syria has become the agency's worst crisis in almost 25 years.
UNHCR cites figures released Thursday that put the total number of Syrian refugees at more than 4 million. The count is based on new and present arrivals in Turkey but excludes an additional 7.6 million people displaced inside Syria without easy access to outside assistance. More than 270,000 Syrian asylum seekers spread out across Europe are also not included.
UNHCR says that the mass exodus in Syria is the largest since 1992, when the number of Afghan refugees fleeing the country after the USSR withdrew in 1990 reached 4.6 million. With the Syrian crisis in its fifth year, more refugees continue to seek asylum in neighboring countries, with the count rising by a million in just 10 months.
UNHCR expects 4.27 million total asylees by the end of 2015.
UN High Commissioner for Refugees Antonio Guterres said Syria and the countries that host its refugees need assistance from nations worldwide. Funding has become an issue, with the latest appeal from UNHCR and its partners reaching $5.5 billion.
As of late June, only a fourth of those funds have been provided, meaning refugees will suffer from lessened food availability, access to health services and schools for their children. Some 1.6 million refugees have lost food assistance, and 750,000 children are unable to go to school.
The desperate situation has led to the rise of negative coping strategies among refugees, such as child labor, begging and child marriages as they compete for jobs and resources in strained environments.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:30:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colombia FARC rebels announce month-long unilateral ceasefire</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Colombia-FARC-rebels-announce-month-long-unilateral-ceasefire/2071436442659/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
HAVANA, July 9 (UPI) -- Colombia's left-wing FARC rebel group has announced a month-long unilateral cease-fire as part of ongoing peace negotiations in Havana, Cuba.
The FARC, or Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia, hopes the cease-fire will lead to an eventual truce. The cease-fire begins July 20, chief FARC negotiator Ivan Marquez said Wednesday .
Peace talks between the Colombian government and FARC began in November 2012. The new cease-fire would be the sixth between the warring sides.
The four countries involved in facilitating peace talks , Cuba, Norway, Chile and Venezuela, urged for the "rapid de-escalation of the armed conflict" on Tuesday.
The last established cease-fire began in December but deteriorated in April after 11 Colombian soldiers were killed in an attack. The government responded by resuming aerial bombings of rebel positions.
Dozens more rebels and soldiers have died since the recent escalation of violence after the FARC suspended the former unilateral cease-fire in May.
"We came to Cuba to reach a peace agreement, to end a war that has lasted for more than half a century," FARC said in a statement. "Nothing could please us more than to end definitively with the confrontation, the violence, new victims and the suffering of the Colombian people as a result of the conflict."
Colombian President Juan Manuel Santos welcomed the move by the rebel guerrilla group, but stated FARC needs to do more.
Valoramos gesto de cese unilateral de fuego de las FARC pero se necesita ms, sobretodo compromisos concretos para acelerar negociaciones.
 Juan Manuel Santos (@JuanManSantos) July 8, 2015
"We appreciate the gesture of a unilateral ceasefire by the FARC but more is needed, especially concrete commitments to accelerate the negotiations," Santos said on Twitter.
More than 220,000 people have died in the Colombian conflict since the FARC's founding in 1964. The militant rebel group has been involved in drug-trafficking, kidnapping and other illicit activity to fund its insurgency campaign.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:28:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA bans former committee member, FBI informant Chuck Blazer for life</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/FIFA-bans-former-committee-member-FBI-informant-Chuck-Blazer-for-life/8911436440812/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
ZURICH, Switzerland, July 9 (UPI) -- FIFA has imposed a lifetime ban on Chuck Blazer, its former executive committee member who turned into an FBI informant against the world's soccer governing body.
Blazer is banned from "taking part in any kind of football-related activity at national and international level for life," FIFA said in a statement .
Blazer, 70, an American, agreed to work undercover for the FBI, supplying information about corruption within the hierarchy of FIFA, after he pleaded guilty in 2013 to 10 charges of bribery, tax fraud and money laundering. He was also formerly the CONCACAF general secretary.
"Mr. Blazer committed many and various acts of misconduct continuously and repeatedly during his time as an official in different high-ranking and influential positions at FIFA and CONCACAF," FIFA wrote. "In his positions as a football official, he was a key player in schemes involving the offer, acceptance, payment and receipt of undisclosed and illegal payments, bribes and kickbacks as well as other money-making schemes."
Blazer agreed to become an FBI informant in exchange for immunity from further prosecution and a commutation of a 75-year prison sentence. He also forfeited nearly $2 million he received in bribes and kickbacks, and must also pay back taxes and penalties on $11 million in unreported income, the plea deal states.
Blazer, currently dealing with cancer, has admitted taking bribes to vote in favor of South Africa's hosting of the 2010 World Cup, as well as accepting bribes over placement of lesser tournaments, some held in the United States.
FIFA has been embroiled in chaos and controversy since late May after the U.S. Justice Department charged 14 FIFA officials and corporate executives of "racketeering, wire fraud and money-laundering conspiracies, among other offenses, in connection with the defendants' participation in a 24-year scheme to enrich themselves through the corruption of international soccer."
The scandal led FIFA President Sep Blatter, who won reelection days after the charges were announced, to declare his pending resignation, which could come as early as December.
High-ranking FIFA officials, including Blatter, FIFA Secretary General Jerome Valcke and former FIFA Vice President Jack Warner, have come under legal scrutiny by the FBI and Swiss authorities.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:27:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WikiLeaks: NSA phone tapped Merkel's aides, chancellery offices</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/WikiLeaks-NSA-phone-tapped-Merkels-aides-chancellery-offices/5661436438177/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WikiLeaks: NSA phone tapped Merkel's aides, chancellery offices
By Tomas Monzon | July 9, 2015 at 8:27 AM
Comments
| License Photo
BERLIN, July 9 (UPI) -- New documents issued by whistle-blower WikiLeaks show that the U.S. National Security Agency has been spying on German officials for more than a decade.
Three leaked NSA intercepts show 125 phone numbers of top German officials, including the lines of the last three German chancellors: Angela Merkel , Gerhard Schroder (1998-2002) and Helmut Kohl (1982-98).
The phones of Merkel and her aides, her political office and even fax machine were tapped by the agency, according to the reports released Wednesday. Other phone taps included the cellphone of Ronald Pofalla , Merkel's chief of staff from 2009 to 2013; a land line belonging to the leader of Merkel's parliamentary caucus; lines belonging to Merkel's office staff; and a cellphone number that Merkel used until 2013.
WikiLeaks reports that a phone tap list has existed since the 1990s and has been updated since 2002.
RELEASE: All the Chancellor's Men: The Merkel NSA target list https://t.co/DVf61ZocIr pic.twitter.com/zB9dia2Tpr
 WikiLeaks (@wikileaks) July 8, 2015
Pofalla had testified on July 2 that there was no proof Merkel had been spied on. In 2013, Pofalla also said the United States agreed to not spy on Germany following the release of documents by whistle-blower Edward Snowden .
WikiLeaks editor-in-chief Julian Assange said that sufficient proof is now available to warrant the reopening of a German investigation into the espionage.
WikiLeaks adds that the long-term tapping of phone lines by the NSA allowed the United States to know how the German government planned to respond to the international financial crisis and the Eurozone bank bailout. Merkel's personal views on Obama 's interactions with Iran were also intercepted from a phone call between Merkel and United Arab Emirates Crown Prince Shaykh Muhammad bin Zayid al-Nuhayyan.
The news accompanies an earlier Wikileaks publication that showed 69 other German government telephone numbers that had been tapped for more than two decades. These included the numbers of German Finance Minister Oskar Lafontaine and former Minister for Economics Werner Mller.
Following that release, U.S. Ambassador John Emerson met with Merkel on July 9. She expressed displeasure at the lack of trust from the United States and insisted that Emerson leave Germany or be expelled under the terms of Vienna Convention.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:54:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State leader in Afghanistan killed in drone strike</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Islamic-State-leader-in-Afghanistan-killed-in-drone-strike/7121436438879/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
KABUL, Afghanistan, July 9 (UPI) -- Shahidullah Shahid, a leader of the Islamic State in Afghanistan , has been killed along with at least 24 other militants by a drone strike.
The drone strike occurred in the Achin district of eastern Nangarhar province on Tuesday . IS deputy commander Gul Zaman was also killed, according to Afghanistan's National Directorate of Security. Shahid wanted to launch a regional fight beginning from Afghanistan's Nangarhar province.
Shahid was the third-most senior commander of the Islamic State in Afghanistan killed in past few months, according to local media outlet TOLO News .
Shahid was the IS leader for Afghanistan's Khorasan province. His real name was Sheikh Maqbool and he previously worked for the Taliban's Pakistani branch, Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan (TTP), until he pledged allegiance to the Islamic State along with five other TPP commanders last year.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 13:54:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek financial proposal deadline looms; capital controls extended</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/09/Greek-financial-proposal-deadline-looms-capital-controls-extended/1301436436974/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 4
| License Photo
ATHENS, Greece, July 9 (UPI) -- The Greek financial reform proposal deadline set by creditors looms Thursday as the government has extended bank closures and capital controls.
The deadline was set by Greece's international creditors , the European Commission, the International Monetary Fund and the European Central Bank, after nearly 61 percent of Greek participants in the Sunday referendum voted "no" on the terms the lenders set for a third bailout.
"I think we're proceeding within the framework of what was agreed and the next hours will be crucial," Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said, promising "new concrete proposals, credible reforms, for a fair and viable solution."
Greece quietly submitted a formal request for a new 3-year bailout aid package while a European Parliament debate was taking place Wednesday. The new amount for the bailout has not been requested, but it could easily be more than $55 billion.
All 28 members of the European Union will attend a summit on Sunday to discuss Greece's fate.
Greece has already received more than $220 billion in two bailouts since the rescue program began about five years ago. The country has a public debt of about $356 billion.
Bank closures and capital controls are extended until Monday.
People in Greece will remain limited to withdrawing up to $66 a day at ATMs due to the capital controls first imposed on June 28 after a failure to reach an agreement led the ECB to cap emergency liquidity assistance to Greek banks.
The ECB will not continue to cap emergency liquidity "until an appropriate support package has been agreed by all parties."
Greece has a $3.9 billion payment due to the European Central Bank on July 20. On June 30, Greece became the first developed nation in history to default on a loan from the IMF.
Greece may be forced out of the Eurozone economic bloc if a deal is not reached.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
