<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="USATODAY">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:46:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry: 'Tough issues' remain for Iran nuke deal</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100111178/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Kerry-Tough-issues-remain-for-Iran-nuke-deal/</Link>
        <Description>Talks had snagged on the fate of sanctions, including a weapons embargo on Iran.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kerry: 'Tough issues' remain for Iran nuke deal
Talks had snagged on the fate of sanctions, including a weapons embargo on Iran.
Post to Facebook
Kerry: 'Tough issues' remain for Iran nuke deal Talks had snagged on the fate of sanctions, including a weapons embargo on Iran. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IMDUZv
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
16
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Kerry: 'Tough issues' remain for Iran nuke deal
Oren Dorell , USA TODAY 3:46 p.m. EDT July 9, 2015
John Kerry has said nuclear negotiations in Vienna would continue past a congressional deadline on Thursday night, insisting that they could not be rushed. The US secretary of state was speaking a few hours before a deadline set by the US Congress. USA TODAY
Secretary of State John Kerry talks to reporters outside the Palais Coburg Hotel where the Iran nuclear talks meetings are being held in Vienna, Austria on July 9, 2015.
(Photo: JOE KLAMAR, AFP/Getty Images)
27 CONNECT 58 TWEET LINKEDIN 16 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Secretary of State John Kerry said Thursday "tough issues remain unresolved" in talks to curb Iran's nuclear program, and the United States is prepared to walk away if they're not settled.
"We believe we are making real progress toward a comprehensive deal," Kerry told reporters in Vienna, where the talks are taking place. "But... we are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever."
World powers  the United States, Britain, France, Russia, China and Germany  have been seeking an agreement by Friday to limit Iran's nuclear program in return for lifting U.S. and international sanctions that have crippled Iran's economy. The U.S. goal in the talks is to prevent Iran from producing a nuclear weapon, which Iran says it does not seek.
"If, in the end, we are to reach a deal, it has to be one that stands the test of time  a test for decades," Kerry said, adding he would not be rushed to reach a deal.
Many members of Congress skeptical of making a deal with Iran have urged the Obama administration not to be bound by deadlines and to focus on getting a good agreement.
White House spokesman Josh Earnest said the effort will last as long there is progress.
If "there does not seem to be a constructive engagement on the part of the Iranians to resolving the remaining sticking points in the negotiations, then the president won't hesitate to bring his team home," Earnest said.
Iran nuke talks snag over lifting arms embargo
The deadline for the current round of talks was extended from June 30 to Tuesday and then to Friday. Many differences were resolved, but the talks snagged on two sensitive issues. The first is the sequence of lifting sanctions and whether they could be easily restored if Iran doesn't comply with its obligations. The second is whether sanctions relief would include international arms embargoes on Iran.
White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely
Each deadline extension also continued the conditions agreed to in November 2013 that required Iran to limit its nuclear activities while talks are ongoing.
In April, the sides announced a general framework for a final deal that would require what President Obama said would be unprecedented scrutiny of Iran's nuclear program. It also called for restrictions for 10 to 15 years on how much nuclear fuel Iran could produce.
Iran, which would commit to keep its program peaceful, says it needs a very large nuclear fuel enrichment capability to supply current and future nuclear power plants. Many members of Congress and Israel worry that could provide Iran the means to supply a secret nuclear weapon.
Secretary of State John Kerry talks to reporters at the Palais Coburg where talks between world powers and Iran continue in Vienna, Austria, 09 July 2015.
(Photo: HERBERT NEUBAUER, EPA)
On Sunday, Kerry said the sides had agreed on much, but that remaining differences were so important they could nix the deal. "If there's absolute intransigence, if there's an unwillingness to move on the things that are important, President Obama has always said we'll be prepared to walk away," Kerry said. "It's not what anybody wants. We want to get an agreement."
Contributing: David Jackson
27 CONNECT 58 TWEET LINKEDIN 16 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1IMDUZv
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:38:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For many Greeks, the lines now start at midnight</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100149408/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~For-many-Greeks-the-lines-now-start-at-midnight/</Link>
        <Description>ATMs are the new town squares in Athens, where Greeks gather to debate the debt crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
For many Greeks, the lines now start at midnight
ATHENS  ATMs are the new town squares here, the place where Greeks gather and furiously debate politics and economics as they wait in line to withdraw a paltry limit of less than $70 a day. The lines start at midnight so people can collect their daily 60-euro allotment as early in the new day as possible for fear banks might run out of cash if they wait.
Post to Facebook
For many Greeks, the lines now start at midnight ATHENS  ATMs are the new town squares here, the place where Greeks gather and furiously debate politics and economics as they wait in line to withdraw a paltry limit of less than $70 a day. The lines start at midnight so people can collect their daily 60-euro allotment as early in the new day as possible for fear banks might run out of cash if they wait. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MiRLWo
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
For many Greeks, the lines now start at midnight
Eric J. Lyman, Special for USA TODAY 5:52 p.m. EDT July 9, 2015
Milton Cappello used to work for an Athens bank's office of sales and promotions. Now, he has been reassigned to wash the graffiti off its walls. The graffiti hes washing off says Your wealth, Our blood with an anarchy sign below.
(Photo: Eric J. Lyman for USA TODAY)
CONNECT 2 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
ATHENS  ATMs are the new town squares here, the place where Greeks gather and furiously debate politics and economics as they wait in line to withdraw a paltry limit of less than $70 a day.
The lines start at midnight so people can collect their daily 60-euro allotment as early in the new day as possible for fear banks might run out of cash if they wait.
As bad as things are in this debt-swollen nation, things could get worse if Greece fails to strike a deal with the European Union by Sunday on a bailout plan that averts bankruptcy and likely expulsion from the eurozone.
Greece submits austerity plan to eurozone leaders
For many Greeks, it's hard to imagine how things could get any worse. Banks, dramatically short on cash, are closed except to pensioners, and many businesses have stopped providing credit to their clients. Some small restaurants and businesses are even offering discounts to customers who pay in cash, both to avoid the tax bill and to accumulate cash.
"We have become second-class citizens in our own country," student Alex Musto, 18, said while waiting in line at an ATM to withdraw from accounts for both his parents and an older brother. "My father says foreigners helped push us to this point and they can come in and take what they want, and we wait in line for what is left over."
For most Greeks, the country's financial crisis is personal.
Ilias Panagopaulos, 51, a taxi driver, said Thursday that clients often reach their destination before revealing they have no money to pay him. Tassos Alevizos, 32, a graduate student, said he delayed getting married and starting a family because of the country's unpredictable economic future. And Maria Kottari, 32, a youth activist, said she recently discovered she didn't have enough in her bank account to cover a transfer fee needed so she could get paid.
"I did some work for a company in the U.K. and was waiting for the payment to be transferred, but it never arrived," Kottari explained. "The company insisted they sent it, so eventually I called my bank. They told me I needed at least 4 euros ($4.40) in the account to pay for the transfer fee, but I only had 2.09 euros ($2.30) there. They couldn't process the transfer until I deposited the difference."
5 things to know about a 'Grexit'
For some, the problems could be life threatening.
Cristos Moraitis, 70, a retired plastics worker whose right foot was amputated eight years ago, spends part of each day asking for spare change from passersby on Panepistimiou Street, one of Athens most exclusive shopping areas. He said he takes a dozen medicines a day to combat infection, diabetes and other maladies. And he says it is increasingly difficult to access his pension payments to buy medicine.
"It breaks my heart when I return home, and my five grandchildren run to greet me and ask, 'What did you bring us papu?' and I have nothing," Moraitis said. Asked if he could envision a solution, he shrugged. "Soon, I will be without medicine and that will be the end of me."
Pro-European Union protesters shout slogans and wave EU flags in front of the Greek parliament in Athens on July 9, 2015.
(Photo: Louisa Gouliamaki, AFP/Getty Images)
Last Sunday's referendum is still a hot topic at the ATMs. The "no" vote won an overwhelming victory against strict bailout terms demanded by the country's international creditors, but the two sides remain at odds.
On Thursday, a major rally on the "yes" side marched down Panepistimiou Street, hoping to encourage the government to strike a deal with EU creditors. A similar "no" rally is scheduled for Friday.
As the protest was getting organized in Constitution Square  Athens' main plaza  Mpaglatzis Christos, 88, was philosophical about the country's problems.
"Nobody knows what they want," said Christos, who used to repair planes for Olympic Airways when the company was owned by Aristotle Onassis, the late Greek tycoon who married Jacqueline Kennedy. Christos said people demonstrate one day to say "yes," and the next day some of the same people will demonstrate on the "no" side.
"Greece has always tried to imitate wealthier European countries and pretend we are the same," Christos continued. "Maybe the whole thing would settle down if we finally realize we are not a wealthy country and be satisfied with that."
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MiRLWo
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 22:25:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.K. tells tourists to leave Tunisia, says attack 'highly likely'</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100112760/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~UK-tells-tourists-to-leave-Tunisia-says-attack-highly-likely/</Link>
        <Description>There are up to 3,000 British tourists currently in Tunisia, and a few hundred British residents live there.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
U.K. tells tourists to leave Tunisia, says attack 'highly likely'
The British government on Thursday told all U.K. tourists to leave Tunisia because a terrorist attack is "highly likely."
Post to Facebook
U.K. tells tourists to leave Tunisia, says attack 'highly likely' The British government on Thursday told all U.K. tourists to leave Tunisia because a terrorist attack is "highly likely." Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MifO7Q
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
U.K. tells tourists to leave Tunisia, says attack 'highly likely'
Doug Stanglin , USA TODAY 3:25 p.m. EDT July 9, 2015
Tunisians observe a minute of silence in honor of the victims of the attack outside the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the popular tourist resort of al-Sousse, Tunisia, on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
16 CONNECT 61 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond warned thousands of British tourists in Tunisia on Thursday that a terrorist attack there is 'highly likely" and urged them to return home immediately.
The official  travel advisory was later updated to advise against all but essential travel to Tunisia "for the time being."
An attack last month on the Tunisian beach resort of Sousse by a suspected Islamic State terrorist left 38 people dead, including 30 British vacationers.
Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani, the alleged gunman, was killed by police during the attack.
The Foreign Office estimates there are up to 3,000 British tourists currently in Tunisia, and a few hundred British residents live there, the BBC reports .
"While we do not have any information suggesting a specific or imminent threat, since the attack in Sousse the intelligence and threat picture has developed considerably, leading us to the view that a further terrorist attack is highly likely," Hammond said.
The foreign office warned of attacks "by individuals unknown to the authorities whose actions may be inspired by terrorist groups via social media."
The statement advised against all travel to
"If you're in Tunisia and you don't have an essential need to remain you should leave by commercial means," the statement said.
Tour operators were arranging extra flights to help get the travelers home, Hammond said.
The Tunisian government said Wednesday it would build a 100-mile wall along its border with Libya to stop Islamic State terrorists from crossing into the country. Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essid said the barrier would stretch inland from the Mediterranean coast.
The foreign office said, however, that it did not believe measures taken by Tunisia to counter such attacks would provide "adequate protection."
Germany's Foreign Ministry said it was observing the situation closely and adjusting travel advice regularly, the Associated Press reported. As of now, however, there was no immediate change to its travel advice last updated five days ago. Two Germans were killed in the Sousse attack.
16 CONNECT 61 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MifO7Q
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Amid detente with Hamas, 2 Israelis held in Gaza</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100047416/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Amid-detente-with-Hamas-Israelis-held-in-Gaza/</Link>
        <Description>Announcement brings back memories of Israeli soldier imprisoned for five years by Hamas.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Amid detente with Hamas, 2 Israelis held in Gaza
Israel on Thursday said that two of its citizens are being held captive in the Gaza Strip, an announcement that brought back bitter memories of the case of an Israeli soldier who was captured and imprisoned for five years by the Hamas militant group.
Post to Facebook
Amid detente with Hamas, 2 Israelis held in Gaza Israel on Thursday said that two of its citizens are being held captive in the Gaza Strip, an announcement that brought back bitter memories of the case of an Israeli soldier who was captured and imprisoned for five years by the Hamas militant group. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1ILwQfL
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
3
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Amid detente with Hamas, 2 Israelis held in Gaza
Josef Federman, Associated Press 2:43 p.m. EDT July 9, 2015
Israeli journalists report outside the apartment building of Ethiopian-Israeli Avraham Mengisto, 28, in the costal city of Ashkelon, Israel, Thursday, July 9, 2015.
(Photo: Tsafrir Abayov, AP)
11 CONNECT 69 TWEET LINKEDIN 3 COMMENTEMAILMORE
JERUSALEM (AP)  Israel on Thursday said that two of its citizens are being held captive in the Gaza Strip, an announcement that brought back bitter memories of the case of an Israeli soldier who was captured and imprisoned for five years by the Hamas militant group.
But circumstances have changed dramatically since Gilad Schalits release in a 2011 prisoner swap, and the case announced Thursday could provide an important test of a new fragile detente that has emerged between Israel and Hamas since their devastating war last year. A relatively subdued reaction in Israel reflected the new reality, though Hamas is likely to push for a new round of prisoner releases by Israel before it returns the two men.
Israeli defense officials identified one of the men as Avraham Mengistu, an Israeli of Ethiopian descent in his late 20s.
According to COGAT, the defense body that handles civilian issues with the Palestinians, Mengistu disappeared after he independently crossed the border fence and entered Gaza on Sept. 7, two weeks after the end of last years war.
It gave no further details on why he had crossed into Gaza, though Israeli media said he had been distraught at the time of his disappearance.
COGAT said the second man was a Bedouin Arab citizen from southern Israel. It refused to identify him or say how long he had been in Gaza or how he got there. Officials also would not say which group had him in custody.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said he held Hamas, which has ruled Gaza since seizing control of the territory in 2007, responsible for the fate of both men. Netanyahu said Israel was working to free them and that he had appointed a representative to deal with the matter.
Yesterday I spoke with the parents and siblings of Avraham Mengistu and I told them that from the moment the incident became known, we have spared no effort to return him to Israel, Netanyahu said, urging the international community to issue a clear call for their release.
But there were no threats of action against Hamas, in contrast to a bruising military campaign that followed Hamas capture of Schalit in a 2006 cross-border raid  or more recently, the arrests of scores of Hamas supporters after the deadly abduction of three Israeli teens in the West Bank last year.
The kidnapping set off a string of events that culminated in a 50-day war that killed more than 2,200 Palestinians in Gaza and 73 people on the Israeli side. It was their third war since the Hamas takeover.
Since then, Israel and Hamas have largely honored a cease-fire and even reached some unspoken understandings to preserve quiet, a reflection of the shared threat to both sides by Gazas Salafi militants inspired by the Islamic State extremist group.
Notably absent on Thursday were also the type of celebrations in Gaza that had accompanied previous kidnappings of Israelis. A Hamas spokesman, Salah Bardawil, said he had no information about the two missing Israelis.
Even if it is true, we dont have instructions to talk about it, he said.
The different circumstances also contributed to the subdued reactions. Where Schalit and the teens were captured in military-style operations, the latest disappearances appeared accidental.
Its a completely different situation, said Gershon Baskin, an Israeli activist who helped mediate the Schalit exchange deal, in which Israel freed more than 1,000 prisoners.
Theyre not dealing with a valuable asset like a captured soldier, Baskin said. Its not the same high-value bargaining card.
Still, a protracted round of negotiations appears likely.
A senior Hamas official said that as a precondition for negotiations, the group would seek the release of nearly 60 militants released by Israel in the Schalit deal and then re-arrested last year after the three Israeli teens were kidnapped.
Hamas will also seek the release of some of the thousands of Palestinians held by Israel, he said, speaking on condition of anonymity because he was discussing the groups internal deliberations.
While Israel said nothing about the Bedouin man held in Gaza, the Hamas official claimed he had served in the Israeli military and was considered a prisoner.
Mkhaimar Abusada, a professor of political science at Gazas Al-Azhar University, said a possible deal could include steps to strengthen the cease-fire. I think the swap would be part of a long-term truce, five years or more, he said.
One of the first issues could be determining the fate of Mengistu. The Hamas official said Mengistu had walked into Gaza and appeared to have psychological problems. He said Mengistu told interrogators in the coastal strip that he did not want to go back to Israel and then left Gaza through a smuggling tunnel into Egypt in hopes of ultimately returning to Ethiopia.
COGAT, however, said it had credible intelligence that Mengistu was being held against his will by Hamas.
Israeli Channel 2 TV said Mengistu arrived at an Israeli beach near the Gaza border on the evening of Sept. 7, left his bag behind and crossed into Gaza through a breach in the border fence that was apparently made by Israeli tanks during the 2014 war.
This is a difficult humanitarian matter, because my brother is not in the best of health, Ilan Mengistu told reporters. He did not elaborate, but Israeli Channel 2 TV said Mengistu was distraught following the death of another brother.
Israeli Channel 10 broadcast an interview with a man it identified as Mengistus father. They didnt do anything, Haili Mengistu said. Where is my son?
While Mengistus disappearance had been well known inside Israels Ethiopian community, Israel had barred publication of the incident for several months.
Israeli media had lobbied hard for permission to publish details on the case, putting pressure on the government to release information.
Khaled Mashaal, the head of Hamas political bureau, also may have forced Israels hand by telling a London newspaper this week that Israel had asked Hamas through a European mediator to release two soldiers and two bodies. Israeli officials have said that the remains of two soldiers killed in combat last summer are held by Hamas.
Israeli lawmaker Yaakov Peri, a former director of the Shin Bet intelligence agency and an ex- government coordinator for prisoner of war issues, said that going public may have hurt the negotiations but that talks could nonetheless succeed in the current climate.
Calculations are a little bit less emotional. And its good. Its good for the negotiations, and I am sure it will affect the outcome, he said.
Associated Press writers Daniel Estrin and Tia Goldenberg in Jerusalem, Mohammed Daraghmeh in Ramallah, West Bank, and Fares Akram in Gaza City, Gaza Strip, contributed to this report.
11 CONNECT 69 TWEET LINKEDIN 3 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1ILwQfL
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:16:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The day in pictures</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/95533850/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~The-day-in-pictures/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
The day in pictures
Britain's Prince William, Duke of Cambridge, speaks with pilot John Romain during a visit to the Imperial War Museum in Duxford, north of London. The prince inspected a rare Spitfire plane gifted to the museum by a U.S. philanthropist on the eve of the 75th anniversary of the Battle of Britain aerial campaign by Nazi Germany.
Post to Facebook
The day in pictures Britain's Prince William, Duke of Cambridge, speaks with pilot John Romain during a visit to the Imperial War Museum in Duxford, north of London. The prince inspected a rare Spitfire plane gifted to the museum by a U.S. philanthropist on the eve of the 75th anniversary of the Battle of Britain aerial campaign by Nazi Germany. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1SbnRa4
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
The day in pictures
Britain's Prince William, Duke of Cambridge, speaks with pilot John Romain during a visit to the Imperial War Museum in Duxford, north of London. The prince inspected a rare Spitfire plane gifted to the museum by a U.S. philanthropist on the eve of the 75th anniversary of the Battle of Britain aerial campaign by Nazi Germany.
Geoff Pugh, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A young girl comforts a Bosnian muslim  woman  near Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, as she touches a truck carrying 136 coffins of newly identified victims of the 1995 Srebrenica massacre.  July 11 marks 20 years since Bosnian Serb forces overran Srebrenica.
Dimitar Dilkoff, AFP/Getty Images
An Indian cyclist travels in New Delhi during a heavy monsoon rain.
Money Sharma, AFP/Getty Images
Pope Francis, riding in the popemobile, greets a soldier in El Alto, a plateau over La Paz, Bolivia.
Cris Bouroncle, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A Chinese investor uses a magnifying glass to look at his mobile phone screen as he monitors stock prices at a brokerage in Beijing. Asian stock markets continue to react as the Chinese government takes measures aimed at stabilizing the market.
Ng Han Guan, AP
A man wears a headdress of feathers and the national flag as he attends an independence day celebration in Juba, South Sudan.
Jason Patinkin, AP
Leslie Minerd holds a sign as she celebrates outside the South Carolina Statehouse in Columbia.  More than 50 years after South Carolina raised a Confederate battle flag to protest the civil rights movement, the banner will be removed Friday.
John Bazemore, AP
A 'Kiliki' or Big Head plays with a crying girl as he takes part in the Parade of the Giants and Big Heads parade in the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain.
Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP
Filipinos cross a swelling river in the City of Las Pinas, south of Manila.
Francis R. Malasig, epa
People enjoy a ride on the roller coaster 'Euro-Mir' in Rust, Germany.
Patrick Seeger, epa
Fullscreen
British loyalists stack pallets and tires on top of their bonfire construct in preparation for their 11th night bonfire at the New Mossley estate in Belfast, Northern Ireland.  Tradition holds that the bonfires commemorate the lighting of fires on the hills to help Williamite ships navigate through Belfast Lough at night when Protestant King William III and his forces landed at Carrickfergus to fight the Catholic Jacobites, supporters of the exiled Catholic King James II.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:34:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama, lawmakers brace for end game of Iran talks</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100095262/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Obama-lawmakers-brace-for-end-game-of-Iran-talks/</Link>
        <Description>The United States looks to nail down a final nuclear agreement with Iran.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Obama, lawmakers brace for end game of Iran talks
The Obama administration and congressional lawmakers monitored talks in Vienna Thursday that could produce a landmark nuclear agreement or further stalemate
Post to Facebook
Obama, lawmakers brace for end game of Iran talks The Obama administration and congressional lawmakers monitored talks in Vienna Thursday that could produce a landmark nuclear agreement or further stalemate Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MhWZlg
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
3
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Obama, lawmakers brace for end game of Iran talks
David Jackson, USA TODAY 1:34 p.m. EDT July 9, 2015
President Obama
4 CONNECT 89 TWEET LINKEDIN 3 COMMENTEMAILMORE
The Obama administration and congressional lawmakers monitored nuclear talks in Vienna on Thursday that hang between a landmark agreement with Iran or further stalemate.
Amid signs that negotiators will blow through another deadline, White House spokesman Josh Earnest said the United States still seeks an agreement that would shut down any path toward Iranian nuclear weapons, as well as inspections to insure that Iran is complying.
"Right now, we're focused on trying to reach an agreement," Earnest said.
Earnest also said U.S. negotiators are prepared to walk away if Iran will not make certain commitments with regard to its nuclear program.
He added: "This is a tough deal."
Iran nuke talks snag over lifting arms embargo
President Obama spoke by video conference Wednesday with Secretary of State John Kerry and other members of the U.S. negotiating team.,The president "reviewed the progress of negotiations to date, and provided guidance related to our ongoing efforts to achieve a good deal," the White House said in a statement.
On Thursday, Kerry told reporters in Vienna that negotiators have made some progress, but "some of the tough issues remain unresolved."
The United States and its allies are offering to reduce sanctions on Iran if it agrees to give up the means to make nuclear weapons.
For their part, the Iranians are demanding a quicker reduction of sanctions, less intrusive inspections and an easing of sanctions on weapons purchases from certain countries, officials said.
Sen. Bob Corker, R-Tenn., chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, told CNN that "what we're hearing is that there's been some breakthroughs," but "not all of the breakthroughs that are necessary" for a final agreement.
"But I think that it's possible people are feeling a little bit more optimistic about getting something done," said Corker, who has been skeptical of some aspects of the Iran proposal.
Critics, including congressional Republicans and Israeli government officials, question whether Iran would live up to an agreement that it give up the pursuit of nuclear weapons.
Report: Obama puts Iran deal odds at 'less than 50-50'
Iran says its nuclear program is for peaceful energy production in any event.
An inability to reach an agreement by Friday would increase the amount of time Congress has to review any Iran deal, expanding it from 30 days to 60 because of the August recess.
Negotiators in Vienna initially set a June 30 deadline for a final agreement, then extended that to July 7, and then again to Thursday at midnight.
For months, the parties have operated under an "interim" agreement that freezes the Iranian nuclear program in place. The U.S. has not ruled out an extension of that interim agreement.
Republican lawmakers, skeptical of the proposed agreement in any event, have warned the administration not to rush into anything because of the congressional calendar.
Corker urged U.S. negotiators this week "to hold firm, take their time and be prepared to step back from the table."
4 CONNECT 89 TWEET LINKEDIN 3 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MhWZlg
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:47:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bitter divisions over Srebrenica massacre persist 20 years later</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100097148/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Bitter-divisions-over-Srebrenica-massacre-persist-years-later/</Link>
        <Description>Serbs refuse to label the killing of 8,000 Bosnians in 1995 as "genocide."</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Bitter divisions over Srebrenica massacre persist 20 years later
SREBRENICA  Fadila Efendic remembers the first time she met Hamaed as if it was just yesterday. She was working behind a store counter in the early 1970s when he came in to buy shaving supplies -- he caught
Post to Facebook
Bitter divisions over Srebrenica massacre persist 20 years later SREBRENICA  Fadila Efendic remembers the first time she met Hamaed as if it was just yesterday. She was working behind a store counter in the early 1970s when he came in to buy shaving supplies -- he caught Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IMsoNG
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Bitter divisions over Srebrenica massacre persist 20 years later
Sumi Somaskanda, Special for USA TODAY 11:47 a.m. EDT July 9, 2015
A Bosnian woman cries as she touches a truck carrying 136 coffins of newly identified victims of the 1995 Srebrenica massacre in the town of Visoko, near Sarajevo on July 9, 2015.
(Photo: Dimitar Dilkoff, AFP/Getty Images)
7 CONNECT 48 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
SREBRENICA, Bosnia-Herzegovina As thousands of survivors, victims' relatives and dignitaries descend on this city Saturday to mark the 20th anniversary of the massacre of 8,000 Bosnians, divisions remain as deep and bitter as ever over what happened on this killing field.
Russia this week vetoed a U.N. Security Council resolution that would have condemned the massacre by Serbian troops as "genocide." The resolution, backed by Britain, urged all sides to accept the term as a significant step towardreconciliation between Serbs and Bosnian Muslims. The International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia in the Netherlands officially deemed the tragedy a genocide in 2004.
But Serbia and Bosnian Serb leaders vehemently reject the label. And Russia, which shares close religious and cultural ties with Serbia, has arguedusing the word "genocide"would create further division by pointing the blame at one group.
For many Bosnian Muslims in Srebrenica, denials of the massacre arean insult."I can't understand (the Serbs) as people," said Elvir Hafizovic, 36, a Bosnian Muslim who lost two brothers and his father in the massacre. "They know what happened here, that there was genocide here, so why don't they admit it?"
For many Bosnian Serbs, doing that would overshadow the suffering of victims on both sides of the conflict. After confirming the U.N. resolution would not be adopted, Serbian Prime Minister Alexander Vucic announced he would attend Saturday's commemoration service. Last month, he called the massacre a "horrific crime" but stopped short of using the word "genocide."
From 1992 to 1995, more than 100,000 people died in an ethnic war that tore Bosnia at the seams. The Dayton Accords, the peace agreement that ended the conflict in November 1995, split the country into two entities  Republika Srpska and the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina  and created a tripartite presidency, with one representative from each of the nation's ethnic groupsBosniacs, Croats and Serbs. It was part of a complex power-sharing structure aimed at mending the wounds and building a new, unified Bosnia.
In Republika Srpska, some of the Bosnian Muslim families who fled have slowly returned. In 2004, the United Nations said about 136,000 of nearly 500,000 Bosnian Muslims who had left were back in the region.
Fadila Efendic is one of them. She returned to her home in Potocari alone in 2003 and restored it. "I had to be the woman, the man, the electrician, the painter, everything," she said.
She settled back into life with the same Serbneighbors she had before the war without incident. She handed out candy to Serbschool children during Bayram, a widely celebrated holiday, to help smooth tensions.
A bird flies over graves at the city cemetery on July 8, 2015 in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina.
(Photo: Matej Divizna, Getty Images)
In 2006, with the support of her daughter in Sarajevo and relatives nearby, Efendic realized her dream of opening her own shop: a small, one-room souvenir and remembrance stand just across the road from the Srebrenica memorial site. From her store, she looks out over the solemn rows of marble tombstones where her son and husband, Fejzo and Hamaed, are buried.
"I'm near them," she said. "I can visit them every day."
These days, many Bosnian, Serb and Croat families co-exist in small villages and towns across eastern Bosnia's idyllic countryside, dotted with Serbian Orthodox Christian churches and Bosnian mosques.
"Time goes by," says Serb Novica Pavlovic, 39, as he filled up his tank at a gas station in the village of Konjevic Polije, a flashpoint in the final days of the war. "We can either live this madness with each other or learn to live together."
Contributing: Jusuf Begic
A general view of buildings destroyed during Bosnian war on July 8, 2015 in Mostar, Bosnia and Herzegovina.
(Photo: Matej Divizna, Getty Images)
7 CONNECT 48 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1IMsoNG
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:20:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Joint Chiefs nominee names Russia top security threat</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100092792/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Joint-Chiefs-nominee-names-Russia-top-security-threat/</Link>
        <Description>He also says he supports supplying Ukraine with weapons to defend against separatists.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Joint Chiefs nominee names Russia top security threat
WASHINGTON  Marine Gen. Joseph Dunford on Thursday identified Russia as the No. 1 threat to U.S. security during his confirmation hearing to be chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. He also offered support
Post to Facebook
Joint Chiefs nominee names Russia top security threat WASHINGTON  Marine Gen. Joseph Dunford on Thursday identified Russia as the No. 1 threat to U.S. security during his confirmation hearing to be chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. He also offered support Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MhUbEw
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
6
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Joint Chiefs nominee names Russia top security threat
Tom Vanden Brook , USA TODAY 2:20 p.m. EDT July 9, 2015
Barack Obama's nominee to be the most senior US military officer on Thursday effectively endorsed the foreign policy of the politician Obama defeated in 2012. Wochit
Marine Gen. Joseph Dunford.
52 CONNECT 109 TWEET LINKEDIN 6 COMMENTEMAILMORE
WASHINGTON  Marine Gen. Joseph Dunford on Thursday identified Russia as the No. 1 threat to U.S. security during his confirmation hearing to be chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
He also offered support for supplying Ukraine with lethal weaponry to defend itself against Russian-backed separatists. Dunford's remarks, coupled with a Pentagon request Wednesday to shift billions of dollars in its budget to provide weaponry and intelligence to confront Russian aggression in Europe and the Atlantic, indicate heightened alarm within the Pentagon about Russia's military actions.
Russia's nuclear capability "combined with their recent behavior" make Russia the primary threat to U.S. security, Dunford said.
Plan for U.S. weapons in Baltic 'in early stages'
Dunford said he also would support sending armor-piercing weapons to Ukraine, enabling their military to destroy Russian tanks and armored vehicles. Such a move, which the Obama administration has not yet endorsed, would represent a significant escalation in the conflict. Last year, Ukrainian separatists backed by Russian artillery, armor and some special operations forces seized Crimea.
U.S. support to Ukraine has been limited to non-lethal aid, including body armor, Humvees and first-aid kits. Javelin anti-tank missiles, which Dunford said he would support supplying, can be fired with relatively little training.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:30:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Reports: ISIL leader in Afghanistan killed in U.S. drone strike</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100051910/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Reports-ISIL-leader-in-Afghanistan-killed-in-US-drone-strike/</Link>
        <Description>Pentagon confirms that strikes were carried out, declines to elaborate</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Reports: ISIL leader in Afghanistan killed in U.S. drone strike
A leader of the Islamic State in Afghanistan  and former Pakistani Taliban spokesman  has been killed in a U.S. drone strike, according to local media reports.
Post to Facebook
Reports: ISIL leader in Afghanistan killed in U.S. drone strike A leader of the Islamic State in Afghanistan  and former Pakistani Taliban spokesman  has been killed in a U.S. drone strike, according to local media reports. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1ILDcf6
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
75
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Reports: ISIL leader in Afghanistan killed in U.S. drone strike
Jane Onyanga-Omara and Gregg Zoroya , USA TODAY 12:30 p.m. EDT July 9, 2015
A video grab taken from an undated video released by the Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan (TTP) and made available 09 July 2015 of the TTP's former spokesperson Shahidullah Shahid at an undisclosed location at the Pakistani-Afghan border.
(Photo: TTP/Handout, EPA)
6036 CONNECT 619 TWEET 15 LINKEDIN 75 COMMENTEMAILMORE
A senior leader for the Islamic State in Afghanistan, currently embroiled in a feud with the Taliban over who will conduct the insurgency there, has been killed in a U.S. drone strike, local media reported Thursday.
The strike killed Shahidullah Shahid and more than two dozen militants in eastern Afghanistan south of the city of Jalalabad.It was in that city where Islamic State militants conducted their first major attack against Afghan civilians in April, killing 35 in a suicide bombing.
The drone strike was Tuesday, the same day Taliban officials met for the first time with an Afghanistan delegation in Islamabad, Pakistan, to open peace negotiations.
The Pentagon said Thursday that "precision strikes" by U.S. forces were carried out Monday and Tuesday south of Jalalabad "against individuals threatening U.S. and coalition forces." There was no elaboration.
Afghan intelligence officials told media that those killed in the drone strike included Shahid, a former Pakistan Taliban spokesman and another senior Islamic State leader in Afghanistan, Gul Zaman.
The Islamic State, also known as ISIS or ISIL, controls vast portions of Syria and western Iraq. Last year, it began recruiting disaffected members of both the Pakistan and Afghan Taliban insurgencies and providing funding for opening a front in South Asia, said Seth Jones, a political scientist with RAND Corp.
"What they've done is they haven't built anything from scratch. They've just reached out to disaffected folks," Jones said. "It's possible, for example, if (Afghanistan government) negotiations continue with the Afghan Taliban, that those who don't want a peace deal may defect to the Islamic State. But the challenge the Islamic State has in this area is its ideology is foreign."
Shahid was named deputy chief for a region the Islamic State identifies as spanning parts of Afghanistan, Pakistan and Iran. A cover story in an Islamic State magazine published in December was highly critical of Taliban leader Mullah Mohammed Omar.
The Afghan Taliban reacted strongly to the intrusion publishing an open letter on its website in June warning the Islamic State to stay out of its territory. "Jihad against the Americans and their allies must be conducted under one flag and one leadership," the letter said.
Last year, Shahid was fired as Pakistani Taliban spokesman after pledging allegiance to the Islamic State. At the time the Pakistan Taliban said Shahidullah Shahid was a "nom de guerre" and that his real name was Sheikh Maqbool, the BBC reported.
A senior leader of Islamic State operations in southern Afghanistan, Mullah Abdul Rauf, who had sworn allegiance to the militants after breaking with the Taliban, was killed in a U.S. drone strike in February.
6036 CONNECT 619 TWEET 15 LINKEDIN 75 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1ILDcf6
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:07:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Now it’s serious! Venezuela almost out of beer</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100081642/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Now-it%e2%80%99s-serious-Venezuela-almost-out-of-beer/</Link>
        <Description>Brewery workers are on strike, and there's a shortage of imported beer ingredients.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Now its serious! Venezuela almost out of beer
LIMA, Peru  Throughout their countrys descent intopolitical and economic crisis, Venezuelans of all stripes have at least been able to rely on one thing: drowning their sorrows in beer.
Post to Facebook
Now its serious! Venezuela almost out of beer LIMA, Peru  Throughout their countrys descent intopolitical and economic crisis, Venezuelans of all stripes have at least been able to rely on one thing: drowning their sorrows in beer. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IMariq
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
13
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Now its serious! Venezuela almost out of beer
Simeon Tegel, GlobalPost 10:07 a.m. EDT July 9, 2015
A man buys beer in an outdoor bar at a Caracas auto show in Venezuela on Oct. 7, 2007.
(Photo: Fernando Llano, AP)
467 CONNECT 127 TWEET 5 LINKEDIN 13 COMMENTEMAILMORE
LIMA, Peru  Throughout their countrys descent intopolitical and economic crisis, Venezuelans of all stripes have at least been able to rely on one thing: drowning their sorrows in beer.
Locals of the sweltering South American nation love to down the kinds of heavily chilledlight lagers popular from Mexico to Argentina.
But pretty soon Venezuela could run dry. And that could be even more devastating than it sounds.
How did it come to this?
For one,brewery workersare on strike demanding higherwages.
Members of the Sintraterricentro union downed tools last week at two bottling plants belonging to the Polar brewery. It supplies roughly 80% of Venezuelas beer, including market leaderPolar Pilsen.The union is tiny but its members hold key positionsat the plant, meaning that production has ground to a halt.
The nation's human rights ombudsman has stepped in to mediate. But Empresa Polarexecutivesaccusehim of a bias toward the union, which is allied with the socialist government of President Nicolas Maduro.
On top of that,there's ashortage of imported beer ingredients.
Add that to the list of basics in short supply, likemedicines and food items, thanks to a raft of economic problems including a lack of dollars.
So far, store shelves are well stocked with beer bottles,according to the Associated Press.But that may change soon. The national brewers association says raw materials for beer-making will run outby August.
The timing could hardly be worse.
Venezuela is suffering615% inflation,saysJohns Hopkins University economistSteve H. Hanke. The country also has one of the world's highest homicide rates. And the government's been locking up critics.
So, you might sayVenezuelans could use a drink.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 16:04:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For Greece's ill, crisis a matter of life or death</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100073932/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~For-Greeces-ill-crisis-a-matter-of-life-or-death/</Link>
        <Description>With some Greek companies threatening to withhold products if they are not paid immediately, fears are spreading that there will soon be a shortage in hospitals of essential medicines and medical supplies.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
For Greece's ill, crisis a matter of life or death
With some Greek companies threatening to withhold products if they are not paid immediately, fears are spreading that there will soon be a shortage in hospitals of essential medicines and medical supplies.
Post to Facebook
For Greece's ill, crisis a matter of life or death With some Greek companies threatening to withhold products if they are not paid immediately, fears are spreading that there will soon be a shortage in hospitals of essential medicines and medical supplies. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MhA7Ck
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
For Greece's ill, crisis a matter of life or death
With some Greek companies threatening to withhold products if they are not paid immediately, fears are spreading that there will soon be a shortage in hospitals of essential medicines and medical supplies. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:44:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sumatra's Mount Sinabung erupts</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100071882/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Sumatras-Mount-Sinabung-erupts/</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of people living in the vicinity of a volcano on Indonesia's Sumatra island have been evacuated from their homes after it began erupting.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Sumatra's Mount Sinabung erupts
Thousands of people living in the vicinity of a volcano on Indonesia's Sumatra island have been evacuated from their homes after it began erupting.
Post to Facebook
Sumatra's Mount Sinabung erupts Thousands of people living in the vicinity of a volcano on Indonesia's Sumatra island have been evacuated from their homes after it began erupting. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mhxuk5
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Sumatra's Mount Sinabung erupts
Thousands of people living in the vicinity of a volcano on Indonesia's Sumatra island have been evacuated from their homes after it began erupting. Time
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:38:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece faces midnight deadline</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100069648/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Greece-faces-midnight-deadline/</Link>
        <Description>Bloomberg's Stephanie Ruhle reports on today's top news stories including the midnight deadline for a deal in the Greek financial crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Greece faces midnight deadline
Bloomberg's Stephanie Ruhle reports on today's top news stories including the midnight deadline for a deal in the Greek financial crisis.
Post to Facebook
Greece faces midnight deadline Bloomberg's Stephanie Ruhle reports on today's top news stories including the midnight deadline for a deal in the Greek financial crisis. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1ILVZXv
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Greece faces midnight deadline
Bloomberg's Stephanie Ruhle reports on today's top news stories including the midnight deadline for a deal in the Greek financial crisis. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 15:17:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The president meets with the general secretary of Vietnam</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100067812/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~The-president-meets-with-the-general-secretary-of-Vietnam/</Link>
        <Description>President Obama speaks after a bilteral meeting with General Secretary Nguyen Phu Trong of Vietnam. July 7, 2015.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
The president meets with the general secretary of Vietnam
President Obama speaks after a bilteral meeting with General Secretary Nguyen Phu Trong of Vietnam. July 7, 2015.
Post to Facebook
The president meets with the general secretary of Vietnam President Obama speaks after a bilteral meeting with General Secretary Nguyen Phu Trong of Vietnam. July 7, 2015. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MhuhRz
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
The president meets with the general secretary of Vietnam
President Obama speaks after a bilteral meeting with General Secretary Nguyen Phu Trong of Vietnam. July 7, 2015. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:41:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuke talks snag over lifting arms embargo</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100066050/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Iran-nuke-talks-snag-over-lifting-arms-embargo/</Link>
        <Description>Iran's push to end a U.N. embargo on arms and missiles divides world powers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuke talks snag over lifting arms embargo
U.N. arms embargo was imposed to pressure Iran on its nuclear program.
Post to Facebook
Iran nuke talks snag over lifting arms embargo U.N. arms embargo was imposed to pressure Iran on its nuclear program. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MhsGLj
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Iran nuke talks snag over lifting arms embargo
Oren Dorell , USA TODAY 11:41 a.m. EDT July 9, 2015
A journalist takes pictures in front of the Palais Coburg in Vienna where talks between world powers and iran continue on July 8, 2015.
(Photo: Georg Hochmuth, European Pressphoto Agency)
8 CONNECT 59 TWEET LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Efforts to wrap up a nuclear agreement between Iran and world powers by Friday have hit a new snag over arms embargoes against Tehran that is dividing the U.S. and its negotiating partners.
Just as the two sides were moving closer to a nuclear agreement, Iran this week demanded that conventional weapons and missile embargoes be among the sanctions lifted in return for curbing its nuclear program.
That demand complicates the talks because the United States, Britain, France and Germany oppose such a move, but Russia and China want the embargo lifted so they can sell ballistic missiles and other weaponry to Iran.
"The arms embargoes themselves are not so much important to Iran, but the point is that no sanctions should be kept if there is to be a deal with Iran," Iran's deputy foreign minister, Abbas Araqchi said in Vienna, where negotiators are trying to complete a deal, according to the Iranian Fars News Agency.
The sanctions imposed by the United States, U.N. Security Council and the European Union include bans on sales of weapons and materials that Iran could use in its ballistic missile program.
White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely
President Obama spoke to his negotiating team by teleconference Wednesday night, and provided guidance on an agreement that meets his requirements, the White House said. Secretary of State John Kerry met Thursday with his negotiating partners and later with Iran's foreign minister, Javad Zarif.
If the weapons embargo is lifted, Iran  which the U.S. says is the world's foremost state sponsor of terrorism  would be free to supply weapons to militias operating in Iraq, Syria. Lebanon and Yemen, said Patrick Clawson, research director at the Washington Institute for Near East Policy.
Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov described the arms embargo as one of the remaining sticking point in the talks. Russia and China have complained about keeping the U.N. weapons embargo on Iran.
"We are calling for lifting the embargo as soon as possible, and we will support the choices that Iran's negotiators make," Lavrov told reporters Thursday, according to Reuters. "Iran is a consistent supporter of the struggle against ISIS and lifting the arms embargo would help Iran to advance its efficiency in fighting terrorism," he added, referring to one of the acronyms for the Islamic State.
The weapons and missiles sanctions were imposed in 2006 and 2007 to pressure Iran to comply with its commitments under the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty. The agreement under discussion would require a new U.N. Security Council resolution that deals with the arms embargoes, but some restrictions would remain, according to a U.S. official involved in the talks. The official spoke on condition of anonymity to protect the sensitive nature of the talks.
The framework for a nuclear deal agreed to in April stipulated that a new U.N. Security Council resolution lifting nuclear sanctions would incorporate "important restrictions on conventional arms and ballistic missiles," according to a White House fact sheet released at the time.
State Department spokesman John Kirby said last week the United States is only discussing nuclear sanctions with Iran, and sanctions that target Iranian support for terrorism and its ballistic missile program would remain in place until Iran discontinues that support.
8 CONNECT 59 TWEET LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MhsGLj
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 14:41:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Young afghans find freedom through freerunning flips</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100062276/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Young-afghans-find-freedom-through-freerunning-flips/</Link>
        <Description>On the dusty streets of Kabul, amid the ruins of war, a group of young Afghans are finding freedom among the blast walls and checkpoints through the jumping, backflipping sport of parkour.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Young afghans find freedom through freerunning flips
On the dusty streets of Kabul, amid the ruins of war, a group of young Afghans are finding freedom among the blast walls and checkpoints through the jumping, backflipping sport of parkour.
Post to Facebook
Young afghans find freedom through freerunning flips On the dusty streets of Kabul, amid the ruins of war, a group of young Afghans are finding freedom among the blast walls and checkpoints through the jumping, backflipping sport of parkour. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mhq2Wa
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Young afghans find freedom through freerunning flips
On the dusty streets of Kabul, amid the ruins of war, a group of young Afghans are finding freedom among the blast walls and checkpoints through the jumping, backflipping sport of parkour. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 13:51:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama no longer sanguine on deal with Iran</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100057114/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Obama-no-longer-sanguine-on-deal-with-Iran/</Link>
        <Description>Bloomberg's Manus Cranny reports on today's "Top Headlines." He speaks on Bloomberg Television's "The Pulse."</Description>
        <MainBody>Obama no longer sanguine on deal with Iran
Bloomberg's Manus Cranny reports on today's "Top Headlines." He speaks on Bloomberg Television's "The Pulse."
Post to Facebook
Obama no longer sanguine on deal with Iran Bloomberg's Manus Cranny reports on today's "Top Headlines." He speaks on Bloomberg Television's "The Pulse." Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1ILGRJD
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Obama no longer sanguine on deal with Iran
Bloomberg's Manus Cranny reports on today's "Top Headlines." He speaks on Bloomberg Television's "The Pulse." Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 13:37:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What a 'Grexit' could mean for Greece and the U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100054922/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~What-a-Grexit-could-mean-for-Greece-and-the-US/</Link>
        <Description>USA TODAY economics reporter Paul Davidson sits down with Shannon Rae Green to discuss what Greece leaving the Eurozone could mean for both Greeks and Americans.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
What a 'Grexit' could mean for Greece and the U.S.
USA TODAY economics reporter Paul Davidson sits down with Shannon Rae Green to discuss what Greece leaving the Eurozone could mean for both Greeks and Americans.
Post to Facebook
What a 'Grexit' could mean for Greece and the U.S. USA TODAY economics reporter Paul Davidson sits down with Shannon Rae Green to discuss what Greece leaving the Eurozone could mean for both Greeks and Americans. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MhiPFv
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
What a 'Grexit' could mean for Greece and the U.S.
USA TODAY economics reporter Paul Davidson sits down with Shannon Rae Green to discuss what Greece leaving the Eurozone could mean for both Greeks and Americans. Paul Davidson, Shannon Rae Green, Jasper Colt, USA TODAY
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 17:33:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Report: Kim Jong Un has executed 70 officials</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100028826/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Report-Kim-Jong-Un-has-executed-officials/</Link>
        <Description>S. Korea previously said dozens of N. Korean officials have been executed, many by machine gun.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Report: Kim Jong Un has executed 70 officials
North Korea's ruler Kim Jong Un has executed about 70 officials "in a reign of terror" since taking power in late 2011, South Korean officials said Thursday, according to the Associated Press.
Post to Facebook
Report: Kim Jong Un has executed 70 officials North Korea's ruler Kim Jong Un has executed about 70 officials "in a reign of terror" since taking power in late 2011, South Korean officials said Thursday, according to the Associated Press. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MgVAv4
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
28
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Report: Kim Jong Un has executed 70 officials
Jane Onyanga-Omara , USA TODAY 10:33 a.m. EDT July 9, 2015
This undated picture released from North Korea's official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) on June 18, 2015 shows North Korean leader Kim Jong-Un at a photo session with the participants of the first reconnoitering officers' conference at an undisclosed location in North Korea.
(Photo: KNS, AFP/Getty Images)
162 CONNECT 110 TWEET 10 LINKEDIN 28 COMMENTEMAILMORE
North Korea's ruler Kim Jong Un has executed about 70 officials "in a reign of terror" since taking power in late 2011, South Korean officials said Thursday, according to the Associated Press.
Speaking at a forum in Seoul, Foreign Minister Yun Byung-se said Kim's late father Kim Jong Il had executed about 10 people in his first years in power  far fewer than his son.
The AP reported an official from South Korea's National Intelligence Service, who refused to be named citing office rules, said the agency believes Kim, who is thought to be around 32 years old, has executed about 70 officials. Information related to the highly secretive North Korea is extremely difficult to independently confirm.
In May, a report emerged that Hyon Yong-chol, North Korea's defense minister, had apparently been executed, possibly with an anti-aircraft gun, in front of hundreds of people at a military school in Pyongyang, the North Korean capital.
Report: N. Korean minister executed for disloyalty to Kim
His offense was disloyalty to Kim, Yonhap news agency reported, citing the NIS. Yonhap added Hyon, 66, was seen dozing off during a military event presided over by Kim and challenged his authority on several occasions. He may have been attempting to start a rebellion against the young leader, the NIS said.
In December 2013, Kim's uncle Jang Song Thaek  once considered North Korea's second most powerful man  was executed for alleged treason. Reports followed the next month that all direct relatives of Jang, who was married to Kim Jong Il's sister, had also been put to death.
South Korea's government has previously said that dozens of North Korean officials have been executed, many by machine gun.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 06:44:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European discounter Ryanair expands to Israel</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/100009932/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~European-discounter-Ryanair-expands-to-Israel/</Link>
        <Description>Israel will be the carrier's 31st country once the flights launch in early November.</Description>
        <MainBody>European discounter Ryanair expands to Israel
Israel will be the carrier's 31st country once the flights launch in early November.
Post to Facebook
European discounter Ryanair expands to Israel Israel will be the carrier's 31st country once the flights launch in early November. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IKOPCZ
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
European discounter Ryanair expands to Israel
Today in the Sky
Ben Mutzabaugh , USA TODAY 11:44 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Two attendants of Europe's biggest low-cost airline Ryanair caress camel "Ernie" standing in front of a Ryanair plane on March 29, 2011 at the airport in Bremen, Germany. The Irish airline started flights from Bremen to the new destination Marrakech in Morocco.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
This file photo from May 25, 2004, shows an employee of the airport in Hahn. Germany, guiding a Ryanair plane.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
Passengers at Dublin Airport pass a row of Ryanair ads highlighting recent service improvements in this Sept. 21, 2014, photo.
(Photo: Shawn Pogatchnik, AP)
Passengers board a Ryanair flight at Dublin Airport on Sept. 18, 2014.
(Photo: Shawn Pogatchnik, AP)
This file photo from Jan. 19, 2014, shows a Ryanair plane flying in front of a rainbow over Rome.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
This file photo from Sept. 21, 2014 shows passengers as they exit a Ryanair flight at Dublin Airport.
(Photo: Shawn Pogatchnik, AP)
This file photo from May 24, 2011, shows fliers queuing at a Ryanair check-in desk at the Dublin airport in Ireland.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
This file photo from Dec. 1, 2008,  shows a Ryanair jet takes off from Belfast City Airport. in Northern Ireland.
(Photo: AP)
Michael O'Leary, CEO of Ryanair (left) and Ray Conner, CEO of The Boeing Company, hold a press conference announcing the first sales of Boeing's new 737 Max 200 to Ryanair on Sept. 8, 2014 in New York.
(Photo: Andrew Burton, Getty Images)
This file photo from Oct. 11, 2014, shows a Ryanair Boeing 737 taking off from the Lille-Lesquin airport in northern France.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
Ryanair planes seen at an airport in southern France on Sept. 28, 2010.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
This Oct. 17, 2010, aerial view shows Ryanair planes at the Marseille-Provence airport in Marignane, France.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
This file photo from Nov. 8, 2006,  Ryanair Boeing 737s at the Marseille-Provence airport in Marignane, southern France.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
This file photo from Sept. 1, 2010 shows a Ryanair plane at the Barcelona airport.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:36:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>El-Nino Fuelled Drought Hits Thailand's Economy</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99998402/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~ElNino-Fuelled-Drought-Hits-Thailands-Economy/</Link>
        <Description>July 9 -- After reaping unsustainable levels of rice from Shinawatra years, Thailand is facing another struggle. Water restrictions are in place in almost a third of provinces and economists are warning of a severe impact on growth. Bloomberg's Sher</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
El-Nino Fuelled Drought Hits Thailand's Economy
July 9 -- After reaping unsustainable levels of rice from Shinawatra years, Thailand is facing another struggle. Water restrictions are in place in almost a third of provinces and economists are warning of a severe impact on growth. Bloomberg's Sher
Post to Facebook
El-Nino Fuelled Drought Hits Thailand's Economy July 9 -- After reaping unsustainable levels of rice from Shinawatra years, Thailand is facing another struggle. Water restrictions are in place in almost a third of provinces and economists are warning of a severe impact on growth. Bloomberg's Sher Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MgjVBf
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
El-Nino Fuelled Drought Hits Thailand's Economy
July 9 -- After reaping unsustainable levels of rice from Shinawatra years, Thailand is facing another struggle. Water restrictions are in place in almost a third of provinces and economists are warning of a severe impact on growth. Bloomberg's Sher Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:15:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Opening Uganda's closet</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99997154/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Opening-Ugandas-closet/</Link>
        <Description>Can Uganda's gay-rights activists stop the government from  enacting another homophobic law?</Description>
        <MainBody>Can Uganda's gay-rights activists stop the government from  enacting another homophobic law?
Post to Facebook
Opening Uganda's closet Can Uganda's gay-rights activists stop the government from  enacting another homophobic law? Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IKwjuo
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Opening Uganda's closet
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:02:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pete Peterson: America can't afford Greek complacency</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99953724/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Pete-Peterson-America-cant-afford-Greek-complacency/</Link>
        <Description>As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pete Peterson: America can't afford Greek complacency
As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest.
Post to Facebook
Pete Peterson: America can't afford Greek complacency As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MfpShQ
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
8
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Pete Peterson: America can't afford Greek complacency
Peter G. Peterson 4:02 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest.
Pensioners line up at the main gate of the national bank of Greece in Athens on July 7, 2015.
(Photo: Emilio Morenatti, AP)
94 CONNECT 38 TWEET 17 LINKEDIN 8 COMMENTEMAILMORE
The world watches as the Greek tragedy unfolds, as pensioners continue to line up at shuttered banks, desperately attempting to withdraw some of their life savings.  These heartbreaking images show us what a debt crisis really looks like, as Greece's economy is in free fall and its most vulnerable citizens are so profoundly affected.
As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest in Greece's condition (my father changed his name to Peterson from Petropoulos, which means "son of Peter").  But I also care deeply about the enduring opportunity for every citizen of the United States to live out the American Dream that I have been so blessed to live.
With more than 60% voting a resounding "no" on a proposed European financing offer, Europe and Greece face fundamental questions about where they go from here.  Greece has unfortunately left itself with few good options.
The world is focused on critical near-term questions, but it is important to remember that the seeds of this despair were planted long before the recent crisis began.  Although austerity measures and currency limitations made matters worse, Greece has faced imbalances between spending and revenues over many years, and the resulting high level of debt gave the Greeks little flexibility for dealing with the current fiscal and economic crisis once it began.
EU technocrats bleed Greece dry: Other views
Unfortunately, now there are no quick fixes or painless paths forward.  The country is left with limited and poor options to stabilize the economy and provide relief, potentially relying on other nations to dictate the terms of their future.  Indeed, the better time to act was well before the crisis.
There are countless differences between the circumstances of the U.S. and Greece. We are in a fundamentally better position and are nowhere near this kind of economic crisis.
Nonetheless, there are important lessons to be learned about the benefits of long-term planning and maintaining fiscal health and flexibility.
Without question, the United States remains on a fiscal path that is unsustainable and dangerous by any international standard.  Last month's non-partisan Congressional Budget Office analysis projects that by 2040, federal debt will climb to more than 100% of gross domestic product based on current laws, and would reach 175% of GDP under less optimistic assumptions. Debt at that level, CBO warns, would significantly harm our economy, reduce incomes and increase the chances of a fiscal crisis.
As just one staggering data point, interest costs alone will reach $5.5 trillion over the next decade , and are on a path to exceed all federal revenues. That's an absurd fiscal trajectory for any country to put itself on  including and especially a strong nation such as America.
While American debt can inflict pain on its citizens the same way that Greece's has, one critical comparative advantage we have is time.  This time gives us a wider range of options to choose from, and to make decisions on our own terms.  Because a major fiscal crisis is not right in front of us, we can implement reforms that are sensible, gradual and compassionate.
Europe must back away from Greek austerity cliff: Joseph Stiglitz
There are major benefits of putting the U.S. on a stable fiscal path.  A strong fiscal foundation is key to increasing incomes, prosperity and opportunity.  With lower interest costs, we will have more resources available for important private and public investments that improve productivity and competitiveness.  And fiscal strength is essential to maintaining a safety net for the most vulnerable, and to our ability to respond to unforeseen crises, foreign and domestic.
It is often hard for the U.S. to make politically difficult choices in the absence of an immediate crisis.  But complacency carries a cost.  A growing debt burden hurts our economy well in advance of any crisis.  And sadly, the situation in Greece is showing us how high the costs of a full crisis can be.
My father often reminded me of the Greek concept of  or "economia"  the importance of saving for the future.  I am sure he is looking down on Greece with great concern, but with the hope that his beloved America will take advantage of the opportunity it has to solve its own fiscal challenges.
Peter G. Peterson is the founder and chairman of the Peter G. Peterson Foundation , the chairman emeritus of the Council on Foreign Relations, the former secretary of Commerce and the co-founder of the Blackstone Group.
In addition to its own editorials, USA TODAY publishes diverse opinions from outside writers, including our Board of Contributors . To read more columns like this, go to the Opinion front page .
94 CONNECT 38 TWEET 17 LINKEDIN 8 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MfpShQ
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:10:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia vetoes U.N. resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99952308/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Russia-vetoes-UN-resolution-calling-Srebrenica-a-genocide/</Link>
        <Description>Russia says singling out Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Russia vetoes U.N. resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide
Russia vetoed a U.N. resolution Wednesday that would have condemned the 1995 massacre of Muslims at Srebrenica during the Bosnian war as a "crime of genocide," saying that singling out the Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division in the Balkans.
Post to Facebook
Russia vetoes U.N. resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide Russia vetoed a U.N. resolution Wednesday that would have condemned the 1995 massacre of Muslims at Srebrenica during the Bosnian war as a "crime of genocide," saying that singling out the Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division in the Balkans. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MfmBiI
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Russia vetoes U.N. resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide
Edith M. Lederer, Associated Press 3:10 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Bosnian people visit graves at memorial center in Potocari near Srebrenica, Bosnia, on July 8, 2015.
(Photo: Amel Emric, AP)
31 CONNECT 43 TWEET LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
UNITED NATIONS (AP)  Russia vetoed a U.N. resolution Wednesday that would have condemned the 1995 massacre of Muslims at Srebrenica during the Bosnian war as a "crime of genocide," saying that singling out the Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division in the Balkans.
Two international courts have called the slaughter by Bosnian Serbs of some 8,000 Muslim men and boys who had sought refuge at what was supposed to be a U.N.-protected site genocide.
But Russia's U.N. Ambassador Vitaly Churkin objected to focusing only on Srebrenica, calling the resolution "confrontational and politically motivated" and stressing that Bosnian Serbs and Croats had also suffered during the 1992-95 war that killed at least 100,000 people.
Britain drafted the resolution to mark the 20th anniversary of the Srebrenica massacre on Tuesday, but the vote was delayed to address Russian concerns.
The defeated resolution states that acceptance of "the tragic events at Srebrenica as genocide is a prerequisite for reconciliation" and "condemns denial of this genocide as hindering efforts towards reconciliation."
Britain's U.N. deputy ambassador Peter Wilson stressed that the resolution "did not point fingers of blame, score political points nor seek to reopen political divisions." It also didn't link the crimes at Srebrenica to the Serb people and recognized there were victims on all sides, he said.
The vote was 10 countries in favor, Russia casting a veto, and four abstentions  China, Nigeria, Angola and Venezuela.
Leaders of the Bosnian Serbs and Serbia, who have close religious and cultural ties to Russia, have lobbied President Vladimir Putin to vote "no.'
Serbia's pro-Russian President Tomislav Nikolic said Russia's veto "not only prevented the throwing of guilt against the whole Serbian nation, trying to show it as  genocidal, but it also proved that Russia is a real and sincere friend."
Wilson said Britain was "outraged" by Russia's veto.
"Russia's actions tarnish the memory of all those who died in the Srebrenica genocide," he said. "Russia will have to justify its behavior to the families of over 8,000 people murdered in the worst atrocity in Europe since the Second World War."
Bosnians reacted bitterly to the veto.
"This is a defeat of justice," said Camil Durakovic, the mayor of Srebrenica. "The world has lost. The world  and especially Serbia  will have to face the truth sooner or later," he said.
Fadila Efendic, a Srebrenica woman who lost her son and husband in the Srebrenica massacre, called the veto "another humiliation of the victims."
"Today's vote mattered," said U.S. Ambassador Samantha Power, who was a 24-year-old journalist in Bosnia at the time of the Srebrenica massacre. "It mattered hugely to the families of the victims of the Srebrenica genocide. Russia's veto is heartbreaking for those families, and it is a further stain on this council's record."
Russia's Churkin began his speech before the vote asking for a minute of silence in memory of the victims of Srebrenica and everyone in the Security Council stood, many bowing their heads.
Instead of Srebrenica, he said the council should commemorate the 20th anniversary of the 1995 peace agreement signed in Dayton, Ohio that ended the Bosnian war later this year, and make every effort to implement it and normalize relations in the Balkans.
"Our vote against ... will, however, not mean that we are deaf to the suffering of victims of Srebrenica and other areas of Bosnia and Herzegovina," Churkin said.
Associated Press writers Aida Cerkez in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Dusan Stojanovic in Belgrade contributed to this report.
31 CONNECT 43 TWEET LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MfmBiI
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:14:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WikiLeaks: NSA targeted German chancellery, Merkel aides</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99946246/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~WikiLeaks-NSA-targeted-German-chancellery-Merkel-aides/</Link>
        <Description>There was no immediate comment from the German government.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
WikiLeaks: NSA targeted German chancellery, Merkel aides
WikiLeaks on Wednesday published a new list of German phone numbers it claims showed the U.S. National Security Agency targeted phones belonging to Chancellor Angela Merkel's close aides and chancellery offices for surveillance.
Post to Facebook
WikiLeaks: NSA targeted German chancellery, Merkel aides WikiLeaks on Wednesday published a new list of German phone numbers it claims showed the U.S. National Security Agency targeted phones belonging to Chancellor Angela Merkel's close aides and chancellery offices for surveillance. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MffFlD
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
WikiLeaks: NSA targeted German chancellery, Merkel aides
AP 2:14 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Visiting German Chancellor Angela Merkel speaks during a news conference after meeting with Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama, on the first stop of her Balkan tour in Tirana on July 8, 2015.
(Photo: Hektor Pustina, AP)
14 CONNECT 47 TWEET LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
BERLIN (AP)  WikiLeaks on Wednesday published a new list of German phone numbers it claims showed the U.S. National Security Agency targeted phones belonging to Chancellor Angela Merkel's close aides and chancellery offices for surveillance.
Wednesday's publication came a week after WikiLeaks released a list of numbers it said showed the NSA targeted officials at various other German ministries and elsewhere. That rekindled concerns over U.S. surveillance in Germany after reports two years ago that Merkel's own cellphone was targeted.
Merkel's chief of staff last week asked the U.S. ambassador to a meeting and told him that German law must be followed.
There was no immediate comment from the German government on the latest publication.
The list includes a cellphone number attributed to Ronald Pofalla, Merkel's chief of staff from 2009-13; a landline number that appears to belong to the leader of Merkel's parliamentary caucus; various other connections at Merkel's office; and a cellphone number for the chancellor that WikiLeaks says was used until 2013.
It was unclear when exactly the partially redacted list of 56 German phone numbers dates from and it wasn't immediately possible to confirm the accuracy of that and other documents released by WikiLeaks.
Those documents, WikiLeaks said, are NSA reports based on interceptions  including one from 2009 that details Merkel's views on the international financial crisis and another from 2011 summarizing advisers' views on plans for the eurozone's rescue fund.
According to the secret-spilling site, the list of phone numbers was updated for more than a decade after 2002 and a "close study" of it shows it evolved from an earlier target list dating back into the 1990s.
14 CONNECT 47 TWEET LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MffFlD
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:26:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Voices: Like post-earthquake Nepal, Red God is in limbo</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99941880/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Voices-Like-postearthquake-Nepal-Red-God-is-in-limbo/</Link>
        <Description>The god, stalled in the midst of its pilgrimage, symbolizes the plight of Nepal.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Voices: Like post-earthquake Nepal, Red God is in limbo
Like more than 3 million Nepalis, the Red God is homeless. Since the 7.8 magnitude earthquake on April 25, his enormous wooden chariot, with its towering jute and vine spire, has been
Post to Facebook
Voices: Like post-earthquake Nepal, Red God is in limbo Like more than 3 million Nepalis, the Red God is homeless. Since the 7.8 magnitude earthquake on April 25, his enormous wooden chariot, with its towering jute and vine spire, has been Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MfaH8u
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Voices: Like post-earthquake Nepal, Red God is in limbo
Donatella Lorch, Special for USA TODAY 5:26 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Like more than 3 million Nepalis, the Red God is homeless. Since the magnitude-7.8 earthquake on April 25, 2015, his enormous wooden chariot, with its towering jute and vine spire, has been parked, or rather stopped, in the middle of a street just up the road from where I live. The spire, leaning precipitously even before the earthquake, is secured with two heavy ropes tied to nearby trees.
(Photo: Donatella Lorch)
82 CONNECT 78 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
LALITPUR, Nepal  Like more than 3 million Nepalis, the Red God is homeless. Since the magnitude-7.8 earthquake on April 25, his enormous wooden chariot, with its towering jute and vine spire, has been parked, or rather stopped, in the middle of a street just up the road from where I live. The spire, leaning precipitously even before the earthquake, is secured with two heavy ropes tied to nearby trees.
The god, known as the Rato Machhendranath, is never alone.  There is always a Hindu or Buddhist priest sitting next to him in his tiny alcove, perched 10 feet above the street, and always two shotgun-toting police officers to guard him as well. Worshipers light butter lamps on the road below him and passersby on motorcycles slow down, touching their foreheads and then the huge carved and brightly painted wooden wheels, demonstrating 'puja' or prayer.
The symbolism of this stalled chariot is not lost on many people in the Kathmandu Valley. In growing competition with a fast-encroaching modern world, this is a land of deep and complex religious rituals, an intricate mix of Hinduism and tantric Buddhism practiced by the Newars, the original inhabitants of the valley. Their traditional villages of brick and mud homes, dotting the area around Kathmandu, were hit hardest by the earthquake.
The Red God's home is in Bungamati, a Newar village just south of Patan, Kathmandu's twin city.  In just over 40 seconds, the April earthquake destroyed or badly damaged almost the entire village. The god's home, a temple in the main square, turned into a pile of rubble.
"We have been stopped here for two months," said Shaunu Shakya, 65, a priest who is accompanying the Red God. "Never in the history of the festival has an earthquake come. The astrologers say we must complete our trip, but that we also cannot move until the aftershocks stop for at least four days."
Machhendranath's limbo is very much Nepal's as it struggles to rebuild, its past damaged and its future uncertain. More than two months since the quake, it is slowly becoming clearer that the tremors, which continue on a daily basis, did more than just destroy homes. They are continuously influencing a way of life and thinking. For many, especially outside Kathmandu, it is a day-to-day struggle for food and shelter. Heavy monsoon rains are destabilizing the earthquakecracked mountains, and landslides have already begun to sweep away villages in the north and east of the country. The international community has committed more than $4 billion to help rebuild Nepal, but that complex work will only begin in early September.
I've lived in Nepal for two years, and for much of that time, I had planned to be in Kathmandu for April 2015.  This April was one of Nepal's most unique festivals, the storied Rato Machhendranath jatra, which occurs only once every 12 years. It is not only one of the largest and longest chariot festivals in the world, lasting two to four months depending on the determinations of local astrologers, but also a massive spectacle involving months of priestly rituals, many animal sacrifices, the construction of the chariot (by hand) and tens of thousands of spectators.
The Red God isn't really much to look at. He is a smallish enigma, just over 3 feet tall, wrapped in shapeless cloth. Every year, a priest gives his flattish wide face a bright new coat of red paint. He is worshiped by both Hindus and Buddhists. He is all powerful, but humans can summon him at will.
The event begins in Bungamati, about 8 kilometers south of Patan, where carpenter clans build the 6-foot-high wooden wheels from scratch, without nails, and vine lashers hand-tie a complex and thick weave of tree trunks, cane and vines into a 60-foot-high spire, called a 'rath.' The chariot is hand-pulled with thick ropes by hundreds of youths.
On April 25, the rath  was about 500 yards from our house. My son Lucas and I were invited to watch the afternoon pulling from the rooftop of a nearby house. An hour later, the earthquake hit Nepal.
There are those who believe that the earthquake happened because the Red God's chariot was built without fully observing construction rituals. Many Nepalis do not believe in these superstitions. Yet there is a link between this festival and life in Nepal. The complexities involved in building and moving the chariot are emblematic of an old world of risk and contingency, where ancient rituals must be observed in an effort to ensure stability, if not progress, and where the line between triumph and disaster is often very fine.
The earthquake brought communities together. Neighbors are helping neighbors. Many are living in transitional shelters, trying to get through the monsoons and the upcoming winter, until they have the means to rebuild their houses.  The Red God's permanent temple will also need to be rebuilt, and he will need to live elsewhere while that happens. But he is not alone, and like many Nepalis, he and his devotees also show the tremendous resilience for which Nepal is famous.
Lorch is a writer based in Nepal
82 CONNECT 78 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MfaH8u
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:38:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99933312/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~White-House-ready-to-let-Iran-talks-continue-indefinitely/</Link>
        <Description>GOP lawmakers say getting a good deal is more important than meeting  a deadline.</Description>
        <MainBody>White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely
An interim agreement in November 2013 required Iran to scale back its nuclear activities.
Post to Facebook
White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely An interim agreement in November 2013 required Iran to scale back its nuclear activities. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mf1tco
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
17
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely
Oren Dorell , USA TODAY 12:38 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
White House press secretary Josh Earnest answers a question on the Iran nuclear talks during the daily press briefing on July 7, 2015.
(Photo: Evan Vucci, AP)
54 CONNECT 79 TWEET LINKEDIN 17 COMMENTEMAILMORE
After missing two deadlines in a week, the White House may allow Iran nuclear talks to continue indefinitely under an interim agreement that already limits Iran's nuclear program.
While the pressure of deadlines set for June 30 and Tuesday succeeded in squeezing important concessions from Iran, "we haven't gotten everything that we wanted yet," White House spokesman Josh Earnest said.
"What we want to make sure of is that we continue to keep in place, an agreement that freezes Iran's nuclear program, rolls it back in some key areas, while we continue to have these conversations," he said.
The negotiations in Vienna between Iran and six world powers  the United States, Britain, France, Russia, China and Germany  aim to curb Iran's nuclear program in return for lifting crippling U.S. and international sanctions on Tehran. Envoys now seek a conclusion by Friday.
Secretary of State John Kerry, left, meets with his counterparts from world powers and Iran at nuclear talks in Vienna on July 6, 2015.
(Photo: Joe Klamar, AFP/Getty Images)
Each time a deadline for the talks is extended,  the negotiators must agree to extend the date of the terms of the interim agreement reached in November 2013 .
Iran's deputy foreign minister, Abbas Araqchi, told reporters in Vienna that Iran is not bound by any deadline and will stay in Vienna as long as it takes, but that there will be no months-long extension to the talks, according to Tasnim News Agency.
Negotiators have made progress on several major sticking areas where the sides seemed far apart two weeks ago. These include tentative agreements by Iran to answer questions by the U.N. nuclear watchdog agency about past nuclear research, and to participate in a process for granting inspectors access to suspected civilian and military nuclear sites.
Diplomats have also reached a tentative agreement on the timing for the lifting of sanctions, which Iran wants eliminated immediately and the United States wants lifted in stages as an agreement is implemented.
Differences remain, however, on whether those sanctions will be suspended, as Western nations want, so they can be reimposed if Iran fails to meet terms of the agreement, or eliminated for good, as Iran would like.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99933308/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Boko-Haram-offers-to-swap-kidnapped-girls-for-detainees/</Link>
        <Description>Boko Haram's offer is limited to the girls taken in April 2014.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees
Boko Haram's offer is limited to the girls taken in April 2014.
Post to Facebook
Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees Boko Haram's offer is limited to the girls taken in April 2014. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mf22CM
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees
Michelle Faul, Associated Press 12:23 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
The parents of children abducted by Boko Haram attend an event linked to the "Bring Back Our Girls" campaign at the presidential residence in Abuja, Nigeria, on July 8, 2015.
(Photo: Olamikan Gbemiga, AP)
28 CONNECT 61 TWEET LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
LAGOS, Nigeria (AP)  Nigeria's Boko Haram extremists are offering to free more than 200 young women and girls kidnapped from a boarding school in the town of Chibok in exchange for the release of militant leaders held by the government, a human rights activist has told The Associated Press.
The activist said Boko Haram's current offer is limited to the girls from the school in northeastern Nigeria whose mass abduction in April 2014 ignited worldwide outrage and a campaign to "Bring Back Our Girls" that stretched to the White House.
The new initiative reopens an offer made last year to the government of former President Goodluck Jonathan to release the 219 students in exchange for 16 Boko Haram detainees, the activist said. The man, who was involved in negotiations with Boko Haram last year and is close to current negotiators, spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to talk to reporters on this sensitive issue.
Fred Eno, an apolitical Nigerian who has been negotiating with Boko Haram for more than a year, told the AP that "another window of opportunity opened" in the last few days, though he could not discuss details.
He said the recent slew of Boko Haram bloodletting   some 350 people killed in the past nine days  is consistent with past ratcheting up of violence as the militants seek a stronger negotiating position.
Presidential adviser Femi Adesina said on Saturday that Nigeria's government "will not be averse" to talks with Boko Haram. "Most wars, however furious or vicious, often end around the negotiation table," he said.
Eno said the 5-week-old administration of President Muhammadu Buhari offers "a clean slate" to bring the militants back to negotiations that had become poisoned by the different security agencies and their advice to Jonathan.
Two months of talks last year led government representatives and Eno to travel in September to a northeastern town where the prisoner exchange was to take place, only to be stymied by the Department for State Service intelligence agency, the activist said.
At the last minute, the agency said it was holding only four of the militants sought by Boko Haram, the activist said.
It is not known how many Boko Haram suspects are detained by Nigeria's intelligence agency, whose chief Buhari fired last week.
The activist said the agency continues to hold suspects illegally because it does not have enough evidence for a conviction, and any court would free them. Nigerian law requires charges be brought after 48 hours.
Thousands of suspects have died in custody, and some detainees wanted by Boko Haram may be among them. Amnesty International alleges that 8,000 detainees have died in military custody  some have been shot, some have died from untreated injuries due to torture, and some have died from starvation and other harsh treatment.
In May, about 300 women, girls and children being held captive by Boko Haram were rescued by Nigeria's military, but none were from Chibok. It is believed that the militants view the Chibok girls as a last-resort bargaining chip.
In that infamous abduction, 274 mostly Christian girls preparing to write science exams were seized from the school by Islamic militants in the early hours of April 15, 2014. Dozens escaped on their own in the first few days, but 219 remain missing.
Boko Haram has not shown them since a May 2014 video in which its leader, Abubakar Shekau warned: "You won't see the girls again unless you release our brothers you have captured."
In the video, nearly 100 of the girls, who have been identified by their parents, were shown wearing Islamic hijab and reciting the Quran. One of them said they had converted to Islam.
International indignation at Nigeria's failure to rescue the girls was joined by U.S. first lady Michelle Obama. In a radio address in May 2014, she said she and President Barack Obama are "outraged and heartbroken" over the abduction.
Jonathan's government initially denied there had been any mass abduction and delays of a rescue that might have brought the girls home became a hallmark of his other failures. He steadfastly refused to meet with the Bring Back Our Girls campaigners, charging they were politicizing the issue.
On Wednesday, President Buhari welcomed those campaigners at the presidential villa in Abuja and pleaded "We only ask for your patience." He said "The delay and conflicting reaction by the former government and its agencies is very unfortunate."
Campaign leader Oby Ezekwesili said, "The rescue of our Chibok girls is the strongest statement that this government could make to showg respect for the sanctity and dignity of every Nigerian life."
There have been unconfirmed reports that some of the girls have been taken to neighboring countries, and that some have been radicalized and trained as fighters. At least three were reported to have died  one from dysentery, one from malaria and one from a snake bite.
Last year, Shekau said the girls were an "old story," and that he had married them off to his fighters.
Lawan Zanna, whose daughter is among the captives, said this week that 14 Chibok parents have died since the mass kidnapping, many from stress-related illnesses blamed on the ordeal.
Some of the Chibok girls who managed to escape have been rejected by their community and now live with family friends, tired of hearing taunts like "Boko Haram wives."
The assumption that all girls and women held by the group have been raped is a difficult stigma to overcome in Nigeria's highly religious and conservative society.
Shekau had threatened in 2013 to kidnap women and girls if Nigeria's military did not release detained Boko Haram wives and children. The government freed them in May of that year as a goodwill gesture ahead of failed peace talks.
Boko Haram has kidnapped hundreds more  girls, boys, women and young men. Some have become sex slaves, while others are used as fighters, according to former captives.
Nigerian opinion on negotiating with the extremists is mixed. Some say the group's crimes are too heinous to be forgiven: The 6-year-old Islamic uprising has killed more than 13,000 people and forced about 1.5 million from their homes.
"A lot of people take a hard-line stance that you must never negotiate with a terrorist," said Sen. Chris Anyanwu. She called it a "very complex" issue, balancing the lives of more than 200 girls against the dangers of freeing extremists.
The militants last year seized a large swath of northeast Nigeria and declared an Islamic caliphate. Nigeria and its neighbors deployed a multinational army that forced them out of towns and villages this year, but the bloodshed has risen at a fierce rate since Buhari's May 29 inauguration amid pledges to crush the insurgency.
Associated Press writer Bashir Adigun contributed to this report from Abuja, Nigeria.
28 CONNECT 61 TWEET LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1Mf22CM
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Battling Islamic State militants</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/87524922/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Battling-Islamic-State-militants/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Battling Islamic State militants
Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq.
Post to Facebook
Battling Islamic State militants Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1ChmkJu
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Battling Islamic State militants
Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters fire at Islamic State positions during a battle near the Baiji oil refinery.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters advance near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Shiite fighters hold a position near the Baiji oil refinery.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters hold a position against Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Sunni fighters battle Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Shiite fighters from the Popular Mobilization Units display an Iraqi national flag in front of an Islamic State mural on April 1 outside a presidential palace in Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government security forces celebrate in Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government soldiers battle Islamic State militants in Tikrit.
European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi counterterrorism forces patrol a street.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces deploy in the city.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi soldier guards a checkpoint.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi army tank advances in Tikrit on March 31 during a battle against Islamic State militants.  Iraqi Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi announced that Iraqi troops, supported by U.S.-led airstrikes, have recaptured most of the town from the Islamic State.
European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke rises during fighting in Tikrit.
European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi security forces conduct a house-to-house search for Islamic State militants on March 30 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces attack Islamic State extremists in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government troops watch an area outside the city. Islamic State militants have booby trapped streets and buildings in Tikrit with explosives.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi officer shouts orders.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces launch a rocket at Islamic State extremists.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security force soldiers run to a position as they surround Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi forces fire rockets at Islamic State positions in Tikrit on March 28.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government vehicles are positioned outside western Tikrit on March 27 during a military operation to retake the city from Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke billows from an air strike as Iraqi government troops hold a position outside Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government vehicles maneuver outside the city.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Explosions rock Tikrit as Iraqi security forces fire rockets against Islamic State militants.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi government vehicle drives to a position.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi security troops fire a mortar at positions held by Islamic State militants.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Smoke rises from buildings during a bombardment in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces fire a rocket at Islamic State militants on March 26 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi helicopter attacks Islamic State positions in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
A member of the Iraqi Shiite militant group the Imam Ali Brigades patrols in Tikrit on March 25.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
A volunteer fighter with the Shiite militant group Jihad Brigades fires his weapon at Islamic State militants on March 21 outside Tikrit, Iraq.
AP
Iraqi fighters with the Saraya al-Salam Brigade, a group formed by Iraqi Shiite Muslim cleric Moqtada al-Sadr, wave their weapons as they leave Najaf to join the fight against Islamic State militants on March 20.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi police leave Najaf to join government and coalition forces battling Islamic State militants in Tikrit.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A U.S. Navy jet takes off on March 19 from the aircraft carrier Carl Vinson on March 19 in the Persian Gulf. The Carl Vinson and French military jets from the French aircraft carrier Charles de Gaulle are flying missions over Iraq against Islamic State militants.
Hasan Jamali, AP
Iraqi security forces and allied Shiite militiamen battle Islamic State fighters in the Qadisiyah neighborhood in Tikrit on March 15.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Members of the group Soldiers of Imam Ali Brigade launch rockets against Islamic State extremists on March 15 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi army armored vehicle prepares to attack Islamic State positions on March 12 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government security forces patrol in Tikrit
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces and allied Shiite militiamen prepare to attack Islamic State extremists at Camp Speicher.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Shiite militiamen prepare to attack Islamic State extremists at Camp Speicher.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Shiite militiamen prepare to fire a mortar at Islamic State extremists in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi government soldier fires at Islamic State militants on March 11 in Tikrit.
AP
Iraqi government soldiers attack Islamic State militants as they attempt to recapture Tikrit. Iraqi soldiers and Shiite militiamen have entered Tikrit, the largest city controlled by the extremists.
AP
Iraqi government forces deploy during a military operation against Islamic State militants near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi government vehicle fires at Islamic State positions near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi pro-government fighters celebrate as they advance into Tikrit. Government forces are conducting a major military operation against Islamic State militants to recapture the city from the jihadist group.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi medics treat wounded fighters at a field hospital.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi fighter from the Popular Mobilization Unit holds a position as pro-government forces advance into Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
A member of a tribal group fighting alongside Iraqi government forces fires at Islamic State militants during a battle in the Hosh district in Ramadi.
Azhar Shallal, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi police officer aims a rocket-propelled grenade during clashes with Islamic State militants in the Hosh district of Ramadi.
Azhar Shallal, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the Popular Mobilization Unit celebrate with a captured Islamic State flag on March 9 after recapturing Albu Ajil village near Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces advance on Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government troops conduct a military operation against Islamic State militants in Albu Ajil village near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces drive toward Al-Alam village on March 8.
Younis Al-Bayati, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi soldier fires at Islamic State positions near Tikrit on March 4.
Iraqi Ministry of Defense via AP
Volunteer pro-government Shiite fighters with the Popular Mobilization Unit fire a howitzer at Islamic State militants on Feb. 28 at Awaynat near Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Egyptian military jet takes off from an undisclosed base on Feb. 16 to strike Islamic State targets in Libya. Egyptian warplanes bombed Islamic State positions in retaliation for the beheading of 21 Egyptian Coptic Christian hostages.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
A video image from an Egyptian warplane shows an airstrike on an Islamic State target in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
A video image shows a bomb hit on an Islamic State position in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
An image from Egypt's television station Al-Masriya shows a Egyptian F-16 fighter jet preparing to take off from an undisclosed location to conduct an airstrike on Islamic State targets in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A United Arab Emirates pilot prepares to take off in an F-16 on Feb. 10 at a base in Jordan. The United Arab Emirates launched airstrikes against Islamic State militants, marking the nation's return to combat operations after it halted flights in late 2014.
WAM via AP
A United Arab Emirates F-16 jet prepares for an airstrike against Islamic State targets at a base in Jordan.
WAM via AP
A Jordanian air force pilot writes a message to Islamic State militants on a missile at Mowafak Al-Salti airbase in Azraq on Feb. 6.
Roya TV via AP
Kayla Mueller speaks to a group on May 30, 2013, in Prescott, Ariz. The White House and her family confirmed the death of Mueller, who was being held by Islamic State militants, on Feb. 10.
Matt Hinshaw, The Daily Courier, via AP
Fullscreen
An image posted by the Islamic State on jihadist forums on Feb. 6 shows a heavily damaged building in Raqa, Syria, after it was allegedly targeted by a coalition airstrike. In a statement posted on jihadist websites the Islamic State group claims a female American hostage had been killed in a raid by coalition warplanes.
AFP/Getty Images
Thousands of people participate in a mass demonstration after Friday prayers near Al Hussein Mosque in Amman, Jordan, to express their solidarity with a Jordanian pilot murdered by the Islamic State group.
Jordan Pix, Getty Images
An image from the Jordanian television on Feb. 5 shows flames erupting from a building hit by an airstrike against Islamic State militants.
AFP/Getty Images
A Jordanian fighter jet takes off from an airbase.
Jordan News Agency via European Pressphoto Agency
A miltary officer writes a message on a missile. The Arabic words reads, "Will show them hell, from the Jordanian air force."
Jordan News Agency via European Pressphoto Agency
Fullscreen
Members of the Kurdish peshmerga forces and the Iraqi security forces patrol on a road as smoke billows from the Khubbaz oil field, some 15 miles west of the northern city of Kirkuk a few days after peshmerga forces and police retook the area from Islamic State group. 
Marwan Ibrahim, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
Members of the Yazidi minority search for clues that might lead them to missing relatives among the remains of those killed by the Islamic State jihadi group, a day after Kurdish forces discovered a mass grave near the Iraqi village of Sinuni, in the northwestern Sinjar area.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
Iraqi Shiite fighters celebrate in al-Mansuriya, in Iraq's Diyala province, after government forces retook the area from Islamic State group's control. Iraqi forces have "liberated" Diyala province from the Islamic State jihadist group, retaking all populated areas of the eastern region.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A Syrian Kurdish sniper sits among the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, Syria. The Islamic State group has acknowledged for the first time that its fighters were defeated there, but vowed to attack the town again.
AP
Fullscreen
A Syrian Kurdish sniper sits among the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, Syria. The Islamic State group has acknowledged for the first time that its fighters were defeated there, but vowed to attack the town again.
AP
Kurdish peshmerga fighters surround extremists inside a hotel near police headquarters in the oil-rich city of  Kirkuk, 180 miles north of Baghdad. 
AP
A Syrian Kurdish man walks among the rubble in Kobani.
AP
Rubble and damaged buildings are seen in the devastated Syrian city of Kobani.
AP
Fullscreen
Members of the Yazidi minority search for clues that might lead them to missing relatives among the remains of those killed by the Islamic State jihadi group, a day after Kurdish forces discovered a mass grave near the Iraqi village of Sinuni, in the northwestern Sinjar area.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units stand on the back of a homemade armored vehicle as they patrol Kobani, Syria.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A member of Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units walks through rubble on a street in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A member of Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units walks through rubble in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A Kurdish peshmerga fighter aims his weapon as other fighters cross a bridge on Nov. 30 near Kirkuk, Iraq.
Marwan Ibrahim, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi soldier inspects destroyed trucks used by Islamic State militants near Amerli.
Ali Mohammed, European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi army soldiers deploy in front of a court building run by the Islamic State militants in Sadiyah on Nov. 24.
AP
A Kurdish People's Protection Units fighter looks at damage from a Nov. 19 truck bomb attack in Kobani, Syria.
Jake Simkin, AP
Islamic State militants stand on Tilsehir Hill near the Turkish border before an Oct. 23 airstrike in Yumurtalik village.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A bomb explodes on Tilsehir Hill.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
People in Turkey watch an explosion following an airstrike carried out by coalition forces.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A Kurdish refugee woman from Kobani, Syria, holds a child in a camp in Suruc.
Kutluhan Cucel, Getty Images
People warm themselves on a hilltop outside Suruc, Turkey. They've gathered to watch fighting across the border in Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises from an airstrike in Kobani, Syria. Kobani and its surrounding areas have been under assault by extremists of the Islamic State group since mid-September and are being defended by Kurdish fighters.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
U.S.-led coalition aircraft strike at Islamic State targets on Oct. 20 in Kobani, Syria.
AP
Kurdish people observe smoke rising from the Syrian town of Kobani following an explosion as seen from the southeastern Turkish village of Mursitpinar in the Sanliurfa province on Oct. 20.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A explosion during an allied airstrike rocks Kobani.
AP
People watch from a hill in Turkey as Syrian Kurdish fighters battle militants from the Islamic State in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Allied warplanes strike Islamic State positions.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
Shiite fighters loyal to Grand Ayatollah Ali al-Sistani fire missiles at Islamic State militants on Oct. 19 in Karbala, Iraq.
Mohammed Swaf, AFP/Getty Images
People gather on a hill outside Suruc, Turkey, to watch fighting between Syrian Kurds and Islamic State militants in Kobane, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
U.S. Navy Aviation Boatswain Mate Jessica Brown directs an aircraft on the flight deck of the aircraft carrier USS Carl Vinson as the ship conducts strike operations in Iraq and Syria.
U.S. Navy via European Pressphoto Agency
Syrian refugees walk through a camp in Suruc, Turkey.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A man uses the scope from a sniper rifle to watch fighting in Kobani, Syria, on Oct. 19.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty Images
Islamic State militants fight in Kobani on Oct. 19.
Aamaq News Agency via AFP/Getty Images
Kurdish fighters detonate an Islamic State land mine in Gwer district, northern Iraq.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
A bomb explodes during an Oct. 18 allied airstrike on Islamic State targets in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
A U.S. Air Force B1-B bomber flies above Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Shiite volunteers participate in a training session in Hillah.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
An explosion rocks Kobani, Syria, on Oct. 18 during an allied strike on Islamic State militants.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
An Islamic State fighter fires a heavy machine gun in Kobani on Oct. 17.
Aamaq News Agency via AFP/Getty Images
Thick smoke rises following an airstrike by the US-led coalition in Kobani, Syria as fighting continued between Syrian Kurds and the militants of Islamic State.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Iraqi federal policemen search a car at a checkpoint in Baghdad.
Karim Kadim, AP
A woman in Mursitpinar, Turkey, reacts as smoke rises from explosions after an Oct. 13 allied airstrike on Islamic State targets in Kobani, Syria.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Coalition aircraft bomb Islamic State positions in Kobani, Syria.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
Heavy smoke rises following an airstrike by allied aircraft.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty images
A vendor sells bread to people watching the ongoing bombing campaign in Kobani, Syria, on a hilltop outside Suruc, Turkey.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
People watch fighting between YPG Kurdish fighters and Islamic State militants in Kobani.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke rises from the Syrian town of Kobani after airstrikes on Islamic State fighters.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty Images
Rabia Ali mourns at the grave of her son, Seydo Mehmud, a Kurdish fighter, who was killed during a battle with Islamic State militants.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Civilians and Turkish military personnel watch fighting between Kurds and militants from the Islamic State group.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish Kurds watch fighting in Kobani.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty images
Smoke rises from Kobani near the Turkish-Syrian border.
Stringer, Getty images
Turkish armored vehicles hold a position on a hill above Kobani on Oct. 9.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
A Kurdish man watches fighting in Kobani, Syria, from a hill in Turkey.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke rises from an allied airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
A Turkish Kurd watches an airstrike in Kobani on Oct. 8.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Personnel on a Turkish army tank watch allied warplanes attack Islamic State targets in Kobani, Syria.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A  plume of smoke rises after an airstrike in eastern Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish Kurds watch an airstrike in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises after an allied airstrike against an Islamic State target in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Turkish Kurds in Mursitpinar, Turkey, watch fighting between Kurdish forces and Islamic State militants in Kobani, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
An allied airstrike hits Islamic State targets in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Turkish armored vehicles patrol the Turkish-Syrian border in Sanliurfa province.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke rises after an airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Turkish Kurds in Turkey watch fighting in Kobani, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish troops watch the results of an airstrike in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Fullscreen
Smoke rises after an airstrike by allied forces against Islamic State targets on Oct. 7 in the Syrian town of Kobani near Suruc district, Turkey. Airstrikes targeted three groups of Islamic State militants in the first daytime action in Syria by U.S.-led coalition forces.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke from an explosion after an allied airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Turkish soldiers stand near their armored vehicles as they hold a position outside Suruc, near the Turkey-Syria border.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises from an explosion in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
An Iraqi military vehicle burns after an Islamic State attack in western Anbar province on Oct. 5.
AP
A photograph from the British Ministry of Defense shows the result of a Brimstone missile strike on an armed Islamic State truck on Sept. 30 in Iraq. The Brimstone missile is circled in red moments before impact.
Ministry of Defense via AP
A British Ministry of Defense photograph shows the result of a missile attack on an Islamic State truck in Iraq.
Ministry of Defense via AP
A British Royal Air Force Tornado GR4 aircraft lands after a mission over Iraq at the Akrotiri airbase in Cyprus.
Cpl. Neil Bryden, Royal Air Force, via AP
Iraqi Shiite militiamen battle Islamic State militants on Sept. 29 in Jurf al-Sakhar.
AP
A Department of Defense photograph released on Sept. 29 shows a pair of U.S. Air Force F-15E Strike Eagles flying over northern Iraq on Sept. 23.
Matthew Brusch, U.S. Air Force, via European Pressphoto Agency
A Sept. 26 photograph released by the U.S. Air Force shows a KC-10 Extender refueling an F-22 Raptor fighter aircraft before a strike operation against Islamic State targets in Syria.
Tech. Sgt. Russ Scalf, U.S. Air Force, via AP
Two photographs provided by the Pentagon on Sept. 25 shows before and after images of an airstrike on the Jerible Modular oil refinery in Syria.
Department of Defense via AP
Two photographs provided by the Pentagon shows before and after images of an allied airstrike on the Gbiebi Modular oil refinery.
Department of Defense via AP
A U.S. Navy F-18E Super Hornet receives fuel from a U.S. Air Force KC-135 Stratotanker over northern Iraq after conducting airstrikes on Islamic State targets in Syria.
Staff Sgt. Shawn Nickel, U.S. Air Force, via AP
A formation of U.S. Navy F-18E Super Hornets leaves after receiving fuel from a U.S. Air Force KC-135 Stratotanker over northern Iraq.
Staff Sgt. Shawn Nickel, U.S. Air Force, via AP
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Sat May 23 21:24:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ireland legalizes gay marriage</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/92962503/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Ireland-legalizes-gay-marriage/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Ireland legalizes gay marriage
Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum.
Post to Facebook
Ireland legalizes gay marriage Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Stu56b
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
9
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Ireland legalizes gay marriage
Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Irish Sen. Katherine Zappone, left, kisses her partner, Ann Louise Gilligan, as supporters for same-sex marriage wait for the result of the referendum at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
A man blows bubbles as supporters for same-sex marriage waited for the result of the referendum at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Supporters wait for the final result in the Irish referendum at Dublin Castle.
Peter Morrison, AP
Supporters wait for the final result in the Irish referendum at Dublin Castle.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Peter Morrison, AP
Michael Barron, right, and Jamie Nanci, who were married in Cape Town, South Africa, kiss at the RDS count center in Dublin.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
