<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Washington Post">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:22:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>9 ways the Greek crisis is making daily life crazy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47fc7f31/sc/11/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A90C90Eways0Ethe0Egreek0Ecrisis0Eis0Emaking0Edaily0Elife0Ecrazy0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Greece's economic crisis is an extremely unusual event with serious implications for the rest of Europe. But the crisis is already making itself known in Greece and outside it, with some unusual knock-on effects. Here are nine unexpected effects the crisis has had so far: 1. Some pilots carry $11,200 in cash to ensure that they don't run [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 20:25:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Do other countries have Donald Trumps? Of course they do.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47fb3944/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cdo0Eother0Ecountries0Ehave0Edonald0Etrumps0Eof0Ecourse0Ethey0Edo0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As America stumbles its way through the early stages of Donald Trump's unlikely and uncomfortable bid for the presidency, some here are wondering what exactly Trump says about the nation. "Do other national cultures create men like Donald Trump?" Atlantic writer Jeffrey Goldberg asked on Twitter. "Asking for the United States." Goldberg probably asked that question [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 19:56:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why the Iranian nuclear negotiators aren’t fasting during Ramadan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47fb34d7/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cwhy0Ethe0Eiranian0Enuclear0Enegotiators0Earent0Efasting0Eduring0Eramadan0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA – The final round of nuclear talks with Iran is being held here during the holy month of Ramadan, when Muslims fast from sunup to sundown. But the Iranian negotiators and the journalists who flew to the Austrian capital with them are not going hungry and thirsty during the long days of contentious talks. [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:31:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>D.C.’s favorite panda celebrates 10th birthday in China</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47faf690/sc/28/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A90Ctai0Eshan0Epanda0Ebirthday0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>&amp;#160; DUJIANGYAN, China — What happens when a panda turns 10? You get cake. And if you're famous like Tai Shan the giant panda, your human friends come and give you well wishes. On Thursday at the almost-new Dujiangyan panda base in China's Sichuan province, Tai Shan had a party. There were balloons and panda-shaped signs [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:25:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia’s Putin, a man of action, may finally try yoga</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47faf698/sc/31/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A90Crussias0Eputin0Ea0Eman0Eof0Eaction0Emay0Efinally0Etry0Eyoga0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The leaders of the BRICS geopolitical bloc are meeting yet again, this time in the Russian city of Ufa. Photos of the summit — which brings together dynamic and important emerging economies (Brazil, India, China and South Africa) and Russia (less dynamic and certainly not "emerging") — are spectacular. ..... pic.twitter.com/rJl7778gAp &amp;#8212; Ishaan Tharoor (@ishaantharoor) [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 12:00:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A Russian political party released a ‘heterosexual flag’ to counter the rainbow flag</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47f8444d/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A90Ca0Erussian0Epolitical0Eparty0Ereleased0Ea0Eheterosexual0Eflag0Eto0Ecounter0Ethe0Erainbow0Eflag0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>В «Единой России» разработали флаг натуралов &amp;#10;http://t.co/iIUsKHQGhY pic.twitter.com/n1Gjf3uLQh &amp;#8212; Известия (@izvestia_ru) July 7, 2015 The Moscow branch of Russian political party United Russia unveiled a "heterosexual flag" this week that was designed to counteract the success of the rainbow flag used to celebrate gay rights. The flag shows a man and a woman standing with three [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 10:30:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The shocking things Indian judges say about rape</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47f7816e/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cthe0Eshocking0Ethings0Eindian0Ejudges0Esay0Eabout0Erape0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A judge in India recently released a rapist from jail so he could attend mediation sessions with his victim, in the apparent hope that the two could put their differences aside and possibly marry. The ruling prompted a public outcry, and the judge was criticized not only for his retrograde reasoning but also for misusing [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 08:00:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Syrian war has now created more than 4 million refugees, says U.N.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47f5dc8b/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A90Cthe0Esyrian0Ewar0Ehas0Enow0Ecreated0Emore0Ethan0E40Emillion0Erefugees0Esays0Eu0En0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Syria's hideous civil war enters its fifth year, the conflict has now led to more than 4 million Syrians fleeing the country. That's according to new numbers published in a report Thursday by UNHCR, the U.N.'s refugee agency. It also estimates that an additional 7.6 million Syrians remain displaced within the country -- meaning that roughly half [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:05:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Could Britain ban the Islamic State flag?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47fd15e3/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A80Ccould0Ebritain0Eban0Ethe0Eislamic0Estate0Eflag0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>https://twitter.com/metesohtaoglu/status/617705104691601408 Over the weekend, a man walked around Westminster, the center of British power, with a young girl on his shoulders and an Islamic State flag draped across his back. Photographs of the man quickly spread on social media, and many found it deeply offensive that he had cloaked himself in a flag so tightly linked to terrorism just days [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:21:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia plans to build a really long wall to keep out terrorists</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47f2fe0f/sc/40/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A80Ctunisia0Eplans0Eto0Ebuild0Ea0Ereally0Elong0Ewall0Eto0Ekeep0Eout0Eterrorists0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In the wake of last month's shocking terror attack at a beach resort in the coastal city of Sousse, the Tunisian government has authorized plans to build a 104-mile-long barrier to better secure its border with Libya. The proposed wall was announced Wednesday by Tunisia Prime Minister Habib Essid, who deemed the lawless situation next [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:00:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>An Israeli minister doubts the Jewishness of many American Jews</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47f01f57/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A80Can0Eisraeli0Eminister0Edoubts0Ethe0Ejewishness0Eof0Emany0Eamerican0Ejews0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A prominent member in the cabinet of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has reiterated his controversial opinions on Reform Jews, a denomination that comprises a sizable proportion of the global Jewish population, including in the United States. David Azoulay, Israel's minister for religious services and a member of the ultra-Orthodox Shas party, told an Israeli radio station [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 12:00:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Norwegian cops fired their guns twice last year and didn’t hit anyone either time</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47ef43fb/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cnorwegian0Ecops0Efired0Etheir0Eguns0Etwice0Elast0Eyear0Eand0Emissed0Eboth0Etimes0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Norwegian government recently released statistics about how the country's police department used guns in recent years, painting a picture of a nation where police officers rarely draw their guns and rarely injure anyone with those guns. The report found that in 2014, Norwegian police threatened to use their weapons 42 times. However, only two shots [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 10:30:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How one weeping man put a face on Greece’s debt crisis</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47eea5d8/sc/25/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cgreece0Ecrying0Eman0Ebanks0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It’s an image that some have said crystallizes the despair felt across Greece, a country in the grips of a spiraling financial crisis. Giorgos Chatzifotiadis, an elderly man in Thessaloniki, sat down in front of a crowd and cried last Friday after he waited for hours in front of numerous banks to withdraw cash but was [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 22:26:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How junk food has helped save the Iran nuclear talks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47eab6a7/sc/14/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A70Chow0Ejunk0Efood0Ehas0Ehelped0Esave0Ethe0Eiran0Enuclear0Etalks0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA -- When exhausted American negotiators take an intellectual break from their endless nuclear talkathon with Iran, they sometimes indulge in flights of fancy imagining who could play them in a movie version of the experience. By common consent, Meryl Steep would revise the look, though not the personality, of the editor in "The Devil Wears Prada" to portray the [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 22:08:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>5 times when deadlines in Iran nuclear talks proved meaningless</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47eab4b9/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A70C50Etimes0Ewhen0Edeadlines0Ein0Eiran0Enuclear0Etalks0Eproved0Emeaningless0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A July 7 deadline for the United States and its partners to reach an accord with Iran over its nuclear program passed Tuesday, with negotiators still hard at work over the terms of what all parties hope will be a lasting agreement. This is the fifth time one of the self-imposed deadlines to clinch a deal [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 18:27:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran talks: How to cover a story that keeps not happening</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e95359/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A70Ciran0Etalks0Ehow0Eto0Ecover0Ea0Estory0Ethat0Ekeeps0Enot0Ehappening0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>On Tuesday morning, my colleague Carol Morello was greeted with this notice in the lobby of the Vienna hotel where she and others in the American press corps had accommodations. Her stay was being extended; a July 7 deadline for the United States and its partners to reach an accord with Iran over its nuclear program [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 17:14:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea says this smiling dog eating a birthday cake is what’s wrong with America</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e895e3/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cnorth0Ekorea0Esays0Ethis0Esmiling0Edog0Eeating0Ea0Ebirthday0Ecake0Eis0Ewhats0Ewrong0Ewith0Eamerica0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>North Korean state media pulls no punches when it comes to describing America's failings. Last year, for example, the official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) released a list of U.S. human rights abuses. "The U.S. is the world's worst human right abuser and tundra of a human being's rights to existence," the report concluded. Recently [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:00:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The U.S. air war against the Islamic State, in numbers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e6a374/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cthe0Eu0Es0Eair0Ewar0Eagainst0Ethe0Eislamic0Estate0Ein0Enumbers0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>"This will not be quick," President Obama told reporters at a Monday briefing in the Pentagon, referring to the ongoing U.S. air war against the Islamic State. "This is a long-term campaign. ISIL is opportunistic and it is nimble. . . . It will take time to root them out." Obama was referring to the acronym used by [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:30:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Germany has defaulted on its debts, too</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e5f6bf/sc/24/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cgermany0Ehas0Edefaulted0Eon0Eits0Edebts0Etoo0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Greek debt crisis is often portrayed as a dispute between two actors with two very different economic visions: a German government that seeks austerity over anything else and a Greek government desperate to escape its debts without suffering the pain that austerity would bring. That is not necessarily an inaccurate vision. It does, however, miss out on an important [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:33:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghans outraged again as a court overturns death sentences in woman’s mob killing</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e2198b/sc/3/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cafghans0Eoutraged0Eagain0Eas0Ea0Ecourt0Eoverturns0Edeath0Esentences0Ein0Ewomans0Emob0Ekilling0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Her brutal killing galvanized Afghanistan in March. Thousands protested, demanding punishment for those involved in Farkhunda's mob lynching. The 27-year-old had been falsely accused of burning a Koran and her death, captured on video, ended with her body being burned and thrown into the Kabul River. Four men were sentenced to death in May after a televised [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
