<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:57:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Technical glitch halts NYSE trading for 3 hours</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/nyse-halts-trading-due-to--technical--issue-164025397.html</Link>
        <Description>An internal technical hiccup halted trading on the New York Stock Exchange for more than three-and-a-half hours Wednesday, but in sign of resilience, other U.S. exchanges successfully picked up the slack.</Description>
        <MainBody>Technical glitch halts NYSE trading for 3 hours
Other U.S. exchanges operate normally
By Yahoo Finance 7 hours ago

Wall Street CEO on NYC shutdown: a Yawn

Wall Street CEO on NYC shutdown: a Yawn
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Wall Street CEO on NYC shutdown: a Yawn
 Replay video
Pepsico and Walgreens could beat Wall Street

By Adam Samson and Andy Serwer

An internal technical hiccup halted trading on the New York Stock Exchange for more than three-and-a-half hours Wednesday, but in sign of resilience, other U.S. exchanges successfully picked up the slack.
The main NYSE platform re-opened at 3:10 p.m. ET, after shutting down at 11:32 a.m. as a result of the issue. The much smaller NYSE MKT re-opened at 3:05 p.m. ET.
NYSE spokesperson Marissa Arnold said in a statement the root of the problem was a "configuration issue." NYSE's all-electronic ARCA equities market was unaffected and continued normal operations. NYSE's AMEX and ARCA options markets were also operating normally.
On Twitter the Big Board headed off any concerns that the trading halt was caused by a malicious cyberattack: "The issue we are experiencing is an internal technical issue and is not the result of a cyber breach. We chose to suspend trading on NYSE to avoid problems arising from our technical issue."
Meanwhile, other major exchanges including Nasdaq ( NDAQ ), and BATS, declared so-called self-helps against NYSE, indicating they were routing trades away from the exchange. However, both exchanges revoked the self-helps in the 3:00-hour as NYSE resolved its issues.
The main NYSE platform handled 6.2% of U.S. volume on Wednesday, according to data from BATS. That compares to about 13.4% in June on average. Nasdaq handled 17.4% of trading on the day, while NYSE ARCA covered 12.6%.
A spokesperson for the Securities and Exchange Commission, Wall Street's top cop, didn't immediately respond to a Yahoo Finance request for comment on the matter. The White House said it was monitoring the situation, but noted the issue was not sparked by a malicious player.
Shares of the IntercontinentalExchange ( ICE ), NYSE's parent, were down 2.4%, compared to a 1.7% drop for the broad S&amp;P 500.
Nasdaq suffered from the so-called Flash Freeze just about two years ago in which a "combined series of technology events" halted trading on the electronic exchange for about three hours. Initially, it was thought that high-frequency trading could have played a role in the freeze, but Nasdaq eventually said that was not part of the cause.
'A yawn'
Ralph Schlosstein, CEO of Evercore, called the suspension "a yawn, saying that trading volume was easily diverted and absorbed by other trading platforms.
Schlosstein equated the unprecedented closure  which lasted three hours and 38 minutes  to trying to drive downtown in New York City on Park Avenue and that road being closed and then simply picking another avenue.
Schlosstein, whos been CEO of Evercorean investment banking advisory businesssince 2009, cautioned against concluding that the shutdown was necessarily simply a computer failure and not a computer hack of some sort.
Despite the fact that the NYSE has said it was a system failure, Schlosstein says that in his experience, it sometimes takes a few days to come to a firm conclusion. Schlosstein, a Wall Street veteran, who co-founded BlackRock, now the worlds largest asset manager, said he contacted his head of equities once he heard about the shutdown at the NYSE to see if his business was OK, and was told the it was fully operational.
Markets tumble on China, Greece worries
Markets were down significantly on Wednesday, but they had been off at the same levels prior to the closure on Greece and China fears. Still, todays closure didnt put traders in any sort of buying mood after the reopen in the afternoon.
The S&amp;P 500 was off 34.7 points, or 1.7%, the Dow Jones Industrial Average was down 261 points, or 1.5%, and the Nasdaq Composite shed 87.7 points, or 1.8%.
China's Shanghai Composite, which already fell into bear-market territory, plummeted 5.9% overnight in volatile action. The move came despite attempts by the country's government to shore up the equity market there.
"Lets not call it a correction in China, lets call it what it really is, a crash. Just because it didnt happen in just one day like other so called crashes doesnt make it any less so," Peter Boockvar, chief market analyst at The Lindsey Group, wrote in a note to clients.
"What is most significant though is that it came in the face of almost every attempt possible by Chinese authorities to prevent it from happening."

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:13:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beyond 'To Kill a Mockingbird': The lost novel of Harper Lee</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/katiecouric/beyond-to-kill-a-mockingbird-the-lost-novel-of-123555389873.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:59:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Veteran journalist uncovers full story of NYPD’s first African-American cop</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/veteran-journalist-uncovers-full-story-of-nypd-s-first-african-american-cop-155937210.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View photo
Mayor Fiorello LaGuardia appoints Lt. Samuel J. Battle as member of the city's parole commission. (via Beacon Press)
He broke the New York Police Departments color barrier 36 years before Jackie Robinson put on a Brooklyn Dodgers cap, but most people dont even know his name.
Samuel J. Battle paved the way for countless African-Americans to protect and serve New York. Over the years, he became the first black person to hold many positions within the department: officer, sergeant, lieutenant and parole commissioner.
View gallery
.
Samuel Jesse Battle was the first black police officer in the city of New York. (Photo: The New York City Police
As an American hero, he showed what one person can do with courage and moral determination, veteran New York City newspaperman Arthur Browne said in an interview with Yahoo News.
Brownes new book , One Righteous Man: Samuel Battle and the Shattering of the Color Line in New York, which makes the case for Battles place among the pantheon of great American heroes, hits shelves amid an ongoing national conversation about tension between police departments and minority communities.
In the past year, the Justice Department launched investigations into the police departments in Ferguson, Mo., Cleveland and Baltimore after alleged cases of excessive force in which white police were involved in the deaths of black men.
Though he couldnt have predicted the current climate when he started writing in 2009, Brownes book seems especially timely as debates rage over police brutality and systemic racism in the criminal justice system.
View gallery
.
Lino Rivera, 16, center, tells Lt. Samuel Battle, left, and Patrolman Alfred Eldridge that he was not mistreated
Browne, the editorial page editor at the New York Daily News, read an article in his own paper that year about the citys plan to rename the intersection at 135th Street and Lenox Avenue in Harlem as Samuel J. Battle Plaza ,after the officer.
He had been covering the Big Apple since the citys golden age of tabloid journalism in the mid-1970s, but he had not previously wondered how the police department had become integrated. This piqued his interest.
View gallery
.
Samuel J. Battle was New York's first African-American police lieutenant. (Photo: Via Beacon Press)
To piece together the details of the trailblazers life,Browne conducted archival research, interviewed people who knew Battle and tracked down the unpublished manuscript to a biography that poet Langston Hughes had been writing about the officer.
You essentially had Langston Hughes taking down Battles words, polishing them up very nicely and putting them as much as he could into a narrative framework, he said.
According to Browne, Hughes book starts off strongly with an almost magical, lyrically brilliant evocation of Battles early life but gets weaker as it progresses.
Battle, who was born in North Carolina in 1883, moved up north and settled in New York, where he became its first black officer in 1911.
He is credited with saving the life of a white cop during a race riot in 1919 at the corner that now bears his name.
Despite his dedication and talent, he endured overt hostility from white civilians and the silent treatment from many colleagues who believed he should not be a police officer. Some even traveled up to Harlem to gawk at him while he worked.
He has been called the Jackie Robinson of the NYPD.
Browne notes that the New York Police Department has undergone radical changes for the better since Battle retired in 1951 at the age of 68. But there are still lessons to be learned from his story today.
View gallery
.
Arthur Browne is the author of 'One Righteous Man: Samuel Battle and the Shattering of the Color Line in New York.'
When Battle became the first black New York City cop, African-Americans made up approximately 3 percent of the citys population, so there was a considerable gap in their representation in the police department, he said.
Never in the history of the NYPD has the ratio of blacks on the police force come close to approximating the ratio of blacks in the New York population, he said. The police department here is working to overcome, but theres a long way to go on that.
Throughout the 20th century, many activists and advocates have argued that having more black police officers could foster greater trust between African-American communities and police departments.
Some rough equality of representation on the force would, I believe, Browne said, enhance some confidence that there is an understanding and a connection between those who are doing the policing and those who are being policed.
Jackie Robinson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:24:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby fallout grows as LAPD investigates claims, Disney removes statue</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/cosby-quaaludes-admission-fallout-statue-whoopi-raven-symone-142419067.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
.
The fallout from Bill Cosby's admission that he gave Quaaludes to at least one woman he wanted to have sex with  a revelation that was unsealed in court documents on Monday  continues to mount.
NBC reports that the woman whose lawsuit led a federal judge to unseal part of the 2005 deposition may ask the judge to unseal all of Cosby's testimony.
Cosby's lawyers fought to keep his testimony secret, but U.S. District Judge Eduardo C. Robreno granted a request by the Associated Press to unseal the deposition, saying Cosby is a public figure whose comments about moral issues, combined with the serious allegations against him, put the release of testimony in the public interest.
Meanwhile, the Los Angeles Police Department is conducting at least one current criminal investigation into allegations of sexual assault against Cosby, NPR reported Tuesday .
The LAPD said the investigation "may have multiple accusations" but would not offer more details because the case is ongoing.
On Tuesday night, a bronze statue of the 77-year-old comedian was removed from Walt Disney World's Hollywood Studios theme park . Park officials confirmed that the Cosby statue, which had been a fixture in Disney's Academy of Television Arts and Sciences Hall of Fame Plaza, was in the process of being taken down, but did not comment further.
Brittany Gavrilova, whose aunt is one of Cosby's alleged victims, launched an online petition seven months ago to have the statue removed .
"To not be able to walk through Disney without having that difficult encounter, it makes me sad," Gavrilova told WESH-TV . "Like, wow, this person hurt a family member of mine."
The Smithsonian Institution, though, is standing behind a museum exhibition that partly relies on the art collection of Bill Cosby and his wife.
"The National Museum of African Art is aware of the recent revelations about Bill Cosby's behavior," t he Smithsonian said in a statement Tuesday . "The museum in no way condones this behavior. Our current 'Conversations' exhibition, which includes works of African art from our permanent collection and African American art from the collection of Camille and Bill Cosby, is fundamentally about the artworks and the artists who created them, not the owners of the collections."
Cosby has been accused of sexual assault by more than two dozen women, including many who say he drugged and raped them in strikingly similar encounters over a four-decade span. Lawyers for Cosby have denied the allegations, and he has never been criminally charged.
View gallery
This excerpt from a 2005 deposition given by entertainer Bill Cosby and released Monday, July 6, 201
Lawyers for the alleged victims say Cosby's admission amounts to corroboration of their allegations. And several of the women gave interviews on Tuesday to discuss the revelation.
"I had a number of reactions," Beverly Johnson told ABC's " Good Morning America." "I was numb."
"I didn't realize that I was going to get this onslaught of people wanting to interview me again, and so naturally, you know, you want to get underneath the covers and put the covers over your head  but you can't do that and I won't do that," Johnson said. "I want my voice to be heard ... I'm telling my truth."
Janice Dickinson, who alleges that Cosby violated her in 1982, says she feels "validated."
"It shows that he and all his people knew all along that we were telling the truth," Dickinson told People magazine .
LAPD May Open Investigation Into Bill Cosby After  Play video
Singer Jill Scott, who defended Cosby last year, said Monday's revelation was a turning point.
"About Bill Cosby," Scott wrote to her Twitter followers. "Sadly his own testimony offers PROOF of terrible deeds, which is ALL I have ever required to believe the accusations."
About Bill Cosby. Sadly his own testimony offers PROOF of terrible deeds, which is ALL I have ever required to believe the accusations.
 Jill Scott (@missjillscott) July 6, 2015
Director Judd Apatow, one of Cosby's most vocal critics in Hollywood, said we shouldn't need him to admit guilt to believe his alleged victims.
"We shouldn't need Bill Cosby to admit it to believe 40 people who were victimized by him," Apatow said Tuesday . "Maybe now more people in show business and all around our country will stand up and tell the people he attacked that 'we support you and believe you.'"
Whoopi Goldberg, though, isn't one of them.
"I don't like snap judgments because I've had snap judgments made on me, so I'm very, very careful," Goldberg said on "The View" Tuesday. "Save your texts, save your nasty comments. I don't care."
"This is my opinion and in America, still  I know it's a shock  but you actually [are] innocent until proven guilty," Goldberg said . "He has not been proven a rapist."
Her "View" co-host Raven-Symon, who co-starred with Cosby on "The Cosby Show," said she needs further proof before judging him.
"I don't really like to talk about it that much, because he's the reason I'm on this panel  he gave me my first job," she said . "But at the same time, you need the proof, and then I'll be able to give my judgment here or there. And now there are real facts, more people can come up."
Bill Cosby
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:48:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>United Airlines suffers 2nd major grounding in 2 months</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/faa-us-united-continental-flights-grounded-131816655--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>United Airlines suffers 2nd major grounding in 2 months
By DAVID KOENIG and SCOTT MAYEROWITZ 4 hours ago

United Airlines Flights Grounded Nationwide Over 'Automation Issues,' FAA Says

United Airlines Flights Grounded Nationwide Over 'Automation Issues,' FAA Says
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
United Airlines Flights Grounded Nationwide Over 'Automation Issues,' FAA Says
 Replay video
Jeb Bush Outlines Immigration Position In NH

The New York Stock Exchange was shut down for hours today, leaving many people concerned and checking their 401Ks.
Load More
NEW YORK (AP)  Hundreds of United Airlines flights were delayed Wednesday after the airline experienced computer problems for the second time in just over a month.
A White House spokesman said President Barack Obama was briefed on the glitch and that it appeared unrelated to an outage hours later at the New York Stock Exchange.
"There is no indication at this point either that there is malicious activity involved," said the spokesman, Josh Earnest.
A United spokeswoman said that the glitch was caused by an internal technology issue and not an outside threat or hacker.
Spokeswoman Jennifer Dohm said that a router problem reduced "network connectivity" for several software applications. "We fixed the router issue, which is enabling us to restore normal functions," she said around midday.
The Federal Aviation Administration lifted a ground-stop order after nearly two hours, allowing United planes to fly again Wednesday morning. But delays continued while the airline fought to regain control of its schedule.
United, the nation's second-biggest airline, said more than 1,150 flights had been delayed and about 60 canceled by late afternoon.
United has had three chief information officers since 2011, with the current CIO joining last September. It has suffered several technology lapses in that time, some leading to mass delays and cancellations.
The airline briefly halted all takeoffs in the U.S. on June 2 because of a problem in its flight-dispatching system. United said then that about 150 flights were affected.
United also struggled through a series of computer outages in 2012 after switching to the passenger-information system of Continental Airlines after that carrier merged with United. Those outages caused hundreds of flights to be delayed. High-paying business travelers were outraged; United CEO Jeff Smisek apologized for failing to provide good customer service.
After a 2010 merger, United elected to combine many computer systems and frequent-flier programs all at once. Executives believed that any disruptions would thus be short-lived. By contrast, Delta and Northwest integrated their systems in stages after a 2008 merger, and American Airlines is taking Delta's same go-slow approach now as it absorbs US Airways.
Other airlines, however, have also been hit by computer problems. In April, more than 50 American flights were delayed when a software glitch prevented pilots from seeing some airport maps on their tablet computers.
After Wednesday's problems, United apologized to customers and said they could change travel plans without being charged the usual $200 reservation-change fee. In some cases, the airline said it would also waive any difference in fare for the rescheduled trip.
At Los Angeles International Airport, Meni Tsirbas arrived an hour early for his morning flight to Newark, New Jersey. There was already a mob around the ticketing counter, and plenty of confusion.
"Everything was done by hand," said Tsirbas, an animation director. "We checked one (bag) and it was done '70s style."
Betsy Fischer Martin's flight to Denver sat on the ground at Dulles Airport near Washington as the captain gave increasingly dismal updates on the delay.
At one point, "The captain said, "Anyone who wants to look at the cockpit and flight deck is welcome  we have nothing better to do,'" said Fischer Martin, a journalist. "He made a bad situation a little better."
Gary Leff, co-founder of frequent-flier website MilePoint, said the breakdown "underscores the sense that something is very wrong at United."
"How could a router bring down one of the world's largest airlines?" asked Henry Harteveldt, a travel analyst at Atmosphere Research Group, who said it appeared that United lacked enough redundancy in its technology systems. Still, he doubted that United would lose many business-travel customers because technology hiccups could happen to any carrier.
Shares of Chicago-based United Continental Holdings Inc. fell $1.49, or 2.7 percent, to close at $52.82.
___
Koenig reported from Dallas. Michelle Chapman in New York, Alina Hartounian in Los Angeles, Matt Small in San Francisco and Joan Lowy in Washington contributed to this report.
Mayerowitz can be reached at http://twitter.com/GlobeTrotScott ; Koenig at http://twitter.com/airlinewriter
Airline Industry
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Hillary Clinton talks trust and Trump in first campaign interview</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/hillary-clinton-talks-trust-and-trump-in-first-123508835936.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:23:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore police commissioner fired after riot, killings</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/baltimore-police-union-slams-freddie-gray-riot-response-175900531.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Baltimore police commissioner fired after riot, killings
By Donna Owens 3 hours ago

Baltimore police Commissioner Anthony Batts accompanies U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch (not seen)
By Donna Owens
BALTIMORE (Reuters) - Baltimore Police Commissioner Anthony Batts was fired on Wednesday following criticism of his handling of rioting over the death of a black man from an injury in police custody and a skyrocketing homicide rate.
Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake said the focus on Batts and the leadership of the 2,500-officer force had become a distraction in fighting resurgent crime and was hurting her goal of attracting families to the city.
"As we have seen in recent weeks, many continue to die. Families are tired of feeling the pain, and so am I," she told a City Hall news conference.
Batts' firing came after three people were shot dead overnight and another was killed on Wednesday, violence cited by the mayor at her news conference.
Batts, who came to Baltimore from California in September 2012 with a reputation as a reformer, will be replaced on an interim basis by Deputy Commissioner Kevin Davis.
Batts came under fire for his handling of rioting that followed the funeral of Freddie Gray, 25, on April 27.
View gallery
Newly appointed Interim Police Commissioner Kevin Davis fields questions next to Baltimore Mayor Ste
Gray died after suffering an injury while being transported in a police van, heightening a national debate on police treatment of minorities. Six officers have been charged in his death.
Batts and other police commanders told officers to "hold the line" with rioters rather than confront people causing damage or threatening police.
Officials have said the orders were aimed at protecting officers and bystanders. About 160 officers were hurt in the rioting, almost 400 buildings were destroyed or damaged and the National Guard was sent in to restore order.
His cautious response was seen as an improvement over other cities, such as Ferguson, Missouri, that had used heavy-handed tactics to shut down protests after complaints of police brutality against black men. But Batts came under criticism for not being better prepared for the rioting.
A review by Baltimore's police union released on Wednesday criticized the police response. It said commanders let unrest spiral into arson and looting, and officers lacked riot gear and training.
A spokesman for Rawlings-Blake called the review "a trumped-up political document."
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake speaks next to Interim Police Commissioner Kevin Davis duri
APOLOGY TO OFFICERS
Batts apologized to officers in May, saying he put them in harm's way.
Batts also had to grapple with an upsurge in killings    after the rioting in the largely black city of 620,000 people. Baltimore has tallied 155 killings for the year versus 105 in the same period in 2014, police said on Wednesday.
Batts blamed the upturn to the looting of pharmacies during and after the rioting, leading to turf wars among drug gangs.
Davis, the interim commissioner, came to Baltimore in January after serving as police chief in Anne Arundel County Maryland. At the City Hall news conference, he said: "It's all about the crime fighting and the relationship with the community."
Batts had been police chief in Oakland and Long Beach, California. He began his career in 1982 in Long Beach and from there went to Oakland, which, like Baltimore, has one of the highest homicide rates in the country.
Billy Murphy, an attorney for Gray's family, praised Batts for trying to change "an entrenched racist police culture and its horrible blue wall of silence which made good cops afraid to tell on bad cops. But he did not succeed.
Batts' firing came a day before a 20,000-strong faith coalition, Baltimoreans United in Leadership Development, planned to ask for his resignation.
The Rev. Andrew Foster-Connors, the group's clergy co-chair, said Batts did not have a plan to address the mayhem and had lost support among the police rank and file.
"That felt like a dangerous situation to us and we were ready for a change," he said.
City Council President Bernard "Jack" Young said in a statement that a growing lack of confidence in Batts' crime-fighting strategy could have hurt Baltimore's long-term health.
(Additional reporting by Ian Simpson in Washington and Fiona Ortiz in Chicago; Editing by Cynthia Osterman and Eric Beech)
Commissioner Anthony Batts
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:00:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confederate flag faces decisive vote in South Carolina legislature</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/confederate-flag-faces-decisive-vote-south-carolina-legislature-091559956.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Confederate flag faces decisive vote in South Carolina legislature
By Harriet McLeod 4 hours ago

.
View photo
A Confederate flag stands in front of the South Carolina State House in Columbia, South Carolina July
By Harriet McLeod
CHARLESTON, S.C. (Reuters) - The campaign to remove the Confederate battle flag from South Carolina's capitol grounds marched forward on Wednesday, as the House of Representatives emotionally debated the banner symbolizing slavery and racism for many and Southern heritage for others.
As debate on a proposed law to take down the flag began in the House of Representatives, the South Carolina Law Enforcement Division said it was investigating threats sent to legislators on both sides of the issue.
The state Senate first took up the bill on Monday less than three weeks after nine black worshippers were gunned down on June 17 during Bible study at a historically black church in Charleston. A white man, Dylann Roof, is accused in the massacre.
The battle over the banner nicknamed the "Stars and Bars" was stoked by photos of Roof showing the 21-year-old man posing with a Confederate flag on a website bearing a racist manifesto.
The murders sparked a bipartisan wave of repudiation across the South, from politicians to businesses, led by South Carolina's Republican Governor Nikki Haley.
On Tuesday, the Republican-controlled Senate approved the bill by an overwhelming 36-3. The legislation - required before the flag can be moved to a museum - went to the House.
If the lower chamber passes it, the bill will go to the governor to be signed into law, perhaps as soon as Thursday.
Wednesday's House debate was civil as conservative defenders of the flag introduced dozens of unsuccessful amendments seeking to replace it with various alternatives, such as a cast bronze replica that would be affixed to the Confederate Soldier Monument on the State House grounds. The flag now flies on a pole next to the monument.
Another amendment sought to put the issue to a statewide referendum.
Representative Wendell Gilliard, a black Democrat from Charleston, urged support for the bill as a tribute to the slain church members' families and their expression of forgiveness for the accused killer.
"This has brought forth a new understanding and new ways of seeing ways to peace and justice. ... The right thing to do is the gentle laying down of the past and a hopeful road to the future," Gilliard said.
The flag's dwindling defenders deny its association with slavery, saying it honors those who fought and died for the state and the southern Confederacy on the losing side of the
1861-1865 Civil War.
House members who support the flag looked to history - and prayer - for answers.
"I grew up holding that flag in reverence because of the stories of my ancestors carrying that flag into battle," Representative Michael Pitts, a white Republican, told the House.
"People gave their lives not to defend slavery but because they were called up to defend a state," added Republican Mike Ryhal, who is also white.
Another white Republican, Eric Bedingfield, said the Civil War was not over slavery but about "fighting a repressive federal government," adding that the fight goes on today.
South Carolina's flag fight is a return to a controversy that arose decades ago. The banner was originally raised atop the State House in 1961 - joining the state flag and the U.S flag - in what was described as a commemoration of the centennial of the Civil War.
Others, however, saw it as a slap in the face to the black civil rights movement then gaining momentum.
In 2000, flag opponents scored a partial victory, getting it moved from atop the capitol to its place by the monument, only yards from the State House entrance.
The current bill's swift progress marks a dramatic turnaround in sentiment from only a few months ago, largely attributed to a national wave of sympathy for the nine victims at Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church in Charleston, about two hours drive southeast of the state capital, Columbia.
The church pastor, Reverend Clementa Pinckney, was also a widely admired state senator.
A Gallup poll released on Wednesday showed 54 percent of Americans view the Confederate flag as a symbol of Southern pride rather than a symbol of racism, down from 59 percent in 2000 and 69 percent in 1992. Another 34 percent believe the  flag is a racist symbol, said Gallup.
The poll was based on telephone interviews with a random sample of 2,013 adults aged 18 and older.
(Writing by David Adams; Additional reporting by Suzannah Gonzales; Editing by Cynthia Osterman, Richard Chang and Jonathan Oatis)
South Carolina
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:19:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawmakers bash U.S. Army plan to cut 57,000 troops and civilians</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/lawmakers-bash-u-army-plan-cut-57-000-011835627.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Lawmakers bash U.S. Army plan to cut 57,000 troops and civilians
By David Alexander 1 hour ago

.
View photo
A U.S. Army sapper uses a mine detector to check the road in advance of a dismounted patrol near Combat
By David Alexander
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Lawmakers on Wednesday sharply criticized long-announced U.S. Army plans to cut nearly 60,000 soldiers and civilian personnel due to tight budgets, warning it was risky and short-sighted at a time of Middle East conflict and rising tensions with Russia.
Senator John McCain, the Republican head of the Armed Services Committee, called the decision to cut 40,000 soldiers and 17,000 civilian personnel "another dangerous consequence of budget-driven strategy" pursued by President Barack Obama.
Republican presidential contender Jeb Bush told veterans in Hudson, New Hampshire, that the United States "can't lead without a strong military" and pursuit of the planned cuts would leave the country with "the smallest Army that we've had since the start of World War Two."
The cuts would reduce the active-duty Army from about 490,000 soldiers to about 450,000. The Army had about 490,000 soldiers before the 2001 attacks, a number that rose to about 570,000 in 2010 before reductions began.
The criticism arose as Army Secretary John McHugh began notifying members of Congress about military units that would be reduced and how states would be affected. The Army plans to present fuller details of the reductions on Thursday, but USA Today published the names of some of the affected units on Tuesday.
The hardest hit bases include Fort Benning, Georgia, and Joint Base Elmendorf-Richardson, Alaska. Army officials planned to convert a 4,000-member brigade combat team at each base into a 1,050-member battalion task force, a loss of nearly 3,000 soldiers apiece, according to an Army document seen by Reuters.
Senator Johnny Isakson, a Georgia Republican, said he learned from McHugh that the Army planned to cut 4,350 soldiers in Georgia including 950 at Fort Stewart and 3,400 at Fort Benning. He said the cuts would take place by the end of 2017.
"I am demanding answers from the Department of Defense on how they are justifying these troop cuts in Georgia," Isakson said in a statement. "We cannot afford to reduce our military readiness at a time when the threats to our security here at home and throughout the world are growing at an alarming rate."
The Alaska congressional delegation said McHugh told them the Army planned to cut 2,600 soldiers at Fort Richardson and another 75 at Fort Wainwright. The lawmakers said in a statement the Army also intended to cut soldiers in Hawaii.
Senator Lisa Murkowski of Alaska called the cuts in her state "devastating" and "short-sighted" given the need for a robust defense in the Arctic as well as potential threats from Russia, China and North Korea.
"This decision was obviously made without a full understanding of the geostrategic importance of Alaska's troops to our national security," the state's other senator, Dan Sullivan, said. "These decisions need to be based on strategy, not on bean-counting."
The personnel cuts come as the Pentagon is attempting to absorb nearly $1 trillion in reductions to planned defense spending over a decade.
The reduction to 450,000 soldiers was initially announced in February 2014 when then-Defense Secretary Chuck Hagel unveiled the Pentagon's 2015 budget. The figures were also included in the Quadrennial Defense Review, its four-year planning document.
(Additional reporting by Steve Holland; Editing by Toni Reinhold and Leslie Adler)
Senator John McCain
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 21:05:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New charges in Charleston church shooting: Attempted murder</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/charges-charleston-church-shooting-attempted-murder-162002126.html</Link>
        <Description>The man accused of killing nine people attending Bible study at a historic black church in Charleston has been indicted on three new charges of attempted murder, prosecutors said Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Police looking into website linked to Dylann Roof.
Load More
COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP)  The man accused of killing nine people attending Bible study at a historic black church in Charleston has been indicted on three new charges of attempted murder, prosecutors said Tuesday.
Dylann Storm Roof, 21, already had been charged with nine counts of murder, one for each person killed in the June 17 attack at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church. He also faces a weapons charge, and has been indicted on that charge and the murder counts.
Prosecutor Scarlett Wilson said in a statement that the new attempted-murder charges stem from survivors of the massacre.
Roof's defense attorney did not immediately return a message. Roof's next court date is expected in October.
The court records released Tuesday show that Roof is accused of trying to kill three females, one of whom is a minor.
Federal authorities have not said whether they will pursue hate crime charges against Roof, although Justice Department officials have said they broadly agree the shootings meet the legal requirements for a hate crime.
View gallery
Dylann Roof appears via video before a judge, in Charleston, S.C., Friday, June 19, 2015. The 21-yea
The new charges comes as South Carolina state lawmakers move closer toward possibly removing the Confederate flag from the Statehouse grounds. Roof, who is white, appeared in photos waving Confederate flags and burning or desecrating U.S. flags, and purportedly wrote of fomenting racial violence. Survivors told police he hurled racial insults during the attack.
After Roof's arrest, Republicans including Gov. Nikki Haley and both of the state's U.S. senators called for the flag's removal. The massacre made taking down the flag  long thought politically impossible in South Carolina  the new go-to position, even for conservative politicians.
State senators gave final approval Tuesday to a bill that would remove the flag. That sends the proposal to the House, where it faces a less certain future.
___
Kinnard can be reached at http://twitter.com/MegKinnardAP
Dylann Storm Roof
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 08:25:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AP source: Fed's gun used in San Francisco pier slaying</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/senators-feds-deported-sfc-man-killing-155946812--politics.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>A British Airways flight from London was diverted to Boston Wednesday after a British passenger allegedly assaulted a travel companion while on the flight. (July 8)
Load More
SAN FRANCISCO (AP)  The gun used in the seemingly random slaying of a woman on a San Francisco pier belonged to a federal agent, a law enforcement official briefed on the matter said Tuesday.
The official, who was not authorized to speak publicly about the case and spoke on condition of anonymity, said a police check of the weapon's serial number shows it belonged to a federal agent. The official declined to elaborate further.
The San Francisco Police Department, which is investigating the case, declined to comment.
The revelation was the latest dramatic twist in a tragic case that has become a new flashpoint in the country's debate over immigration policies.
The suspected gunman, Juan Francisco Lopez Sanchez, has been deported to his native Mexico five times and is suspected of living in the United States illegally when Kathryn Steinle, 32, was gunned down last week while on an evening stroll with her father along San Francisco's popular waterfront area.
Federal officials transferred Sanchez to San Francisco's jail in March to face a 20-year-old marijuana charge after Sanchez completed his latest prison term for illegally entering the country.
View gallery
Father Cameron Faller, right, and Julio Escobar, of Restorative Justice Ministry, conduct a vigil fo
The San Francisco sheriff, citing the city's "sanctuary city" policy, released Sanchez in April after prosecutors dropped the drug charge, despite an Immigration and Customs Enforcement request to hold him for federal authorities so deportation proceedings could begin.
Sanchez pleaded not guilty Tuesday to first-degree murder.
He told two television stations who interviewed him in jail that he found the gun used in Steinle's killing wrapped in a shirt on the pedestrian pier she was walking on. Sanchez said the gun went off in his hands, and his public defender, Matt Gonzalez, said Tuesday that the San Francisco woman's death appeared accidental.
Regardless of the reason behind Steinle's death, the shooting has touched off criticism from leading Republican lawmakers  and from top Democrats, including both of California's U.S. senators.
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton told CNN that San Francisco was wrong to ignore the ICE detainer request and release Sanchez from custody.
View gallery
Francisco Sanchez walks into the court for his arraignment at the Hall of Justice on Tuesday, July 7
"The city made a mistake, not to deport someone that the federal government strongly felt should be deported," Clinton said. "So I have absolutely no support for a city that ignores the strong evidence that should be acted on."
Sen. Dianne Feinstein called on San Francisco Mayor Ed Lee to start cooperating with federal immigration officials who want to deport felons such as Sanchez. Feinstein served as San Francisco mayor from 1978 to 1988.
"I strongly believe that an undocumented individual, convicted of multiple felonies and with a detainer request from ICE, should not have been released," Feinstein said. "We should focus on deporting convicted criminals, not setting them loose on our streets."
The mayor's office said it has reached out to Homeland Security officials to determine if there's a way to cooperate while still upholding the city's sanctuary policy.
"Mayor Lee shares the senator's concerns surrounding the nature of Mr. Sanchez's transfer to San Francisco and release," said Christine Falvey, a spokeswoman for the mayor. "As the mayor has stated, we need to gather all of the facts as we develop potential solutions."
View gallery
San Francisco Public Defender Jeff Adachi, left, talks to members of the media after Francisco Sanch
Democratic Sen. Barbara Boxer, also from Northern California, said she asked Gov. Jerry Brown if state law was followed in Sanchez's release.
"For decades, I have supported deporting violent criminals, and I have always believed that sanctuary should not be given to felons," Boxer said.
San Francisco Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi has defended Sanchez's release and the city law requiring it to ignore ICE detainer requests. The sheriff said ICE could have obtained a warrant or court order to keep Sanchez in custody.
"ICE knew where he was," Mirkarimi said Monday.
State and federal Republicans, meanwhile, said they would look into the matter.
View gallery
Flowers and a candle form a makeshift memorial for shooting victim Kathryn Steinle on Pier 14 in San
Wisconsin Sen. Ron Johnson, who chairs the Senate's homeland security committee, criticized federal officials and demanded to know why Sanchez was not deported.
"Does that make any sense to you?" Johnson demanded to know at a hearing Tuesday. "Because I'll tell you it doesn't make any sense to the American public."
Republican state Sen. Jeff Stone said he would introduce legislation in Sacramento to require cities to comply with ICE detainer requests.
At Sanchez's arraignment Tuesday, prosecutor Dianna Garcia argued against releasing Sanchez on bail, saying, "This was an act of random violence, shooting an innocent victim in the back."
The judge set bail at $5 million, which Gonzalez said will keep Sanchez jailed pending trial.
View gallery
San Francisco Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi gestures during an interview Monday, July 6, 2015, in San Franc
A downcast Sanchez spent most of the hearing with his head bowed, appearing to fight back tears while the judge explained the charged to him. Sanchez was aided by a Spanish-language interpreter and entered his plea in Spanish.
Outside court, his attorney said Sanchez has a second-grade education and a non-violent criminal record.
He could face life in prison if convicted.
___
Associated Press writers Amy Taxin in Los Angeles, Janie Har in San Francisco and Erica Werner in Washington contributed to this report.
San Francisco
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:44:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US stocks open lower as China fails to halt market slide</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/china-leads-dive-asia-stocks-greece-rattles-investors-062740378.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>US stocks open lower as China fails to halt market slide
13 hours ago
.
View photo
People sit on a bench near the New York Stock Exchange, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. Hong Kong's main stock index plummeted as much as 8.5 percent on Wednesday as a sell-off in mainland Chinese shares accelerated despite new measures to support the market. U.S. stocks were poised to open lower. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)
NEW YORK (AP)  U.S. stocks are opening lower as investors worry about China's ability to stem a stock market slide there.
The Dow Jones industrial average declined 132 points, or 0.7 percent, to 17,649 as of 9:35 a.m. Eastern time.
The Standard &amp; Poor's 500 gave up 13 points, or 0.6 percent, to 2,068. The Nasdaq fell 32 points, or 0.7 percent, to 4,965.
Stocks fell 6 percent in Shanghai despite the Chinese government's latest efforts to shore up the market. Chinese stocks have plunged in the last month but are still up 70 percent over the past year.
European markets were broadly higher as talks continue on Greece's debt woes.
United Continental lost 1.5 percent after grounding all of its flights in the U.S. due to computer problems.
Stocks &amp; Offerings
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 18:48:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI agents search Subway spokesman Jared Fogle’s home</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/subway-jared-fbi-raid-home-154836815.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FBI agents search Subway spokesman Jared Fogles home
Raid comes after Jared Foundation executives arrest on child pornography charges
By Dylan Stableford July 7, 2015 11:48 AM
Yahoo News
Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle`s Home Raided In Child Pornography Investigation

Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle`s Home Raided In Child Pornography Investigation
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Subway Spokesman Jared Fogle`s Home Raided In Child Pornography Investigation
 Replay video
Emotions High During SC Confederate Flag Debate

The gun that was allegedly used by Juan Francisco Sanchez to fatally shoot Kathryn Steinle was stolen from a federal agent.
Load More
The FBI and state police searched the Indiana home of Subway restaurant spokesman Jared Fogle early Tuesday, and later in the day the food franchise announced it has suspended its relationship with him.
The Indianapolis Star reports that electronics were removed from Fogles house in Zionsville, Ind., and loaded into a mobile forensics van parked in his driveway.
Fogle was seen entering and exiting the van during the search and later left with his attorney, according to the paper.
According to Foxs Indianapolis affiliate , state and federal agents served warrants at Fogles home in connection with a child pornography investigation. An FBI spokeswoman confirmed the agency was conducting an investigation in the area but would not specify its nature.
Subway and Jared Fogle have mutually agreed to suspend their relationship due to the current investigation, a company spokesman told Yahoo News on Tuesday afternoon in a written statement. Jared continues to cooperate with authorities, and he expects no actions to be forthcoming. Both Jared and Subway agree that this was the appropriate step to take.
Earlier Tuesday, Subway said in a statement to CNBC that it was shocked by the law enforcement activity and believed it is related to a prior investigation of a former Jared Foundation employee.
View gallery
Federal authorities and a Zionsville police office arrive at the home of Subway restaurant spokesman
In April, Russell Taylor, the executive director of the Fogles Jared Foundation , was arrested on child pornography charges. Authorities said a search of Taylors home turned up more than 400 videos with images of child pornography.
Fogle quickly distanced himself and his foundation from Taylor.
I was shocked to learn of the disturbing allegations against Mr. Taylor, Fogle said in a statement. Effective immediately, the Jared Foundation is severing all ties with Mr. Taylor.
Taylor, 43, attempted suicide in jail a week after his arrest.
Fogle, 37, gained national fame as the restaurant chains pitchman after losing more than 240 pounds  weight loss he attributed to eating Subway sandwiches.
According to the New York Daily News , Fogle has an estimated net worth of $15 million.
He started the Jared Foundation in 2004 to eliminate childhood obesity by raising awareness and developing programs that educate and inspire kids to live healthier, happier lives.
I am starting the Jared Foundation to help kids who are in the same situation I was in growing up, Fogle told Food Processing magazine at the time . I was an overweight kid who turned into an even heavier teenager who turned into an obese young adult, and this negatively affected every aspect of my life. Now I am in a position where I can have some influence with kids and, hopefully, can help them learn to make better choices.
Jared Fogle
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 06:21:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NTSB: 2 killed when F-16, small plane crash; jet pilot safe</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/officials-f-16-small-plane-collide-midair-162154763.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Another day in the UK, another member of the Queens Guard annoyed with a pedestrian.
Load More
MONCKS CORNER, S.C. (AP) -- An F-16 fighter jet smashed into a small plane Tuesday over South Carolina, killing two people and raining down plane parts and debris over a wide swath of marshes and rice fields.
The two people aboard the smaller Cessna were killed, and the plane was completely destroyed, National Transportation Safety Board spokesman Peter Knudson said. The pilot of the F-16 ejected and "is apparently uninjured," he said.
A press release from Shaw Air Force Base in Sumter said the pilot, Maj. Aaron Johnson from the 55th Fighter Squadron, was taken to Joint Base Charleston's medical clinic for observation.
View photo
.
Fallen debris in Berkeley County after a F-16 fighter and CessnaC150 collided falling from the sky near Moncks
"We heard the plane crash. And then we took off from where I was at, I guess I was about a half-mile from it, when we saw a cloud of smoke," said Leo Ramsey, who's worked at the plantation for about 30 years.
He and two other co-workers went out to the flaming spot where the jet had crash-landed into some of the wooded acreage around the plantation, Ramsey said. They found burning metal, splintered trees and a crater where the empty jet crashed, he said.
The NTSB is investigating the cause.
Debris was scattered across a wide swath of the sparsely populated area about 20 miles northwest of Charleston, though there were no reports of anyone being hurt or any homes being damaged on the ground, Berkeley County spokesman Michael Mule said.
A witness reported that the military plane broadsided the Cessna, said Berkeley County Coroner Bill Salisbury. Officials said during a news conference that most of the debris was in a marshy area, including a rice field.
Wayne Ware told The Post and Courier of Charleston he was going for a walk when he heard the crash happen. He did not see the initial impact, but heard it.
"I turned around, and I saw the jet. Pieces started falling out of the sky," Ware said, telling the paper the jet's engine landed at a campground.
The fighter pilot was flying solo practicing instrument approaches to a military base and was communicating with Charleston air traffic controllers, military officials said.
Col. Stephen Jost, commander of the 20th Fighter Squadron at Shaw Air force Base, said the pilot was on his cellphone as soon as he parachuted to the ground.
Jost said workers at the plantation picked up the pilot and took him to Berkeley County EMS workers, who took him to the Charleston base.
It wasn't clear if a flight plan had been filed, but Berkeley County officials say the civilian pilot had indicated he was traveling to Myrtle Beach.
Jost said he thought it was overcast at the time of the collision, but he was not aware of any weather-related problems.
The Air Force has flown F-16s since the 1970s, though very few active-duty squadrons still fly them. F-16s from Shaw Air Force Base, about 35 miles east of Columbia, routinely fly training missions over eastern South Carolina and the Atlantic.
The smaller plane was a Cessna 150, according to the Federal Aviation Administration, a two-seat plane that debuted in 1959 and remains one of the most common single-engine planes in the U.S.
The Cessna 150's maximum altitude is about 15,000 feet, according to the Aircraft Owners and Pilots Association. Most models weigh about 1,500 pounds when fully fueled. By comparison, an F-16 is about 50 feet long and weighs nearly 10 tons, not counting fuel or weapons. Jost said the F-16 was not carrying any live munitions at the time of the collision.
___
Associated Press writers Jack Jones in Columbia, and Emery Dalesio and Martha Waggoner in Raleigh, North Carolina, contributed to this report.
Shaw Air Force Base
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
