<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:46:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina governor: Confederate flag comes down Friday</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/south-carolinas-confederate-flag-removed-week-150437498.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>A female foal was born on Tuesday at the Illinois zoo displaying brown stripes which will turn to black by her first birthday (July 9).
Load More
COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP)  South Carolina's governor relegated the Confederate flag to the state's "relic room" on Thursday, more than 50 years after the rebel banner began flying at the Statehouse to protest the civil rights movement.
Compelled to act by the slaughter of nine African-Americans at a church Bible study, Gov. Nikki Haley praised lawmakers for acknowledging that the long-celebrated symbol is too painful and divisive to keep promoting.
"The Confederate flag is coming off the grounds of the South Carolina Statehouse," Haley said before signing the bill. "We will bring it down with dignity and we will make sure it is stored in its rightful place."
Police then surrounded the rebel flag with barricades and rope, a siege of sorts that will end Friday after the banner is furled for the last time at a 10 a.m. ceremony.
South Carolina's leaders first flew the battle flag over the Statehouse dome in 1961 to mark the 100th anniversary of the Civil War. It remained there to represent official opposition to the civil rights movement.
Mass protests against the flag decades later led to a compromise in 2000 with lawmakers who insisted that it symbolized Southern heritage and states' rights. They agreed then to move it to a 30-foot pole next to a Confederate monument out front.
South Carolina to Remove Confederate Flag Play video
But even from that lower perch, the flag was clearly visible in the center of town, and flag supporters remained a powerful bloc in the state.
The massacre 22 days ago of state Sen. Clementa Pinckney and eight others inside Charleston's Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church suddenly changed this dynamic, not only in South Carolina but around the nation.
Police said the killings were racially motivated. By posing with the Confederate flag before the shootings, suspect Dylann Storm Roof, who has not yet entered a plea to nine counts of murder, showed that the flag also has symbolized white supremacy and racial oppression.
Haley moved first, calling lawmakers to vote the flag down. Very quickly thereafter, Republican leaders in other states who have long cultivated the votes of Confederate flag supporters announced that Civil War symbols no longer deserve places of honor.
"These nine pens are going to the families of the Emanuel Nine," Haley said after signing the bill into law. "Nine amazing individuals who have forever changed South Carolina history."
Emotions High During SC Confederate Flag Debate Play video
The governor said the way the victims welcomed the gunman into their Bible study, and the forgiveness survivors expressed when the suspect later appeared in court, have inspired change nationwide.
"Nine people took in someone who did not look like them or act like them. And with true love and true faith and acceptance, they sat and prayed with him for an hour. That love and faith was so strong that it brought grace to them and the families," Haley said.
"We saw the families show the world what true grace and forgiveness look like," she added. "That set off an action of compassion by people in South Carolina and all over this country. They stopped looking at their differences and started looking at their similarities."
The flag removal bill passed easily in the Senate, where the Rev. Pinckney served, but then stalled as House members proposed dozens of amendments. Any changes could have delayed the flag's removal and blunted momentum for change.
The debate stretched on for more than 13 hours as representatives shared anger, tears and memories of their ancestors. Flag supporters talked about grandparents passing down family treasures. Some lamented that the flag had been "hijacked" or "abducted" by racists.
View gallery
A protester waves a Confederate battle flag in front of the South Carolina statehouse, Thursday, Jul
Rep. Mike Pitts recalled playing with a Confederate ancestor's cavalry sword while growing up, and said the flag reminds him of dirt-poor Southern farmers who fought Yankees, not because they hated blacks, but because their land was being invaded.
Black Democrats, frustrated at being asked to honor those who fought for slavery, offered their own family histories.
Rep. Joe Neal traces his ancestry to four brothers, brought to America in chains and bought by a slave owner named Neal who pulled them apart from their families.
"The whole world is asking, is South Carolina really going to change, or will it hold to an ugly tradition of prejudice and discrimination and hide behind heritage as an excuse for it?" Neal said.
Rep. Jenny Horne, a white Republican who said she is a descendent of Confederate President Jefferson Davis, scolded her party members for stalling.
View gallery
Leslie Minerd, of Columbia, S.C., holds a sign as she celebrates outside the South Carolina Statehou
"I cannot believe that we do not have the heart in this body to do something meaningful such as take a symbol of hate off these grounds on Friday," she shouted. "For the widow of Sen. Pinckney and his two young daughters, that would be adding insult to injury and I will not be a part of it!"
The bill ultimately passed by a 93-27 vote  well above the two-thirds supermajority needed to make changes to the state's "heritage" symbols.
Republican Rep. Rick Quinn said he was satisfied after lawmakers promised to find money  perhaps millions of dollars for a special display in the state's Confederate Relic Room for the flag being removed, as well as the one taken down from the dome in 2000.
"It's just like the conclusion of the war itself," Pitts said Thursday afternoon after the vote. "The issue was settled, and the nation came back together to move on."
But Republican Rep. Jonathon Hill, who voted against removing the flag, said he fears a larger movement has begun to eliminate Civil War-era history.
"Hopefully it ends here, and we move forward, and we can put all of this behind us," Hill said.
Some groups are already seeking to do just that. The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People will consider ending its 15-year boycott of South Carolina's economy at its national convention this weekend. The NCAA, which honored that ban, said it will resume holding championship events in the state.
---
Follow Jeffrey Collins on Twitter at https://twitter.com/JSCollinsAP and Meg Kinnard at http://twitter.com/MegKinnardAP .
South Carolina
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:26:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI says it thwarted Islamic State-inspired July 4 attacks</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/fbi-says-arrested-10-july-4-plots-inspired-172336100.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Load More
By Julia Edwards and Mark Hosenball
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. authorities foiled attacks planned around the Fourth of July, arresting more than 10 people in the month before the holiday who were inspired by Islamic State online recruitment, FBI Director James Comey said on Thursday.
"I do believe our work disrupted efforts to kill people likely in connection with July 4th," Comey told reporters at the headquarters of the Federal Bureau of Investigation. He did not detail the number of plots uncovered or their targets.
Separately, a national security source said multiple overseas plots by Islamic State sympathizers had also been halted in recent days.
The FBI and the U.S. Department of Homeland Security had warned local law enforcement to be on alert for attacks around the July 4 holiday celebrating the 1776 U.S. Declaration of Independence. No such attacks occurred.
Authorities' concern heightened around the holiday as Islamic State leaders called for followers to do what they could wherever they could to carry out violence on behalf of the militant group.
View gallery
Police officers patrol Times Square in New York, United States, July 3, 2015. New York Governor Andr
Comey described the tactic as "crowd sourcing terrorism" and said the FBI had accepted the heightened state as the "new normal."
Some of those arrested were communicating with Islamic State via encrypted data, a second U.S. security source said.
The FBI has pressured tech companies to remove encryption that gives users privacy protections that cannot be broken by law enforcement.
Comey estimated that dozens of people influenced by Islamic State have "gone dark" and disappeared from the FBI's watch because of encrypted data.
The United States is engaged in a military campaign with allies in the Middle East to fight Islamic State militants who have taken over parts of Iraq and Syria and created cells in other countries racked by conflict in the region.

(Reporting by Julia Edwards and Mark Hosenball; Writing by Julia Edwards; Editing by Doina Chiacu and Howard Goller)
FBI
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:50:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. says hackers stole personal data of 22M people</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/25-million-affected-opm-hack-officials-195504398--abc-news-topstories.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>22 Million Affected by OPM Hack, Officials Say
By MIKE LEVINE and JACK DATE 14 minutes ago

View photo
22 Million Affected by OPM Hack, Officials Say (ABC News)
The U.S. agency burglarized by suspected Chinese hackers has completed its long-awaited damage assessment and more than 22 million people inside and outside government likely had their personal information stolen, officials announced today.
That number is more than five times larger than what the Office of Personnel Management announced a month ago when first acknowledging a major breach had occurred. At the time, OPM only disclosed that the personnel records of 4.2 million current and former federal employees had been compromised.
The extent of the hacking was first reported earlier today by ABC News.
Investigators ultimately determined that 19.7 million applicants for security clearances had their Social Security numbers and other personal information stolen and 1.8 million relatives and other associates also had information taken, according to OPM. That includes 3.6 million of the current and former government employees for a total of 22.1 million.
"If an individual underwent a background investigation through OPM in 2000 or afterwards ... it is highly likely that the individual is impacted by this cyber breach," OPM's statement said today.
Even before today's announcement, there was little doubt that the universe of victims was vastly larger because the hackers had access to far more than personnel records, including files associated with background investigations and information on government workers' families, sources said.
In fact, the hackers allegedly rummaged through various OPM databases for more than a year -- and lawmakers and U.S. officials alike have described the breach as a significant threat to national security .
"It is a huge deal," FBI Director James Comey told a Senate panel on Wednesday.
Since reports surfaced saying more than just personnel records were stolen, the Obama administration has publicly maintained the theft of background-investigation files was a "separate incident" still under investigation. Some U.S. officials and lawmakers believe that distinction -- encompassing the same cyber-campaign -- kept the full scope of the OPM breach hidden for weeks.
"I'm sure you will probably obfuscate, [but] when will the American people know ... the extent of this penetration?" Sen. John McCain , R-Arizona, asked OPM Director Katherine Archuleta at a hearing on Capitol Hill two weeks ago.
Despite mounting public pressure and push-back from top FBI officials during closed-door briefings, senior OPM officials continued to say they couldnt offer even an estimate until they determined exactly how many people were affected by the "separate but related incident." As part of a "time-consuming analysis," investigators had to ensure they weren't double-counting people whose personal information may have been stored in more than one system breached, Archuleta said two weeks ago.
"Throughout this investigation, OPM has been committed to providing information in a timely, transparent and accurate manner," OPM said in a statement today.
U.S. intelligence and law enforcement officials are particularly concerned over the theft of forms known as SF-86s that current and prospective federal workers, including certain military personnel and even contractors, submit for security clearances. The forms require applicants to provide personal information not only about themselves but also relatives, friends, associates and foreign contacts spanning several years. The forms also ask applicants about past drug use, financial history, mental health history and personal relationships.
Such information could be exploited to pressure or trick employees and U.S. officials into further compromising their agencies, or they could provide ways for hackers to target people outside government, sources have told ABC News.
An OPM system known as "e-QIP" that allows applicants to submit SF-86s and other materials online remains suspended in the wake of the breach.
The attack on OPM began in late 2013, when hackers infiltrated the systems of a government contractor, KeyPoint Government Solutions, and stole the "credentials" of an employee, according to two days of testimony on Capitol Hill.
Sources suspect that was the start of an unprecedented cyber-campaign out of China to collect information on federal workers inside the United States and others around the world.
A major breach of OPM systems wasn't detected until April, after OPM began implementing new cyber-security measures. That led investigators to realize the files associated with background investigations had been taken.
OPM is now offering what it calls "a comprehensive suite of monitoring and protection services" to those impacted.
Editors Note: The story has been updated. A previous version stated that the total number of people affected was more than 25 million.
More ABC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 21:07:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>John Boehner calls for 'adult' debate about Confederate symbols</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/john-boehner-calls-for-adult-debate-in-congress-123653546236.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 18:46:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jenny Horne delivers emotional speech stirring Confederate flag vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/jenny-horne-delivers-emotional-speech-123641215636.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:12:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New delay complicates U.S. ability to implement Iran nuke deal</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/iran-nuke-talks-lurch-toward-another-deadline-072956595.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>US threatens to quit nuke talks; Iran blames West for divide
By BRADLEY KLAPPER and MATTHEW LEE 52 minutes ago

Kerry on Nuke Talks: 'We Will Not Be Rushed'

Kerry on Nuke Talks: 'We Will Not Be Rushed'
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Kerry on Nuke Talks: 'We Will Not Be Rushed'
 Replay video
Daughter wins awesome beatbox battle against her dad

South Carolina&amp;#39;s governor Nikki Haley signed into law Thursday a bill that removes the Confederate flag from the state&amp;#39;s capitol grounds.
Load More
VIENNA (AP)  U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry threatened Thursday to walk away from nuclear talks as he signaled that diplomats won't conclude an agreement with Iran over the coming hours  another delay that this time could complicate American efforts to quickly implement any deal. The Iranians immediately fired back, accusing the U.S. and its European allies of causing the deadlock.
Kerry and other Western officials said Iran still hadn't made the tough political decision to roll back its nuclear program. But a senior Iranian official said it was the Americans and their partners who were backtracking on several key commitments related to Iran's permitted level of nuclear activity and definitively ending economic sanctions against Tehran.
"This is not open-ended," Kerry told reporters outside the 19th-century Viennese palace hosting the negotiations. "We can't wait forever for the decision to be made. If the tough decisions don't get made, we are absolutely prepared to call an end to this process."
It was the strongest indication yet of U.S. frustration with Iran, and vice versa, coming two days after President Barack Obama vowed a similar response to Iranian intransigence and suggesting patience was running out as the current round of talks headed into its 14th day.
Thursday's latest delay for a comprehensive deal is significant. Iran is demanding prompt easing of economic penalties for nuclear concessions, and the longer it takes world powers to make good on their promises, the longer they'll have to wait for the Iranians to scale back their nuclear program.
Under U.S. law, the seven nations negotiating in Vienna have to complete the accord before the end of Thursday in Washington to avoid invoking a 60-day congressional review period during which President Barack Obama cannot waive sanctions on Iran. If they meet the target, the review would only be 30 days.
View gallery
German Foreign Minister Frank Walter Steinmeier, left, French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius, 2nd l
The specter of prolonged public relations campaigns for and against the pact also may not work in Obama's favor. The delay could imply that the U.S., Iran and other negotiating powers may end up having to push off the talks until September when any deal would again only amount to a 30-day review period.
"We will not rush and we will not be rushed," Kerry said.
"We would not be here continuing to negotiate just for the sake of negotiating. We're here because we believe we are making real progress toward a comprehensive deal," he said. But, he added: "We are not going to sit at the negotiating table forever."
Kerry spoke after discussing the state-of-play with other world powers for almost an hour Thursday evening. That conversation followed a flurry of other closed-door meetings, including a 45-minute session between Kerry and his Iranian counterpart.
"We're working hard, but not rushed, to get the job done," Zarif tweeted.
View gallery
U.S. Secretary of Energy Ernest Moniz, centre, arrives for a meeting at an hotel in Vienna, Thursday
A senior Iranian official, who briefed foreign reporters covering the talks on condition no one quote him by name, declared the West's reluctance to ease economic penalties the biggest obstacle. The U.S. is "obsessed" with sanctions, said the official, adding that the deadlock could prove a major setback.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said he would remain in Austria's capital for negotiations into Friday morning, citing "good things, but there is still work to do."
However, U.S. Energy Secretary Ernest Moniz, who has been leading the American negotiating team alongside Kerry, was to leave for Portugal for most of Friday to discuss climate change matters with the president, prime minister and other senior officials.
The current round of talks has already been extended twice since it started on June 27, as has an interim nuclear accord with Iran that these negotiations are meant to finalize. The preliminary deal was due to expire on June 30, then July 7 and then Friday. It would have to be renewed a third time if the talks go beyond Friday.
At an economic summit in Russia, Iran's President Hassan Rouhani said his nation was preparing for a "post-sanctions" era, suggesting a deal may be in sight to curb Iran's nuclear program in exchange for the lifting of economic sanctions.
View gallery
Dark clouds hang over Palais Coburg where closed-door nuclear talks with Iran take place in Vienna, 
Kerry spoke by phone with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, who was also in Russia and voiced optimism, saying he was prepared to return to Vienna.
And in what was widely seen as a hint that the talks might soon wrap up, the White House late Wednesday issued a brief statement saying President Barack Obama had conferred with the U.S. negotiating team through a secure video call.
The last time Obama held a secure conference call with his negotiators on the road was shortly before the framework for a final accord was reached on April 2 in Lausanne, Switzerland.
Kerry, nursing a broken leg, has been in Vienna since June 26, while Zarif has made one short trip to Tehran for consultations. Other foreign ministers have come and gone. All but the top diplomats from Russia and China were present at Thursday's meetings.
When the talks missed their second deadline it raised new questions about the ability of world powers to cut off all Iranian pathways to nuclear weapons through diplomacy.
View gallery
U.S. Secretary of Energy Ernest Moniz and Head of the Iranian Atomic Energy Organization Ali Akbar S
Long-standing differences persist over inspections of Iranian facilities and the Islamic republic's research and development of advanced nuclear technology.
New difficulties also have surfaced over the past few days. Iran is pushing for an end to a U.N. arms embargo on the country but Washington opposes that demand.
Russia's Lavrov took Tehran's side.
"Our Western partners, who did not support a draft resolution entirely acceptable to the other parties, are at fault, not Iran," he tweeted.
___
Associated Press writer George Jahn contributed to this report.
John Kerry
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:25:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>25 million records affected by hacking: U.S. personnel office</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/u-personnel-office-over-25-million-records-affected-195050865.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Estimate of Americans hit by government personnel data hack skyrockets
By Patricia Zengerle and Megan Cassella 5 minutes ago

.
View photo
A man types on a computer keyboard in Warsaw in this February 28, 2013 illustration file picture. REUTERS/Kacper
By Patricia Zengerle and Megan Cassella
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Data breaches at the U.S. government's personnel management agency by hackers, with suspicions centering on China, involved millions more people than previously estimated, U.S. officials said on Thursday.
The Office of Personnel Management (OPM) said the stolen data included Social Security numbers and other sensitive information on 21.5 million people who have undergone background checks for security clearances.
That is in addition to data on about 4.2 million current and former federal workers that was stolen in what the OPM called a "separate but related" hacking incident. Because many people were affected by both hacks, a total of 22.1 million people were affected, or almost 7 percent of the U.S. population.
Those exposed included 19.7 million who applied for the clearances, plus 1.8 million non-applicants, mostly spouses or co-habitants of applicants, the agency said. The breach had already been considered one of the most damaging on record because of its scale and, more importantly, the sensitivity of the material taken.
The United States has identified China as the leading suspect in the massive hacking of the U.S. government agency, an assertion China's Foreign Ministry dismissed as "absurd logic."
Asked during a conference call with reporters on Thursday whether China was responsible, a White House National Security Council official, Michael Daniel, said "we're not really prepared to comment at this time on the attribution behind this event."
Daniel, special assistant to the president and cybersecurity coordinator at the National Security Council, said that "at this point the investigation into the attribution of this event is still ongoing and we are exploring all of the different options that we have."
The incidents have outraged members of Congress and worried the millions of Americans affected since they were revealed last month. Some lawmakers have called for the resignation of Katherine Archuleta, the OPM director.
AGENCY CHIEF WILL NOT RESIGN
Archuleta said neither she nor OPM chief information officer Donna Seymour would be resigning. "I am committed to the work that I am doing at OPM," Archuleta told reporters. "I have trust in the staff that is there."
OPM said in a statement that its investigation had found no information "at this time" to suggest any misuse or further dissemination of the information stolen from its systems.
It said some records included findings from interviews conducted by background investigators and about 1.1 million include fingerprints.
Background investigation records contained some information on mental health and financial history provided by security clearance applicants and others contacted during their investigations. OPM said there was no evidence that separate systems storing information on health, financial, payroll and retirement records of federal employees were affected by the hacking.
OPM said it is highly likely that anyone who went through a background investigation after 2000 was affected by the cyber breach. Those who underwent background checks before 2000 might be impacted but it is less likely, the personnel agency said.
The Social Security numbers are just the tip of the iceberg.
The critical information, which was not encrypted, involves a complete rundown of the personal lives of some 90 percent of applicants for security clearances, mainly excepting most undercover CIA agents.
That includes drug use, romantic histories and close friends abroad of those in the military, National Security Agency (NSA) and sensitive State Department posts, among many others, essentially a road map for what weaknesses might be used for blackmail by a foreign power.
Though not attributing the attack in public to China, investigators have told Reuters that their prime suspect is a team tied to that nations Ministry of State Security. The evidence includes a specific piece of malicious software and the use of a stolen digital certificate, both of which had been seen in only a small number of attacks that had been tied to the same group.
Dmitri Alperovitch, chief technology officer at security firm CrowdStrike, said his companys analysis of data about the breach provided by the government made it clear that one or another part of the Chinese government directed the hacking.
"Its a tremendous coup for China," Alperovitch said.
(Additional reporting by Joseph Menn and Will Dunham; Editing by Sandra Maler and Bill Trott)
Social Security numbers
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jul 10 00:30:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina governor signs bill to remove Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/confederate-flag-debate-nears-decisive-vote-south-carolina-031737867.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>South Carolina governor signs bill to remove Confederate flag
By Harriet McLeod 34 minutes ago

South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley spoke to a gathered crowd before signing a legislation permanently
By Harriet McLeod
COLUMBIA, S.C. (Reuters) - South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley signed legislation on Thursday to permanently remove the Confederate battle flag from the state capitol grounds, following an emotional debate spurred by the massacre of nine black churchgoers last month.
Haley signed the bill into law in the State House Rotunda before an audience of legislators and dignitaries shortly after 4 p.m. EDT (2000 GMT), and her office said the flag would be taken down at 10 a.m. (1400 GMT) on Friday.
The rebel banner will go to the "relic room" of South Carolina's military museum in Columbia, the state capital.
"The Confederate flag is coming off the grounds of the South Carolina State House," Haley said to cheers and applause. "We will bring it down with dignity and we will make sure it is put in its rightful place."
The flag, carried by Confederate troops on the losing side in the 1861-1865 Civil War, is seen as a symbol of racism and slavery by many. But others proudly hail it as an emblem of Southern heritage.
View gallery
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley signs a legislation permanently removing the Confederate battle 
The flag has flown for 54 years at the capitol of the first state to secede from the United States, and the state where the Confederacy fired the first shots of the Civil War, in Charleston.
South Carolina plans to keep Friday's flag relocation "as low-key as the national media will let us," said Haley spokeswoman Chaney Adams.
Among those attending the signing were relatives of "the Charleston 9," the black men and women gunned down on June 17 at a landmark church in an apparently racially motivated slaughter.
Haley paid special tribute to the victims' families' forgiveness of the white man charged in the killings, Dylann Roof, 21. She said their inspirational actions played a major role in the law's passage, and said a pen from the signing would go to each of the families.
Also joining Haley, a Republican of Indian descent who is South Carolina's first non-white chief executive, were predecessors who supported the measure.
View gallery
Alan Hoyle of North Carolina holds a confederate battle flag and bible outside the statehouse in Col
The governor signed the bill after the state House of Representatives gave it final approval in the wee hours of Thursday after 13 hours of emotional debate.
Before Thursday's signing, a small crowd gathered on the State House lawn waving "Take Down the Flag" signs as drivers honked their horns.
Others snapped photos on the last full day the banner will fly from its pole at a memorial to Confederate war dead.
"I love this," said Hammie Johnson. "It's about time people came to the realization of what that flag represents to us as African-Americans, and that's slavery."
He and his wife, Esther, watched the House debate the bill on television. "We watched all of it, every last bit," he said.
View gallery
A man holds a confederate flag outside the statehouse in Columbia, South Carolina July 9, 2015 hours
Jim Felder, 76, one of the first blacks to be elected to state House, said he never thought he would live to see the flag come down.
"I'm so proud today. ... I thought maybe my grandchildren would get it down," he said.
He and others credited Haley with lobbying Republican state representatives on Wednesday to pass the bill. "She was just trying to hold them together, like herding cats," he said, adding that he had new respect for the governor.
The House overwhelmingly approved the legislation after 1 a.m. EDT (0500 GMT) on Thursday. The Senate passed it earlier in the week, also by a huge margin. Both chambers are Republican-controlled.
The flag controversy has extended across the U.S. South as the Charleston killings spurred a wave of repudiation by politicians and businesses.
In Washington, Republican leaders in the U.S. House of Representatives Thursday abruptly canceled a vote on a measure that would allow the flag to be flown in cemeteries operated by the National Park Service, after an outcry by opponents.
White House spokesman Josh Earnest described the bipartisan flag vote as a sign of "progress."
He added, "Republicans in Congress, however, seem to have values and priorities that lie elsewhere," a reference to the park service bill.
(Writing by David Adams; Additional reporting by Susan Cornwell; Editing by Jonathan Oatis)
South Carolina
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 23:26:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As deadline looms, Kerry says U.S. in no rush to get Iran deal</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/russia-says-iran-talks-most-difficult-phase-060732200.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>As deadline looms, Kerry says U.S. in no rush to get Iran deal
By Louis Charbonneau and Parisa Hafezi 5 minutes ago

Russia wants Iran's arms embargo 'lifted as soon as possible'

Russia wants Iran's arms embargo 'lifted as soon as possible'
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Russia wants Iran's arms embargo 'lifted as soon as possible'
 Replay video
SC Gov. Signs Bill Removing Flag From Statehouse

Load More
By Louis Charbonneau and Parisa Hafezi
VIENNA (Reuters) - The United States and other major powers are not in a rush to reach a nuclear deal with Iran, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry said on Thursday, suggesting an accord was unlikely hours ahead of a deadline set by the U.S. Congress for a quick review.
In another sign an agreement was not at hand, a senior Iranian official accused the United States and others nations of shifting their positions and backtracking on an April 2 interim agreement that was meant to lay the ground for a final deal.
The comments suggested Iran and the major powers - Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States - have a way to go to reach a deal under which Iran would curb its nuclear program in exchange for sanctions relief.
"We're here because we believe we are making real progress," Kerry told reporters in the Austrian capital. "We will not rush and we will not be rushed."
However, Kerry said Washington's patience was not unlimited. We cant wait forever," he said. "If the tough decisions dont get made, we are absolutely prepared to call an end to this."
View gallery
U.S. Secretary of Energy Ernest Moniz, US Secretary of State John Kerry, British Foreign minister Ph
He did not say how much longer the talks could continue. Shortly after Kerry spoke, the White House said the talks would not likely drag on for "many more weeks."
Briefing reporters on condition of anonymity, the senior Iranian official sought to put the onus on the West for any  failure to reach an agreement.
"There have been changes of position ... particularly since last night," said the official, "Suddenly everyone has their own red lines. Britain has its red line, the U.S. has its red line, France, Germany..."
The official also said that Iran was looking forward to seeing whether the United States would "abandon its obsession with sanctions."
Negotiators have given themselves until the end of the day on Friday. But if a deal is not reached by 6:00 a.m. in Vienna (0400 GMT), the skeptical Republican-led U.S. Congress will have 60 days rather than 30 days to review it, extra time U.S. President Barack Obama's administration worries could derail it.
U.S. Secretary of Energy Ernest Moniz, centre, arrives for a meeting at an hotel in Vienna, Thursday
'96 PERCENT COMPLETE'?
The central bargain of an interim deal struck on April 2 in Lausanne, Switzerland as well as of the final deal that the two sides are now trying to work out is to limit Iran's nuclear work in return for easing economic sanctions crippling its economy.
Iran's Deputy Foreign Minister Abbas Araqchi has said the main text of a final agreement, as well as five technical annexes, were "around 96 percent complete."
While the lifting of sanctions was largely agreed, Araqchi said Tehran's demand for an end to a U.N. Security Council arms embargo was among the most contentious unresolved points.
Other sticking points in the negotiations have included Iran's research and development on advanced centrifuges and access to Iranian military sites and nuclear sites.
View gallery
Russian President Vladimir Putin (R) shakes hands with Iran's President Hassan Rouhani during their 
Tehran says a U.N. embargo on conventional arms has nothing to do with the nuclear issues and must be lifted in any deal. Western countries do not want allow Iran to begin importing arms because of its role supporting sides in Middle East conflicts.
Iran has powerful support on this issue from Russia. Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said at a summit of BRICS countries - Brazil, China, India, Russia and South Africa - that the U.N. arms embargo should be among the first sanctions lifted.
Over the past two weeks, Iran, the United States, Britain, France, Germany, Russia and China have twice extended deadlines for completing the long-term nuclear agreement.
In a sign that the Friday morning U.S. congressional deadline was likely to be missed, Energy Secretary Ernest Moniz, a key member of the U.S. negotiating team, was due to fly to Portugal on Friday to accept an honor and make a speech, returning on Friday evening.
Western countries accuse Iran of seeking the capability to build nuclear weapons, while Tehran says its program is peaceful. A deal would depend on Iran accepting curbs on its nuclear program in return for the easing of economic sanctions imposed by the United Nations, United States and European Union.
A successful deal could be the biggest milestone in decades towards easing hostility between Iran and the United States, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries stormed the U.S. embassy in Tehran in 1979.
It would also be a political success for both Obama and Iran's pragmatic President Hassan Rouhani, who both face resistance from powerful hardliners at home.
(Additional reporting by John Irish and Arshad Mohammed and Shadia Nasralla in Vienna and Katya Golubkova and Denis Pinchuk in Russia, writing by Louis Charbonneau; Editing by Anna Willard, Peter Graff and Giles Elgood)
Iran
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:13:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beyond 'To Kill a Mockingbird': The lost novel of Harper Lee</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/katiecouric/beyond-to-kill-a-mockingbird-the-lost-novel-of-123555389873.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
