<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Scene in Atlanta where police are investigating a home found to contain bomb-making materials - @wsbtv</title>
        <Link>http://www.wsbtv.com/news/news/local/bomb-making-materials-found-inside-hapeville-home-/nmtrm/</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Scene in Atlanta where police are investigating a home found to contain bomb-making materials - @wsbtv</Description>
        <MainBody>Posted: 10:31 p.m. Wednesday, July 8, 2015
Bomb-making materials found inside Hapeville home, police say
Related
Police closed part of the road as they investigated the home.
Sponsored Links
HAPEVILLE, Ga. 
Police are investigating after they said they found bomb-making materials inside a metro Atlanta house.
Police tell us they found chemicals inside the home on Virginia Avenue at Rainey Avenue in Hapeville Wednesday night.
Police closed part of the road as they investigated. Atlanta police and the bomb squad are on the scene.
Channel 2s Carl Willis is at the scene gathering details. He talks to the suspect's father, who says his son is studying to be a chemical engineer, on the Channel 2 Action News Nightbeat at 11.
Sign up for our WSB TV Daily Headlines Newsletter
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Urban and small stream flood advisory issued for Central Lake County, Calif., until 8:15 pm PT - @abc7newsBayArea</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/SandhyaABC7/status/618950183770939392/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Urban and small stream flood advisory issued for Central Lake County, Calif., until 8:15 pm PT - @abc7newsBayArea</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Update: 2 dead, 1 critically injured in Marieville, Quebec, shooting; suspect still at large, authorities say - @CBCMontreal</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/CBCMontreal/status/618965527399124993</Link>
        <Description>Update: 2 dead, 1 critically injured in Marieville, Quebec, shooting; suspect still at large, authorities say - @CBCMontreal</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Video: Republican South Carolina state lawmaker Jenny Horne makes emotional appeal to remove Confederate flag; plea came after dozens of amendments were proposed by lawmakers who appear to oppose an expedited removal - @ABCNews4</title>
        <Link>http://www.abcnews4.com/story/29506379/no-flag-blue-flag-white-flag-a-wild-day-in-the-house</Link>
        <Description>Video: Republican South Carolina state lawmaker Jenny Horne makes emotional appeal to remove Confederate flag; plea came after dozens of amendments were proposed by lawmakers who appear to oppose an expedited removal - @ABCNews4</Description>
        <MainBody>No flag? Blue flag? White flag? A wild day in the House
Posted:
A white flag flying on Statehouse grounds?
How about the American flag - flying upside-down?
These were just some of the 68 amendments proposed Wednesday by members of the S.C. House representatives who don't want to see the Confederate flag simply removed from the Statehouse grounds.
The amendments pushed the debate past 11 hours, threatening to delay an attempt by opponents to do what the Senate did a day before - vote to remove it.
Finally, one representative had enough of what she called an obvious attempt to stall the vote. Rep. Jenny Horne (R-Summerville), with tears in her eyes, stood and gave an impassioned plea for her colleagues to end the discussion and do what's right.
Her speech, the first to call for the removal of the flag since the amendments began, was applauded on social media. See some of the best tweets from the lengthy debate below
.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>At least 2 killed, 2 injured as Typhoon Chan-hom causes heavy rainfall, floods in Philippines, state disaster management agency says - @XHNews</title>
        <Link>http://news.xinhuanet.com/english/2015-07/08/c_134394586.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 2 killed, 2 injured as Typhoon Chan-hom causes heavy rainfall, floods in Philippines, state disaster management agency says - @XHNews</Description>
        <MainBody>2 killed, 2 injured due to severe weather in Philippines
English.news.cn 2015-07-08 22:20:21
MANILA, July 8 (Xinhua) -- At least two people were killed and two others injured due to weather disturbance affecting central and northern parts of the Philippines , the state disaster management agency said Wednesday.
Metro Manila, the country's capital, and other parts of the country have been experiencing monsoon rains due to the effect of typhoon Chan-Hom, locally named as Falcon, the state weather forecasting agency said.
It warned that monsoon rains which may trigger flash floods and landslides would be experienced over most regions in northern part of the country.
Classes in Metro Manila and nearby provinces were suspended Wednesday and some local government units have declared to continue the class suspension on Thursday.
[Editor: huaxia]
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>South Korea's central bank freezes key rate at record low - @YonhapNews</title>
        <Link>http://english.yonhapnews.co.kr/news/2015/07/09/0200000000AEN20150709002451320.html?input=www.tweeter.com</Link>
        <Description>South Korea's central bank freezes key rate at record low - @YonhapNews</Description>
        <MainBody>Print
SEOUL, July 9 (Yonhap) -- South Korea's central bank on Thursday held the key interest rate steady at 1.5 percent for this month after cutting it to a record low in June to fend off the fallout from the Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) outbreak.
Last month, the Bank of Korea (BOK)'s Monetary Policy Committee voted to cut the base rate by a quarter percentage point, sending the policy rate lower by a total of 1 percentage point since August last year.
The MERS outbreak has claimed 35 lives so far, sparking a health scare and dampening consumer spending, which has emerged as an important growth engine amid slumping exports.
The July decision is in line with a poll by Yonhap Infomax, the financial news arm of Yonhap News Agency, in which all 17 analysts and economists projected the BOK would freeze the key rate to monitor the impact of previous rate cuts and ease household debt risks.
Some analysts had also pointed out that monetary policy has taken a back seat in Seoul's efforts to boost growth after the finance ministry unveiled an 11.8 trillion won (US$10.4 billion) extra budget earlier this month.
Growing household debt, which reached a record 1,099 trillion won as of end-March, is also a policy headache in Asia's fourth-largest economy as it is feared to constrict consumption and potentially spur financial risks.
The polled analysts and economists forecast the rate freeze to continue until the end of the year as the U.S. Federal Reserve is expected to start hiking its rates later this year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Tennis ball size hail falls in Channing, Texas - @DisasterShep</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/DisasterShep/status/618952341698449408</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Tennis ball size hail falls in Channing, Texas - @DisasterShep</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>17-year-old girl from Chicago's Hyde Park neighborhood found strangled in abandoned Gary, Ind., building, police say - @nbcchicago</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcchicago.com/news/local/Chicago-Teen-Found-Strangled-in-Abandoned-Gary-Building-312699831.html?_osource=SocialFlowTwt_CHBrand</Link>
        <Description>17-year-old girl from Chicago's Hyde Park neighborhood found strangled in abandoned Gary, Ind., building, police say - @nbcchicago</Description>
        <MainBody>&gt; local
Chicago Teen Found Strangled in Abandoned Gary Building
Connita L. Richardson, of the 800 block of East Hyde Park Boulevard, was found dead in an abandoned building in the 700 block of East 7th Avenue in Gary
Privacy Policy | More Newsletters
Getty Images
A female found killed in an abandoned Gary, Ind. building Tuesday night has been identified as a 17-year-old girl from Chicagos Hyde Park neighborhood.
Connita L. Richardson, of the 800 block of East Hyde Park Boulevard, was found dead in an abandoned building in the 700 block of East 7th Avenue in Gary Tuesday night, authorities said.
Video Subway Suspends Ties With Spokesman Jared Fogle
Police initially received an anonymous call about a suspicious person inside an abandoned building, according to a statement from Gary police.
When officers arrived, they found the body of an unidentified female lying facedown with minor trauma to the body, police said.
Video WATCH: Naked Man Steals Police Car on July 4
She was dead at the scene and her death was ruled a homicide, according to the Lake County coroners office.
An autopsy Wednesday found her cause of death to be asphyxiation by strangulation, according to the coroners office.
Published 2 hours ago
News breaks at inconvenient times. 
Download one of the NBCChicago mobile apps and have the news come to you. Watch live streaming newscasts, receive critical push notifications on the go and stay in touch with your city around the clock.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Walt Disney World in Orlando, Fla., removes Confederate flag from Epcot display, park confirms - @orlandosentinel</title>
        <Link>http://www.orlandosentinel.com/business/tourism/os-disney-confederate-flag-epcot-down-20150708-story.html?utm_content=buffer4250d&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer</Link>
        <Description>Walt Disney World in Orlando, Fla., removes Confederate flag from Epcot display, park confirms - @orlandosentinel</Description>
        <MainBody>11
The banner, which was among more than 40 displayed from throughout America's history, was the third flag of the Confederacy. The familiar "Southern Cross" symbol does not take up the entire banner as it does in the Confederate battle flag. Instead the blue cross with white stars on a red background is displayed in the upper-left-hand corner, bordered by a field of white with a thick, red stripe at the other end.
Sheri Labowski, a Connecticut tourist relaxing outside the American Adventure on Wednesday, said she agreed with the flag's removal.
"I think in this day and age we shouldn't be promoting a part of our history we're not proud of," she said.
The American Adventure includes an animatronics show taking the audience through American history. It makes references to the Civil War, slavery and abolitionists, including Frederick Douglass.
In the wake of last month's slaying of nine parishioners at a black church in Charleston, S.C., the flag of the South in the Civil War is undergoing new scrutiny.
It is viewed by many as a symbol of racism, though others argue it is a part of history that represents their Southern heritage.
Dylann Roof, a 21-year-old white man charged in the Charleston church shootings, was captured after a motorist spotted his Confederate license plate. Images on a website created in his name months before the attacks show him posing with the Confederate flag.
A bill is passing through South Carolina's Legislature that would remove the flag from above a memorial on the State House grounds. Wal-Mart and Amazon.com announced they would stop selling merchandise displaying the "Stars and Bars." Alabama's governor has ordered Confederate flags removed from a war memorial at the Capitol.
The banner is the second controversial object Disney World has removed recently. On Tuesday, Disney said it is taking down a statue of disgraced comedian Bill Cosby from the Academy of Television Arts &amp; Sciences Hall of Fame Plaza at its Hollywood Studios theme park. Disney's decision came a day after unsealed court documents revealed Cosby testified in 2005 he had obtained quaaludes with the intent of giving them to women with whom he wanted to have sex. More than two dozen women have alleged that Cosby drugged and sexually assaulted them during four decades.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Chinese authorities suspend train services, close schools and call trawlers back to port as 2 typhoons in south and east of the country approach, state media reports - @MailOnline</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/wires/reuters/article-3154322/China-suspends-trains-closes-schools-typhoons-approach.html#ixzz3fM0FWCg1</Link>
        <Description>Chinese authorities suspend train services, close schools and call trawlers back to port as 2 typhoons in south and east of the country approach, state media reports - @MailOnline</Description>
        <MainBody>Published: 01:14 GMT, 9 July 2015 | Updated: 01:15 GMT, 9 July 2015
18 shares
BEIJING, July 9 (Reuters) - Chinese authorities have suspended train services, closed schools and bought trawlers back to port before two typhoons in the south and east of the country make landfall later this week, state media said.
Typhoon Linfa is expected to make landfall in the southern province of Guangdong on Thursday. The more powerful Typhoon Chan-Hom could land further up the coast in Fujian or Zhejiang province late on Friday, Xinhua news agency said.
China's commercial capital, Shanghai, will stop all passenger trains running south along the coast on Friday and Saturday, the report said.
Guangdong province has closed primary and middle schools in 15 counties, it said.
Typhoons are common at this time of year in the South China Sea, picking up strength from the warm waters before dissipating over land.   (Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Paul Tait)
Share or comment on this article
18
Sorry we are not currently accepting comments on this article.
Bing
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Tornado spotted near Valle De Oro, Texas, moving southeast at 20 mph, weather service says - @stormchaser4850</title>
        <Link>http://kamala.cod.edu/offs/KAMA/1507090121.wfus54.html</Link>
        <Description>Tornado spotted near Valle De Oro, Texas, moving southeast at 20 mph, weather service says - @stormchaser4850</Description>
        <MainBody>TO REPEAT...A TORNADO IS ON THE GROUND. TAKE COVER NOW. MOVE TO AN 
INTERIOR ROOM ON THE LOWEST FLOOR OF A STURDY BUILDING. AVOID 
WINDOWS. IF IN A MOBILE HOME...A VEHICLE OR OUTDOORS...MOVE TO THE 
CLOSEST SUBSTANTIAL SHELTER AND PROTECT YOURSELF FROM FLYING DEBRIS. 

HEAVY RAINFALL MAY HIDE THIS TORNADO. DO NOT WAIT TO SEE OR HEAR THE 
TORNADO. TAKE COVER NOW. 
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>NBA salary cap set at record $70 million for 2015-16 season; cap increased by 11% from last season, league says - @espn</title>
        <Link>http://espn.go.com/nba/story/_/id/13224161/nba-salary-cap-set-70-million-2015-16-season</Link>
        <Description>NBA salary cap set at record $70 million for 2015-16 season; cap increased by 11% from last season, league says - @espn</Description>
        <MainBody>Print
Comment
NEW YORK -- The NBA salary cap was set Wednesday for next season at $70 million, a higher-than-expected number that paves the way for free-agent contracts to be signed.
The league said the cap increased by 11 percent from last season's $63.1 million and the 2015-16 cap will be the highest ever -- though it will be shattered next summer. It had been projected to come in closer to $67 million until recently.
With the cap set, the league's moratorium will be lifted at midnight, and deals and trades that were agreed to since free agency opened on July 1 can become official beginning Thursday at 12:01 a.m. EDT.
The salary cap took a larger jump than anticipated, to $70 million from last season's $63.1 million, before what is expected to be a massive increase next summer.
Andrew D. Bernstein/NBAE/Getty Images
Also, the tax level increased 10.3 percent to $84.7 million. Teams whose payrolls exceed it will be subjected to penalties.
The salary cap is derived in part on league revenues. It is expected to vault to about $90 million for the 2016-17 season, when the league's new national TV contracts begin.
In the meantime, there's plenty of money for teams and players next season. Maximum salaries will rise because they are based on a percentage of the cap, depending on a player's years of service.
LeBron James , should he sign for the max, would make $23 million next season with more than 10 years in the league.
There will be three spending exceptions available to teams. The non-taxpayer midlevel for this season is $5.5 million, the taxpayer midlevel is $3.4 million and the midlevel for a team with room under the salary cap is $2.8 million.
0 Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Overturned chicken hauler prompts highway closure in Lula, Ga.; some chickens escaped their cages, local media reports - @FOX5Atlanta</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/FOX5Atlanta/status/618952247955849216</Link>
        <Description>Overturned chicken hauler prompts highway closure in Lula, Ga.; some chickens escaped their cages, local media reports - @FOX5Atlanta</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>South Carolina State Law Enforcement Division investigating threats against lawmakers on Confederate flag issue, spokesperson says - @Live5News</title>
        <Link>http://www.live5news.com/story/29502150/sled-investigating-threats-against-lawmakers-on-confederate-flag-issue</Link>
        <Description>South Carolina State Law Enforcement Division investigating threats against lawmakers on Confederate flag issue, spokesperson says - @Live5News</Description>
        <MainBody>SLED investigating threats against lawmakers on Confederate flag - Live5News.com | Charleston, SC | News, Weather, Sports
Member Center:
SLED investigating threats against lawmakers on Confederate flag issue
Posted:
Photo Source: WCSC
COLUMBIA, SC (WCSC) -
The South Carolina State Law Enforcement Division is investigating threats against state lawmakers over the Confederate flag.
SLED Spokesman Thom Berry confirmed "a number of threatening communications" had been sent to members of the state's General Assembly over the flag.
"We recognize the First Amendment protections offered for free speech," Berry said in a statement. "That's not what this is about. Legislators on both sides of the issue have received communications that include death threats. That's not free speech; it's illegal to threaten to kill or injure a public official or their immediate family."
Berry recognized the "strong emotions" on bothsides of the issue, adding that SLED's goal is to keep the discussion on a "constructive path that will be best for all South Carolinians."
"To threaten the life or well-being of a lawmaker or their family is inexcusable," he said in the statement.
SLED Chief Mark Keel said the agency will work with law enforcement partners at all levels in South Carolina and elsewhere to investigate, make arrests and bring those responsible for the threats to justice.
The news comes as lawmakers in the State House debate a bill to remove the Confederate flag from the State House grounds.
State Representatives began debating 26 amendments for the bill Wednesday morning.
All of the amendments were introduced by Rep. Mike Pitts, who has 20 minutes to talk about each one, which adds up to about eight hours. But Rep. Todd Rutherford said before the session began that he did notthink it wouldtake that long.
"I can tell you that a number of Democrats and Republicans are on the same page," Rutherford said. "There are obviously some outliers -- we have 124 members -- each one has the opportunity to have their say and we're going to allow them to do that. What we will have is a good debate. We look forward to that and we look forward to talking about the flag."
A second reading of the bill cannot take place until all amendments have been voted on.
Copyright 2015 WCSC. All rights reserved.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>2 critically injured in Marieville, Quebec, shooting; gunman at large, police say - @CTVNews</title>
        <Link>http://montreal.ctvnews.ca/two-critically-injured-shooter-at-large-in-marieville-1.2460523</Link>
        <Description>2 critically injured in Marieville, Quebec, shooting; gunman at large, police say - @CTVNews</Description>
        <MainBody>Two dead, shooter at large in Marieville
A large perimeter has been established in Marieville. (CTV Montreal / Shannon Kelly)
CTV Montreal
Published Wednesday, July 8, 2015 8:08PM EDT
Last Updated Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:13PM EDT
A major police operation is underway in Marieville, about 45 kilometres east of Montreal.
Police confirm two people are dead following a shooting.
They say the shooter is at large.
The Surete du Quebec is at the scene, where a large perimeter has been cordoned off. Police dogs are helping the tactical squad comb the area.
Police would not provide any more details at this time.
More details to come.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>Hong Kong kindergarten classes and some special schools suspended as Tropical Storm Linfa (Egay) approaches city; tropical cyclone signal to increase, education bureau says - @SCMP_News</title>
        <Link>http://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/1834418/hong-kong-issues-storm-signal-1-tropical-cyclone</Link>
        <Description>Hong Kong kindergarten classes and some special schools suspended as Tropical Storm Linfa (Egay) approaches city; tropical cyclone signal to increase, education bureau says - @SCMP_News</Description>
        <MainBody>Order your FREE copy of AT YOUR SERVICE 2015
Tropical storm Linfa's path, forecast by the Hong Kong Observatory. It is set to move slowly north then in a westerly direction towards Guangdong. Photo: HKO
Kindergarten classes and some special schools were suspended on Thursday morning when Hong Kong began to batten down the hatches as Typhoon Linfa approached the city.
The Hong Kong Observatory raised typhoonsignal No.3at 8.40am.The Education Bureau announcedit was suspending classes an hour before.The Observatory said it would consider issue the No.8 storm signal later on Thursday as Linfa upgraded into a typhoon and moved closer to Hong Kong.
"According to the present forecast track, Linfa is expected to come closest to Hong Kong tonight and tomorrow morning. Local winds will then strengthen further," it said.
"The Observatory will consider whether to issue the No.8 gale or storm signal this afternoon and tonight depending on Linfa's movement and intensity changes," it said.
A standby typhoon signal was hoisted in Hong Kong on Wednesdayas Linfa came within 800km of the city.
Typhoon signal No.1, the lowest on the alert scale, was issued at 7.40am and means that the storm "may affect the city".
On Thursday morning, the Observatory said that at 10am Linfa was estimated to be about 250kmeast of Hong Kong and was forecast to move west at about 16km/hin the general direction of the vicinity of the Pearl River Estuary.
In the past few hours, Linfa continued to steadily move westwards. According to the present forecast track, local winds are expected to significantly strengthen this afternoon and there will be squally showers.
Local winds are expected to strengthen further tonight, but wind strengths will depend upon Linfa's movement and intensity changes.
This the third tropical storm named Linfa to hit the northwestern Pacific Ocean this century. The name means "lotus flower" in English and was submitted by Macau to the Regional Specialised Meteorological Centre in Tokyo.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Former AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd sentenced to 8 months home detention on charges of drug possession and threatening to kill, New Zealand court rules - @NZStuff</title>
        <Link>http://www.stuff.co.nz/national/crime/70031619/Former-AC-DC-drummer-Phil-Rudd-sentenced-to-home-detention?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter</Link>
        <Description>Former AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd sentenced to 8 months home detention on charges of drug possession and threatening to kill, New Zealand court rules - @NZStuff</Description>
        <MainBody>Former AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd sentenced to home detention
TONY WALL
Last updated14:38, July 9 2015
BRUCE MERCER/Stuff.co.nz
AC/DC drummer, Phil Rudd appears is sentenced to eight months home detention on drugs and threatening to kill charges.
As the judge dressed Phil Rudd down, perhaps his most stinging rebuke was that the former AC/DC drummer's playing wasn't anything special.
Rudd was sentenced in the Tauranga District Court on Thursday to eight months home detention on drugs and threatening to kill charges.
Rudd appeared in front of Judge Thomas Ingram for sentencing after pleading guilty to possession of cannabis and methamphetamine and one charge of threatening to kill. He has been on bail the whole time.
BRUCE MERCER/ FAIRFAX NZ
Phil Rudd appearing at the Tauranga District Court for sentencing.
The judge warned Rudd he would go to prison if he breached the terms ofhis sentence.
"I stone cold guarantee that's where you'll end up. I'm not yourheadmaster, I'm not your father, I'm a judge."
He said Rudd would be monitored 24 hours a day during his homedetention, to be served at his waterfront Tauranga mansion.
"There is simply no place to hide"
Earlier, the court was told Rudd's actions were the result ofmethamphetamine psychosis and he was addicted to the drug.
Affidavits to the court said Rudd would lose tens of millions ofdollars if he was convicted because he couldn't tour to certaincountries with AC/DC.
Judge Ingram said there was no evidence he had an offer from the bandand he was not convinced that Rudd's drumming was integral to theAC/DC sound.
"Queen replaced Freddie Mercury," he said.
He refused Rudd's application to be discharged without conviction.
RUDD'S OFFENDING
It was revealed in November last year that Rudd had been arrested and charged with drugs offences and attempting to procure a murder, a charge that was dropped 24 hours later.
In April, when Rudd pleaded guilty to possessing drugs and threatening to kill, the court heard he'd made a call to an associate asking him to "take out" a former security guard turned personal assistant after becoming angry when his solo album launch in August last year flopped.
He fired a number of employees, including his victim.
On September 25 at 8.12pm Rudd phoned an associate in Australia saying he wanted the victim "taken out", and "taken care of because they were a bunch of f***en c****.
Rudd then offered the associate $200,000, one of his cars, a motorbike or a house, which the associate believed was payment for the request.
The next day at 8.27am, Rudd called the victim and asked if he was "on today", the victim said yes at which point Rudd said "I'm going to come over and kill you".
Rudd made two further calls to the same victim, who hung up after realising it was Rudd.
Police then obtained a warrant to search Rudd's Bureta home in Tauranga on November 6.
When police arrived Rudd was in the lounge and attempted to conceal a container of crumbs, which after testing was found to be 6gms of cannabis.
Rudd then pulled out a bag of cannabis from the couch, the court was told.
ESR testing found the bag contained a further 20.2gms of cannabis.
When police arrived at the home Rudd was wearing jeans and no shirt. In his front jeans pocket police discovered a white powder, which turned out to be 0.273gms of methamphetamine.
Police searched the home where they found 0.205g of methamphetamine in the master bedroom, 47.2gms of cannabis in the hallway cupboard, and a further 17.9gms of cannabis in the pool room bedroom.
A total of 0.478gms of methamphetamine and 91gms of cannabis was found.
ADRIFT FROM THE BAND
Previously Rudd has said he's seen the error of his ways and wished he was touring with AC/DC again.
Rudd told an Australian TV station in May his former bandmates, including guitarist Angus Young, weren't talking to him.
"They haven't called me. I wrote them a letter and I tried to get in touch with Angus but I've had no contact from anybody," Rudd told A Current Affair. "I'm very disappointed, but that's life."
Rudd said he was "fit and ready to go" and wished he was touring with AC/DC.
"I've seen the error of my ways and it's onward and upward from here."
Angus Young said last year that Rudd was not himself and needed help.
Last year, Rudd was ordered to pay more than $72,000 after kicking a door in and sacking workers during a tantrum at his restaurant, Phil's Place.
AC/DC are due to play concerts in Wellington and Auckland in December, the last gigs of a world tour.
-Stuff
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Virgin Australia cancels all flights to and from Bali due to volcanic ash cloud from Mount Raung, airline says - @SkyNewsAust</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/SkyNewsAust/status/618942335833911296/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Virgin Australia cancels all flights to and from Bali due to volcanic ash cloud from Mount Raung, airline says - @SkyNewsAust</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Fire burning south of Grande Prairie, Alberta - @CBCAlerts</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/CBCAlerts/status/618935123665403904/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Fire burning south of Grande Prairie, Alberta - @CBCAlerts</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>Tornado reported about 8 miles southeast of Crystal City, Mo; warning continues until 7:30 pm CT - @weatherchannel</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/weatherchannel/status/618936660349202432</Link>
        <Description>Tornado reported about 8 miles southeast of Crystal City, Mo; warning continues until 7:30 pm CT - @weatherchannel</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
