<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="express">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Family's joy as student injured in balcony collapse tragedy starts waking from coma</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/WjE6OiPRDFY/Aoife-Beary-coma-Berkeley-balcony-collapse-tragedy-family-Ireland-Stanford-Dublin</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Family's joy as student injured in balcony collapse tragedy starts waking from coma
Family's joy as student injured in balcony collapse tragedy starts waking from coma
A STUDENT who was seriously injured after a balcony collapsed as she celebrated her 21st birthday has started to wake from a coma.
PUBLISHED: 03:13, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 03:43, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
FACEBOOK
Aoife Beary was seriously injured after a balcony collapsed as she celebrated her 21st birthday
Aoife has also started some communication with her parents and the medical team
Beary family
Six students plunged to their deaths from a fifth-floor apartment in Berkeley, California , last month while attending Aoife Beary's party.
She suffered a serious head injury but has started to communicate with her parents and medical team in hospital in Stanford.
Beary, from Dublin, had successful heart surgery 10 days after the incident and "continues to make progress", her family said.
They said: "Aoife is still in the ICU but is no longer on the critical list.
"She has slowly started to awaken from the induced coma  this process is expected to take some time.
"Aoife has also started some communication with her parents and the medical team."
FACEBOOK
Beary "continues to make progress", according to her family
The students killed were on J1 working visas for the summer and were among 40 people attending the birthday party.
Five of them were from Dublin, while the other, Ashley Donohoe, was Irish-American and lived in California.
Around 700 Irish students are in the region on J1 working visas for the summer.
AFP  GETTY
The balcony collapse caused a group of around 14 people to plunge to the ground
The balcony collapse, at around 12.45am local time on 16 June, caused the group of around 14 people to plunge about 40ft (12.2m) to the ground.
One Irish citizen said he heard screams around the same time at the apartment complex.
When officers arrived they found the balcony on the fourth floor of the building on Kitteridge Street had smashed and disintegrated.
GETTY
Five of the students were from Dublin, while the other was Irish-American
AFP  GETTY
Investigations found severe dry rot in the balcony which collapsed
Philip Grant, of the Irish Department of Foreign Affairs in San Francisco, spoke of his grief as the death toll rose last month.
He said: "For many of my countrymen it's a formative experience and to have this happen at the start of this season is something that has left us all frozen in shock and disbelief.
"We are a very close, tight-knit group. Ireland is a small country and when you have the numbers that we had here today very few of us have been left untouched by this tragedy."
New safety rules for buildings in the university city were drawn up after investigations found severe dry rot in the balcony which collapsed.
According to officials, emergency orders had been set out to enhance the safety of all new and existing buildings in the area.
Most Read Stories in World
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Flight drama as 'British man attacks wife – forcing pilot to make emergency landing'</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/z7NQ23iK5LM/Darren-Halliwell-British-Airways-assault-Wigan-Boston-Houston-London</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Flight drama as 'British man attacks wife  forcing pilot to make emergency landing'
Flight drama as 'British man attacks wife  forcing pilot to make emergency landing'
A BRITISH Airways flight was forced make an emergency landing yesterday after a British man allegedly assaulted his wife.
PUBLISHED: 01:11, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
| UPDATED: 01:42, Thu, Jul 9, 2015
GETTY FILE PICTURE
Darren Halliwell allegedly attacked his wife on a British Airways flight
The flight from London to Houston was diverted to Boston Logan International Airport after the alleged assault.
48-year-old Darren Halliwell was then restrained by multiple passengers, according to reports.
The father-of-two was charged with interfering with a flight crew and is expected to appear at East Boston District Court today.
Authorities said more charges could be filed against Halliwell, from a village near Wigan, Manchester.
A Foreign Office spokesman said: "We are aware of reports of the arrest of a British national at Boston Logan International Airport and stand ready to offer consular assistance as necessary."
The plane continued to Houston after his arrest.
A British Airways spokesman said: "Our customers and crews deserve to enjoy their flights, and not to suffer any form of abuse.
"This sort of behaviour will not be tolerated, and the Captain took the decision to divert the aircraft to Boston as a precaution.
"The matter will now be handled by the police."
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eurozone crisis: Greece caves in and promises 'credible reforms' to taxes and pensions</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/MMk1_jfUCyQ/Eurozone-crisis-Greece-promises-credible-reforms-taxes-pensions</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Eurozone crisis: Greece caves in and promises 'credible reforms' to taxes and pensions
Eurozone crisis: Greece caves in and promises 'credible reforms' to taxes and pensions
GREECE caved into demands to slash its lavish state pensions and begin collecting taxes tonight in a desperate last-ditch attempt to stay in the euro.
PUBLISHED: 21:22, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
| UPDATED: 21:43, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
REUTERS
Alexis Tsipras has promised to put 'credible reforms' before European leaders on Sunday
Prime minister Alexis Tsipras promised to rush through emergency legislation meaning wide-reaching reforms could be in place by next week.
The last-minute plea could be enough to convince European leaders to authorise a three-year loan which could stop the country defaulting on its debts and crashing out of the eurozone.
However, it may also see his part abandon its staunchly anti-austerity rhetoric which has played so well with voters. On Sunday the Greek people overwhelming voted against accepting the terms of an international bailout in a stunning rejection of the public spending constraints demanded by other European leaders.
In a letter to the European Stability Mechanism, which is responsibly for authorising the finance Greece needs, finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos said: "We propose to immediately implement a set of measures as early as the beginning of next week including tax reform related measures, pension related measures."
Mr Tsipras today promised his government will submit "credible reforms" to an emergency meeting of all 28 European Union (EU) leaders on Sunday .
REUTERS
Disgruntled Greek politicians showed their displeasure with the EU
My country has over the past five years been transformed into an austerity laboratory
Greek PM Alexis Tsipras
However, during a fractious meeting of the Greek parliament the left-wing leader also savaged the EU for turning his country into an "austerity laboratory".
He said: "In many European countries, austerity programmes have been put into effect.
"However, nowhere have those programmes been so harsh and so long lasting as in Greece and it is no exaggeration to say that my country has over the past five years been transformed into an austerity laboratory.
"This experiment, I think all of us have to accept, has not been a success. Over these five years we have seen a sky rocketing of poverty, unemployment has soared, as has debt.
"Today, the majority of the Greek people feel that they have no other choice other than to demand that they be given a way out of this dead end and they have expressed this in the most direct way possible and we have to implement that decision."
His government today confirmed that Greek banks will remain closed for the foreseeable future, with people restricted to withdrawing just 60 a day.
The announcement came as the country's Ministry of Economy, Infrastructures, Maritime Affairs and Tourism had to issue a statement reassuring people that food supplies were not about to run out.
There have been reports of Greeks stripping supermarket shelves of food in a panic as they look to stock up on supplies in case of an economic catastophe.
In a statement the ministry said it "reassures both the Greek citizens and the visitors (tourists) that there are adequate food supplies in the market and that their prices remain stable".
REUTERS
Greek banks will remain closed for the foreseeable future
REUTERS
Greece is on a knife-edge, with its place in the euro hanging by a thread
Yesterday a succession of European leaders warned that the unprecedented meeting of European leaders on Sunday would represent Greece's last chance to salvage its position in the eurozone.
If it does not persuade its international creditors to provide fresh finance the country's banking system will collapse, causing widespread economic chaos.
It is understood that the Greek government's promised reforms are just part of a wider package which will be needed to assuage the concerns of EU leaders.
However, Spain's Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy tonight welcomed the latest Greek proposals as a "positive" change in tone.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>University graduate 'plunges 40ft to her death after attempting selfie by side of bridge'</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/OqtkHlIDzyo/Russian-university-graduate-falls-death-selfie-attempt-bridge</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>University graduate 'plunges 40ft to her death after attempting selfie by side of bridge'
University graduate 'plunges 40ft to her death after attempting selfie by side of bridge'
A UNIVERSITY graduate plunged 40ft to her death after leaning against the side of a bridge to take a selfie, according to reports.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:24, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
CEN
Anna Krupeynikova died in Moscow, Russia
Anna Krupeynikova, who had just completed a degree in tourism, was travelling around Moscow on a bus with a group of friends when the tragedy happened.
The 21-year-old, a keen dancer and member of an amateur troupe, had wandered away from the group when the bus stopped near a bridge.
She had decided to use the break to take some pictures, but a fence which she had leaned on by the side of the bridge - while holding her camera - reportedly gave way.
Ms Krupeynikova, from Russia, died after falling 40ft - just two weeks before she was due to celebrate her 22nd birthday.
CEN
Ms Krupeynikova had reportedly been trying to take a selfie
Police were said to be investigating whether she had been drinking with friends, according to local media.
However, a fellow passenger on the bus told local television that everyone on the vehicle was sober.
Another youngster on the trip, known only as Anton, said: "We met her a few months ago and she'd become one of our gang, she was quiet but always cheerful and when we got to the place where she died we had been taking photographs.
"Suddenly I heard a yell and someone said 'Anna fell'. I thought it was a joke but then I saw the reaction of people who went and looked over the side of the bridge."
Police spokeswoman Julia Ivanova confirmed they were investigating the death - and are also reportedly looking for the person responsible for maintaining the railing at the side of the bridge.
Ms Ivanova said all 18 people who were on the bus had been questioned by police as part of the investigation.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NYSE denies 'cyber attack' as trading resumes following nearly four hour suspension  </title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/zgwaEixNzzQ/New-York-Stock-Exchange-NYSE-trading-suspended</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>NYSE denies 'cyber attack' as trading resumes following nearly four hour suspension
NYSE denies 'cyber attack' as trading resumes following nearly four hour suspension
THE New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) has denied it was the victim of a cyber attack after trading was suspended for more than three hours earlier today.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
| UPDATED: 21:47, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
GETTY
The New York Stock Exchange denied being the victim of a cyber breach
Trading was brought to a standstill at around 11:30am local time this morning with business resuming at around 3:10pm.
It is not yet known what caused the disruption but the NYSE denied they had been hacked.
The NYSE said in a series of tweets: "The issue we are experiencing is an internal technical issue and is not the result of a cyber breach.
"We chose to suspend trading on NYSE to avoid problems arising from our technical issue.
I don't feel good for our customers who are having to deal with the fallout
Tom Farley
"NYSE-listed securities continue to trade unaffected on other market centers."
NYSE President Tom Farley told CNBC it was "not a good day" for the business.
He said: "I don't feel good for our customers who are having to deal with the fallout."
Problems had first started arising for the NYSE at around 8am local time this morning, when the company put out an alert about "a reported issue with a gateway connection".
However, an issue was noticed at just after 10:30am saying that the problem had been solved.
Mr Farley said: "We opened the market as usual. All the NYSE-listed stocks opened without incident.
"Around mid-morning, we started to see some concerns about the way trading was occurring. Customers weren't getting all of the messages back that you otherwise expect."
All other US stock markets appeared to be up and running today, meaning investors were still able to buy and sell stocks.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens of ISIS fighters 'POISONED' after eating post-Ramadan feast in Iraq</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/peWKeCGhG9Y/Islamic-State-45-militants-DEAD-eating-poisoned-meal-Iraq</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Dozens of ISIS fighters 'POISONED' after eating post-Ramadan feast in Iraq
Dozens of ISIS fighters 'POISONED' after eating post-Ramadan feast in Iraq
DOZENS of fighters allied to the depraved jihadi group Islamic State (ISIS) have died after eating a poisoned meal.
PUBLISHED: 17:01, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
| UPDATED: 17:10, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
TWITTER
The photos show another dinner spread laid on by ISIS fighters
A group of around 150 militants attended a feast in the Iraqi city of Mosul to mark the end of another day of fasting for Ramadan.
But only 100 of the barbaric gang were said to have walked away live.
The contaminated meal was eaten during 'iftar' - the evening meal when Muslims end their daily Ramadan fast.
A spokesman for the Kurdish Democratic Party said it was unclear if the deaths were caused by deliberate contamination or accidental food poisoning.
Mosul, Iraq's second biggest city, was taken by ISIS militants over a year ago - one of the first areas to fall to the newly-created caliphate last summer.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:10:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea's Kim Jong-un orders farmer's execution - after his favourite terrapins die</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/rmRIbyU6eRc/Kim-Jong-Un-executes-farmer-firing-squad-starving-sea-baby-turtles-terrapins</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>North Korea's Kim Jong-un orders farmer's execution - after his favourite terrapins die
North Korea's Kim Jong-un orders farmer's execution - after his favourite terrapins die
KIM JONG-UN has ordered a farmer to be ruthlessly executed - after his favourite terrapins died.
PUBLISHED: PUBLISHED: 15:10, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
GETTY
The North Korean leader on a happier farm tour
The North Korea dictator is believed to have been so shocked at the farm's treatment of the reptiles - where they were kept in dirty tanks and starved - he condemned its owner to death by firing squad.
Jong-un is also reported to have been outraged at the manager's excuse that "inadequate power supply and food" were to blame - viewing it as an insult to his regime.
The 32-year-old leader's brutal action came following an embarrassing tour at Taedonggang Terrapin Farm in May.
The farm holds a special place in the Jong-un's heart, as his father, Kim Jong Il, had personally opened and praised the farm in October 2011.
In a drive to provide the country with "tasty and nutritious seafood", the late leader of the country had sent freshwater lobsters to the facility for breeding.
During his recent visit, Jong-un also promised grave consequences" for not producing the lobsters that had been promised at the farm's opening, while he raged at the manager's "incompetence".
The portly autocrat was also aghast to see that the farm owner had "no room at the farm dedicated to honouring" his father.
The state's 'Supreme Leader' denounced the manager as "defeatist" and had him shot after the tour.
Professor Remc Breuker, an expert in Korean studies at Leiden University in the Netherlands, confirmed accounts of Jong-un's extreme reaction are likely to be true.
He said: "There's a good chance this happened.
GETTY
Kim Jong-Un is preparing his nation for the 70th anniversary of the country
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 13:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sobbing Greek pensioner who became symbol of crisis offered help - from 8,000 miles away</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/mJrj8JSa-FI/Sobbing-Greek-pensioner-symbol-debt-crisis-help-Australia</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greek debt crisis: Another day of turmoil as talks stall and UK shares slide
Mr Koufos said: When I saw this, I said to mum, What can we do?
I got my mother to take out some cash, to find the man and give him some immediate support.
Were going over there to surprise him and just give him quite a substantial amount of money.
Were also raising some money from corporations who want to donate.
Were dealing with a few shelters in Athens and Thessaloniki to offer immediate support where we can with shelter and food.
Those photos had such an impact, not just on me, but a lot of people I know.
Ive had grown men that I know in front of me and over the phone bawling their eyes out on just how much it hit them.
Australia has one of the largest expat Greeks communities in the world, with more Greek-speakers living in Melbourne than anywhere else in the world outside of Greece.
GETTY
Greeks queue and wait outside a national bank for their daily withdrawal
Mr Koufos is set to fly to Thessaloniki from Sydney on Saturday.
The Greek government decided to shut all national banks last Monday to stop the country running out of cash, with locals only allowed to withdraw up to 42 (60 euros) a day - although pensioner have been allowed to get up to 85.
After sobbing in the street, Mr Chatzifotiadis revealed he broke down because he "cannot stand to see my country in this distress".
"That's why I feel so beaten, more than for my own personal problem.
"I see my fellow citizens begging for a few cents to buy bread. I see more and more suicides.
"I am a sensitive person. I cannot stand to see my country in this situation.
"Europe and Greece have made mistakes. We must find a solution."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Madrid's memorial to Margaret Thatcher torn down by 'petty' socialist mayor</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/numjehYT0U4/Madrid-Margaret-Thatcher-Plaza-torn-down-socialist-mayor</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Madrid's memorial to Margaret Thatcher torn down by 'petty' socialist mayor
Madrid's memorial to Margaret Thatcher torn down by 'petty' socialist mayor
A SPANISH square dedicated to Margaret Thatcher will have all connections to Britain's 'Iron Lady' removed by a socialist mayor, just nine months after it was named.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
| UPDATED: 09:47, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
REX
Maragret Thatcher Plaza was named in Madrid in September
Plaza Maragret Thatcher in Madrid has not even existed for a year but new mayor Manula Carmena wants to rid the city of the admiration because it was the "Iron Lady who enslaved the workers".
She now wants to name it after socialist politician and gay rights campaigner Pedro Zerolo, who died last month.
Mark Thatcher, the former Conservative Party prime minister's son, unveiled the plaque last September.
It had been commissioned by the previous mayor of Madrid, conservative Ana Botella, who was also wife to the former Spanish prime minister Jose Maria Aznar.
Related articles
A burden has been lifted from my shoulders: Margaret Thatcher's...
But since Ms Carmena gained power in May, left-wing Podemos, which is the second biggest political party in Spain, has piled on the pressure to change the name and make a statement.
Sir Bernard Ingham, Baroness Thatcher's press secretary during her time as prime minister, said: "It is the latest in a long list of petty acts by socialist mayors.
SOLARPIX
Mark Thatcher unveiling the Margaret Thatcher Plaza
SOLARPIX
Mark Thatcher with former Mayor of Madrid Ana Botella (left) who commissioned the plaza dedication
It is the latest in a long list of petty acts by socialist mayors
Sir Bernard Ingham
"Her name is being removed in favour of a gay rights campaigner but she did more for human rights than most people because if you improve the economy then you give people a better chance."
Ms Botella, who admired Baroness Thatcher for years, wanted to name a square after the British stalwart soon after the former Tory leader's death in April 2013.
But Ms Carmena has other ideas, and also plans to rename 150 other sreets, squares and public spaces to erase names of those with links to General Franco, the dictator who ruled Spain from 1939 to his death in 1975.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two women facing jail for WEARING SKIRTS in British holiday hotspot Morocco</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/eZ_47reszc0/Women-jail-Inezgane-court-WEARING-SKIRTS-Morocco-holiday</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two women facing jail for WEARING SKIRTS in British holiday hotspot Morocco
Two women facing jail for WEARING SKIRTS in British holiday hotspot Morocco
TWO Moroccan women have gone on trial for WEARING SKIRTS, sparking mass demonstrations across the north African country.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
| UPDATED: 09:19, Wed, Jul 8, 2015
YASTOCH
Protestors outside the Inezgane court during the trial of two women prosecuted for wearing skirts
The hairdressers are accused of gross indecency, a charge that has also seen 26,000 people sign a petition calling for the case to be dropped.
The pair, aged 23 and 29, were walking through an open-air market in Inezgane, a suburb outside the popular coastal holiday destination of Agadir, last month on their way to work.
A market trader drew attention to what they were wearing and an angry mob of merchants swarmed around them, accusing them on wearing tight and "immoral" clothes.
Security then rescued the pair, but took them to the police station to be charged.
Related articles
We're closer to gender equality but we've lost something along the...
Protestors have demonstrated across Morocco saying women should be free to wear what they please.
British tourists have told Express.co.uk they too have faced censure from market traders despite dressing respectfully in long clothing.
One said: "I was called a whore every time I walked past shops, by numerous men. It was scary."
Activists also gathered at the court house on Monday to support the detainees on their day of trial.
ALAMY
The Inezgane souk where the skirt-wearing women were walking
ALAMY
The women were in Inezgane open-air market when they were surrounded by traders
This is an infringement on individual freedoms and human rights
The judge will give a verdict on July 13.
Anyone found guilty of committing an act of "public obscenity" in Morocco can be jailed for up to two years.
Organisers of the online petition, named 'Wearing a dress is not a crime' said if this prosecution is successful it will set a worrying precedent for the future.
It reads: "This is an infringement on individual freedoms and human rights.
YASTOCH
Protestors have been demonstrating around Morocco
"A significant number of Moroccan women have worn dresses for decades.
"Are these the laws that manage public space today or is it the individuals with the least respect for the freedoms and rights of others, on behalf of their own standards?
"This is a regression and a case that opens the way for those who want to rise up in moralizing or preaching to impose their own laws."
Bouchra Chetouani, a member of the Moroccan Association for Human Rights (AMDH), said: "They were dressed in a very respectable fashion."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
