<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Global News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:38:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Firefighters from Mexico arrive in Edmonton to help battle Alberta wildfires</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100403/firefighters-from-mexico-arrive-in-edmonton-to-help-battle-alberta-wildfires/</Link>
        <Description>Sixty-two firefighters arrived in Edmonton from from Jalisco, Mexico Wednesday evening. After being briefed on the situation, they will head up to help the 1,700 firefighers who have been working tirelessly for weeks to douse the blazes.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 10:38 pm
Updated: July 8, 2015 10:41 pm
Firefighters from Mexico arrive in Edmonton to help battle Alberta wildfires
By Caley Ramsay Web Producer Global News
Fire crews from Jalisco, Mexico arrived in Edmonton Wednesday, July 8, 2015 to help battle wildfires in northern Alberta.
Quinn Ohler, Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
EDMONTON  Dozens of firefighters have arrived in Edmonton from Mexico to help battle wildfires in northern Alberta.
Sixty-two firefighters arrived at Edmonton International Airport from from Jalisco, Mexico Wednesday evening. After being briefed on the current wildfire situation, they will head up to help the 1,700 firefighers who have been working tirelessly for weeks to douse the blazes.
The guys are good to go, said firefighter Hector Trejo. Our season just ended a couple weeks ago so were happy to help up here.
Winds could pose challenge as Sask. wildfire situation called dire
Most of the guys, this is their passionfight fires, get to know the forestand what better way to do it than come to another country and help others.
Fire crews from Jalisco have been helping battle fires in Alberta for the past 10 years; theyve been called in to assist several times.
Weve been working with them on training and a number of different things, said Geoffrey Driscoll, a wildfire information officer with Alberta Agriculture and Forestry. What we did was we have brought their training standards up to our own, so thats why we can have these firefighters here.
As of Wednesday evening, there were 92 wildfires burning in Alberta, 33 of which were listed as out of control.
The fire season in Alberta has been particularly busy. Well take the help that we can get, said Driscoll. Every little bit helps and were certainly happy that our partners in Jalisco were able to give us some firefighters.
But theyve got a big job ahead of them.
READ MORE: Troops ready to help battle northern Sask. wildfires
While conditions have improved over the past few days, on the weekend there were upwards of 120 wildfires burning in Alberta, Driscoll says cooler temperatures and rain would be welcomed by fire crews.
The situation is starting to look up; however, there is still a lot of work to be done, probably weeks or months, said Driscoll.
Trejo says his crews are ready for the challenge and eager to get to work.
Its exciting. The guys know theyre coming to fight fires, theyre anxious to do it and they like coming up here. Its a good feeling for them.
The wildfire season in Jalisco ended in late June.
For the latest wildfire status in Alberta, visit the Government of Albertas website .
Want your weather on the go? Download the Global News Skytracker weather app for iPhone, iPad or Android.
!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?http':https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, script, twitter-wjs);
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:27:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Flight 21 crash near 100 Mile House remains a mystery 50 years later</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100390/flight-21-crash-near-100-mile-house-remains-a-mystery-50-years-later/</Link>
        <Description>On July 8, 1965, an explosion occurred on board Canadian Pacific Air Lines Flight 21 from Vancouver to Prince George, sending wreckage down just west of 100 Mile House.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 10:27 pm
Flight 21 crash near 100 Mile House remains a mystery 50 years later
By Jon Azpiri Web Producer Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
One by one they read out the names of the 52 passengers and crew members who died50 years ago today in a plane crash near 100 Mile House that remains one of Canadas greatest aviation mysteries .
On July 8, 1965, an explosion occurred on board Canadian Pacific Air Lines Flight 21 from Vancouver to Prince George, sendingwreckage down just west of 100 Mile House.
Story continues below
The wreckage is still there, holding clues that suggest a bomb went off in the washroom. Who planted the bomb has never been determined. No one was ever charged but a coroners investigation identified four suspects, one of whom took out a $125,000 life insurance policy the day before the flight.
For years after the crash, family and friends could only mourn their loved ones by placing flowers and notes near the aircrafts debris field. On Wednesday, loved ones visiteda stone monument at 100 Mile House Airport that lists the names of every passenger on the doomed flight, even the one responsible for their demise.
We know whoever did it was on the plane so they died as well, said supporter Didi Henderson. God only knowswhat made someone do something like that.
To view more photos of the wreckage, click here
-with files from Ted Chernecki, Peter Meiszner and Julia Foy
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece asks for 3-year aid program as it races to submit reforms proposal</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100401/greece-asks-for-3-year-aid-program-as-it-races-to-submit-reforms-proposal/</Link>
        <Description>Greece has requested a new three-year rescue from its European partners Wednesday as signs grew its economy was sliding toward free-fall without an urgently needed bailout.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 10:24 pm
Updated: July 8, 2015 10:36 pm
Greece asks for 3-year aid program as it races to submit reforms proposal
By   Staff The Associated Press
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WATCH: Greeces prime minister made his final pitch to Europes financial giants, aiming to secure a new bailout deal after holding a referendum to vote against the last one. The country desperately needs a new financial lifeline, while Europe is once again at a crossroads. Stuart Greer reports.
Story continues below
ATHENS, Greece  With a deadline just hours away to come up with a detailed economic reform plan, Greece requested a new three-year rescue from its European partners Wednesday as signs grew its economy was sliding toward free-fall without an urgently needed bailout.
As its banking system teetered near the edge, the government extended bank closures into next week, while international creditors were in open disagreement over whether to award the country debt relief  with Germany at odds with the International Monetary Fund.
Without a deal, Greece faces an almost inevitable collapse of the banking system, which would be the first step for the country to fall out of the euro.
READ MORE: Greece gets until Sunday for proposals to stave off collapse
As Thursdays deadline loomed, the government sought to reassure its European creditors that it would enact tax and pension reforms quickly in exchange for loans from Europes bailout fund, the European Stability Mechanism.
In a formal request that was filled with vague promises but short on details, the Greek government pledged to immediately implement a set of measures as early as the beginning of next week  but did not specify what these were.
After months of fruitless negotiations with the Greek government, the skeptical eurozone creditor states have said they want to see a detailed, cost-accounted plan of the reforms by Thursday. That is meant to give enough time to review the plan before all 28 leaders of the full European Union meet on Sunday in what has been termed as Greeces last chance to stay in the euro.
But Greeces major creditors were hardly in lock-step over what path to take in dealing with the struggling but defiant EU member nation.
VIDEO GALLERY:
Whats next for Greece after they refused EU bailout?
IMF chief Christine Lagarde reiterated Wednesday that Greeces massive debt would need restructuring, something that Germany  Greeces largest European lender  has resisted.
Speaking in Washington, Lagarde said Greece needed to continue cost-cutting reforms, but added: The other leg is debt restructuring, which we believe is needed  for debt sustainability.
It well may be that the numbers may have to be revisited, but our analysis has not changed, she said of the need for granting Greece better repayment terms.
U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew added pressure on the European lenders, arguing debt relief was needed for a deal  and describing a Greek euro-exit as a geopolitical mistake.
I dont think any prime minister of Greece could sell all the additional fiscal measures, plus the structural reforms that are needed without some sense of what the debt sustainability looks like, he said in Washington.
READ MORE: Can Canadians send money to friends and family in Greece?
Earlier Wednesday, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said his country was seeking a deal that would bring a definitive end to his countrys financial crisis. Greece has had two bailouts from its European partners and the International Monetary Fund since May 2010, totalling 240 billion euros ($260 billion).
We need to ensure the medium-term funding of our country with a development and growth program, Tsipras told lawmakers at the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France.
Applause rose from left-wing lawmakers in the turbulent chamber when Tsipras said aid to Greece has only helped banks, not ordinary Greeks, as some held up No signs to back Greek voters rejection of more austerity.
Tsipras insisted he has no hidden agenda to drive Greece out of the euro and that last Sundays referendum in which Greeks roundly rejected more belt-tightening reforms does not mean a break with Europe.
The head of a conservative group in the parliament, Belgiums Guy Verhofstadt, said he was furious at Tsipras failure to spell out specifics of his reform plans.
READ MORE: Greek PM races to restart talks after vote win
Tsipras said Greeces troubles predated his arrival in office in January and condemned the austerity experiment his country has endured over the past five years that he blames for spiraling unemployment and poverty.
We demand an agreement with our neighbours, but one that gives us a sign that we are on a long-lasting basis exiting from the crisis  which will demonstrate to us that there is light at the end of the tunnel, he said.
Tsipras vowed to continue reforms, but warned of the austerity-weariness of the Greek public. This has exhausted the patience and resilience of the Greek people, he said.
In Greece, meanwhile, people already struggling with eight days of shuttered banks and limits on money withdrawals learned the finance ministry was extending the closures until next Monday. Greeks cannot take out more than 60 euros ($67) a day from ATMs and are unable to send money abroad, including to pay bills or to stock their businesses, without special permission.
The head of Frances central bank said he feared the collapse of the Greek economy and chaos if Greece doesnt strike a deal by Sunday.
In unusually strong language, Christian Noyer told Europe-1 radio he predicted riots in Greece if no deal is reached. He also indicated the European Central Bank would effectively pull the plug on its emergency liquidity measures for Greek banks if no deal is struck.
Highlighting the rising anger with Tsipras, European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker had a stark warning for Greece after Tuesdays eurozone summit.
We have a Grexit scenario, prepared in detail, he said, apparently referring to the situation in which Greece would be forced out of the currency union.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:10:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canada announces more than $10M in funding to combat child marriage</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100372/canada-announces-more-than-10m-in-funding-to-combat-child-marriage/</Link>
        <Description>The Canadian government made two major funding announcements Wednesday to help worldwide efforts to help fight maternal and child malnutrition and child, early and forced marriage.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 10:10 pm
Updated: July 8, 2015 10:14 pm
Canada announces more than $10M in funding to combat child marriage
By Andrew Russell Breaking News Reporter Global News
In this Wednesday, April 24, 2013 file photo, Somali mothers and their babies wait in line for the babies to receive a five-in-one vaccine against several potentially fatal childhood diseases, at the Medina Maternal Child Health center in Mogadishu, Somalia
(Ben Curtis/AP Photo)
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
TORONTO  The Canadian government made two major funding announcements Wednesday to help worldwide efforts to help fight maternal and child malnutrition and child, early and forced marriage.
Citizenship and Immigration Minister Chris Alexander announced the 11 Ontario-based NGOs and civil society groups that will share $180.3 million from 2015 to 2020 to carry out initiatives aimed at reducing maternal and child mortality in developing countries, while addressing issues like nutrition, sanitation and health worker training.
READ MORE: 5 made-in-Canada ideas helping women and babies around the world
Four NGOs based in British Columbia will share another $16.1 million in funding.
One of the NGOs receiving funding is World Vision, who received $41.5 million to lead a project aimed at improving nutrition in five countries: Kenya, Tanzania, Bangladesh, Pakistan and Myanmar.
The key challenge that we face is around malnutrition, said Elly Vandenberg, senior director with World Vision Canada. Its about trying to get kids and young mothers enough food and the right food.
The new funding follows the governments $3.5-billion pledge to focus foreign aid between 2010-2015 on maternal, newborn and child health, known as the Muskoka Initiative . The government has set aside $420 million for NGO-run programs.
The 11-Ontario based NGOs that received funding include:
Action Against Hunger
Amref Health Africa in Canada
Christian Childrens Fund of Canada
CUSO International with the Canadian Association of Midwives
effect: hope  The Leprosy Mission Canada
GRID &amp; NEA: Ghana Rural Integrated Development
Jane Goodall Institute of Canada
Plan International Canada
The Presbyterian Church in Canada
The Primates World Relief and Development Fund
World Vision Canada
The four B.C.-based NGOs are:
Global Aid Network
Tula Foundation
World Neighbours Canada
The announcement came on the same day as Foreign Affairs Minister Rob Nicholson said Canada will contribute more than $10 million to help fight child, early and forced marriage around the world.
READ MORE: Girls Not Brides: Ending child marriages
In a statement, Nicholson said Canada will invest more than $2.3 million to promote secondary schooling and skills development training for girls and women in Commonwealth countries through open learning and distance education.
Another $8 million will be devoted over a two year period to support local community groups and governments, as well as NGOs and civil society groups, to combat child and forced marriages. The funding will be dispersed through Canadian embassies and high commissions.
According to the federal government there is an estimated 375 million women living in Commonwealth countries today who were married as children.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:59:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Leslieville craft brewery and supporters fighting back against noise complaints</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2099899/leslieville-craft-brewery-and-supporters-fighting-back-against-noise-complaints/</Link>
        <Description>City Council has voted to withdraw the motion against The Left Field Brewery in Leslieville.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 9:59 pm
Updated: July 8, 2015 10:05 pm
Leslieville craft brewery and supporters fighting back against noise complaints
By Mark Carcasole Reporter Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WATCH ABOVE:The Left Field Brewery in Leslieville has come under fire by neighbours for excessive noise. The issue has made its way into the City Council agenda. Mark Carcasole reports.
TORONTO  An hour into its noon opening timethings are fairly quiet, relatively speaking, at the Left Field Brewery on Leslievilles Wagstaff Drive which is basically a laneway.
Story continues below
Staff are busy brewing their various craft beers, stocking the shelves in the shop, and pouring pints for customers stopping in their tap room to sample the goods.
As small of an operation as it is, some neighbours on Ivy Avenue  whose houses back on to the Wagstaff Driveare taking issue with the craft brewery and saying itsnoise levels are too high.
Amelie Waddells backyard falls almostdirectly in front of the brewerys main entrance. She says at its busiest usually Friday and Saturday afternoons and evenings  the sound of customers talking and laughing can inhibit her and her partners quiet enjoyment of their backyard.
Shes not trying to shut the place down, just looking for a compromise.
There will be a certain level of noise and we are completely fine with that. What were having issues with is when the noise becomes too loud, then how can we work together to find ways to reduce the noise?
Waddell says she has asked management to keep the garage door that leads into the brewery closed during busy hours to keep the sound in; but Left Field officials say that would trap too much heat from the brewing operation inside.
Not wanting to debate this publicly, owners Mark and Mandie Murphy directed Global News to a recent blog post on the brewerys website for comment .
The post insiststhey visited every home on Ivy Avenue before opening and even designed and printed No Parking signs for every home backing onto Wagstaff Drive.
Despite being allowed to keep it open until11:00 p.m., they stop serving in the tap room at 9:00 p.m. andhave signs warning clients to keep it down and keep the area clean.
They say they dont know what else they can do.
When complaints arose, the Murphys bought a noise meter and found that at its busiest peaks, The decibels registered lower than light mid-day traffic on Greenwood Avenue.
So far the brewery, concerned locals and Councillor Paula Fletcher have had just one meeting on the issue. The Murphys say that when they called for follow-up meetings to discuss their sound data they were given no reply.
Waddell says she feels those discussions have reached a stalemate becauseour issue is the noise and their issue is, Well we feel that were being reasonable.'
With the local Community Council not sitting again untilSeptember, Fletcher put the issue onto the full City Councils agenda for this week.Her motion calledon city staff to help mediate the situation before Left Fields license is up for renewal in February.
On Wednesday evening, City Council voted to withdraw the motion .
Council has voted to withdraw item MM8.20: Concerns Regarding Liquor Sales Licence  Left Field Brewery: http://t.co/pEQXJeJl6t #tocouncil
 Toronto City Clerk (@TorontoCouncil) July 8, 2015
Fletcher, seconded by Councillor Shelley Carroll, recommended council usestaff from Legal Services, Economic Development and Culture and Municipal Licensing and Standards to work with the brewery, the local councillor and concerned neighbours to come to a solution before their licence is due for renewal in Feb. 2016.
There are many new and exciting craft breweries opening across the City, including Left Field Brewery, Fletchers summary on the motion read.
This popular new brewery is a welcome addition to the east-end neighbourhood and has become a neighbourhood hot spot, as well as an east-end destination.
Fletcher wrote that she was happy to support the business in Dec. 2014 when they were offering free samples to visitors who tour the brewery when it first open, for example, but added that noise had become an increased issue.
It has become such a popular spot that increased noise has impacted the residential neighbours to the south, it read.
At a meeting with the neighbours and brewery owners to discuss these issues, it was suggested that the large garage door at the brewery be closed when patrons are in the facility in order to contain the noise. Unfortunately, this has not happened.
Fletcher wrote that with cooperation betweenall involved, a positive outcome can surely be reached before the February 2016 renewal deadline.
Its a positive outcome for the situation for now, as someIvy Avenue residents say that support for the brewery is strong.
A link to the owners blog post on its Facebook page has hundreds of supportive comments posted under it, while neighbours like Michael Rusnak and Kevin Pook tell Global News its a great addition to the neighbourhood.
Our cars have been broken into a few times, so having traffic in that alley, very positive traffic, has been nothing but good, says Pook.
Rusnak addsA Saturday afternoon noise complaint is ridiculous.
While some mayworry aboutthe bad publicity the story can bring the community, the brewery does admitthe added attention hasbrought by at least a few more customers to come check out their beers this week and they seem to be happy with the outcome.
Were happy to work together with neighbours to find solutions, a post on their Facebook page read.
Big thanks to all those who visited and who voiced their support.
With files from Adam Miller
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:47:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oakville woman gets refund on used car after Global News report</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100376/oakville-woman-gets-refund-on-used-car-after-global-news-report/</Link>
        <Description>An Oakville woman who agreed to buy a used vehicle from a Toronto dealership is getting her money back, a day after a Global News story about her case aired.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 9:47 pm
Updated: July 8, 2015 9:52 pm
Oakville woman gets refund on used car after Global News report
By Sean OShea Reporter Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WATCH ABOVE:An Oakville woman who says she was misled by a Toronto used car dealership is getting her money back. As Sean OShea reports, the company agreed to refund the money after her story aired.
TORONTO  An Oakville woman who agreed to buy a used vehicle from a Toronto dealership is getting her money back, a day after a Global News story about her case aired .
Story continues below
Mignonne Baddeliyanage says Curve Motors didnt disclose all of the information it should have when she agreed to buy a 2014 Porsche Cayenne for $68,000.
The dealership did tell her the vehicle had been in an accident and sustained about $30,000 in damages. It shared at least part of a CarProof vehicle history report that listed the vehicle as having frame damage and structural damage.
But she says Curve Motors did not tell her that the report showed the vehicle listed as a total loss which is insurance jargon for a vehicle that has been written off.
They did withhold that information that was very important to me to make an educated purchase, Baddeliyanagesaid.
It turns out the report was not entirely correct. The vehicle had not been written off, as the report stated, but had sustained extensive damage to both sides requiring repairs to door pillars, replacement of all four doors and other damage.
Still, the customer says she didnt receive the full report until after she signed a purchase agreement and put down a $1,000 deposit. She says had she seen the report, she never would have bought the vehicle.
READ MORE: Customers frustrated after car wash owner refuses to fix damage
Curve Motors refused to refund the deposit. The owner Amir Haji Hosseini told Global News the customer lied because she wanted to get out of the deal. However, he said she could get the refund if she agreed to apologize to the salesman.
Apologize for what? said Baddeliyanage, who said the dealerships representatives were rude and condescending after she raised concerns.
The salesman, who identified himself as Shane, repeated to Global News on camera that the dealership would give a refund in exchange for an apology.
She apologizes and she gets her money back, every penny, said the salesman.
Within hours of the Global News story airing, Baddeliyanage says she got a call from the dealerships manager promising to cancel the deal and return her money. On Wednesday, she went to Curve Motors and left with the full refund on her credit card.
Im so happy, I am so thankful I called you! said a beaming Baddeliyanage who earlier bought a new vehicle. She says she felt soured by the used car experience.
Hosseini told Global News he fired Shane, whom he described as his best salesman days earlier.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:32:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Premier Christy Clark likens B.C. wildfire fight to game of chess</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100347/christy-clark-likens-b-c-wildfire-fight-to-game-of-chess/</Link>
        <Description>Firefighters battling the flames in British Columbia's forests are playing a dangerous game with an opponent that doesn't play by the rules, said Premier Christy Clark.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 9:32 pm
Updated: July 8, 2015 10:33 pm
Premier Christy Clark likens B.C. wildfire fight to game of chess
By   Staff The Canadian Press
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
PEMBERTON, B.C.  Firefighters battling the flames in British Columbias forests are playing a dangerous game with an opponent that doesnt play by the rules, said Premier Christy Clark.
Story continues below
The premier was in Pemberton, B.C., on Wednesday, a small community east of the Elaho blaze . The fire, at 200 square kilometres, is one of the largest in the province and B.C.s Wildfire Service said it is burning uncontained because its generating too much smoke for aircraft to fight.
Fire information officer Kevin Skrepnek said about 190 wildfires are burning around the province, 31 of those started on Tuesday alone.
Clark told reporters the government will spend whats needed to fight the flames and call upon the necessary resources, even if that means going around the world.
You know I was saying to one of the guys, fighting fires, fighting these kinds of fires is like playing a chess game, she said.
Youve got to figure out the people that you need, the resources that you need, have them deployed in the right spot. The difference is, when you are playing a chess game with a forest fire, your opponent cheats. They dont play by the rules and thats the problem that these brave men and women are facing every day.
Clark also referred to the three-square-kilometre fire burning north of the Sunshine Coast community of Sechelt that claimed the life of a 60-year-old man on Sunday .
Logger John Phare was struck and killed by a falling tree.
WATCH: The topic of Clarks absence so far came up on Global News BC1s Unfiltered on Tuesday
We should all be really grateful for what they are doing, she said of the firefighters. They are blackened and dirty and sweaty and theyre very much in harms way every minute of the day and theyre doing that for all of us in the province.
Forty properties in B.C. remained on evacuation order Wednesday, including some cabins, and about 500 homes were on evacuation alert.
A fire east of Lake Kookanusa has been contained and all evacuation alerts issued by the Regional District of East Kootenay for areas around the wildfire have been lifted.
Forests Minister Steve Thomson said earlier in the week that 70 firefighters from Ontario were expected to arrive in B.C. , and the province will be getting help from Australian crews.
Skrepnek said a six-member firefighting crew who came with three aircraft from Ontario were being briefed before heading to Vancouver Island to drop fire retardant or water on blazes.
READ MORE: B.C. voters ask where is Christy Clark with hashtag #FindChristyClark
Over 1,000 of B.C.s firefighters have been deployed, along with more than 600 who are on contract.
The air quality in Whistler, B.C. , not far from the Elaho fire, is rated at 12 on a scale that normally doesnt surpass 10. A B.C. government advisory said the air quality in the area is a very high health risk, and people should avoid strenuous outdoor activities.
Metro Vancouver said an air quality advisory issued Sunday is continuing as wildfire smoke remains in the region and surrounding areas.
It said people with chronic conditions should avoid strenuous exercise and that infants, the elderly, those with diabetes and lung or heart disease should stay indoors in air conditioned spaces to reduce exposure to fine particulates.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:56:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Missing man featured on Global’s B.C. Crime Stoppers segment found alive and well</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100273/missing-man-featured-on-globals-b-c-crime-stoppers-segment-found-alive-and-well/</Link>
        <Description>A missing man featured on one of Global BC's Crime Stoppers segments has been found alive and well.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 8:56 pm
Updated: July 8, 2015 9:25 pm
Missing man featured on Globals B.C. Crime Stoppers segment found alive and well
By Yuliya Talmazan Web Producer Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
A missing man featured on one ofGlobals B.C. Crime Stopperssegments has been found alive and well.
Walter Simekwas last seen on March 7, 2013 at the Brookswood Plaza in Langley.
He was dropped off near the 7-11 by an Enterprise Rent-A-Car employee after returning a car rental.
He lived alone in a RV park in White Rock, but had just moved his belongings to an unknown location. However, his cell phone and bank accounts remain untouched.
Simek was born in the Czech Republic and moved to Canada in 1986.
B.C. Crimestoppers toldGlobal Newson Wednesday Simek was foundliving outside of the Lower Mainland.
He and his family have asked that their privacy be respected.
Simekhas now been removed from the Crime Stoppers website and related police databases.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:41:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calgary residents claim community mailbox left open for hours</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100281/calgary-residents-claim-community-mailbox-left-open-for-hours/</Link>
        <Description>Several residents from a southeast Calgary neighbourhood reported a Canada Post community mailbox was left open for hours, with their mail in full view, on Wednesday afternoon.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 8:41 pm
Calgary residents claim community mailbox left open for hours
By Erika Tucker Online Reporter Global News
Residents said the mailbox that was open for hours was on 30 Avenue S.E. between 26 Street and 29 Street S.E.
Viewer submission
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
CALGARY  Several residents from a southeast Calgary neighbourhood reported a Canada Post community mailbox was left open for hours, with their mail in full view, on Wednesday afternoon.
Brenda Miller said the mailbox had been open since around 1 p.m. She said after a call to the post office through a number listed on the box, as well as a call to police, a postal worker came and gathered the mail around 5 p.m.
My neighbour sat out there and just guarded itin 30 degree heat, Miller told Global News. We got the runaround several times. One of the fellason the phone said, Oh just walk away and leave it.
You could see peoples cheques! In good conscience, none of us wanted to do that.
READ MORE: Canada Post reveals next Calgary addresses to lose home delivery
Residents said the mailbox was on 30 Avenue S.E. between 26 Street and 29 Street S.E.
I called the non-emergency police number, and they did get a number for me and whatnot, but she went ahead and called it herself, said Miller. She said it would be a four-hour window before someone could come.
READ MORE: Canada Post changes 700 super mailbox locations after outrage
A Canada Post spokesperson said theres an automatic process in which contractors are dispatched to secure mail if a customer calls in such a complaint. Canada Post documents all calls, but couldnt immediately provide information on the reports in Millers neighbourhood.
The spokesperson said the incident was under investigation, and whenever theres a delay, theres usually a good reason for it.
This article will be updated with Canada Posts comments as they are provided.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:37:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saskatchewan wildfire evacuees trying to stay connected with family</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2100278/saskatchewan-wildfire-evacuees-trying-to-stay-connected-with-family/</Link>
        <Description>It’s the largest evacuation in Saskatchewan’s history and the wildfires have left many displaced residents separated from family and friends.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015 8:37 pm
Updated: July 8, 2015 9:45 pm
Saskatchewan wildfire evacuees trying to stay connected with family
By Thomas Piller Associate Technical Producer Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Watch above: Its the largest evacuation in the provinces history and the wildfires have left many displaced residents separated from family and friends. Joel Senick finds out how evacuees are reconnecting and whos helping to achieve that.
SASKATOON  Saskatchewan wildfire evacuee Michael Thackeray, from Montreal Lake, spends part of his day online. Hes checking back home and communicating with family, seeing and hoping to go home soon.
READ MORE: Troops ready to help battle northern Sask. wildfires
For many, getting in contract with loved ones means logging on.
Facebook is the only way to get ahold of family, wherever youre at, said evacuee Ben Sanderon, of Hall Lake.
Saskatoons public libraries could be making the connection easier. Their doors are open to evacuees who want to freely use computers at branches near shelters.
Theres an issue people are having, if we can step in and do our part to help, then were happy to do that, said Carol Cooley, CEO of Saskatoon Public Library.
An issue thats present across the province.
Red Cross officials say many of their shelters do not feature internet access at this time.
We are looking with a private provider to this option, so its hopefully something that we could set up where possible, said J.P. Taschereau, with Canadian Red Cross.
READ MORE: Northern economy feeling the effects of Saskatchewan wildfires
For Thackeray and others, the issue goes beyond a WiFi signal; he doesnt own a cell phone and doesnt want to be a hassle either.
People have their own phones and doing their own communicating with their own families  Try not to bother them, said Thackeray.
This makes social media websites all the more important to reach family members and bring peace of mind hundreds of miles from home. One less thing to worry about, in a situation that could produce many more.
Joel Senick contributed to this story
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
