<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Google">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:36:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gun Used in San Francisco Killing Was Stolen From Federal Agent - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHB_84C1ovP1eaVV3ISVqkbY9q65w&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896564375&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/09/us/gun-used-in-san-francisco-killing-was-stolen-from-federal-agent.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:42:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clinton Foundation hangs on to donations from Donald Trump - Politico</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHKPW6X3bMgQZxdhObHZvtjN4B2HA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896853968&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.politico.com/story/2015/07/clinton-foundation-keeps-donations-from-donald-trump-119883.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Share on Facebook Share on Twitter
The Clinton Foundation has no plans to return tens of thousands of dollars in donations it received from Donald Trump  or at least none that its willing to share.
Trump has been feeling the heat after saying that Mexico sends rapists and murderers to the United States. His fellow Republican contenders, with the notable exception of Sen. Ted Cruz, have denounced those remarks, as has Hillary Clinton, who said on Tuesday that she was very disappointed in Trumps comments.
Story Continued Below
A number of companies have severed ties with Trump: NBC dropped The Apprentice; Serta mattresses dumped him; NASCAR and the PGA distanced themselves; Macys stopped carrying his merchandise, including a cologne called Success.
But not, apparently, the Clinton Foundation, which still lists one Donald J. Trump on its website under the category of donors who have given between $100,000 and $250,000. The listing does not say when any donations were made.
Trump has since tarred the Clinton family as criminals, following a spate of stories accusing Bill and Hillary Clinton of trading political favors for donations.
If this was a Republican sitting right there, this would absolutely be considered illegal.  This is about jail time, he said on Fox News Fox &amp; Friends back in April.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:42:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Setting a Deadline for Greece Proves Much Easier Than Sealing a Fate - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG-ohSfJ7Oi75iSURdqbQZB-AW8Ow&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778894022955&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/09/world/europe/setting-a-deadline-for-greece-proves-much-easier-than-sealing-a-fate.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:12:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>SC Legislators Getting Death Threats Over Confederate Flag Debate - NBCNews.com</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH2cTGR2HKA9oBjDYVS9TsIktK_wQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778897977096&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.nbcnews.com/storyline/confederate-flag-furor/s-c-legislators-getting-death-threats-over-confederate-flag-debate-n389046</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jul 8 2015, 10:14 pm ET
S.C. Legislators Getting Death Threats Over Confederate Flag Debate
by M. Alex Johnson
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_shorttake_allen_150708" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
State investigators are looking into numerous death threats against South Carolina legislators as they debate whether to pull a Confederate battle flag down from the state capital grounds, authorities said Wednesday.
"Legislators on both sides of the issue have received communications that include death threats," Mark Keel, chief of the State Law Enforcement Division, said in a statement. "We recognize the First Amendment protections offered for free speech. That's not what this is about."
House members continued deliberating well into the night on a Senate bill that would remove the banner and the pole where it flies. Republican Gov. Nikki Haley called for the flag to be removed after the fatal shootings of nine people at Bethel African Methodist Episcopal Church last week in Charleston, including its pastor, state Sen. Clementa Pinckney.
Related: Tears, Family Memories Emerge During Confederate Flag Debate
Keel acknowledged that "there are strong emotions on all sides of this issue," but "to threaten the life or well-being of a lawmaker or their family is inexcusable."
Rep. Todd Rutherford, a Democrat representing Richland County, seat of the state capital, Columbia, told The Greenville News that he has received "unbelievable" mail.
"It's simply uncalled for in the legislative process, but it is also part and parcel about why the flag needs to come down," Rutherford told the newspaper. "We don't need any more divisive symbols that cause people to fight and issue threats."
M. Alex Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:49:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Medicare proposes paying doctors for end-of-life counseling - Kansas City Star</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEhn8rD5Y6KX_j_Lt9U_wEqVL6IVw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778895263123&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.kansascity.com/news/business/health-care/article26833729.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>July 8, 2015
Medicare proposes paying doctors for end-of-life counseling
Conversations among physicians, patients and loved ones is the standard of care, said Wayne J. Riley, president of the American College of Physicians, which represents internists. He said the group is pleased that Medicare has recognized what the medical community is doing to address the needs and requests made by patients and their loved ones. | Corbis
By PAM BELLUCK
Order Reprint of this Story
Medicare, the federal program that insures 55 million older and disabled Americans, announced plans Wednesday to reimburse doctors for conversations with patients about whether and how they would want to be kept alive if they became too sick to speak for themselves.
The proposal will be open for public comment for 60 days, but it is expected to be approved and to take effect in January. If adopted, it would settle a debate that raged before the passage of the Affordable Care Act, when Sarah Palin labeled a similar plan as tantamount to setting up death panels that could cut off care for the sick.
Medicares plan comes as many patients, families and health providers are pushing to give people greater say about how they die  whether that means trying every possible medical option to stay alive or discontinuing life support for those who do not want to be sustained by ventilators and feeding tubes.
We think that todays proposal supports individuals and families who wish to have the opportunity to discuss advance care planning with their physician and care team, said Patrick Conway, the chief medical officer for the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid, which administers Medicare. We think those discussions are an important part of patient- and family-centered care.
Conway said a final decision on the proposal will be made by Nov. 1. The proposal would allow qualified professionals like nurse practitioners and physician assistants, as well as doctors, to be reimbursed for face-to-face meetings with a patient and any relatives or caregivers the patient wants to include. Conway said the proposal did not limit the number of conversations reimbursed.
The reality is these conversations, their length can vary based on patients needs, he said. Sometimes, theyre short conversations  the person has thought about it. Sometimes, theyre a much longer conversation. Sometimes, theyre a series of conversations.
Major medical organizations endorsed Medicares proposal Wednesday, even as the National Right to Life Committee opposed it on the grounds that it could lead to patients being pressured to forgo treatment.
Conversations among physicians, patients and loved ones is the standard of care, said Wayne J. Riley, president of the American College of Physicians, which represents internists. He said the group is pleased that Medicare has recognized what the medical community is doing to address the needs and requests made by patients and their loved ones.
The college was among several medical groups pushing for Medicare to pay for the planning.
The reimbursement rate paid under the proposal and other details will be determined after public comments are received, Conway said. People covered by Medicare account for about 80 percent of deaths each year.
Because Medicare often sets the standard for private insurers as well, the new policy would prompt many more doctors to engage patients in such discussions about their preferences. Some private health insurance companies have recently begun covering such advance care planning conversations, and more are likely to do so once Medicare formally adopts its new rules.
Efforts to support end-of-life planning were derailed in 2009 during the debate over the Affordable Care Act. The next year, Medicare decided through its regulatory powers to allow coverage for voluntary advance care planning in annual wellness visits. But soon after, the Obama administration capitulated to political pressure and rescinded that part of the regulation.
As a big swath of the American population ages, and more people live longer with grave illnesses, a growing number of people want to be able to talk over options with their doctors  deciding, for example, whether they want to die at home or in the hospital, or under what circumstances they would want life-sustaining treatment.
Last September, a national nonpartisan panel of medical, legal and religious leaders issued a far-reaching report saying that the countrys system for dealing with end-of-life care was seriously flawed and should be thoroughly overhauled. Among its recommendations was that insurers reimburse health providers for advance care planning conversations.
Filling out advance directives can help, and some states have created central databases of these forms so that they are easier for a patients doctor or specialist to find in moments of crisis. But end-of-life experts, and the members of the national panel, said that simply checking boxes on a form was of limited value because many patients needed several conversations to consider their options and to talk them over with their families.
Its a huge step forward, said Diane Meier, a member of the national panel and the director of the Center to Advance Palliative Care. I think its great news that Medicare, the major payer for health care in the U.S., is now formally recognizing that advance care planning is worthy of its attention and reimbursement and that, in fact, is a way to restore power and control to patients.
But, she said, its not enough to pay for it. You have to make sure people know what theyre doing and are well trained.
Meier said that in the final policy, Medicare should identify and require documentation of specific components of end-of-life discussions. What you dont want to have is a check-box, she said. Yes, I had a conversation  Im billing for it should not be enough.
Burke Balch, the director of the National Right to Life Committees Powell Center for Medical Ethics, said his organization would oppose Medicares plan.
We feel there is pervasive bias against treatment that is occurring in advance care planning that involves nudging individuals to reject lifesaving medical treatment, he said. He said such pressure on patients was motivated in large part by a desire to cut health care costs.
Balch said his organization was trying to find a congressional sponsor for a bill that would direct Medicare to produce materials about end-of-life decisions that reflect a range of views, including those concerned with protecting peoples right to treatment.
In the rural upstate New York community of Dundee, Joseph Hinterberger, a family physician who has been conducting end-of-life discussions with his patients at no cost, took a different view. He praised several aspects of the plan and suggested also covering social workers and other trained providers.
I think what it will mostly do is decrease confusion at the end of life, he said. It will potentially decrease unnecessary use of resources because it will be very clear what the patient did and did not want. And it should also make it easier for physicians and other caregivers to make decisions because they can say, We all know what Mildreds wishes were. We shall not tread upon them.
Bloomberg News contributed to this report.
Related content
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:52:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Stock Market Bell Rings, Computers Fail, Wall Street Cringes - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGqSXp0qhlJgP9CiV_hdgm-qqbiBg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778897298841&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/09/business/dealbook/new-york-stock-exchange-suspends-trading.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:41:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore Fires Police Chief in Wake of Unrest and Crime Surge - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHLHjKR8Z5ZXh6sc5UCcHsei24iIQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896705857&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/09/us/baltimore-police-commissioner-is-fired-by-mayor.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:08:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bush: End Sanctuary Cities for Immigrants in US Illegally - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHqGaw0Y7iVFQbxDO6mwIxLUeXEyA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778898225888&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/2015/07/08/us/politics/ap-us-gop-2016-bush-sanctuary.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:44:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Super PAC backing Rubio raises more than $16M - USA TODAY</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFGlbxuT4yKqihLmTd0F5He8JMozw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778898066467&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://onpolitics.usatoday.com/2015/07/08/rubio-super-pac-fundraising/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>SEND
EMAIL
Sen. Marco Rubio, R-Fla. speaks at the International Association of Firefighters Legislative Conference and Presidential Forum in Washington on March 10, 2015. (Pablo Martinez Monsivais, AP)
A super PAC supporting Republican Marco Rubios White House bid raised more than $16 million since April and started July with $15.95 million in cash available to tap for the upcoming primary fight, officials announced Wednesday.
Weve definitely benefited from the strong response to Marco Rubios first few months on the campaign trail, allowing us to exceed all our goals for the first half of the year, Warren Tompkins, a top official with the Conservative Solutions PAC, said in a statement.
Tompkins described fundraising as setting up very well for the second half of the year, ensuring well have the resources we need to share Marcos conservative vision with voters.
Super PACs can raise unlimited amounts from individuals, corporations and unions but must avoid coordinating their advertising spending with their favored candidates. Details on who has contributed tothe super PAC wont be known until officials file reports later this month with the Federal Election Commission. Billionaire Florida car dealer Norman Braman has indicated that he intends to contribute heavily to advance the Florida senators campaign.
All of the major 2016 White House candidates are relying on an array of outside groups to boost their presidential ambitions .
Rubios campaign also is aided by a related nonprofit group, the Conservative Solutions Project, that plans to spend about $25 million ahead of the elections. This week, the group announced that it has raised more than $15.8 million since its inception last year. It already has spent more than $3 million on advertising highlighting Rubios opposition to nuclear deal the Obama administration is negotiating with Iran and five other nations.
Unlike the super PAC arm, the Conservative Solutions Project does not have to reveal its donors.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawmakers bash US Army plan to cut 57000 troops and civilians - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFCQJEvuMho3HQQGQTyMq7sSCGHOw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778897366843&amp;ei=7d-dVaDlPImsasTlgsAP&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/07/08/us-usa-army-cuts-idUSKCN0PI2TE20150708</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WASHINGTON | By David Alexander
A U.S. Army sapper uses a mine detector to check the road in advance of a dismounted patrol near Combat Outpost Terra Nova in the Arghandab Valley north of Kandahar April 8, 2011.
Reuters/Bob Strong
WASHINGTON The Obama administration was criticized by lawmakers on Wednesday over U.S. Army plans to cut nearly 60,000 soldiers and civilian personnel, warning the reductions were risky for U.S. forces at a time of conflict in the Middle East and rising tensions with Russia.
Senator John McCain, the Republican head of the Armed Services Committee, called the plan to cut 40,000 soldiers and 17,000 civilian personnel "another dangerous consequence of budget-driven strategy" pursued by President Barack Obama.
The cuts would reduce the active-duty Army from about 490,000 soldiers to about 450,000, its smallest number since before the United States entered World War Two. The Army was about 490,000 before the 2001 attacks and rose to about 570,000 in 2010 before reductions began.
Criticism arose as Army Secretary John McHugh began notifying members of Congress about military units that would be reduced and how states would be affected. On Tuesday, USA Today published some details of the reductions.
The hardest hit bases include Fort Benning, Georgia, and Joint Base Elmendorf-Richardson, Alaska. Army officials planned to convert a 4,000-member brigade combat team at each base into a 1,050-member battalion task force, a loss of nearly 3,000 soldiers apiece, according to an Army document seen by Reuters.
Senator Johnny Isakson, a Georgia Republican, said he learned from McHugh that the Army planned to cut 4,350 soldiers in Georgia including 950 at Fort Stewart and 3,400 at Fort Benning. He said the cuts would take place by the end of 2017.
"I am demanding answers from the Department of Defense on how they are justifying these troop cuts in Georgia," Isakson said in a statement. "We cannot afford to reduce our military readiness at a time when the threats to our security here at home and throughout the world are growing at an alarming rate."
Isakson denounced the Army over the Pentagon's "failure to give Congress a heads-up" before locations of the cuts were reported by the media. He said he would block a vote on Obama's nominee to be the Pentagon's new congressional liaison.
The personnel cuts come as the Pentagon is attempting to absorb nearly $1 trillion in reductions to planned defense spending over a decade.
The reduction to 450,000 soldiers was initially announced in February 2014 when then-Defense Secretary Chuck Hagel unveiled the Pentagon's 2015 budget. The figures were also included in the Quadrennial Defense Review, its four-year planning document.
(Reporting by David Alexander; Editing by Toni Reinhold )
Our top photos from the last 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
