<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:08:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama To Upgrade Malaysia On Human Rights Despite Mass Graves</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f57baf/sc/31/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cobama0Emalaysia0Etrade0In0I77585920Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON -- The Obama administration will remove Malaysia from its official list of the world's worst human trafficking offenders, </Description>
        <MainBody>Obama To Upgrade Malaysia On Human Rights Despite Mass Graves
Posted:
Updated:
6 minutes ago
A Malaysian Muslim man looks on inside a pit during the re-burial of remains believed to be those of ethnic Rohingya found at human-trafficking camps in the country's north, at Kampung Tualang some 16kms east of Alor Setar on June 22, 2015. Malaysian authorities on June 22 held a sombre mass funeral for 21 suspected ethnic Rohingya found in human-trafficking graves last month, with fellow Muslims praying for the unidentified victims to find a place in heaven. AFP PHOTO / MANAN VATSYAYANA         | MANAN VATSYAYANA via Getty Images
reddit
WASHINGTON -- The Obama administration will remove Malaysia from its official list of the world's worst human trafficking offenders, according to Reuters , a move human rights advocates fear will damage U.S. credibility.
The maneuver would allow the administration to continue negotiating a controversial trade agreement with Malaysia and 10 other Pacific nations. Legislation authored by Sen. Robert Menendez (D-N.J.) effectively bars the U.S. from enacting trade deals with countries deemed "Tier 3" violators of human trafficking standards -- the worst of the worst in the State Department's formal reckoning of governments that facilitate modern-day slavery.
Malaysia earned its spot on that list, alongside Iran and North Korea, from years of human trafficking, including rampant sex slavery and forced labor in the agriculture and the textile industries, according to 2014 State Department documents. Malaysia's electronics industry also is rife with forced labor . This year, mass graves for trafficking victims were discovered in Malaysia near its northern border with Thailand.
Reuters reports that Malaysia will soon be upgraded to a "Tier 2" country, allowing it to sidestep the ban imposed by the Menendez legislation. The State Department said it does not comment on its human trafficking list before it is formally issued. In a statement to HuffPost, Menendez said the maneuver would undermine the international legitimacy of America's human rights efforts.
"If true, this manipulation of Malaysias ranking in the State Departments 2015 TIP report would be a perversion of the trafficking list and undermine both the integrity of this important report as well as the very difficult task of confronting states about human trafficking," Menendez said in the statement. "The deplorable human trafficking crisis in Malaysia merits a global cry for action and justice -- not an attempt to sweep them under the rug for political expediency."
Malaysia passed a law in June amid international controversy over its human trafficking record that would provide additional protections for victims. Human trafficking has long been illegal in Malaysia, however. The country's critics -- including the State Department -- have not focused on its legal standards, but on its willingness to enforce those standards.
Human Rights Watch has persistently criticized Obama administration efforts to undermine the Menendez language.
Malaysia partially controls the Strait of Malacca , a key shipping lane for Middle Eastern oil bound for China. The Obama administration has repeatedly argued that its Trans-Pacific Partnership trade pact is designed to contain China's growing economic clout.
Also on HuffPost:


From left: House Minority Whip Steny Hoyer (D-Md.), Rep. Joseph Crowley (D-N.Y.), Senate Minority Whip Richard Durbin (D-Ill.), House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi (D-Calif.), Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid (D-Nev.) and Rep. Xavier Becerra (D-Calif.) prepare for a news conference at the U.S. Capitol on June 25, 2015. The Democratic leaders called on congressional Republicans to halt their "reckless inaction on the Export-Import Bank and the Highway and Transit Trust Fund."
U.S. Rep. Jeff Denham (R-Calif.), right, holds hands with Sen. Chris Coons (D-Del.), second from right, and Rep. Sheila Jackson Lee (D-Texas), as they stand with Sen. Chuck Grassley (R-Iowa), second from left, and Rep. Joe Wilson (R-S.C.), left, in front of the U.S. Capitol on June 18, 2015, during a moment of silence for the nine killed in a church shooting in Charleston, South Carolina.
From left: Sen. Cory Booker (D-N.J.), Rep. John Lewis (D-Ga.) and Sen. Joe Manchin (D-W.Va.) pray with other members of the U.S. Congress during a prayer circle on June 18, 2015, in front of the Capitol to honor those gunned down inside the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston, South Carolina.
President Barack Obama and House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi of Calif. leave meeting with House Democrats on Capitol Hill in Washington, Friday, June 12, 2015. The president made an 11th-hour appeal to dubious Democrats on Friday in a tense run-up to a House showdown on legislation to strengthen his hand in global trade talks. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
House Majority Leader Kevin McCarthy of Calif., left, walks with Rep. Darrell Issa, R-Calif., toward the House Chamber on Capitol Hill in Washington, Friday, June 12, 2015. Earlier, President Barack Obama made an 11th-hour appeal to dubious Democrats on Friday in a tense run-up to a House showdown on legislation to strengthen his hand in global trade talks. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
Senators arrive, from left, Sen. Thad Cochran, R-Miss., Sen Dianne Feinstein, D-Calif., Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell of Ky., Sen. Johnny Isakson, R-Ga., and Sen. Shelley Moore Capito, R-W.V., for a group photo for National Seersucker Day on Capitol Hill in Washington, Thursday, June 11, 2015. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)
Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell of Ky, center, rear, waves during group photo of Senators for National Seersucker Day, Thursday, June 11, 2015, on Capitol Hill in Washington. Back row, from left are, Sen. Johnny Isakson, R-Ga., Sen. Dianne Feinstein, D-Calif., McConnell, Sen. Amy Klobuchar, D-Minn., and Sen. Roger Wicker, R-Miss.. Front row, from left are, Sen. Bill Cassidy, R-La., , Sen. Susan Collins, R-Maine, Sen. Thad Cochran, R-Miss., and Sen. Shelley Moore Capito, R-W.Va.  (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)
Ukrainian Prime Minister Arseniy Yatsenyuk (second from left) speaks during a meeting on Capitol Hill on June 10, 2015. Yatsenyuk  met with Republican lawmakers while visiting Washington.
U.S. Capitol Police gather after a suspicious package was found forcing a partial evacuation of the Dirksen Senate Office Building and of a hearing of the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee on Capitol Hill on June 9, 2015.
Democratic presidential candidate and U.S. Sen. Bernie Sanders (I-Vt.) arrives at a news conference June 3, 2015, on Capitol Hill in Washington, D.C. Congressional Democrats held a news conference to oppose fast-tracking the Trans-Pacific Partnership.
Rep. Thomas Massie (R-Ky.), left, and Sen. Rand Paul (R-Ky.), center, exit the Senate floor after Paul spoke about surveillance legislation on Capitol Hill on May 31, 2015.
From left: U.S. Speaker of the House John Boehner (R-Ohio), Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.), Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid (D-Nev.), House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi (D-Calif.) and Sen. Joe Manchin (D-W.Va.) place their hands over their hearts during the playing of the national anthem during a presentation ceremony for the Congressional Gold Medal in recognition of the American Fighter Aces' service to the United States at the U.S. Capitol on May 20, 2015. Congress honored the service of the pilots with the highest civilian honor Congress can bestow.
President Barack Obama (from left), Attorney General Loretta Lynch and Department of Homeland Security Secretary Jeh Johnson attend the 34rd Annual National Peace Officers' Memorial Service on Capitol Hill on May 15, 2015.
Singer Elton John (right), founder of the Elton John AIDS Foundation, and Pastor Rick Warren (left) of the Saddleback Church, arrive to testify about global health programs during a Senate Appropriations Subcommittee hearing on Capitol Hill on May 6, 2015.
U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch (right) appears before the Senate Appropriations Committee hearing on Capitol Hill on May 7, 2015. The committee is hearing testimony on the Justice Department's budget request for fiscal year 2016.
U.S. Sen. Bernard Sanders (I-Vt.) leaves after a news conference to speak on his agenda for America on Capitol Hill on April 30, 2015, after announcing he would run for U.S. president.
Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe waves before he addresses a joint session of Congress at the U.S. Capitol in Washington, D.C., on April 29, 2015.
Sen. Robert Menendez (D-N.J.), second from left, smiles as he rides a Senate subway with a member of the press, left, after a vote April 23, 2015, to confirm Loretta Lynch as the next U.S. attorney general.
Members of the Minnesota delegation taste each other's entries during the Minnesota Congressional Delegation Hotdish Competition on Capitol Hill on April 22, 2015. Hotdish is a meal similar to a casserole.
House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi (D-Calif.) speaks while flanked by members of the Congressional Black Caucus during a news conference on Capitol Hill on April 22, 2015. Pelosi urged the Senate to immediately confirm Loretta Lynch's nomination as attorney general.
Henry Singleton of New York City holds up a sign as U.S. Rep. John Lewis (D-Ga.) speaks during a rally to mark the finish of March2Justice on April 21, 2015, on the West Lawn of the U.S. Capitol in Washington, D.C. Dozens of marchers took part in an eight-day, 250-mile march from Staten Island, New York, to the nation's capital to demand congressional intervention to tackle "the national crisis of police violence."
Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed al-Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, second from left, speaks with Sen. John McCain (R-Ariz.), second from right, as they pose for a photo alongside Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.), left, and Sen. Ben Cardin (D-Md.), right, prior to a meeting at the U.S. Capitol in Washington, D.C., on April 21, 2015.
Capitol Hill police officers and other officials lift a gyrocopter that landed on the U.S. Capitol's South Lawn, onto a trailer on April 15, 2015. A man identified as Doug Hughes, 61, illegally landed his aircraft on the Capitol lawn, triggering street closures around the building and prompting a police investigation. Hughes is described as a mailman, and a logo appearing to be that of the U.S. Postal Service was visible on the tail fin of the aircraft.
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry is trailed by staff and security while departing a meeting with members of the U.S Senate on the proposed deal with Iran at the U.S. Capitol on April 14, 2015. Kerry met with members of the House and Senate to discuss the ongoing Iran nuclear negotiations.
A large abstract painting of Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid of Nevada is visible on a wall next to a stuffed eagle in his office on Capitol Hill in Washington on March 27, 2015. Reid recently announced he will not seek re-election to another term.
Senate Armed Services Committee Chairman Sen. John McCain (R-Ariz.) applauds the final comments from fellow committee member, Sen. Lindsey Graham (R-S.C.), as they conclude a news conference on Capitol Hill in Washington on March 26, 2015, to discuss the situation in Yemen. Sen. Kelly Ayotte (R-N.H.) is at right.
Actor, filmmaker and founder of the Eastern Congo Initiative Ben Affleck testifies before a Senate Appropriations Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs hearing on "Diplomacy, Development, and National Security" on March 26, 2015. His wife, Jennifer Garner, looks on.
Bill Gates testifies during the Senate Appropriations Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations and Related Programs hearing on "Diplomacy, Development, and National Security" on March 26, 2015.
Golf legend Jack Nicklaus, left, and Speaker of the House John Boehner (R-Ohio) wipe away tears after listening to the remarks of Nicklaus' son Jack Nicklaus II during the elder Nicklaus' Congressional Gold Medal ceremony in the U.S. Capitol Rotunda on March 24, 2015. Nicklaus was lauded by family, friends and politicians for his many sports achievements and his philanthropy.
House Minority Whip Steny Hoyer (D-Md.) and House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi (D-Calif.) lead the way down the House steps for the House Democratic Caucus media event to mark the fifth anniversary of President Barack Obama signing into law the Affordable Care Act on March 24, 2015.
Conference aide SoRelle Wyckoff films a news conference in the Capitol after a meeting of the House Republican Conference using the live streaming app Meerkat on March 24, 2015.
Golf legend Jack Nicklaus, center, is presented the Congressional Gold Medal by, from left, House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi (D-Calif.), Speaker John Boehner (R-Ohio), Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid (D-Nev.) and Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.) in the Capitol Rotunda on March 24, 2015.
Joseph Clancy, director of the U.S. Secret Service, testifies during a Senate Appropriations Subcommittee hearing on Capitol Hill in on March 19, 2015.
Code Pink peace activists discuss a letter to Iran's leaders written by Sen. Tom Cotton (R-Ark.) outside his office in the Russell Senate Office Building on Capitol Hill on March 19, 2015. The group organized a "spring cleaning of Congress."
House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi (D-Calif.) right, prepares to take a picture in her Capitol office with Supreme Court Justices, from left, Elena Kagan, Ruth Bader Ginsburg and Sonia Sotomayor, before a reception on March 18, 2015. The justices were in the Capitol to be honored at Pelosi's annual Women's History Month reception in Statuary Hall.
From left: Rep. Peter King (R-N.Y.), Speaker of the House John Boehner (R-Ohio), President Barack Obama (D) and Irish Prime Minister Taoiseach Enda Kenny depart the annual Friends of Ireland luncheon on Capitol Hill on St. Patrick's Day 2015.
Dressed in colonial garb, Adam Eidinger and fellow D.C. marijuana advocates visit the office staff of Rep. Jason Chaffetz (R-Utah) at the Rayburn House Office Building on Capitol Hill on March 17, 2015, to protest the congressman's stand in regard to legalized marijuana in the District of Columbia. Legislative Director Amber Kirby Talley receives a pipe from Eidinger.
Shawna Blair, of the Senate Periodical Press Gallery, holds her dog George Clooney, a 4-month-old Goldendoodle, for Kate Hunter of Bloomberg News to pet in the Capitol's Senate Press Gallery on March 13, 2015.
Protesters from Code Pink hold up signs as Secretary of State John Kerry and Defense Secretary Ashton Carter arrive to testify before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on Capitol Hill on March 11, 2015.
Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas) speaks during the International Association of Fire Fighters Presidential Forum at the Hyatt Regency on Capitol Hill on March 10, 2015.
Sen. Elizabeth Warren (D-Mass.) speaks during the International Association of Fire Fighters Legislative Conference General Session at the Hyatt Regency on Capitol Hill on March 9, 2015.
Former astronaut Mark Kelly, husband of former congresswoman and handgun violence survivor Gabby Giffords, is joined by Reps. Mike Thompson (D-Calif.), Bob Dold (R-Ill.), Elizabeth Esty (D-Conn.) and Kathleen Rice (D-N.Y.) for a news conference about background checks for gun purchases in the Canon House Office Building on March 4, 2015.
Rep. Sean Duffy (R-Wis.), shoots a video selfie as he heads to the House floor for votes on March 4, 2015.
Former Congresswoman and handgun violence survivor Gabby Giffords (D-Ariz.) speaks during a news conference about background checks for gun purchases at the Canon House Office Building on Capitol Hill on March 4, 2015.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu waves as he steps to the lectern prior to speaking before a joint meeting of Congress on Capitol Hill in Washington on March 3, 2015. House Speaker John Boehner of Ohio, left, and Sen. Orrin Hatch (R-Utah) applaud.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu waves after speaking before a joint meeting of Congress on Capitol Hill in Washington on March 3, 2015.
House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi (D-Calif.) chuckles as she starts a news conference by donning dark glasses, a teasingly sympathetic gesture to Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid (D-Nev.) as he recovers from a serious injury to his right eye, suffered while exercising at his Nevada home during the holidays. (AP Photo/J. Scott Applewhite)
House Speaker John Boehner (R-Ohio) responds to reporters about the impasse over passing the Homeland Security budget because of Republican efforts to block President Barack Obama's executive actions on immigration on Feb. 26, 2015, during a news conference on Capitol Hill in Washington.
Code Pink protesters hold up a sign as Secretary of State John Kerry arrives on Capitol Hill in Washington on Feb. 25, 2015, to testify before a House Foreign Affairs Committee hearing.
U.S. Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid (D-Nev.) (left) speaks as  Sen. Charles Schumer (D-N.Y.) listens during a news briefing after the weekly Senate Democratic Policy Luncheon on Feb. 24, 2015. Reid was wearing glasses following a recent eye surgery.
The socks of former NASA astronaut Buzz Aldrin are shown as he testifies before the Senate Space, Science, and Competitiveness Subcommittee on Capitol Hill on Feb. 24, 2015.
Secretary of State John Kerry appears before the Senate Appropriations Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations and Related Programs on Feb. 24, 2015, to talk about fiscal year 2016 funding for the State Department.
A cardboard cutout of Las Vegas star Liberace stands outside the office of Rep. Dina Titus (D-Nev.) in the Cannon House Office Building on Feb. 18, 2015.
Rep. Keith Ellison (D-Minn.) attends a rally with labor groups, including the American Federation of Government Employees, in Upper Senate Park to support federal workers and the working class, on Feb. 10, 2015.
Sen. Charles Schumer (D-N.Y.) (3rd L) laughs as he talks to (L-R) Sen. Lindsey Graham (R-S.C.), Sen. Debbie Stabenow (D-Mich.), Sen. Sherrod Brown (D-Ohio) and Sen. Jeff Sessions (R-Ala.) before a news conference on currency and trade Feb. 10, 2015, on Capitol Hill.
Rep. Darrell Issa (R-Calif.) walks through the basement of the Capitol with a painting of former President Ronald Reagan by artist Steve Penley on Feb. 11, 2015. The painting will be added to Issa's collection of Reagan memorabilia.
Speaker of the House John Boehner (R-Ohio) holds his weekly press conference in the Capitol on Feb. 5, 2015.
Sen. Tim Scott (R-S.C.) gives a group hug to students from the Richard Wright Public Charter School in Washington, D.C., during his National School Choice Forum in the Hart Senate Office Building on Feb. 9, 2015.
Patriarch Filaret, head of the Ukrainian Orthodox Church of the Kyivan Patriarchate, speaks during a press conference on Capitol Hill in Washington, D.C., on Feb. 5, 2015. Delegates from the Ukrainian Parliament joined members of the House of Representatives to appeal for lethal military aid from the U.S.
Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid (D-Nev.) speaks to the media as Sen. Chuck Schumer (D-N.Y.) listens, following the Senate Democrats' policy lunch on Feb. 3, 2015.
The protest group CodePink disrupts a Senate Armed Services Committee hearing, carrying banners calling former Secretary of State Henry Kissinger a "war criminal" as he and fellow former Secretary of States George Shultz and Madeleine Albright were set to testify on U.S. national security on Capitol Hill on Jan. 29, 2015.
Naomi Sherman, 4, right, along with her father, Rep. Brad Sherman (D-Calif.); mother, Lisa; and sisters, Lucy, 2, and Molly, 5, prepares to board a bus that will take House Democrats and their families to a retreat in Philadelphia on Jan. 28, 2015.
Sen. Dan Sullivan (R-Alaska), left, and Rep. Don Young (R-Alaska) talk before a news conference in the Capitol's Senate studio to "respond to the Obama administration's efforts to lock up millions of acres of the nation's richest oil and natural gas prospects on the Arctic coastal plain and move to block development of Alaska's offshore resources" on Jan. 26, 2015.
U.S. Sen. Chuck Grassley (R-Iowa), left, reacts as Sen. Patrick Leahy (D-Vt.) brings out a giant gavel while making remarks during an executive business meeting of the Senate Judiciary Committee on Jan. 22, 2015. Leahy ceremonially passed the gavel to Grassley who has taken up the chairmanship after the Republicans won the majority in the Senate.
Sen. Elizabeth Warren (D-Mass.) speaks with Rep. Sheila Jackson Lee (D-Texas) as senators arrive for President Barack Obama's State of the Union address in the Capitol on Jan. 20, 2015.
Rep. Linda Sanchez (D-Calif.) takes a selfie with Rep. Zoe Lofgren (D-Calif.) as Rep. John Shimkus (R-Ill.) sits nearby before President Barack Obama's State of the Union address on Jan. 20, 2015.
President Barack Obama, bottom right, is greeted by Rep. Terri Sewell (D-Ala.), center, as he arrives to deliver the State of the Union address to a joint session of Congress on Jan. 20, 2015.
Sen. Bernie Sanders (I-Vt.) holds a news conference on the budget on Jan. 16, 2015.
Sen. Bill Cassidy (R-La.) and his wife, Laura, have their luggage inspected by a police dog before boarding a bus that will take Republican senators to a retreat in Hershey, Pa., January 14, 2015.
Rep. Erik Paulsen (R-Minn.) walks by immigration protesters on his way to one of the buses outside the Rayburn House Office Building as House Republicans prepare to head to Hershey, Pa., for their retreat with Senate Republicans on Jan. 14, 2015.
Sen. John McCain (R-Ariz.) fools around with colleagues upon arriving for a news conference on Guantanamo detainees in the Senate studio on Jan. 13, 2015.
Rep. Luis Gutierrez (D-Ill.) speaks during a press conference on Capitol Hill on Jan. 13, 2015. House Democrats spoke about U.S. President Barack Obama's executive actions on immigration.
From left, Sens. Sherrod Brown (D-Ohio), Jeff Merkley (D-Ore.), Ron Wyden (D-Ore.) and Rob Portman (R-Ohio) make symbols that spell "Ohio" on Jan. 13, 2015, as the result of a football bet. Ohio State beat the University of Oregon 42-20 in the NCAA national football championship.
Sen. Richard Burr (R-N.C.) sanitizes his hands while talking on his cell phone outside the Mansfield Room in the Capitol on Jan. 8, 2015.
Rep. Frederica Wilson (D-Fla.) walks with her family through the Will Rogers Hallway after the swearing-in of the 114th Congress on the House floor on Jan. 6, 2015.
Rep. Henry Cuellar (D-Texas) holds Andrea Elena Castro, daughter of Joaquin Castro (D-Texas), second from right, before the 114th Congress was sworn in on the House floor of the Capitol on Jan. 6, 2015.
Speaker of the House John Boehner (R-Ohio) leaves a church service on Capitol Hill on Jan. 6, 2015, the first day of the 114th Congress.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:10:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Air Force Head Considers Russia 'Biggest Threat' To U.S. National Security</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f584c0/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Crussia0Eus0Enational0Esecurity0In0I77585840Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON, July 8 (Reuters) - Russia is the biggest threat to U.S. national security and America must boost its military presence throughout Europe even as NATO allies face budget challenges and scale back spending, U.S. Air Force Secretary Deborah James said on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Air Force Head Considers Russia 'Biggest Threat' To U.S. National Security
Reuters
Updated:
47 minutes ago
US President Barack Obama walks to a group photo session with Russian President Vladimir Putin (L) at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit at Yanqi Lake, north of Beijing on November 11, 2014. Top leaders and ministers of the 21-member APEC grouping are meeting in Beijing from November 7 to 11. AFP PHOTO/Greg BAKER        (Photo credit should read GREG BAKER/AFP/Getty Images) | GREG BAKER via Getty Images
reddit
WASHINGTON, July 8 (Reuters) - Russia is the biggest threat to U.S. national security and America must boost its military presence throughout Europe even as NATO allies face budget challenges and scale back spending, U.S. Air Force Secretary Deborah James said on Wednesday.
"I do consider Russia to be the biggest threat," James told Reuters in an interview after a series of visits and meetings with U.S. allies across Europe, including Poland.
James said Washington was responding to Russia's recent "worrisome" actions by boosting its presence across Europe, and would continue rotational assignments of F-16 fighter squadrons.
"This is no time to in any way signal a lack of resolve in the face of these Russian actions," she said.
James said she was disappointed that only four of NATO's 28 members had thus far met the NATO target of spending 2 percent of gross domestic product on defense.
"This is not something that came up out of thin air. This is something that we as NATO members agreed to do. All of us need to be advocates," she said.
The top Air Force civilian leader acknowledged that Europe was facing difficult immigration and economic challenges at the moment, but said the NATO military alliance and associated commitments should be a clear priority.
Britain on Wednesday said it would commit to the 2 percent spending pledge for the next five years, which will raise the number of NATO allies meeting the spending goal to five in 2015.
Given the tensions, the Air Force is continuing its effort to reduce U.S. reliance on Russian RD-180 rocket engines for military and intelligence satellite launches, James said.
She said there were huge demands on U.S. Air Force assets now, given the tensions with Russia and the fight against Islamic State, but the Air Force was also working hard to defend its weapons systems and networks against growing cyber attacks.
James said her records were among those involved in a massive breach of personnel records held by the Office of Personnel Management that some U.S. officials have blamed on China. China denies any involvement in hacking U.S. databases.
James said the Air Force took a hard look at its cyber security immediately after the revelations and decided to redouble its efforts, although no new actions were needed.
She said the service was cataloging weapons and IT systems to detect any possible vulnerabilities, while also working to set up 39 cyber security teams around the country.   (Reporting by Andrea Shalal; Editing by Leslie Adler)
Also on HuffPost:
Ukrainian Troops Move Against Separatists
of


Residents gather to speak to Ukrainian soldiers at a checkpoint which they seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Ukrainian soldiers communicate with a local resident at a checkpoint they seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
A resident holding a religious icon stands next to Ukrainian soldiers at a checkpoint in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
A Ukrainian military helicopter lands at a checkpoint which troops seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Ukrainian soldiers stand guard at a checkpoint they seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Ukrainian soldiers take position at a checkpoint they seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Ukrainian soldiers wait on the road as pro-Russia separatists block the Kramators to Slavyansk road to prevent them from advancing on May 2, 2014. (GENYA SAVILOV/AFP/Getty Images)
A masked Ukrainian soldier takes position at a checkpoint which troops seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
A resident offers flowers to Ukrainian soldiers at a checkpoint they seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Ukrainian soldiers take position at a checkpoint they seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
An Ukrainian soldier speaks with pro-Russia separatists blocking the Kramators to Slavyansk road to prevent the Ukrainian national guard troops from advancing on May 2, 2014. (GENYA SAVILOV/AFP/Getty Images)
A Ukrainian soldier stands guard near a checkpoint which troops seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, on May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Pro-Russia separatists shelter from the rain as they block the Kramators to Slavyansk road on May 2, 2014. (GENYA SAVILOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Ukrainian soldiers wait on the road as pro-Russia separatists block the Kramators to Slavyansk road to prevent them from advancing on May 2, 2014. (GENYA SAVILOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Ukrainian soldiers wait on the road as pro-Russia separatists block the Kramators to Slavyansk road to prevent them from advancing on May 2, 2014. (GENYA SAVILOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Pro-Russia separatists block the Kramators to Slavyansk road on May 2, 2014. (GENYA SAVILOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Religious icons are placed on bricks as residents gather near a checkpoint which Ukrainian troops seized in the early morning in the village of Andreevka, May 2, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Ukrainian National Guard troops wait as pro-Russia supporters block the Kramators-Slavyansk road on May 2, 2014. (GENYA SAVILOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Pro-Russia supporters block the Kramators-Slavyansk road to prevent Ukrainian National Guard troops from avancing on May 2, 2014. (GENYA SAVILOV/AFP/Getty Images)
Pro-Russian militants hit leaving  policemen as a crowd of some 300 of them stormed the prosecutor's office in eastern Ukrainian city of Donetsk on May 1, 2014. (Alexander KHUDOTEPLY/AFP/Getty Images)
Police officers take cover under their shields as pro-Russian activists storm the prosecutors office on May 1, 2014 in Donetsk, Ukraine. (Scott Olson/Getty Images)
Ukrainian soldiers stand near a tank at a checkpoint near the south eastern Ukrainain city of Slavyansk on May 1, 2014. (VASILY MAXIMOV/AFP/Getty Images)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:50:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What Greece's 'No' Vote Reveals About The Rest Of Europe's Youth</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f536ed/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cgreece0Eno0Eeurope0Eyouth0In0I77575840Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>What Greece's 'No' Vote Reveals About The Rest Of Europe's Youth
Posted:
Updated:
2 hours ago
A banner hangs from the White Tower, a prominent landmark in the northern Greek city  of Thessaloniki on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The banner, put up by the youth wing of the governing radical left Syriza party, reads, in Greek: "Peoples of Europe, rise! Rupture with austerity. No to fear." There is also the phrase "No to austerity," in English, French and German. Greece's fraught bailout talks with its creditors took a dramatic turn early Saturday, with the radical left government announcing a r | ASSOCIATED PRESS
reddit
Theyre the ones who said "no" the loudest. Young Greeks rose together to reject the proposals of Athens creditors during Sunday's referendum. According to polling data , more than 85 percent of youths checked oxi on their ballots. This is 20 points higher than the total final tally, and more than 40 points higher than the elderly vote.
Young voters, more than any other part of the Greek population, definitively affirmed they do not want the policy of austerity to continue in their country. The most obvious consequence is the overwhelming unemployment affecting their age group. By the end of 2014, 52.4 percent of younger voters were unemployed in Greece, a figure surpassed only by Spain (53.2 percent).
Myrto, a 28-year-old living in Greece, explained to HuffPost France in January how she had to move in with her parents when faced with the loss of her job.
For Laura Slimani, the president of the Young French Socialists and the head of the European Young Socialists movement, the resounding No vote by young Greeks on Sunday is very revealing.
If the only possibility offered to our generation is to become a sacrificed generation with an enormous unemployment rate, the risk of seeing young Europeans turn away violently and decisively from the European project is very great. With this vote, theyre showing a rejection of Europe, as it exists today, Slimani warned in an interview with HuffPost France, insisting that for so many, Europe only means more disasters, higher unemployment and a lower quality of life.
Laura Slimani, president of the Young French Socialists and the head of the European Young Socialists movement.
As seen from France, the results from the Greek referendum are not surprising. Is the sentiment the same elsewhere in Europe? We asked our colleagues from other European publications. Their responses might surprise you.
Within France, those 18 to 24 have a history of showing their distrust in regard to the European construction. The latest example: Their political abstention during the Spring 2014 European elections. While the participation rate reached 42 percent for the whole population, it was only 26 percent for voters ages 18 to 24, according to the French Institute of Public Opinion . Turnout for those 35 and older was reported at 47 percent.
Their view isnt darker, its more lucid," noted Slimani. "This is why a total of 70 percent didnt vote in the European elections. They think their vote wont change much, given the many privileges accorded to institutions they deem illegitimate. Its the same with domestic politics."
For Jean-Paul Hagon, a researcher at IRIS and the author of a memorandum on European disillusion, the "Euroskepticism" of European youth has grown enormously over the last 10 years .
In France, 61 percent believed Europe was a source of hope in 2003, versus 31 percent 10 years later. There are twice as many Euroskeptic youths as there are people ages 65 and older, Hagon wrote weeks before the latest European vote.
This feeling is shared on the other side of the Alps. Young people in Italy are proof of a growing skepticism towards European institutions, a growing mistrust against the Euro, but also against other countries in the Union, notes the Toniolo Institute . Fifty-eight percent of young people interviewed for a major survey affirmed that the European Union is fundamentally a failure, and only 32 percent maintain a good image of the shared currency.
In Spain, the exact opposite is occurring. Of course the crisis caused a decline in the interest and confidence of the younger generation towards European institutions, but they remain the most optimistic and convinced of the advantages from belonging to the European Union, said sociologist Jos Pablo Ferrandis of the polling institute Metroscopia. For the 30th anniversary of Spains membership to the EU, Metroscopia conducted a survey that found that 73 percent of those ages 18 to 30  believe participating in the EU has been beneficial. Meanwhile, 70 percent of 35- to 54-year-olds agreed, while only 68 percent of  those over 55 agreed.
The fact remains that when young Europeans are asked if things are going in the right direction, fewer than one-third of them respond yes.
Were a generation that hasnt experienced the great conflicts of the European interior: neither the Second World War, nor the Cold War," Slimani said. "So for us, a united Europe is a fact; its taken for granted by my generation. The project for peace, even if important, is not enough. Its like the Erasmus exchange programs. Weve reached a point where we can no longer expect Europe to draw its legitimacy from a number of programs. It must do so from its democratic character."
Before eventual advancements in the economic sphere, Slimani wants to believe we can at least learn something from this vote. What Tsipras has succeeded in for the moment has been showing that a political desire can pay off. Whats essential, then, is a political desire to come up with a different project.
This article originally appeared on HuffPost France and was translated into English.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:12:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man Punches, Shoots Cougar Who Tried To Eat His Adorable Dog</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f4efdc/sc/14/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Ccougar0Eattacks0Edog0In0I77572440Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Never get between a Canadian and his mini dachshund. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Never get between a Canadian and his mini dachshund.
Shawn Hanson, a British Columbia resident, posted the following heroic story on a Facebook group dedicated to sightings of dangerous animals.
Hanson was filleting a fish on Salmon Beach in Ucluelet, British Columbia, July 2. His 10-pound mini dachshund, Bailey, was at his side. Suddenly, he wrote, "A f***ing cougar jumps out of the bushes and grabs the puppy."
"I hear a yelp, and see it dragging the puppy off into the bushes. Without thinking I chase in after it, catching up as it stops to see what is following. I grab Bailey (puppy) with one hand, punch the cougar in the face with the other, and it releases its grip on her neck," he wrote.
He handed off Bailey to his wife, grabbed his 12-gauge shotgun and headed back into the bushes. The cougar made aggressive moves towards him and didn't flee when he fired a warning shot.
"I put a round right at its head, and it spun around still moving. I pumped 2 more at the body," Hanson wrote. Here's a photo of him with the dead cougar.
Hanson told The Huffington Post he "absolutely" felt bad about killing the cougar. "It's sad, because the cats are beautiful," he said.
Ultimately, though, he believes the shooting was justified. The undernourished animal was desperate for food, which made it dangerous. It came after Hanson and had reportedly grabbed another dog earlier in the week.
Hanson called the police and conservation officers, who concluded he wasn't at fault.
Conservation officers had been tracking the emaciated animal, the Canadian Ministry of Environment told Good Morning America , adding that the case was closed.
Hanson says his love for his "amazing" pooch motivated him. "She's one of the family, and that's why I reacted the way I did," he said.
While Bailey is still stiff and sore from the attack, the dog's puncture wounds are healing up well, Hanson said. Meanwhile, he's embracing his new nickname: "Cougar Puncher."
Also on The Huffington Post
Close
Cougar Enters Home Through Doggie Door
of
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:58:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Malnutrition Rates Are Up Worldwide. Here's Why.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f4eb8e/sc/26/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cmalnutrition0Erates0Eup0Eworldwide0In0I77580A0A40Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Malnutrition Rates Are Up Worldwide. Here's Why.
Leigh Weingus Healthy Living Writer at The Huffington Post
Posted: 07/08/2015 | Edited: 3 hours ago
Seventy percent of the world's population is expected to live in a city by 2050, according to a University Of Minnesota study. But with urbanization comes the spread of the Western diet -- and that's not a good thing.
Developing countries have generally relied on vegetables, fruits and legumes as their main food sources . But as these countries gain more access to more calorie-rich foods like red meat, salt, sugar and processed foods,malnourishment is paradoxically on the rise.
"People around the world, as incomes go up, choose more calories and meat in their diet," study author David Tilman said, according to CNN . "We have a whole new group of people who are malnourished because they eat foods that are no good for them, that have no nutritional benefit."
So, what does malnourishment mean? According to the United Nations World Food Programme , a malnourished person "finds that their body has difficulty doing normal things such as growing and resisting disease" and "physical work becomes problematic and even learning abilities can be diminished." Yikes.
Another study out of Tufts University looked at unhealthy food consumption in middle and low income countries and found that it increased dramatically between 1990 and 2010.
"Most global nutrition efforts have focused on calories -- getting starchy staples to people," study author DariushMozaffarian told the Thomson Reuters Foundation . "We need to focus on the quality of calories for poor countries, not just the quantity."
One thing's for sure: The Western diet, the world over, needs a huge revamp.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:36:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A Novel Solution for the Greek Debt Crisis: Join Turkey</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f4a223/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Ctom0Eginsburg0Ca0Enovel0Esolution0Efor0Ethe0E0Ib0I7750A4740Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Should they stay or should they go? Last weekend, Greeks voted in a </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Should they stay or should they go?  Last weekend, Greeks voted in a hastily-organized referendum that gave the proverbial finger to the country's creditors.  With insurmountable debts, Greece's populist government is threatening to leave the Euro, something for which there is no precedent and no mechanism.  On the European side, creditors insist on painful economic cuts. No one is quite sure what will happen next, and the only thing everyone agrees on is that a Greek departure from the Euro would be ugly and painful.
What are Greece's options?  There do not seem to be many. With policymakers at an impasse, its time to think outside the box.  Here's a radical idea for Greece: join Turkey.
The two countries have more than a little history together, of course. Let's not forget that the Iliad and Odyssey take place in Troy, located in "Asia Minor". Istanbul itself was a Greek colony in ancient times.  More recently, Greece obtained its independence from the Ottoman Empire only in 1821, and the two countries have fought at least four wars since then.  While it is safe to say the two peoples don't care much for each other, perhaps being forced to live in the same country would help them let bygones be bygones.
The idea is less fantastic than one might think. Greece could leave the Euro and start to use the Turkish Lira, which has been a relatively stable currency that has adjusted with changing economic conditions. Politically, the two countries could start with a loose federation, in which monetary and fiscal policy was made in Ankara but local decisions on social policy continue to be made from Athens.
The Turkish economy has been one of the world's darlings in the past few years. At roughly 40% of GDP, Turkish debt is quite manageable. Even if it were to absorb the entire debt of Greece in one fell swoop, it would still have a debt ratio below that of the United Kingdom and France.   Furthermore, Turkey's economy is already deeply linked with the EU.  Turkey is already a part of the EU customs union, the European Convention of Human Rights, and many other regional agreements.  Regulatory and human rights standards would remain more or less the same, and Greeks could continue to live their lives as before.
Turkey's population of 75 million could absorb the 11 million Greeks fairly easily (so long as they don't move across the Aegean.)  And while the absorption of Greece might fuel the empire-building fantasies of Tayyip Erdogan in the short term, he would soon find that the addition of 11 million angry Christians changed the calculus.  Turkey absorbing Greece might actually change Turkish electoral politics for the better, if Erdogan's domestic opponents make common cause with the new voters.
A union of Greece and Turkey would bring some additional bonuses. The long-standing territorial dispute in Cypru s, which has proved singularly unamenable to international solutions, might fade away.  And the move could end the long-standing disputes over which country invented baklava and dolma .
Have no fear, Greece! The glorious past offers a way out of the current impasse.
Follow Tom Ginsburg on Twitter: www.twitter.com/TomGinsburg
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:00:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hungry for Heroes and Still Starving</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f4346a/sc/25/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cdiane0Emantouvalos0E0Chungry0Efor0Eheroes0Eand0Estill0Estarving0Ib0I77575220Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
Somewhere nestled in a trunk with my baby book and purple satin Boston Latin jacket is a heirloom box filled with Greek drachma. Like most sentimental objects, these notes and coins are only valuable to me, but that may be about to change.
More than 48 hours have passed since the Greek people delivered their resounding 'No' vote in Greece's referendum. Desperate for heroes, the Greeks were seduced by Prime Minister Tsipras's shameless "Oxi" rallying cry (Google: OXI Day for context). Still, no deal is on the table as he had promised. Banks remain shuttered. Shortages grow by the hour. And ATMs are drying up faster than a bikini on Mykonos. Yet people dance.
So why is their collective OPA! my OMG?
For me, as a Greek immigrant's daughter, it's right back to the '70s. Traveling to Greece as a child left me with a ferry full of culturally-awkward memories that stay with me today. In the first grade, when my classmates returned from summer vacation boasting of hugging Mickey, I was saddled with tales of a sweaty dude in an unbuttoned shirt and smashed dinnerware. Nia Vardalos has got nothing on me.
Arriving at dusty, old Ellinikon Airport, we were greeted by not one or two relatives, but twelve. Can you imagine? We came bearing suitcases filled with tube socks, cigarettes, and toiletries. But I remember it was the contents of the manila envelopes padding my dad's jacket that mattered: American dollars. The Greeks went nuts for those.
Today, in a world where wealth is largely digitized, good old-fashioned cash is once again king -- or Zeus, if you like -- in Greece. Money is power. Money is safety. Here in America, some say money is greed. For the Greek people, money is pride.
There is no dignity in watching Greek pensioners, some near the end of their lives, toeing the line for another inept Greek government. Queuing, in some cases for hours, under a hot Greek sun, they have been robbed, but not of money. Is this the stuff of heroes? For all the heroic chatter swirling around Mr. Tsipras, surely it didn't need to come to this.
Greece needs heroes, but more than that, she needs investors.
I shall leave debt restructuring and the Eurozone's culpability for the experts to dissect. Less obvious -- but just as complicit in this epic bailout saga -- are the deeply embedded ideas about the role of the state in the lives of the Greek people.
As one of the most inefficiently run countries in the civilized world, Greece must not only adopt painful reforms but shock its political and economic system toward a path of growth and innovation. Strikes and snap elections have long dominated a reflexive, distrusting populace on the brink. Corruption is tacitly accepted, because it works. And if you've ever had to navigate a civil matter in Athens, pack your patience. Stamping documents is not only an art form in Greece; it helps justify another useless government job. Greece needs a CEO, not another party-peddling ideologue. And if that doesn't work, there's always the Michael Bay approach: blow the whole thing up! (Figuratively, of course.)
Tsipras slayed the Minotaur (in Merkel) -- but can he lead Greeks out of the labyrinth?
Maybe Prime Minister Tsipras had a master plan beyond Sunday's so-called 'Greferendum.' If so, he'll join the ranks of Achilles among the Greek legends. But with each passing hour, it's seems doubtful. Instead of continuing on a rehabilitative road -- albeit slow and unsexy -- to real economic recovery, Tsipras has rendered Greece gasping for air and on life support. Now, in addition to Greece's credibility and the welfare of its citizenry, everything is at risk: partnerships with global industry, small business survival, and start-up creation -- as investors and CEOs increasingly compare Athens to Caracas.
Let's face it, the Grexit drama -- replete with its international cast of acronyms -- has become a cottage industry, particularly for the media. The endless headlines, metaphors, countdowns and ironies are simply too addictive for the world to ignore. But after the live reports from Syntagma Square end, it is the Greek people who must make their country work.
No one can predict what the future holds, let alone the next five days. Echoing Socrates' humility, there is only one thing I can say with absolute certainty: the daily pain of Greeks is palpable, and it won't leave on the journalists' outbound flights.
Please watch: "I Am One Greece," a campaign that captures the collaborative pulse connecting Greeks in the diaspora with the people of Greece.
Follow Diane Mantouvalos on Twitter: www.twitter.com/@AndoniaPR
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:57:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece -- the Decisive Factor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f4346b/sc/15/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cjoergen0Eoerstroem0Emoeller0Cgreece0E0E0Ethe0Edecisive0Efac0Ib0I77576820Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The conclusion first! Greece will stay in the Euro. Agreement with the creditors will be reached and it is not difficult to see how it will look. The challenge is to trace how to get there. It will probably be a bumpy ride, messy flavored with mutual accusations, disagreement among Eurozone members, drama, walk outs, and statements that 'now it is all over' - but it isn't. With a lot of good luck a solution may be found over the coming week-end, but it is possible that it will take three months. There may be a need for tempers to calm down and a cool appreciation to replace hot tempers on both sides. Greece can stay formally in the Euro over three months even if steps casting doubt over membership - and causing raised eyebrows in the Eurozone - are taken to keep the economy going albeit at a slow pace.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
The conclusion first! Greece will stay in the Euro. Agreement with the creditors will be reached and it is not difficult to see how it will look. The challenge is to trace how to get there. It will probably be a bumpy ride, messy flavored with mutual accusations, disagreement among Eurozone members, drama, walk outs, and statements that 'now it is all over' - but it isn't. With a lot of good luck a solution may be found over the coming week-end, but it is possible that it will take three months. There may be a need for tempers to calm down and a cool appreciation to replace hot tempers on both sides. Greece can stay formally in the Euro over three months even if steps casting doubt over membership - and causing raised eyebrows in the Eurozone - are taken to keep the economy going albeit at a slow pace.
It was never realistic to expect a solution before the absolute deadline. Both sides had to show how hard they fought to defend interests against a stubborn opponent. Both sides have parliaments and an electorate to keep in mind.
An agreement will be forged around two axes.  The first one is measures to reform and restructure the economy in a convincing way - that will be implemented and work. The second one is dexterity with regard to the debt burden. Many parameters such as interest rate subsides or scheduling of repayments can be brought into play reducing the debt burden without writing off much of the debt. The problem, which has harassed the negotiations from January 2015, is that the two sides do not trust each other therefore demanding too much and insisting on a vocabulary that prevents a bit of blurring, a trick often mobilized in diplomacy.
Such a solution cannot and will not be the final words in the Greek drama. It is a kind of breathing space lasting a couple of years. Both sides will be able to judge how well the Greek economy performs and how trustworthy the other side turned out to be. Thereafter the time will come for a longer lasting plan to change Greece from a country with a non-viable economy into an economy that works or if that proves impossible for the Eurozone to decide whether it will continue to support Greece. Already now transfers from EU-funds is running at 3 percent of Greek Gross Domestic Product (GDP) and a hike with one or two percentage points is by no means impossible.
Prime Minister Tsipras won a resounding victory with 61 percent of the electorate following his appeal to vote no. Paradoxically that puts him under pressure. The voters will say 'we did what you asked us to do, you promised that if so everything would be all right and a better deal obtained. Now you must deliver'. If he comes back from the week-end summit (11-12 July 2015) without a deal, voters will question his judgment. This feeling will be accentuated if banks keep closed and capital controls remain in place.
Recalling his political past on the extreme left the uncertainty about his policies is not easy to discount. Officially numerous statements in his name have stressed that Greece should stay in the Euro, but with a better deal. There is, however, not much evidence to support that he worked to achieve that. Maybe he planned from the start to take Greece out of the Euro, but the majority of Greeks preferring to stay in the Euro blocked that road. Alternative theories attribute to him the goal of forcing the left wing of Syriza out of the party allowing him to form a center-left coalition, but again there is little evidence to support this view. There is no real basis for judging what he wants - obscurity and contradiction suffuse the agenda. Going into negotiations without communicating the final objective - an achievable one - is a grave mistake. The art of diplomacy consists of mapping out a course of actions taking the country to the final objective through a step by step approach patiently and cautiously weeding out obstacle after obstacle. Neither the domestic audience nor opponents around the negotiating table should be surprised by the final result. It emerges as the natural outcome; decision is taken when time has come and the fruit is ready to be picked. The chain of events over the preceding six months is an illustration of violating all of these principles whoever is to blame.
From the Eurozone perspective the lack of dedication to 'Europe' has played a crucial role. Prime Minister Tsipras has never conveyed convincingly that he feels committed to Europe and wants to keep Greece in the Euro and the EU to take part in building a Europe reflecting the phrase from the treaty preamble 'an ever closer union among the peoples of Europe'. Apparently Greece under Prime Minister Tsipras and the Eurozone do not look upon each other as fellow members of the Eurozone, but conceptually as 'some of us inside' and 'one of us outside' and  the one outside  not subscribing to the survival of the Euro as the principal and common objective for ALL of them. That being the case a good deal of European politicians asks how much should be done for Greece? The EU is a political and economic enterprise and if Greece represented by Prime Minister Tsipras exclusively see it as an economic enterprise to fund a persistently weak Greek economy the gap in political beliefs may be too deep to bridge.
Observers and commentators point to the geopolitical role of Greece as a Western ally (EU and NATO membership) in the Eastern Mediterranean and at the southern tip of the Balkans - traditionally a powder keg. This is not wrong, but if Greece does not feel it is part of the EU and the Western alliance, how much can it be counted upon if or when a crisis calls for its support to allies and partners? How much does Greece weighs as an ally if it is not member of these organizations by conviction, but by convenience? Prime Minister Tsipras meetings and communications with President Putin and especially the timing immediately before summits are at best bizarre for a member of EU and NATO.
Over the coming days, weeks, and months the Eurozone will look for a convincing stance by Prime Minister Tsipras that Greece belongs in the 'Western' camp. If such communication is forthcoming negotiations will be smoother, much smoother.
This may well prove to be a decisive factor and lift the problem from economics to politics. Then it is solvable.
If on the other hand such statements are not put forward it is possible that the negotiations end with Greece leaving the Euro and a question arises over its EU membership. The consequences for the rest of the Eurozone and the EU will not be dire as maintained by some observers who predict severe negative repercussions. For the simple reason that Greece has signaled that it is not a European country sharing common values with the other member states.
Joergen Oerstroem Moeller
Visiting Senior Research Fellow, Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, Singapore.
Adjunct Professor Singapore Management University &amp; Copenhagen Business School.
Honorary Alumnus, University of Copenhagen.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:49:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>It's Still the Occupation</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f53701/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cpaul0Escham0Cits0Estill0Ethe0Eoccupation0Ib0I77576280Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Jewish and Israeli worlds -- and to some degree the America political world -- are being roused to battle by a growing campaign highlighting the evils and dangers of BDS (Boycott, Divestment and Sanctions against Israel). It is being termed the greatest danger since Hitler, one that </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
The Jewish and Israeli worlds -- and to some degree the America political world -- are being roused to battle by a growing campaign highlighting the evils and dangers of BDS (Boycott, Divestment and Sanctions against Israel).  It is being termed the greatest danger since Hitler, one that threatens Israel with over $10 billion in losses a year (with a lot of questionable assumptions). While at the moment, Prime Minister Netanyahu and the US right wing are issuing ever more dire warnings about the purported dangers of the seemingly imminent Iran nuclear deal, they undoubtedly recognize that they have probably lost that fight, so BDS will clearly be the next big push.
Push for what?  Why, to distract attention from the ongoing Occupation of the West Bank and the expansion of settlements.  And it may be working, at least in certain quarters.  It seems to be part of a larger strategy of delegitimization; not of Israel, as is being widely claimed, but, rather, of those, especially Jews, who oppose the Israeli rightwing and who are trying to stop it leading Israel towards isolation and disaster.
Necessary Disclaimer: There is no doubt that the Middle East in general, and Israel in particular, faces real and dangerous threats, some of which have been metastasizing to an alarming degree.  A nuclear Iran, worldwide anti-semitism, the success of ISIS, the failure of Iraq, Yemen, Syria and Libya as states with no solution in sight; all of these are genuine crises, and some are causing far more immediate death and destruction in the short term.  So why am I and others pushing for settlement of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict in the face of all these?  No one seriously believes that such a mutually-agreed on settlement will stop ISIS, Iran or the Arab civil wars in their tracks.
There are several crucial reasons why the US government, Israel, the international community and American Jews, as well as Palestinians, Arab states and others should be focusing on this as a priority, from all their different vantage points.  And, unfortunately, peaceful settlement of the conflict is opposed by powerful forces, including the American and Israeli right wings, ISIS, al Qaeda and extremists around the world, from Islam and Judaism, left and right and elsewhere.  Of course, I am not alleging a conspiracy among these forces, which mostly loathe each other.  But continuation of the status quo, which includes expanding and open-ended settlements, punctuated by increasingly horrific wars, has had and continues to have an extremely exacerbating effect on the region and the world.
Part of its danger is that it is as old as the modern Middle East. This conflict has been ongoing, in various forms, since before World War I as an inter-communal dispute, and since 1947 as a regional and international conflict.   Every generation, it seems to change shape, and sometimes parties even change sides, to a degree that partisan rhetoric doesn't keep up with it.  For example, in 1947, Israel accepted a partition plan giving it 55 percent of historic Palestine (Eretz Yisrael) and went to war with the Arab world over it.  In 2002, the Arab League unanimously offered Israel 78 percent of the land and full diplomatic relations in return for a Palestinian state on the remaining 22 percent, repeating and sweetening the offer several times.  Israel has never fully responded.
More recently, Israel now finds itself in de facto alliance with the major Arab powers, including Saudi Arabia, Egypt, Jordan and the Gulf States.  This is because of their shared fear of two factors, both Islamic, namely Iran and ISIS.  No one believes either of these are short-term dangers, nor is this simply a temporary alliance of convenience.  All of these Arab states are conservative, status quo powers.  They realize, correctly, that Israel has an equally large stake in the status quo, and shares many of their interests.  The last thing they would want would be a new and unstable Palestinian state replacing Israel.
Nevertheless, except for Jordan and Egypt, Israel has no official government-to-government dealings with any Arab states, and their public relationships are frosty. Why?  Solely because of the Palestinian issue.  The Arab and Muslim worlds are so heavily invested in that issue that the governments cannot 'normalize' relations with Israel until there is a Palestinian state.  Thus, the ongoing conflict is preventing Israeli integration into the region and preventing it from concluding strong regional alliances.
Domestically, it is equally toxic.  The Occupation constitutes an objective threat to Israeli democracy.  When a democratic state rules over a population as large as its own which has no vote and little say in its governance, it cannot be called a democracy any longer.  It was one thing when the occupation seemed temporary.  But after 48 years, and with Israel led by a government whose members range from total rejection of a Palestinian state to 'not in the foreseeable future;" to call it temporary is to squeeze any meaning out of the word.  The Occupation has poisoned Israeli politics internally, and led to increasing international isolation of the country.  All of this in the name of 'defense'.  In fact, numerous studies have shown, as common sense does as well, that a demilitarized and poor Palestinian state cannot offer any credible threat to Israel or, if it teams up with others who do, Israel will be perfectly capable of defending itself.  Most of us have learned that there are no absolute guarantees in life, for anything, but the odds here are immensely in Israel's favor.
What about BDS and the 'new anti-semitism'?  Doesn't this prove Israel is in genuine danger and that the world will always hate it?
In fact, it proves the opposite. The BDS phenomenon is being cynically used by the Israeli government and some American Jewish organizations as evidence that whatever it does, it will never be safe.  The Occupation is irrelevant, they insist.  BDS is Israel's and the Jewish people's real enemy, along with Iran, ISIS and President Obama.
In fact, the vast majority of those who support BDS do so because they believe Israel has no business ruling over the West Bank and blockading Gaza, and that it has no intention of changing that situation in real time.  Of course the leadership, those who purport to speak in the name of BDS, says differently.  Many, if not most, make clear that they do not accept Israel's existence, certainly not as a Jewish state.  They proclaim that BDS supports a full right of return and other measures which would indeed change Israel into a majority-Arab country.
However, BDS is neither a state nor a Leninist party.  Many of its supporters proclaim ad infinitum that they support Palestinian rights -- not Israel's destruction.  I know a number of Jews who support Israel but who have concluded that the only way to end the Occupation is through BDS.  I don't agree with them, but they are not a danger to Israel.
However, BDS is increasingly being used as an excuse to purge the Jewish community and weed out of it those who recognize that the Occupation is the greatest single danger threatening Israel.  The Occupation is the lynchpin of support for BDS and for much of the anti-semitism that is rearing its head around the world.  Most Jews do identify with Israel, and it is far too easy for those who hate Israel to attack Jews, since Israel is a much tougher target.  Yes, there is indeed growing anti-semitism, but most of it is related to Israel's actions, not religious or 'racial' hatred of Jews.
Ending the Occupation and the establishment of an independent Palestinian state will not change those whose hatred for Israel is existential.  But this small minority swims in a sea which is filled with those whose beef with Israel is primarily the Occupation.  Neither the leaders of BDS nor the leaders of Israel want to recognize this fact.  For opposite reasons, both want to exaggerate the adherents and successes of the movement which have, for the most part, been few and far between.
Moreover, the most recent tactic is to surreptitiously attempt to blur the distinction between Israel and the Occupied Territories. Many people and institutions have chosen to boycott the settlements but not Israel proper.  Anti-boycott legislation is being introduced now around the US that specifically includes "territory Israel controls" as effectively part of Israel proper.  This is not only objectively false -- Israel has never annexed the West Bank -- but it is also in direct contradiction to 47 years of US government policy, which has steadfastly refused to recognize the West Bank as part of Israel.  And anti-boycott legislation -- not including the Occupied Territories -- has been on the books for many years.
Thus, the only way to change this dangerous trajectory is to end the Occupation as quickly as possible.  Some ideas for doing that are in articles and statements I have contributed to here and here .  Many others are published daily.
As I've stressed, ending the Occupation is not a panacea.  But only with that as a start can Israel return to the path of peace, democracy, regional integration and worldwide acceptance.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:25:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>If Greece Takes On a New Outlook, So Will Europe</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f49a47/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cjacques0Edelors0Cgreece0Etakes0Eon0Ea0Enew0Eoutlook0Ib0I77541780Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PARIS -- Greece is in a dramatic condition and the situation will only deteriorate further if the country were to end up defaulting on its debts -- or even leaving the eurozone altogether. Emerging from the current crisis requires first and foremost that a complete change of outlook take root in Greece itself. </Description>
        <MainBody>

A supporter of the No vote reacts after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote celebrate after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag in front of the parliament after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote react after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote chant slogans after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote chant slogans after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote wave Greek flags after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
A supporter of the No vote shouts slogans after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
A supporter of the No vote shouts slogans after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
Supporters of the No vote celebrate after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, left, speaks with the Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos after the results of the referendum at the Presidential Palace in Athens, early Monday, July 6, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras speaks with the Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos after the results of the referendum at the Presidential Palace in Athens, early Monday, July 6, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)
A vendor sells Greek flags walks at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Three opinion polls carried out during Greece's bailout referendum, which could affect the country's future in the eurozone, indicate the "no" vote will win. Tsipras called Sunday's referendum last weekend, urging voters to reject creditor reform proposals. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote wave Greek flags after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as officials counted the results of a referendum Sunday on whether to accept creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans, with three opinion polls showing a tight race with a narrow victory likely for the "no" side. (AP Photo/Petr David Josek)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag as celebrates after the results of the referendum in Synatagma square in central Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Karadjias)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras casts his vote at a polling station in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks began voting early Sunday in a closely-watched, closely-contested referendum, which the government pits as a choice over whether to defy the country's creditors and push for better repayment terms or essentially accept their terms, but which the opposition and many of the creditors paint as a choice between staying in the euro or leaving it. (AP Photo/Petros Karadjias)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, center, speaks to the media after voting at a polling station in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks began voting early Sunday in a closely-watched, closely-contested referendum, which the government pits as a choice over whether to defy the country's creditors and push for better repayment terms or essentially accept their terms, but which the opposition and many of the creditors paint as a choice between staying in the euro or leaving it. (AP Photo/Spyros Tsakiris)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag after the referendum's exit polls at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as officials counted the results of a referendum Sunday on whether to accept creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans, with three opinion polls showing a tight race with a narrow victory likely for the "no" side. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote react after the first results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as its interior ministry predicted Sunday that more than 60 percent of voters in a hastily called referendum had rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote react after the first results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as its interior ministry predicted Sunday that more than 60 percent of voters in a hastily called referendum had rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
A woman waits to cross a street in front of an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
A woman walks past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
People walk past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015. Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
People walk past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties.(AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
A cleaner walks past display boards at the Australian Stock Exchange in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
A television journalist works in front of display boards at the Australian Stock Exchange in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
A display board at the Australian Stock Exchange flashes red indicating the losses of several names in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:23:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How the Greek and Chinese Crises Are Linked</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f49a49/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cmohamed0Ea0Eelerian0Cgreek0Eand0Echinese0Ecrises0Elinked0Ib0I77571880Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At first sight, there is little to connect the ugliness in China and Greece. The former reflects the unwinding of a market bubble; and the latter is driven by weak and deteriorating economic and financial fundamentals. Yet both share a common element, and they are not the only ones: They have benefited from the ultra-loose experimental policies that have been pursued by major central banks around the world.</Description>
        <MainBody>

A man walks past an electric board displaying stock prices at a brokerage house in Beijing, China, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. China's central bank has promised more credit to finance stock trading in the latest move aimed at stopping a plunge in stock prices that has prompted hundreds of companies to suspend trading in their shares. (AP Photo/Andy Wong)
A woman walks past as investors monitor the stock prices at a brokerage house in Beijing, China, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. Chinese stocks led a slump in Asian markets on Wednesday as the sell-off in Shanghai intensified and Greece's future in the euro remained highly uncertain. (AP Photo/Andy Wong)
A man rubs his head while browsing his smartphone outside a brokerage house in Beijing Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Chinese stocks fell Tuesday despite official efforts to shore up slumping prices while other Asian markets were mixed after Greece's spiraling crisis weighed on Wall Street. (AP Photo/Andy Wong)
Investors chat as they check stock prices at a stock firm in Hangzhou, eastern China's Zhejiang province on July 8, 2015. China's benchmark Shanghai stock index was down more than 4.5 percent by mid-morning as additional government moves failed to shore up the tumbling market and contagion began to spread elsewhere.
FUYANG, CHINA - JULY 07: (CHINA OUT) An investor observes stock market at a stock exchange hall on July 7, 2015 in Fuyang, Anhui Province of China. Chinese shares rebounded to 3,700 points from 3585 points on Tuesday, while by the end of Tuesday's close, the benchmark Shanghai Composite Index dropped 47.72 points, or 1.26 percent, to close at 3728.19 points. The Shenzhen Component Index slid 700.17 points, or 5.80 percent, to 11375.60 points. (Photo by ChinaFotoPress/ChinaFotoPress via Getty Images)
CORRECTION - DATE A man rests in front of a banner about the 'China Dream', Chinese President Xi Jinping's vision for China's future, in Beijing on July 7, 2015, with Chinese characters translate as 'To realise the revitalisation is the biggest dream in modern times of Chinese nationals'.  Chinese shares sank further July 7, defying government efforts to arrest a precipitous fall that has wiped an estimated 3.2 trillion USD off markets and threatens the world's number two economy.  Analysts say heavy-handed intervention by the government throws into question the pace of China's economic reforms and the ability of the government to deflate what many describe as a stock market bubble.
TO GO WITH China-economy-politics-stocks,ANALYSIS by Bill SAVADOVE This photo taken on July 6, 2015 shows investors monitoring stock market movements at a brokerage house in Shanghai.  With the benchmark Shanghai stock index falling more than 30 percent in less than a month, wiping out around 3.2 trillion USD of value, Chinese government officials have cobbled together rescue measures aimed at propping up the market.
TO GO WITH China-economy-politics-stocks,ANALYSIS by Bill SAVADOVE This photo taken on July 6, 2015 shows an investor reacting in front of a screen showing stock market movements at a brokerage house in Shanghai.  With the benchmark Shanghai stock index falling more than 30 percent in less than a month, wiping out around 3.2 trillion USD of value, Chinese government officials have cobbled together rescue measures aimed at propping up the market.
This photo taken on July 6, 2015 shows investors using computers under screens showing stock market movements at a brokerage house in Shanghai.  With the benchmark Shanghai stock index falling more than 30 percent in less than a month, wiping out around 3.2 trillion USD of value, Chinese government officials have cobbled together rescue measures aimed at propping up the market.
This photo taken on July 6, 2015 shows investors sitting in front of screens showing stock market movements at a brokerage house in Shanghai.  With the benchmark Shanghai stock index falling more than 30 percent in less than a month, wiping out around 3.2 trillion USD of value, Chinese government officials have cobbled together rescue measures aimed at propping up the market.
A man stands in front of an electronic board showing the closing trade numbers of the Hang Seng Index in the Central district of Hong Kong on July 6, 2015. Hong Kong stocks plunged 3.18 percent by lunch July 6, with big-name firms taking a heavy hit, as Greece's 'No' vote to further austerity overshadowed news China had unveiled fresh measures to support slumping mainland markets. The benchmark Hang Seng Index fell 827.83 points to 25,236.28 on turnover of 212.71 billion HKD (27.45 billion USD).
A pedestrian is reflected in a glass window in front of a screen displaying share prices at a security firm in Shanghai on July 6, 2015. Shanghai stocks were up 2.15 percent at midday on July 6 after the government unveiled its biggest package of measures so far to shore up the slumping market, but an initial surge was pared as analysts questioned their effect.
A stock investors check computers under letters under Chinese writing which translates as 'stock market has risk' at a brokerage house in Shanghai on July 6, 2015. Shanghai stocks were up 2.15 percent at midday on July 6 after the government unveiled its biggest package of measures so far to shore up the slumping market, but an initial surge was pared as analysts questioned their effect.
A stock investor checks his phone under Chinese writing in the background which translates as 'stock market has risk' at a brokerage house in Shanghai on July 6, 2015. Shanghai stocks were up 2.15 percent at midday on July 6 after the government unveiled its biggest package of measures so far to shore up the slumping market, but an initial surge was pared as analysts questioned their effect.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:12:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>This Is How A Species Goes Extinct: More Than A Ton Of Frozen Pangolin Meat Seized In Indonesia</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f49a4d/sc/32/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cpangolins0Eindonesia0In0I77564540Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Previous Story
Next Story
This Is How A Species Goes Extinct: More Than A Ton Of Frozen Pangolin Meat Seized In Indonesia
reddit
Pangolins are one of the most trafficked animals in the world.
Pangolins are one of the planet's most unique and adorable species. The scaly, anteater-like creatures live in parts of Asia and Africa, and there's an entire task force dedicated to their protection. A popular Pokemon character, Sandslash , was even based on these " artichokes on legs ."
And yet, humans can't seem to stop killing them.
Authorities in Indonesia recently busted smugglers trying to transport 1.3 tons worth of dead pangolins into Singapore. Heart-wrenching photos taken by a Getty photographer show dozens of the animals frozen in their trademark armored ball before they were burned by customs officials on Wednesday.
Warning: The pictures below may be upsetting to some readers.
Pangolins are the world's " most-trafficked " mammal. The International Union for Conservation of Nature classifies the Chinese pangolin -- one of eight species of pangolins -- as " critically endangered ."
But despite this designation, consumers in parts of Asia -- primarily China -- see pangolins as a delicacy, and they're frequently caught as bushmeat and smuggled across borders. Many believe pangolin meat can help nourish the kidneys, The New York Times wrote earlier this year. And, like many of their endangered brethren, attempts at conservation have been stymied by the unfounded belief that parts of their bodies (in this case, pangolin scales ) have medicinal value.
A frozen pangolin seized by customs officials in East Java, Indonesia.
Indonesian officials seized 1.3 tons of frozen pangolin bound for Singapore on July 8.
"The pangolin runs the risk of becoming extinct before most people have even heard of them," Britain's Prince William said last year .
Pangolins have suffered due to their relative obscurity compared to other, better-known endangered species like polar bears.
Thats one of the problems with species like pangolins, Annette Olsson, an adviser for Conservation International, told the Times earlier this year. Its not huge and not very charismatic. Its small and weird and just disappearing.
But concerned nations plan to vault them to the forefront of conservation efforts during next year's Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora meeting in Vietnam.
"We consider pangolins a priority species and fear that without concerted and strategic international cooperation and action, pangolins will disappear," the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service wrote earlier this month.
Soldiers guard an unidentified suspect arrested for attempting to export an illegal shipment of pangolin meat.
Customs officials burn the seized pangolin carcasses.
Also on HuffPost:


Scientific Name: Diceros sumatrensis  Common Name: Sumatran rhino  Category: Rhino  Population: &lt; 250 individuals   Threats To Survival: Hunting for horn -used in traditional medicine
Scientific Name: Eleutherodactylus thorectes  Common Name: Macaya Breast-Spot Frog  Category: Frog  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction due to charcoal production and slash-and-burn agriculture  Credit: Robin Moore
Scientific Name: Scaturiginichthys vermeilipinnis  Common Name: Red-Finned Blue Eye  Category: Freshwater Fish  Population: 2,000 - 4,000 Individuals  Threats To Survival: Predation by introduced species
Scientific Name: Rafetus Swinhoei  Common Name: Red River Giant Softshell Turtle  Category: Turtle  Population: 4 known individuals   Threats To Survival: Hunting for consumption and habitat destruction and degradation as a result of wetland destruction and pollution
Scientific Name: Neurergus kaiseri  Common Name: Luristan newt  Category: Newt  Population: &lt; 1000 mature individuals   Threats To Survival: Illegal collection for pet trade
List Provided By Zoological Society Of London/ International Union For Conservation Of Nature"  width="52" height="52"/&gt;
Scientific Name: Poecilotheria metallica  Common Name: Peacock Parachute Spider  Category: Spider  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and degradation as a result of deforestation, firewood collection and civil unrest
Scientific Name: Atelopus balios  Common Name: Rio Pescado Stubfoot Toad  Category: Toad  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Chytridiomycosis and habitat destruction due to logging and agricultural expansion
Scientific Name: Johora Singaporensis  Common Name: Singapore Freshwater Crab  Category: Crab  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation - reduction in water quality and quantity
Scientific Name: Abies beshanzuensis  Common Name: Baishan Fir  Category: Conifer  Population: 5 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Agricultural expansion and fire
Scientific Name: Actinote zikani   Common Name: None  Category: Butterfly  Population: Unknown, one population remaining  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation due to pressure from human populations
Scientific Name: Aipysurus foliosquama  Common Name: Leaf Scaled Sea-Snake  Category: Sea snake  Population:  Unknown, two subpopulations remain  Threats To Survival: Unknown - likely degradation of coral reef habitat
Scientific Name: Amanipodagrion gilliesi  Common Name: Amani Flatwing  Category: Damselfly  Population: &lt; 500 individuals est.  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation due to increasing population pressure and water pollution
Scientific Name: Antilophia bokermanni  Common Name: Araripe Manakin  Category: bird  Population: 779 individuals (est 2010)  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction due to expansion of agriculture and recreational facilities and water diversion
Scientific Name: Antisolabis seychellensis  Common Name:  Seychelles Earwig  Category: Earwig   Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Invasive species and climate change
Scientific Name: Aphanius transgrediens  Common Name: None  Category: Freshwater fish  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Competition and predation by Gambusia and road construction
Scientific Name: Ardeotis nigriceps  Common Name:  Great Indian Bustard  Category: Bird  Population:  50 -249 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and modification due to agricultural development
Scientific Name: Aproteles bulmerae  Common Name: Bulmer's Fruit Bat  Category: Bat  Population: 150 individuals (est)  Threats To Survival: Hunting and cave disturbance
Scientific Name: Ardea insignis  Common Name: White Bellied Heron  Category: Bird  Population: 70-400 individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction and degradation due to hydropower development
Scientific Name: Astrochelus yniphora  Common Name:  Ploughshare Tortoise / Angonoka  Category: Tortoise  Population: 440-770  Threats To Survival: Illegal collection for international pet trade
Scientific Name: Aythya innotata  Common Name: Madagascar Pochard  Category: Bird  Population:  Approximately 20 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation due to slash-and-burn agriculture, hunting, and fishing / introduced fish
Scientific Name: Azurina eupalama  Common Name:  Galapagos damsel fish  Category: Pelagic fish  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Climate Change - oceanographic changes associated with the 1982 / 1983 El Nino are presumed to be responsible for the apparent disappearance of this species from the Galapagos
Scientific Name: Bahaba taipingensis   Common Name:  Giant yellow croaker  Category: Pelagic fish  Population:  Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Over-fishing, primarily due to value of swim-bladder for traditional medicine - cost per kilogram exceeded that of gold in 2001
Scientific Name: Batagur baska  Common Name:  Common Batagur/ Four-toed terrapin  Category: Turtle  Population:  Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Illegal export and trade from Indonesia to China
Scientific Name: Bazzania bhutanica  Common Name: None  Category: Liverwort  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation and destruction due to forest clearance, overgrazing and development
Scientific Name: Beatragus hunteri  Common Name: Hirola  Category: Antelope  Population: &lt; 1000 individuals  Threats To Survival:  Habitat loss and degradation, competition with livestock, poaching
Scientific Name: Bombus franklinii  Common Name: Franklin's Bumble Bee  Category: Bee  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Disease from commercially bred bumblebees and habitat destruction and degradation
Scientific Name: Brachyteles hypoxanthus  Common Name:  Northern muriqui  Category: Primate  Population: &lt; 1,000 individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and fragmentation due to large-scale deforestation and selective logging
Scientific Name: Bradypus pygmaeus  Common Name: Pygmy sloth  Category: Sloth  Population: &lt; 500 individuals   Threats To Survival: Habitat loss due to illegal logging of mangrove forests for firewood and construction and hunting of the sloths
Scientific Name: Callitriche pulchra  Common Name: None  Category: Freshwater plant  Population:  Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Exploitation of the species' habitat by stock, and modification of the pool by local people
Scientific Name: Calumma tarzan  Common Name: Tarzan's Chameleon  Category: Chameleon  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction for agriculture
Scientific Name: Cavia intermedia  Common Name: Santa Catarina's Guinea Pig  Category: Guinea Pig  Population:  40-60 individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat disturbance and possible hunting; small population effects
Scientific Name: Cercopithecus roloway  Common Name: Roloway Guenon  Category: Primate  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Hunting for consumption as bushmeat, and habitat loss
Scientific Name: Coleura seychellensis  Common Name: Seychelles Sheath-Tailed Bat  Category: Bat  Population: &lt; 100 mature individuals (est 2008)  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation and predation by invasive species
Scientific Name: Cryptomyces maximus  Common Name: None  Category: Fungus  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Limited availability of habitat
Scientific Name: Cryptotis nelsoni  Common Name: Nelson's Small-Eared Shrew  Category: Shrew  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: habitat loss due to logging cattle grazing, fire and agriculture
Scientific Name: Cyclura collei  Common Name: Jamaican Iguana  Category: Iguana  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Predation by introduced species and habitat destruction
Scientific Name: Dendrophylax fawcettii  Common Name: Cayman Islands Ghost Orchid  Category: Orchid  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction due to infrastructure development
Scientific Name: Diomedea amsterdamensis  Common Name: Amsterdam Island Albatross  Category: Bird  Population: 100 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Disease and incidental capture in long-line fishing operations
Scientific Name: Diospyros katendei  Common Name:  None  Category: Tree  Population: 20 individuals, one population  Threats To Survival: High pressure from communities for agricultural activity, illegal tree felling, habitat degradation due to alluvial gold digging and small population
Scientific Name: Dipterocarpus lamellatus  Common Name: None  Category: Dipterocarp (tree)  Population: 12 individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and degradation due to logging of lowland forest and creation of industrial plantations
Scientific Name: Discoglossus nigriventer  Common Name:  Hula painted frog  Category: Frog  Population: Unknown (recent rediscovery in 2011)  Threats To Survival: Predation by birds and range restriction due to habitat destruction
Scientific Name: Discorea strydomiana  Common Name: Wild Yam  Category: Yam  Population: 200 Individuals  Threats To Survival: Collection for medicinal use
Scientific Name: Dombeya mauritiana   Common Name: None  Category: Flowering plant  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation and destruction due to encroachment by alien invasive plant species and cannabis cultivation
Scientific Name: Eleocarpus bojeri  Common Name: None  Category: Flowering plant  Population: &lt; 10 individuals  Threats To Survival: Small population and degraded habitat
Scientific Name: Eleutherodactylus glandulifer  Common Name: La Hotte Glanded Frog  Category: Frog  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction due to charcoal production and slash-and-burn agriculture
Scientific Name: Eriosyce chilensis  Common Name: Chilenito  Category: Cactus  Population: &lt; 500 individuals  Threats To Survival: Collection of flowering individuals
Scientific Name: Erythrina schliebenii  Common Name: Coral Tree  Category: Flowering tree  Population: &lt; 50 individuals  Threats To Survival: Limited habitat and small population size increasing vulnerability to stochastic events
Scientific Name: Euphorbia tanaensis  Common Name: None  Category: Semi-deciduous tree  Population: 4 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Illegal logging and habitat degradation due to agricultural expansion and infrastructure development
Scientific Name: Eurynorhynchus pygmeus  Common Name: Spoon-Billed Sandpiper  Category: Bird  Population: &lt; 100 breeding pairs  Threats To Survival: Trapping on wintering grounds and land reclamation.
Scientific Name: Ficus katendei  Common Name: None  Category: Tree (ficus)  Population: &lt; 50 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Agricultural activity, illegal tree felling and habitat degradation due to alluvial gold digging
Scientific Name: Geronticus eremita  Common Name: Northern Bald Ibis  Category: Bird  Population: 200-249 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation and destruction, and hunting
Scientific Name: Gigasiphon macrosiphon  Common Name: None  Category: Flowering tree  Population: 33 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Timber extraction and habitat degradation due to agricultural encroachment and development, seed predation by wild pigs
Scientific Name: Gocea ohridana  Common Name: None  Category: Mollusc  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation due to increasing pollution levels, off-take of water and sedimentation events
Scientific Name: Heleophryne rosei  Common Name: Table Mountain Ghost Frog  Category: Frog  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation due to invasive plants and water abstraction
Scientific Name: Hemicycla paeteliana  Common Name: None  Category: Mollusc  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction due to overgrazing and trampling by goats and tourists
Scientific Name: Heteromirafa sidamoensis  Common Name: Liben Lark  Category: Bird  Population: 90- 256 individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and degradation due to agricultural expansion, over-grazing and fire suppression
Scientific Name: Hibiscadelphus woodii  Common Name: None  Category: Hibiscus  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation due to feral ungulates and invasive introduced plant species
Scientific Name: Hucho perryi (Parahucho perryi)  Common Name: Sakhalin Taimen  Category: Salmonid  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Overfishing (sport fishing and commercial bycatch) and habitat loss from damming, agriculture and other land use practices.
Scientific Name: Lathyrus belinensis  Common Name: None  Category: Sweet-pea  Population: &lt; 1,000 (2010 est)  Threats to Survival: Habitat destruction due to urbanisation, over-grazing, conifer planting and road widening
Scientific Name: Leiopelma archeyii   Common Name: Archey's Frog  Category: Frog  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Chytridiomycosis and predation by invasive species
Scientific Name: Lithobates sevosus  Common Name: Dusky Gopher Frog  Category: Frog  Population: 60-100 individuals (est 2003)  Threats To Survival: Fungal disease and habitat limitation due to climate change and land-use changes
Scientific Name: Lophura edwardsi   Common Name: Edward's pheasant  Category: Bird  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Hunting and habitat loss
Scientific Name: Magnolia wolfii  Common Name: None  Category: Magnolia  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival:  Isolation of species and low regeneration rates
Scientific Name: Margaritifera marocana  Common Name: None  Category: Mussel  Population: &lt; 250 individuals (2010 est)  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation and disturbance due to pollution and development
Scientific Name: Moominia willii  Common Name:  None  Category: Mollusc  Population: &lt; 500 individuals  Threats To Survival:  Invasive species and climate change
Scientific Name: Natalus primus  Common Name: Cuban Greater Funnel Eared Bat  Category: Bat  Population: &lt; 100 individuals (est 2005)  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and human disturbance
Scientific Name: Nepenthes attenboroughii  Common Name: Attenborough's Pitcher Plant  Category: Carnivorous plant  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Poaching
Scientific Name: Nomascus hainanus  Common Name: Hainan Gibbon  Category: Primate  Population: &lt; 20 individuals  Threats To Survival: Hunting
Scientific Name: Oreocnemis phoenix  Common Name: Mulanje Red Damsel  Category: Butterfly  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction and degradation due to drainage, agricultural expansion and exploitation of forest
Scientific Name:Pangasius sanitwongsi   Common Name: Pangasid Catfish  Category: Freshwater fish  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Overfishing and collection for aquarium trade
Scientific Name: Parides burchellanus   Common Name: None  Category: Butterfly  Population: &lt; 100 individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat degrdation due to pressure from human populations and range restriction
Scientific Name: Phocoena sinus  Common Name: Vaquita  Category: Porpoise  Population:  200+ individuals and declining  Threats to Survival: Incidental capture in gillnets
Scientific Name: Picea neoveitchii  Common Name: None  Category: Conifer  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Forest destruction
Scientific Name: Pinus squamata   Common Name: Qiaojia Pine  Category: Conifer  Population: &lt; 25 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Limited distribution and small population size
Scientific Name: Pomarea whitneyi  Common Name: Fatuhiva Monarch  Category: Butterfly  Population: 50 individuals  Threats To Survival: Predation by introduced species - Rattus rattus and feral cats
Scientific Name: Pristis pristis   Common Name: Common Sawfish  Category: Sawfish  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Exploitation - has removed the species from 95% of its historical range
Scientific Name: Prolemur simus  Common Name: Greater Bamboo Lemur  Category: Primate  Population: 100-160 individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction due to slash-and-burn agriculture, mining and illegal logging
Scientific Name: Propithecus candidus  Common Name: Silky Sifaka  Category: Primate  Population: 100 -1,000 individuals  Threats To Survival: Hunting and habitat disturbance
Scientific Name: Psammobates geometricus  Common Name: Geometric Tortoise  Category: Tortoise  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction and degradation, and predation
Scientific Name: Pseudoryx nghetinhensis  Common Name: Saola  Category: Saola (bovid affinities)  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Hunting and habitat destruction
Scientific Name: Psiadia cataractae  Common Name: None  Category: Flowering plant  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation and destruction due to development project and alien invasive plant species
Scientific Name: Psorodonotus ebneri  Common Name: Beydaglari Bush-cricket  Category: Cricket  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: climate change, habitat loss
Scientific Name: Rhinoceros sondaicus  Common Name: Javan Rhino  Category: Rhino  Population: &lt; 100 individuals  Threats To Survival: Hunting for traditional medicine and small population size
Scientific Name: Rhinopithecus avunculus  Common Name: Tonkin Snub-Nosed Monkey  Category: Primate  Population: &lt; 200 individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and hunting. Known from only a few records in small area of habitat ( less than 10km2)
Scientific Name: Rhizanthella gardneri  Common Name: West Australian Underground Orchid  Category: Orchid  Population: &lt; 100 individuals  Threats To Survival: Land clearance for agriculture (96% habitat cleared to date), climate change and salinisation
Scientific Name: Rhyncocyon spp  Common Name: Boni Giant Sengi  Category: Sengi  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Highly restricted habitat and distribution, security issues, oil development in area with associated increase in human population in area
Scientific Name: Risiocnemis seidenschwarzi  Common Name: Cebu Frill-Wing  Category: Damsel fly  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat degradation and destruction.
Scientific Name: Rosa arabica  Common Name: None  Category: Flowering tree  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Domestic animals grazing, climate change and drought, medicinal plant collection and restricted range
Scientific Name: Salanoia durrelli  Common Name: Durrell's Vontsira  Category: Vontsira (small carnivore)  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss
Scientific Name: Santamartamys rufodorsalis  Common Name: Red-Crested Tree Rat  Category: Rat  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss through urban development and coffee cultivation
Scientific Name: Squatina squatina  Common Name: Angel Shark  Category: Shark  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Benthic trawling
Scientific Name: Sterna bernsteini  Common Name: Chinese Crested Tern  Category: Bird  Population: &lt; 50 mature individuals  Threats To Survival: Egg collection and habitat destruction
Scientific Name: Sygnathus watermeyeri  Common Name: Estuarine Pipefish (River Pipefish)  Category: Pipefish  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Construction of dams altering river flows and flood events into estuaries
Scientific Name: Tahina spectabilis  Common Name: Suicide Palm  Category: Palm  Population: 90 Individuals  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss due to fires, logging and agricultural developments
Scientific Name: Telmatobufo bullocki juvenile  Common Name: Bullock's False Toad  Category: Toad  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction as a result of energy development
Scientific Name: Tokudaia muenninki  Common Name: Okinawa Spiny Rat  Category: Rat  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and predation by feral cats
Scientific Name: Trigonostigma sompongsi  Common Name:  Somphongs's rasbora  Category: Freshwater fish  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat loss and degradation from farmland conversion and urbanization
Scientific Name: Valencia letourneuxi  Common Name:  None  Category: Freshwater fish  Population: Unknown (declining)  Threats To Survival: Habitat destruction, water abstraction and agressive interaction with Gambusia
Scientific Name: Voanioala gerardii  Common Name:  Forest Coconut  Category: palm  Population: &lt; 10 individuals  Threats To Survival: Harvesting for consumption of palm heart and deforestation
Scientific Name: Zaglossus attenboroughii  Common Name:  Attenborough's Echidna  Category: echidna  Population: Unknown  Threats To Survival: Habitat modification and degradation due to logging, agricultural encroachment shifting cultivation and hunting by local people
Watch one National Geographic photographer's attempt at saving endangered species.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:11:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek Pensioners Are Surviving On Just 120 Euros. Here's What That Buys.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f49a4e/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cgreek0Epensioner0E120A0Eeuros0In0I77550A0A20Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Greeces debt crisis rolls on, many Greek pensioners have been living off a paltry 120 euros ($132) for nearly two weeks. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
As Greeces debt crisis rolls on, many Greek pensioners have been living off a paltry 120 euros ($132) for nearly two weeks.
Greece last week shuttered banks and limited cash withdrawals to 60 euros ($66) per day, in an effort to stop a growing run on the banks after negotiations for a new bailout deal broke down and the country missed a loan repayment to the International Monetary Fund.
The closure of banks left many elderly Greeks who dont have bank cards with no way to access their pensions. Greek banks threw them a lifeline last week by briefly opening their doors to allow pensioners to collect a one-off payment of 120 euros. It's unclear when pensioners will be able to get more cash from the banks, and 12 days later, their resources are stretched thin.
Greece's 2.6 million pensioners were already struggling after years of austerity measures imposed by Greece's creditors in the aftermath of the 2008 financial crisis. The average monthly pension fell from 1,350 euros ($1,494) in 2009 to just 833 euros ($922) this year, according to the BBC . At the same, pensioners were more likely to have to support younger members of their families, as unemployment rates soared to 25 percent.
For all Greeks, living off 60 euros a day is hard enough -- in fact,  its less than half than what the average American spends in a day, according to TIME Magazine . Pensioners are even harder hit, making agonizing decisions between, for example, paying their electricity bill or medical expenses. The WorldPost took a snapshot of the estimated cost of basic goods in Athens today, to better understand just how hard living off 120 euros might be for 12 days.
Rent of a small apartment in a cheap neighborhood of Athens
90
A man checks his phone inside his house in the Anafiotika neighborhood in Athens, June 24, 2015. (Daniel Ochoa de Olza/AP)
Electricity bill for a small apartment
25
Anastasia Ioannou and Giorgos Vogiatzis sit in their kitchen lit by candlelight after their power was cut in Thessaloniki on Dec. 8, 2013.
(Sakis Mitrolidis/AFP/Getty Images)
Basic cell phone plan
15
A man checks his phone inside his house in the Anafiotika neighborhood in Athens, June 24, 2015.
(Daniel Ochoa de Olza/AP)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:09:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Investing in Youth Employment Today Will Reap Dividends for Generations to Come</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f4efe2/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cbertrand0Ebadre0Cinvesting0Ein0Eyouth0Eemploy0Ib0I77572960Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Most 18-year-olds have no idea where life's journey will lead, and I was one of them. At that point in my life, though, I was lucky enough to be selected as the first French student to attend the annual St Gallen Symposium as one of the future "Leaders of Tomorrow." I remember vividly taking the night train from my home outside Paris to the Swiss campus where my fellow students and I would bring a youth perspective to the conversations engaging that generation of leaders. At that time, Japan was a rising star on the world economic stage, and the Cold War was coming to a close. One of the speakers told us, "The world is about to change," and I couldn't have imagined almost 30 years ago how dramatic those changes would be.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Most 18-year-olds have no idea where life's journey will lead, and I was one of them. At that point in my life, though, I was lucky enough to be selected as the first French student to attend the annual St Gallen Symposium as one of the future "Leaders of Tomorrow." I remember vividly taking the night train from my home outside Paris to the Swiss campus where my fellow students and I would bring a youth perspective to the conversations engaging that generation of leaders. At that time, Japan was a rising star on the world economic stage, and the Cold War was coming to a close. One of the speakers told us, "The world is about to change," and I couldn't have imagined almost 30 years ago how dramatic those changes would be.
That experience changed my life and opened up a new way of thinking about what leadership could be and how young people could share in moving the global agenda forward. Today, I am Managing Director and World Bank Group CFO and believe completely that youth will be leaders in helping us achieve our mission of ending poverty and boosting shared prosperity by 2030.
I spoke earlier this month at Rencontres Economiques d'Aix-en-Provence, an economics conference devoted to the theme of employment.  We know that global growth and poverty reduction over the next 20 years will be driven by today's young people. Access to productive employment is the most effective way to capitalize on the growth dividend. Investing in youth employment -- especially for the most disadvantaged -- will reap huge economic rewards.
Even so, many of today's young people can't find jobs.
In 2014, there were 1.1 billion people between the ages of 15 and 24, but nearly 500 million young people around the world are under- or unemployed.
The global economy needs to create 5 million jobs each month during the next decade to meet the expected growth in the labor force. However, nearly one third of youth are not getting the adequate education or training they need to succeed in today's job market. And a third of those who are employed are earning under their national poverty lines.
What can be done? Addressing barriers to youth employment requires both public and private action. At the country level, investments can be made to provide technical skills to young people. Better information flows can connect youth to jobs that are available. Apprenticeships can also help young people build their experience.
Importantly, we need to document what works and what doesn't. This evidence then can be shared across regions and adapted locally to help inform future policies and investments.
We at the World Bank Group are partnering with governments, the private sector and civil society in a unique global coalition called the Solutions for Youth Employment (S4YE). The coalition will support 150 million youth by designing and implementing effective employment programs and mobilizing financial and technical resources for research and innovation.
One of our greatest resources on Earth is our young people. They have the passion and drive to make this world a better place. Shouldn't we give them a fighting chance to achieve their dreams and ambitions? Investing in youth employment today will have an impact for generations to come.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:45:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman Rants About Ocean Dangers Because It's The 'Shark's House'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f40dbe/sc/14/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cwoman0Erants0Eabout0Eocean0Edangers0Ebecause0Eits0Ethe0Esharks0Ehouse0In0I775710A80Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman Rants About Ocean Dangers Because It's The 'Shark's House'
Andy McDonald Associate Editor, The Huffington Post
Posted: 07/08/2015 | Edited: 5 hours ago
This is a wholesome, God-fearing, shark-fearing, bear-fearing woman.
Veronica "Pooh" Nash Poleate posted this video to her Facebook because she has a dire warning for the people of Earth: Stay out of the ocean. As she explains, the ocean is the "shark's house" and "he has the right to eat you when you're in his house." 
"When chickens come in my house, guess what?" You know how this goes.
Her advice doesn't stop at sharks, though. Poleate also insists that you stay out of the woods. "Don't go fooling around with the bears."
This women is humanity's greatest protector. Daily videos would be fine with us. There are other dangersin the world that need her attention.

To subscribe to our HuffPost Entertainment WhatsApp account:
1. Download WhatsApp on your phone.
2. Save this number, 347-334-1794 , in your phones contacts.
3. Text "POP" to that number via your WhatsApp account.
You can unsubscribe at any time by texting STOP" to the same number.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:41:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why The Polls In Greece Got It Wrong</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f40dbf/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Cgreece0Epolls0Ewrong0In0I77548740Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Sunday was a bad day for pollsters, adding yet another poor performance following a string of recent </Description>
        <MainBody>Why The Polls In Greece Got It Wrong
Posted:
Updated:
5 hours ago
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras prepares to vote during the Greek referendum in Athens on July 5, 2015. | ARIS MESSINIS via Getty Images
reddit
Sunday was a bad day for pollsters, adding yet another poor performance following a string of recent high-profile polling misfires . This time the final round of polls on the Greek referendum showed the bailout deal failing by 3 to 4 percentage points, but the actual vote was not nearly as close. The "no" side prevailed by a 22-point margin -- 61 to 39 percent.
To be fair, polls on the referendum faced an unusually high degree of difficulty. Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called for the special vote just eight days before it occurred. In between, Greece failed to meet an International Monetary Fund deadline , effectively putting itself into default and creating a genuine crisis. The lengthy, technical ballot language added another element of complexity. All together, Greece's pollsters had "some pretty good excuses," as Nate Silver put it .
Although definitive conclusions about why the polls missed in Greece will come only after the pollsters thoroughly investigate their methods and data, there are signs that the same challenges facing survey-takers elsewhere may have made a bad situation worse in Greece. Here are some reasons why the polls in Greece erred:
A late "no" trend? The public polls showed considerable volatility over the eight days between June 27, when Tsipras announced the referendum, and July 5, the day of the vote. The predicted "no" vote dropped significantly for five days before nudging back upward during the last 48 hours.
But that slight "no" trend at the end cannot explain why the polls deviated so widely from the actual results, especially since the four conducted on Election Day still understated the size of the "no" vote. Ultimately, the "yes" position received 39 percent of votes cast, far less than the estimates of more than 20 different polls conducted over the last few days of the campaign.
A hidden "no" vote? Researchers with experience in ballot referendums believe that polling often understates the number of "no" supporters -- usually, those who will vote for the status quo -- in such situations. Two highly relevant examples are the sovereignty votes in Quebec in 1995 and Scotland in 2014. In both cases, people cast far more "no" votes than polls had forecast. In both cases, those who had been undecided in earlier polling appeared to swing decisively toward "no" in the final hours of the campaign. That pattern led Canadian survey researcher Claire Durand to speculate that a "systematic bias" might exist that pollsters "will have to take into account in future referendum votes."
Yet simple math tells us that the full "no" vote could not have been hiding only among those who said they were undecided. Even if every undecided respondent went on to vote "no," poll results still exaggerated the "yes" vote.
Confusing ballot wording: Another potential problem came from the ballot wording. In the U.S., most pollsters try to replicate ballot language as closely as possible in their questions, and they struggle when that language is lengthy or confusing .
Most of the polls in Greece asked fairly straightforward questions, such as, "How will you vote in Sunday's referendum on whether to ratify the agreement that Greece's creditors offer" (as translated by the Bloomberg/Macedonia Research Institute poll ).
The actual question that voters considered was far more complex (as translated by The New York Times ):
Should the deal draft that was put forward by the European Commission, the European Central Bank and the International Monetary Fund in the Eurogroup of June 25, 2015, and consists of two parts, that together form a unified proposal, be accepted? The first document is titled Reforms for the Completion of the Current Program and Beyond and the second Preliminary Debt Sustainability Analysis.
"For those who can't read Greekdebtspeak, well, you're on your own," the BBC warned its readers after providing its own translation. The language looked "borderline surreal" to University of Chicago political scientist Stathis Kalyvas, who also noted the "irregularity" of putting the "no" option before the "yes."
Pollsters are understandably reluctant to read lengthy paragraphs to respondents over the telephone, but it is possible that questions closer to the actual ballot language might have obtained a more accurate result in this case.
Missing cell phones: Although most of the Greek polls were conducted by telephone, none of the public reports examined by The Huffington Post (in both Greek and English) made explicit reference to calling both landline and mobile phones. That doesn't mean that no pollsters were calling both landline and mobile, but those who failed to sample mobile-only households risked understating the "no" vote.
While 77 percent of Greek households have a landline phone, 18 percent are accessible by mobile phone only. According to the 2014 Eurobarometer , the European Commission report that compiled these statistics, "the main socio-demographic differences relate to age. The younger the respondents, the more likely they are to have only mobile telephone access."
The problem is that younger voters were apparently far more likely to oppose the bailout package on the ballot. Results from the Public Issue poll , re-weighted after the election to match the overall vote results, showed 85 percent of those aged 18 to 24 voting "no," compared to just 45 percent of those over 65.
That pattern alone cannot explain the polling misfire. Pollsters who failed to sample cell phones were likely weighting by age -- i.e., adjusting their data -- to account for the missing younger voters without landlines. In practice, that would entail giving greater weight to younger voters who were reachable via landline. Thus, the bigger issue is whether the younger voters with landlines had opinions different from those of their mobile-only counterparts.
Voters who didn't respond: The 2012 U.S. presidential election yielded circumstantial evidence that varying response rates can affect polling estimates. Following President Barack Obama's lackluster performance in the first debate in early October, his support fell dramatically in national polls. Many showed Republican challenger Mitt Romney pulling slightly ahead, but Obama regained a slight lead before Election Day and ultimately received a greater share of the vote than most of the national polls predicted. Research conducted among voters who were interviewed before and after the debate, however, showed few had actually changed their minds in this period. The seemingly dramatic shifts were due mostly to a difference in the willingness of partisans to be interviewed -- Obama supporters were briefly less willing to participate in polls after the first debate.
Did something similar happen in Greece last week? The initial surveys showed opposition to the bailout deal that came close to the final vote, but heavy television news coverage of the growing crisis, particularly once Greece defaulted on Wednesday , may have caused "no" voters to take a step back. Events may have led to true volatility in public opinion, but polls would have exaggerated that volatility if "no" voters were suddenly less willing to answer pollsters' questions.
In addition, as a general rule, survey response rates are lower among younger people and those with lower incomes, exactly the voters most likely to vote "no" in Greece last Sunday. Roula Nezi, a political scientist who has worked with many survey researchers in Greece and across Europe, noted that lower response rates are also typical among those hardest hit by austerity measures. "This is something we've observed in all bailout countries," she said.
At very least, some saw a possible voter backlash against apparently one-sided media coverage favoring the bailout proposal. "TV media's very open support of the YES vote seems to have discouraged them from supporting what they [the media] were suggesting," political scientist Iannis Konstantinidis told The Huffington Post via email. "Mass media are regarded as pillars of the old party system in Greece and therefore whatever they are saying is discredited."
Herding? Nate Silver sees evidence that polls "herded" toward a consensus in Greece. "Whereas the first few polls were all over the place," he wrote, "the polls began to track one another closely by a few days into the campaign. And all polls conducted on election day itself showed nearly identical results, each with 'no' ahead by 3 or 4 percentage points."
Whatever the full explanation for the misfire, Silver is right that conditions faced by pollsters in Greece were "a recipe for a polling disaster." Pundits should heed the lesson and exercise more caution in interpreting polls, especially in such a volatile environment.
Janie Velencia and Thanos Kampylis contributed reporting.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:29:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece's 'No' Is No Victory for Democracy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f43bc2/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cbernardhenri0Elevy0Cgreece0Eno0Evote0Edemocracy0Ib0I77540A860Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PARIS -- Despite what many are saying -- especially those who do not have to bear the consequences of their words -- Greek voters' rejection on Sunday of the latest bailout offer from their country's creditors did not represent a "victory for democracy." For democracy, as the Greeks know better than anyone, is a matter of mediation, representation and orderly delegation of power. It is not ordinarily a matter of referendum.</Description>
        <MainBody>

A supporter of the No vote reacts after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote celebrate after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag in front of the parliament after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote react after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote chant slogans after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote chant slogans after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote wave Greek flags after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
A supporter of the No vote shouts slogans after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
A supporter of the No vote shouts slogans after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
Supporters of the No vote celebrate after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, left, speaks with the Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos after the results of the referendum at the Presidential Palace in Athens, early Monday, July 6, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras speaks with the Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos after the results of the referendum at the Presidential Palace in Athens, early Monday, July 6, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)
A vendor sells Greek flags walks at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Three opinion polls carried out during Greece's bailout referendum, which could affect the country's future in the eurozone, indicate the "no" vote will win. Tsipras called Sunday's referendum last weekend, urging voters to reject creditor reform proposals. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote wave Greek flags after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as officials counted the results of a referendum Sunday on whether to accept creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans, with three opinion polls showing a tight race with a narrow victory likely for the "no" side. (AP Photo/Petr David Josek)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag as celebrates after the results of the referendum in Synatagma square in central Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Karadjias)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras casts his vote at a polling station in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks began voting early Sunday in a closely-watched, closely-contested referendum, which the government pits as a choice over whether to defy the country's creditors and push for better repayment terms or essentially accept their terms, but which the opposition and many of the creditors paint as a choice between staying in the euro or leaving it. (AP Photo/Petros Karadjias)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, center, speaks to the media after voting at a polling station in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks began voting early Sunday in a closely-watched, closely-contested referendum, which the government pits as a choice over whether to defy the country's creditors and push for better repayment terms or essentially accept their terms, but which the opposition and many of the creditors paint as a choice between staying in the euro or leaving it. (AP Photo/Spyros Tsakiris)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag after the referendum's exit polls at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as officials counted the results of a referendum Sunday on whether to accept creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans, with three opinion polls showing a tight race with a narrow victory likely for the "no" side. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote react after the first results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as its interior ministry predicted Sunday that more than 60 percent of voters in a hastily called referendum had rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote react after the first results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as its interior ministry predicted Sunday that more than 60 percent of voters in a hastily called referendum had rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
A woman waits to cross a street in front of an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
A woman walks past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
People walk past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015. Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
People walk past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties.(AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
A cleaner walks past display boards at the Australian Stock Exchange in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
A television journalist works in front of display boards at the Australian Stock Exchange in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
A display board at the Australian Stock Exchange flashes red indicating the losses of several names in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:20:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lion Cubs Snuggle On Journey To Safety From Gaza Refugee Camp</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f43bc6/sc/13/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Clion0Ecubs0Egaza0Efour0Epaws0In0I7756550A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Two lion cubs rescued from a ravaged Gaza zoo will be released at a wildlife sanctuary in Jordan in the fall. </Description>
        <MainBody>

Ibrahim Al-Jamal, 17, carries Mona, the female lion cub, to see her off before the two lion cubs depart from Gaza to the Erez border crossing between Israel and the Gaza Strip, in Beit Hanoun, in the northern Gaza Strip, Friday, July 3, 2015. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
In this Monday, June 15, 2015 photo, Palestinians gather around Mona, a female lion cub, while Ibrahim Al-Jamal, 17, her at the main garden in Gaza City, in the northern Gaza Strip. Saduldin al-Jamal had bought the cubs from the Gaza zoo, hit during last summer's Israel-Hamas war. His family would take them to parks or the beach and children those brave enough would come up to pet them. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
In this Monday, June 15, 2015 photo, Ibrahim Al-Jamal, 17, kisses Max, the male lion cub, while sitting inside a car in Gaza City, in the northern Gaza Strip. Saduldin al-Jamal had bought the cubs from the Gaza zoo, hit during last summer's Israel-Hamas war. His family would take them to parks or the beach and children those brave enough would come up to pet them. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
Saduldin Al-Jamal, 54, caresses Mona, the female lion cub, as Amir Khalil from the British Four Paws charity, left, talks to people gathered to see them off, as they wait to leave Gaza to the Erez border crossing between Israel and the Gaza Strip, in Beit Hanoun, in the northern Gaza Strip, Friday, July 3, 2015. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
Palestinians gather to see a lion inside a cage as Ibrahim Al-Jamal, 17, says goodbye to Mona, the female lion cub, as they wait to leave Gaza to the Erez border crossing between Israel and the Gaza Strip, in Beit Hanoun, in the northern Gaza Strip, Friday, July 3, 2015. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
Ibrahim Al-Jamal, 17, hugs Mona, the female lion cub, as his father Saduldin, 54, right, looks on, before the two lion cubs depart from Gaza to the Erez border crossing between Israel and the Gaza Strip, in Beit Hanoun, in the northern Gaza Strip, Friday, July 3, 2015. A pair of lion cubs are stuck at a Gaza-Israel border crossing en route to a Jordan animal sanctuary, after being kept for a year by a family in crowded Gaza. Saduldin al-Jamal had bought the cubs from the Gaza zoo, hit during last summer's Israel-Hamas war. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
In this Tuesday, June 16, 2015 photo, Saduldin Al-Jamal, 54, left, and his son Ibrahiml, 17, and his his grandson, Malak, 7 months, play with lion cubs Mona and Max, at his family house in Rafah refugee camp, in the southern Gaza Strip. Saduldin al-Jamal had bought the cubs from the Gaza zoo, hit during last summer's Israel-Hamas war. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
In this Monday, June 15, 2015 photo, Ahmad Abu Jereda, 16, carries Mona, the female lion cub, while walking during the sunset at the beach of Gaza City, in the northern Gaza Strip. Saduldin al-Jamal had bought the cubs from the Gaza zoo, hit during last summer's Israel-Hamas war. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
In this Monday, June 15, 2015 photo, lion cubs Mona and Max walk as children run next to them at the beach of Gaza City, in the northern Gaza Strip. Saduldin al-Jamal had bought the cubs from the Gaza zoo, hit during last summer's Israel-Hamas war. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
In this Monday, June 15, 2015 photo, Ibrahim Al-Jamal, 17, and Ahmad Abu Jereda, 16, carry Mona and Max, the female and male lion cubs, as they walk at beach of Gaza City, in the northern Gaza Strip. Saduldin al-Jamal had bought the cubs from the Gaza zoo, hit during last summer's Israel-Hamas war. (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
In this Monday, June 15, 2015 photo, Ibrahim Al-Jamal, 17, carries Mona, the female lion cub, as Max the male lion cub is petted by people on the  beach of Gaza City, in the northern Gaza Strip. Saduldin al-Jamal had bought the cubs from the Gaza zoo, hit during last summer's Israel-Hamas war.  (AP Photo/Adel Hana)
One of the cubs in Rafah.
The two cubs cuddle in a crate at their temporary home in Jordan.
The two cubs at their temporary home in Jordan.
The two cubs at their temporary home in Jordan.
The two cubs at their temporary home in Jordan.
The two cubs at their temporary home in Jordan.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:03:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Norwegians Thrive In This Small Town Where The Sun Doesn't Rise</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f3cdf0/sc/32/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A80Ctromso0Enorway0In0I77558660Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In Troms, Norway, a town 200 miles north off the Arctic Circle, the sun doesn't rise between November and January. Some who aren't used to such conditions could be </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
In Troms, Norway, a town 200 miles north off the Arctic Circle, the sun doesn't rise between November and January. Some who aren't used to such conditions could be crippled by the darkness, but when Fulbright scholar Kari Leibowitz spent a year there to research the northern town's wellbeing in such extreme environments, she learned that, for the most part, it's embraced.
In the video above, Leibowitz explains to HuffPost Live's Alyona Minkovski how Troms residents thrive with just a few hours of twilight during the "polar night."
Sign up here for Live Today, HuffPost Live's new morning email that will let you know the newsmakers, celebrities and politicians joining us that day and give you the best clips from the day before!
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:47:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How the BRICS New Development Bank Can Avoid the World Bank's Mistakes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47f3cdf4/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cmuhammad0Eyunus0Cbrics0Edevelopment0Ebank0Eworld0Ebank0Emistakes0Ib0I77564240Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At their annual summit in Russia in July this week, BRICS (Brazil, Russia, India, China, South Africa) leaders will announce the world's newest multilateral development bank -- the New Development Bank -- which will have </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
At their annual summit in Russia in July this week, BRICS (Brazil, Russia, India, China, South Africa) leaders will announce the world's newest multilateral development bank -- the New Development Bank -- which will have U.S. $100 billion as initial capital to fund infrastructure and sustainable development projects both in their own countries as well as elsewhere.
Obviously, the NDB should not become another World Bank that finances the same types of projects in the same countries, using the same tools and mindset. At the same time, its purpose should not be symbolic of emerging countries' desire to show off their financial and political power. The reason for its creation must be very substantive.
The NDB should be based on entirely new objectives, to be carried out with new strategies. It would be easy for the NDB to fall into the same track as that of the World Bank since it is in the same business. But the NDB must resist this from day one.
I am proposing some objectives for the NDB that I feel are globally relevant. The primary objectives of the NDB should be to achieve three zeros by 2050: zero poverty, zero unemployment and zero net carbon emission. Every year the NDB could publish a report on the BRICS' progress on these objectives.
The NDB could achieve these goals using four basic strategies.
The first strategy would be to unleash the creative power and commitment of the new generation of youth. If the BRICS can mobilize the power of the youth, it will become easier to achieve the goals.
The second strategy would be to focus on technological innovations to solve human problems. Technology today is under the command of moneymakers and war-makers. Socially committed drivers must take charge of technology. They are invisible today.
Combining the power of the youth with that of technology will create an unshakeable force.
This brings us to the third strategy: build up social businesses to mobilize their creative power to solve long-standing and complex social, economic and environmental problems.
Social business is a new variety of business that delinks itself from a profit motive. They are mission driven-businesses and non-dividend companies exclusively devoted to solving human problems. After the company makes profit, the investor recoups their investment money but does not take any profit after that. Additional profits made are ploughed back into the business to expand it and improve it.
Conventional businesses cannot solve social problems. Other actors such as the state and private charities may be unsustainable and inefficient. Social businesses are sustainable, efficient, replicable and transferable.
I have been creating and promoting this type of business around the world with great results. I believe that the social business model should be the centerpiece of the NDB's institutional structure and policy package. It is a model that can easily be replicated across a number of contexts.
In fact, unemployment can be brought down to zero through social business initiatives. Unemployment is the product of a flawed interpretation of human beings as per the theoretical framework of economics. Human beings are not job-seekers, they are entrepreneurs by birth. Entrepreneurship is in the DNA human beings. They are go-getters and problem solvers. Social business can turn the unemployed into entrepreneurs. We are doing that in Bangladesh. The NDB can adopt this as its prime program.
Once the NDB creates a new window for financing and promoting social businesses, it will attract the young, old, men, women, individuals and organizations with social business ideas. It can encourage each conventional business to undertake social businesses alongside their main business activities.
The NDB could create country-level social business funds as joint ventures with local partners. It can create provincial level social business funds in which it holds a minor equity with majority equity coming from local investors.
Ensuring financial services to the poor, healthcare to the poor and hard to reach people can be done through creating social businesses.
While the NDB will undertake many types of infrastructure projects, it should give serious consideration to the ownership and maintenance of these infrastructures. We now have examples of major infrastructures being owned by moneymakers. In the old days, this was the exclusive preserve of governments. Apart from government ownership and commercial ownership, there is now a new type of ownership: ownership by social businesses. From the perspective of its users, ownership by social businesses will be much more satisfying than the other two alternatives.
Finally, human rights and good governance should lie at the heart of the NDB's operations.
At its inception, the NDB has the opportunity to create the right objectives and appropriate strategies for their implementation.
I wish the NDB every success in redesigning the world to make it sustainable.
Close
Where The Super-Rich Population Is Exploding
of


Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022: 88 percent  (Source: Wealth-X, via Knight Frank)  (SANKA VIDANAGAMA/AFP/Getty Images)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:99 percent  (Spencer Platt/Getty Images)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:101 percent  (SAJJAD HUSSAIN/AFP/Getty Images)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:107 percent  (AP Photo/Heng Sinith)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:125 percent  (AP Photo/Karim Kadim)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:137 percent  (AP Photo/Eugene Hoshiko)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:138 percent  (Photo by Shaun Botterill/Getty Images)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:179 percent  (GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:226 percent  (AP Photo/Ouahab Hebbat)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:281 percent  (AP Photo/Tsvangirayi Mukwazhi)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:305 percent  (TONY KARUMBA/AFP/Getty Images)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:310 percent  (AP Photo/Tsvangirayi Mukwazhi)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:369 percent  (Photo by Paula Bronstein/Getty Images)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:402 percent  (ROMEO GACAD/AFP/Getty Images)
Projected increase in the number of high-net-worth individuals between 2012 and 2022:687 percent  (Photo by Paula Bronstein/Getty Images)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
