<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="irishtimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:00:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Grubbs: 19th-century Irish stargazers</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/science/the-grubbs-19th-century-irish-stargazers-1.2272676</Link>
        <Description>The Grubb family pioneered telescope manufacturing in the early 19th century from their Dublin base   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
The Grubbs: 19th-century Irish stargazers
The Grubb family pioneered telescope manufacturing in the early 19th century from their Dublin base
Thomas Grubb: his apparent lack of formal education did not prevent him from tinkering with telescopes and becoming an astronomical observer
Juliana Adelman
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 03:00

I always associate stargazing with summer, when we were allowed to stay up late while vacationing far enough away from city lights to get a good view of a meteor shower. In fact, winter is a much better time of year to see celestial objects.
Still, if you can manage to stay up until it is fully dark, you might catch the Delta Aquariads meteor shower this month. If you do, you will be joining a long history of stargazing and amateur astronomy. Both of these activities experienced a heyday during the 19th century as the technical skills needed to produce large lenses and mirrors, and thus larger telescopes, improved dramatically.
The Grubb family were among the most talented innovators. Their telescope and instrument factory was based in Dublin, but they contributed to telescopes in India, Australia, South Africa and the Crimea as well as Greenwich and Dublin.
Astronomy in the early 19th century was dominated by the gentleman amateur. Thomas Grubbs apparent lack of formal education did not prevent him from tinkering with telescopes and becoming an astronomical observer himself. He probably gained knowledge of engineering and instrument-making through experience. His early business made not only telescopes but parts for billiard tables. Thomas eventually entered into a correspondence with Irelands premier astronomer at the time, Thomas Romney Robinson, who was director of Armagh Observatory. Robinson assisted Thomas in gaining early commissions, including modifications to Lord Rosses Leviathan telescope at Parsonstown.
Thomass son, Howard Grubb (1844-1931), was sent to Trinity College for an academic version of engineering. However, he was withdrawn to assist his father in casting a 4ft mirror for the Great Melbourne telescope and did not return. That telescope was the making of the Grubb enterprise, and the commission was one example of a shift towards government-sponsored observatories and away from the gentleman amateur.

Astronomical growth
Another major change over the lifetime of the Grubbs business was the great expansion of the British empire and the involvement of Irish men and women in it. As European empires grew, so too did the territories open to scientific endeavour.
Astronomers became part of the network of imperial scientists, and astronomical observatories sprung up across European colonial territories.
Of particular interest was astronomical observation in the southern hemisphere. As explorers and colonisers were filling in the terrestrial map, astronomers sought to do the same with the celestial one. Southern hemisphere telescopes could see parts of the sky that those in the northern hemisphere could not.
In 1887, an international congress of astronomers representing 19 countries took advantage of this network to begin an ambitious project. They proposed a photographic Map of the Sky, with photographs taken through specially designed telescopes. Each observatory was assigned a specific portion of the sky to photograph. The Grubbs created astrographic telescopes for several of the observatories, but the project was not completed until 1964.
Scientific astronomy now benefits from different ways of visualising the cosmos, including radio waves. Nonetheless, huge mirrors and large telescopes remain important. In 2014, construction began on the European Extremely Large Telescope at the European Southern Observatory in Chile. The name basically says it all: instead of a Grubbs 4ft-6ft mirror, this telescope will have a mirror of 39m in diameter. No one has found a way to cast (or indeed transport) a mirror of this size. Instead it will be composed of almost 800 smaller hexagonal mirrors.
Howard Grubb continued to produce instruments, including submarine periscopes, throughout the first World War. Soon after the war he left the business, but the name continued in the firm of Grubb-Parsons, which made telescopes until its closure in 1985.

Tribute: I would like to dedicate this column to the memory of Ian Elliott, a solar physicist at Dunsink Observatory and historian, who died in May. Ian was a frequent contributor to conferences and publications on the history of Irish science. This article draws on Ian Elliotts Grubbs of Dublin: Telescope Makers to the World in J Adelman and E Agnew (eds), Science and Technology in Nineteenth-Century Ireland (2011).

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 05:00:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explore space from the comfort of your home</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/science/explore-space-from-the-comfort-of-your-home-1.2272647</Link>
        <Description>Spacehack.org helps people to find ways to contribute to space research. No formal training is required</Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Explore space from the comfort of your home
Spacehack.org helps people to find ways to contribute to space research. No formal training is required
Ariel Waldman at Inspirefest in Dublin recently: I want to give people the same realisation that I had a few years ago in discovering that I could contribute to space exploration in a meaningful way despite not having a background in it. Photograph: Conor McCabe Photography
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 03:00

Wouldnt it be fascinating to help find a previously undiscovered black hole? Or to pave the way towards human exploration of Mars? Well you can, and you dont have to leave your computer to do it.
In a bid to make such projects more accessible, US-based Ariel Waldman set up the website Spacehack.org as a directory of ways to participate in space exploration, whether or not you have formal training in science or engineering.
Waldman started the directory in 2008 after she worked with Nasa and saw the many ways people could contribute to space work. She wanted to put those opportunities at peoples fingertips.
The strange dynamic of Plutos chaotic family
Among her favourite initiatives listed on Spacehack.org is Galaxy Zoo Radio, a project that asks for help classifying black holes at different stages so as to better understand their evolution, but whats really exciting is that you might be able to discover black holes that havent yet been seen by anyone, she says.
Another is the multidisciplinary Austrian Space Forum, which focuses on generating research that could help humans one day live on Mars. They look for volunteers from all different disciplines to help navigate all the challenges that are anticipated to crop up when humans are on Mars: everything from testing spacesuit materials to how we could search for life, to psychological aspects, says Waldman, who was in Dublin recently to speak at the Inspirefest2015 conference.
Other projects listed on Spacehack.org include Moon Zoo, which asks people to classify lunar craters; Milky Way Project, which asks people to find bubbles, star clusters and unusual characteristics in infrared images acquired from the Spitzer Space Telescope; and Spacelog, which asks volunteers to help put information from early space flights online in order to digitally preserve those historic missions.
Waldman, who has been honoured at the White House for her work, says there was an overwhelmingly positive reaction when Spacehack.org was set up. I think a lot of people saw it as a signal of an emerging area, she says. It has been encouraging to see new projects emerge from completely different disciplines within space exploration, [such as] astrobiology, astrophysics, rover design and satellite experiments.
Her wish for the space site directory is modest, she says. I simply want to give people the same realisation that I had a few years ago in discovering that I could contribute to space exploration in a meaningful way despite not having a background in it, she says.
I think by having a fresh set of eyes from those who solve different types of problems across a variety of industries inside and outside of science, new concepts often emerge and go on to influence science in unexpected ways.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>State spends €3m a year abroad for care of  young people</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/state-spends-3m-a-year-abroad-for-care-of-young-people-1.2278152</Link>
        <Description>Woman (20) detained for  20 months in psychiatric unit in England returns home   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
State spends 3m a year abroad for care of  young people
Woman (20) detained for  20 months in psychiatric unit in England returns home
The HSE has pledged to develop services to ensure that no Irish citizen should need to be sent overseas for a care placement. Photograph: Jean-Philippe Ksiazek/AFP/Getty Images
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Irish authorities have been spending about 3 million a year on facilities abroad to provide care for vulnerable young people due to a lack of specialised services here.
The issue of care abroad has been the focus of attention after a judge on Tuesday granted a young Irish womans plea for her return to Ireland after being detained for more than 20 months in a specialised psychiatric unit in England against her wishes.
Varadkar stands by his claim of lower hospital waiting times
The 18-year-old woman, who has a borderline personality disorder and who has tried take her own life, is understood to have returned to Ireland on Wednesday and will reside in a psychiatric facility on a voluntary basis.
She has spent almost all of the last four years in various psychiatric units in Ireland and England.
Latest available figures show that in 2013 health authorities spent about 3.5 million on care places abroad.
Eight young people were placed in St Andrews, Northampton, a specialist service which provides care and support to people with conditions ranging from mental health problems to autism. The cost for each child is about 375,000 a year.
Another child at the time was placed in St Marys in Scotland , a residential service for children with emotional and behavioural difficulties. The cost was 414,000 year.
Criticised
Boystown in Nebraska in the US is another centre which has been used by social services in Ireland. One child was resident there at the time, at a cost of 133,000 a year.
The practice of sending vulnerable young people abroad for treatment has been criticised by campaigners, who say these services should be available in Ireland.
The HSE has pledged to develop services to ensure that no Irish citizen should need to be sent overseas for a care placement.
However, latest figures show authorities are still required to look abroad to find specialised treatment programmes for some children with difficult or challenging behaviour.
Health and social authorities, however, say children placed abroad represent a tiny proportion of the thousands of young people in the care or health system.
Proceedings
Legal proceedings, meanwhile, concerning the care and treatment of the 18-year-old girl at the centre of this weeks case are estimated at more than 1 million.
In delivering his ruling, Mr Justice Samus Noonan said such costs would have afforded a purpose-built unit for her here.
When asked whether the HSEs handling of the case would be reviewed in light of legal expenditure, the executive released a brief statement. It said it involved difficult and complex circumstances and was subject of oversight by the courts.
Patients who require specialised treatment not available in this country can be referred to mental health services abroad where clinically indicated. Patients being treated abroad often have a complex and broad range of conditions, the statement said.
The case itself was before the courts over a number of months. Last March, the High Court directed an arrangement should be put in place for her return to Ireland by June 12th last.
The HSE subsequently brought further proceedings arguing her circumstances had changed since the March order of Ms Justice Bronagh OHanlon.
Those circumstances included a view of some doctors that she could not be kept safe in the Irish services and should remain in the UK unit, where high levels of security could be put in place.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Howlin rejects call for extra €1 billion for health services</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/howlin-rejects-call-for-extra-1-billion-for-health-services-1.2278049</Link>
        <Description>Minister for Public Expenditure responds to  Varadkar request for supplementary funds   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Howlin rejects call for extra 1 billion for health services
Minister for Public Expenditure responds to  Varadkar request for supplementary funds
Minister for Public Expenditure  Brendan Howlin. Photograph: Eric Luke/The Irish Times
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Minister for Public Expenditure Brendan Howlin has reacted coolly to Minister for Health Leo Varadkars call for an extra 1 billion to meet existing health service demands.
A billion seems to be the annual figure that ministers for health demand. Its a nice round figure, Mr Howlin said.
For the four years Im here its been the sum looked for . . . we havent spare billions to give to anybody.
Existing health demands require extra 1bn, says Varadkar
Mr Howlin was speaking at the launch of a progress report on the Civil Service Renewal Plan on Tuesday.
He said a significant supplementary estimate was allocated to the Department of Health last year, because of the recovery of the economy.
Existing needs
Writing in The Irish Times last week, Mr Varadkar said meeting existing, unmet needs would cost between 700 million and 1 billion, on top of the natural increase needed every year to cope with a rising and ageing population.
This would restore health budgets to where they were eight years ago, he said.
Meanwhile, the Governments capital plan, due to be published before the Dil recess, has been delayed until early September.
The plan will announce funding for roads, flood defences and housing.
Mr Howlin has also confirmed he has written to all departments setting out budgetary parameters.
Were already working obviously on the October budget, he said.
Ive had a number of bilateral meetings on the capital plan, obviously with all colleagues, multiple meetings with some colleagues.
I havent started bilateral meetings in relation to the current expenditure side yet.
The letters sent on Tuesday would kick off the process, he said.
Mr Howlin said he could not further reduce the pensions of former ministers and taoisigh, following controversy over an increase in some six-figure pensions as part of the unwinding of emergency financial measures.
Senior politicians were paid too much ahead of the last election and the sums had been dramatically reduced, he said.
I pointed out to the Taoiseach his salary is 40 per cent less than his predecessor. My salary is 35 per cent less than my predecessor.
He said the problem was that pensions were based on an end-of-career salary.
Under our Constitution pensions are preserved property rights.
I can no more take somebodys pension than I can arbitrarily decide to take their house, he said.
He said he had sought a general application for the reduction of pensions under emergency financial measures.
I have begun to unwind that for the lowest pension cohort but I cant exclude anybody from that . . . it has to have general application.
Marginal tax rates
The secretary general of Mr Howlins department, Robert Watt , added: The gross changes obviously dont take account of the marginal tax rates and the pension levy. So its not correct to say the former taoiseach is getting 1,600 extra. Theyre not, theyre getting less than half of that.
Turning to the first progress report of the Civil Service Renewal Plan, Mr Watt said some 90 economics graduates had been recruited over the last three years and the recruitment would continue.
He highlighted developments such as the establishment of an accountability board, along with the first performance review process for secretaries general.
Options to strengthen the disciplinary code had been identified and open recruitment had been extended in key areas to fill skills gaps.
When we launched the plan we said that the Irish civil service had many attributes. Its been very effective, particularly during the crisis, in supporting the Government and getting through the difficulties that we faced, Mr Watt said.
But of course were very ambitious for the service, and we recognised that we had lots of strengths but we also had weaknesses.
The plan was building on the strengths while addressing the weaknesses, he added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miriam Lord: Anglo golf day puts Cowen in the rough</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/miriam-lord-anglo-golf-day-puts-cowen-in-the-rough-1.2278270</Link>
        <Description>‘Picture the scene: the guys in    casual slacks,  swapping deep thoughts on fiscal matters’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Miriam Lord: Anglo golf day puts Cowen in the rough
Picture the scene: the guys in    casual slacks,  swapping deep thoughts on fiscal matters
Former taoiseach Brian Cowen. File photograph: Eric Luke/The Irish Times
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
An ordinary afternoon of golf, it seemed.
Picture the scene: the guys in their neatly pressed casual slacks and Pringle sweaters, sauntering around the course, shootin the breeze and swapping deep thoughts about fiscal matters.
Just the taoiseach and a few directors of Anglo Irish Bank .
Live blog: Banking inquiry
Brian Cowen was a bit worried at the time. The national bottom-line was taking a bit of battering.
So he thought it would be a good idea to talk to a few people who were experienced in the whole money thing. They might give him some useful ideas. A few tips and pointers.
As a former minister for finance, Cowen (being a very sociable man) might have been expected to have had an extensive list of contacts to call upon.
But not so, it seems. Instead, a good pal, Fintan Drury, formerly of Anglo, suggested hed get a few lads together for him.
Funnily enough, Brian says he met Fintan regularly because they know each other for years, but they never talked about bank stuff. Was Cowen surprised when the people suggested by his high-flying mate were all bankers?
It was nearing the end of July, the Dil term was coming to a close and the taoiseach was about to take his summer break.
Fintan suggested he could kill two birds with the one stone and start his holiday on the golf course while having that discussion he wanted.
In hindsight, it was a perfect match. The economy was going down the tubes. Anglo Irish Bank was going down the tubes. With so much in common they must have had plenty to talk about.
As it happened, then Anglo chairman Sen FitzPatrick and his colleagues had come to the taoiseachs notice some months earlier, before he had taken over the top job.
He had been alerted to major problems in Anglos operation  the share price had collapsed and rumours about Sen Quinns massive debts were causing big trouble.
FitzPatrick personally rang the then minister for finance to tell him how bad things were looking. Brian told him to get in touch with the regulatory authorities.
And he didnt concern himself with Anglo after that. But the rumours about the bank didnt go away. In fact, they gathered pace.
Conspiracy theories
During his second appearance at the Oireachtas banking inquiry yesterday, Cowen took offence at suggestions that he had discussed Anglos problems with his golfing partners in Druids Glen.
He doesnt buy into conspiracy theories that insinuate contact equals nefarious collusion.
It was economic issues. It was nothing about Anglo Irish Bank at all. As God is my witness. And thats the truth.
We believe him. Its incredible enough to be true.
No. According to the former taoiseach there were plenty of other topics they could have discussed. Employment was on the rise for example.
Any ideas there for the taoiseach from his playing partners?
Theres something macabrely comic about the idea of Sen FitzPatrick advising on job creation when he must have known his overblown financial institution was about to collapse, leading to the loss of countless jobs  directly and indirectly.
But then again, this was the same FitzPatrick who thought nothing about delivering a speech in November, when the banks were guaranteed, calling for cuts to the sacred cows of child benefit and universal pensions.
So Senie knew that Cowen knew that Senie knew that. . . And not one person in that golfing group mentioned a thing about the ailing bank. Perhaps the Anglo boys were dying to bring it up in conversation and the taoiseach pretended not to hear.
What we do know is that when the politician and the money men left Druids Glen, the course was in a terrible state.
Greens ploughed up, divots the size of bunkers everywhere, huge dungheaps all over the fairways.
But then, thats what happens when theres an elephant in your golfing party and nobody chooses to notice it.
Chaos in Merrion Street
Cowens testimony pointed to chaos in Government Buildings in the hours leading up to the bank guarantee. The weeks preceding it didnt sound much better.
Although the ship was going down, the taoiseach seemed content to leave decisions and actions to others, rather than assuming a captains role.
He only contacted one outsider on the night, Alan Gray, who was on the board of the Central bank . Hed been on that golf outing too. Cowen valued his advice.
When the taoiseach telephoned him, Gray never mentioned to him that FitzPatrick and then Anglo chief executive David Drumm had come to see him in his office that afternoon.
This happened a lot to Cowen: people didnt seem to keep him in the loop.
He still isnt in the loop, because no record remains of that night in September, because no note was taken. Im sorry there isnt a record, he admitted.
Then there was the story of the two representatives from the National Treasury Management Agency , who had been summoned to the Department of Finance and had been kept waiting outside the crisis meeting, until they were finally sent away.
Was the taoiseach aware they were present? They might have offered valuable advice?
He hadnt a clue they were there. I wouldnt have known who was outside the door until they came in the door.
Amid these charged scenes  It was an emotional time  recalled Cowen, it was decided to hold a cabinet meeting in the early hours of the morning by ringing all the ministers and asking them to agree to the guarantee.
Again, the former taoiseach regrets doing this. He feels he should have held a proper meeting at 6am.
Thats what happens in a crisis. It moves and takes on a life of its own.
When his government decided to accept a bailout, again, Cowen admits there was political miscalculation and miscommunication in not informing the public earlier.
He was certainly not served well by his regulators and some of his advisors. He believed there were sufficient buffers to meet the situation.
Plenty of old buffers all right, but none willing to move fast and take swift remedial action before the crisis spiralled completely out of control.
As Cowen explained what happened, there was no doubting his determination to do the best for the country he served.
And though there was a lot of waffle and hot air from him yesterday, the situation he faced as leader of the country was an unenviable one.
Could things have been handled better? Could the committees hotshots  none of whom had ministerial experience  have done a better job?
Cowen didnt do a good job as taoiseach. The whole daft episode at Druids Glen goes some way towards explaining it.
If he didnt ask FitzPatrick and his directors questions, he should have. Given the banks difficulties, he should never have accepted the invitation. As for seeking their advice?
In retrospect, was it poor judgment on your behalf? asked Kieran ODonnell.
He didnt answer.
Of course it was.
What has motivated me throughout all my political career is to serve my country. I never compromised my political integrity or breached the public trust, he said in his closing remarks.
Few would dispute that.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 100 breaches of HSE patient data in past year</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/health/more-than-100-breaches-of-hse-patient-data-in-past-year-1.2278079</Link>
        <Description>In one case,   community services worker lost client report after leaving it on    roof of car   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
More than 100 breaches of HSE patient data in past year
In one case,   community services worker lost client report after leaving it on    roof of car
More than 100 data protection breaches involving sensitive personal information held by the HSE occurred over the past year. File photograph: Getty Images/iStockphoto
Darragh McDonagh, Brian McDonald
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
More than 100 data protection breaches involving sensitive personal information held by the Health Service Executive (HSE) occurred over the past year, internal documents indicate.
Details of the incidents, which occurred between April 1st, 2014 and April 1st, 2015, have been released under the Freedom of Information Act.
They include a case in Cork, where patient files were discovered by a member of the public in the drawer of a filing cabinet they had purchased in a second-hand furniture shop in June 2014.
The incident was notified to the Data Protection Commissioner .
In Sligo, a diary containing sensitive client information was misplaced by a community services worker but was later found on the roof of her car.
However, a sealed envelope containing an assessment report that had been placed in the diary was not recovered.
Wrong documentation
Last November, data relating to 19 patients at Wexford General Hospital was found on the grounds of a housing estate.
Affected parties were contacted by telephone and a meeting was held with doctors who had generated the report.
A number of incidents were reported in which the wrong patients were issued with the wrong documentation.
This occurred at HSE South Community Addiction Services in Cork last February, where two clients received each others correspondence.
In Limerick, a letter confirming a hospital appointment was mistakenly issued to the twin of a patient on two occasions in 2014.
The incident resulted in staff being reminded of the importance of checking all patient details when creating appointments.
Autism assessment
Last September, an autism assessment report concerning a child was accidentally posted to the parents of another child.
An apology was issued but a similar incident occurred in March, when a report on a five-year-old with autism was put in the wrong envelope, along with another childs report, and posted to the wrong family.
Both incidents were notified to the Data Protection Commissioner and the HSE noted that the affected family will not be taking the matter any further.
In Cavan/ Monaghan Mental Health Services, a folder containing clinical letters went missing from a consultants clinic last November.
The folder was found in a photocopying room but the letters were not recovered.
In total, 103 incidents involving data protection breaches occurred between April 1st, 2014, and April 1st, 2015.
As many as 16 laptops and phones containing confidential data were also reported lost or stolen by HSE staff.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Government considers proposal on undocumented migrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/government-considers-proposal-on-undocumented-migrants-1.2278107</Link>
        <Description>Officials  review programme aimed at regularising  the status of up to 20,000   residents   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Government considers proposal on undocumented migrants
Officials  review programme aimed at regularising  the status of up to 20,000   residents
Demonstrators in Dublin  supporting the undocumented in Ireland. File photograph: Eric Luke/The Irish Times
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Department of Justice officials are considering a proposal aimed at regularising the status of up to 20,000 undocumented migrants living and working in the Republic.
The proposal, drawn up by the Migrant Rights Centre of Ireland (MRCI) in consultation with Department of Justice officials, is described as a once-off, time-bound regularisation scheme which offers a problem-solving solution to an unsustainable situation.
Research indicates a large majority of the undocumented people living in the Republic entered the country legally on visas in recent years and subsequently became undocumented.
The most common nationalities among undocumented people living here include people from the Philippines , China , Mauritius , Brazil and Pakistan .
A spokesman for Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald said the proposal was being considered.
The Department of Justice has traditionally opposed any large-scale measures to regularise the status of migrants and has examined individuals on a case by case basis.
However, former minister for justice Alan Shatter has expressed support for regularisation measures.
Migrant residents
The latest proposal would be eligible only to those resident here over the past four years and would exclude anyone with a serious criminal conviction.
A two-year probationary period would apply and, on exiting the scheme, the person granted residency could earn their way to citizenship.
Individuals would not have access to social security or social housing during the period, in common with existing rules on the need for housing applicants to be habitually resident here.
The scheme also claims to have the potential to generate almost 20 million in the form of registration fees.
It estimates a further 165 million in employer PRSI contributions could be raised by those able to move out of the shadow economy.
Helen Lowry of the MRCI said undocumented men, women and children in Ireland had the same struggles, hopes and dreams as undocumented Irish in the United States .
Many are here long-term, working, paying taxes and rearing families. The improving economy and the significant length of time undocumented migrants have lived here make this an opportune time for a comprehensive solution.
Significant problems
The MRCIs research indicates that undocumented migrants encounter significant problems in accessing basic and essential services, such as health and education. They also remain unable to leave the country to visit extended families.
The centre says it is particularly concerned about the vulnerable situation of the estimated 5,000 children of undocumented migrants, many of whom have gone to school here yet face an uncertain future.
In all, the centre estimates there are between 20,000 and 26,000 undocumented migrants living here at present.
Most are working, according to research, while more than a half of adults have third-level education.
A large majority (81 per cent) have been in Ireland for five years or more.
Department officials have previously said the Republic is a country which welcomes non-nationals, with more than 80,000 people naturalised over the past four years.
But they have pointed out that the State is entitled to expect that people coming to the Republic will obey our immigration laws, and that most people become undocumented through their own conscious actions or omissions.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Horizons prepares for a close encounter with mysterious Pluto</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/science/new-horizons-prepares-for-a-close-encounter-with-mysterious-pluto-1.2272698</Link>
        <Description>Much of our understanding of Pluto is educated guesswork. That should change when a probe completes its flyby of the dwarf planet on July 14th</Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
New Horizons prepares for a close encounter with mysterious Pluto
Much of our understanding of Pluto is educated guesswork. That should change when a probe completes its flyby of the dwarf planet on July 14th
Artists concept of the New Horizons spacecraft as it approaches Pluto
The launch of New Horizons in January 2006. Photograph: Bruce Weaver/AFP/Getty Images
Previous Image
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00

On July 14th, the Nasa space probe New Horizons will make its closest flyby over the dwarf planet Pluto and begin its first scientific observations in a mission that has been nine years and 4.67 billion miles in the making.
The spacecraft hopes to shed light on one of the least-known bodies in our solar system. It primary mission will be to chart both the surface and the atmosphere of Pluto. It also marks the first in-depth space exploration of its kind since Voyager 2 explored Neptune in 1989.
This is probably the last opportunity for such a significant step, from knowing nothing about one of the traditional worlds to knowing quite a lot about it in a very short space of time says Kevin Nolan , lecturer in physics at Institute of Technology Tallaght . This will fill in the last link in terms of major solar-system bodies. It can add a complete picture, and that can help us in terms of how we travel in space in the future. This mission  combined with others such as Rosetta  are starting to fill in a complete picture of the solar system.
It adds to the broader understanding of who we are in the cosmic context.

The probe awakens
The probe, which was launched at Cape Canaveral in January 2006, is the first in Nasas $700 million New Horizons programme.
The spacecraft carrying the probe used the gravity of Jupiter to swing itself forward through space, saving itself three years of flight time. For most of its seven years travelling through space, the probe remained mostly dormant, sending only the occasional message back to mission control that all was well, and running tests to ensure its equipment was working correctly. It was only fully woken up in December last year as it began its final stages of approach to Pluto.
New Horizons is continuing from where the Voyager missions left off in the 1970s, says Dr Apostolos Christou of Armagh Observatory. Its like finishing a chapter of solar system exploration.
Although now considered a dwarf planet (it was downgraded just seven months after the probe was launched), Pluto still holds a lot of intrigue for astronomers. Much of our current understanding of Plutos surface and atmosphere is educated guesswork. It was only in April that the probe was able to get the very first close-range colour image of Pluto and its moon Charon.
We have actually visited most other locales in the solar system, says Christou. But weve never been to one of those trans-Neptunian objects. Its a real voyage of discovery because nobody knows what were going to find. The best telescopes on the Earth cant put [together] more than a few pixels.

Ice, rock and methane
When it makes its closest pass at 11.57am, the probe will be 12,500km from the surface of Pluto. It is thought to be composed mostly of ice and rock, although astronomers think the atmosphere is rich enough in methane gas to create winds on Pluto. It can then characterise specific details on the surface as well as the various temperatures of its surface.
If you look at the instruments on board, they range from viewable cameras to infrared cameras, to radio monitoring to particle detectors, says Nolan. We will get a huge amount of signs about what Pluto is made of and therefore how it came about.
The probe carries links with its past: on board are some of the ashes of Plutos discoverer, Clyde W Tombaugh. One of the scientific devices has been named after Venetia Burney Phair, the woman who named the planet when she was 11 years old.
After charting Pluto, the probe could go on to investigate other objects in the area that interest Nasa. It could also travel outwards beyond the solar system much in the way Voyager 1 travelled beyond the solar system after completing its mission of charting Neptune.
When this final phase of space exploration ends, a new one will open up. Going to Pluto now sets a new goal for a new generation says Nolan. The next generation will have to think far wider, and indeed even into interstellar space.


CUT DOWN TO SIZE: HOW PLANET PLUTO BECAME A DWARF
Pluto was discovered in 1930 by American astronomer Clyde W Tombaugh, based on the hypotheses of two previous astronomers who wanted to explain an orbital wobble observed in Plutos closest neighbour, Neptune. However, just 76 years later, it would lose this honour to become what is now known as a dwarf planet. What went wrong?
The main problem stemmed from the very term planet. The word had been left almost intentionally vague for most of human history. Until recently, many were content to put that label on whatever rotated around the sun and could be found with the naked eye or, later, telescopes.
It was Pluto that caused the modern debate about what exactly constitutes a planet. After it was discovered at an Arizona observatory, initial calculations put Plutos mass as equal to the Earths. However, as astronomical equipment and techniques improved throughout the century, this calculation was lowered to less than 1 per cent: smaller than our moon.
Things became worse in 1978, when Plutos moon Charon was discovered. Charon is more than half Plutos size and remarkably close to it; a flight from Ireland to Australia covers roughly the same distance. This led some astronomers to call Pluto a double dwarf planet: two mini-planets that act as one. As the number of moons rose to five, serious debate about the future of planet Pluto began to be discussed.
In 2006 the International Astronomical Union released its formal definition of a planet as something that:
(1) revolves around the sun
(2) has enough mass to form a round shape
(3) has cleared the neighbourhood around its orbit.
It is this third condition that Pluto failed to meet. Pluto moves around countless large asteroids and debris along its path, an area in the outer solar system known as the Kuiper Belt.
While New Horizons wont help to disprove Pluto as being a dwarf planet, astronomers will soon find out just how planet-like it is.
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Temporary order to take three children into care </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/district-court/temporary-order-to-take-three-children-into-care-1.2278133</Link>
        <Description>Social worker found children in home with little food, no bedsheets and no toys to play with   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Temporary order to take three children into care
Social worker found children in home with little food, no bedsheets and no toys to play with
At the Dublin District Family Court, Judge Rosemary Horgan was told two of the children had missed 12 weeks of school since September. Photograph: Michaela Rehle/Reuters
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Three children have been taken into the care of the Child and Family Agency after a social worker found there was little food in their home, no sheets on one childs bed and no toys for them to play with.
At the Dublin District Family Court , Judge Rosemary Horgan was told two of the children had missed 12 weeks of school since September and the baby had developmental delays and was in his buggy every time social workers called.
The infant had missed vaccinations, had no cot and slept in a double bed, the social worker told the court, while the mother slept on a couch downstairs. One of the children had missed 10 appointments for an eye problem, which could lead to long-term damage. Although there was a prescription for glasses, he had none, the court heard.
Unannounced
At an unannounced visit to the home last month, the social worker said there was little evidence of food and rooms were dirty. There was a build-up of rubbish in the back garden and the dog had brought in two rats.
The court heard the mother, who was consenting to an interim care order, was coping with the death of her partner and had chaotic drug use, which resulted in the childrens needs being neglected. But she had taken the initiative to address her problems, was on methadone, seeing a counsellor and awaiting a bed in a drugs rehabilitation unit.
They are lovely children, mannerly and smiling, and they get that from their mother, the social worker said. Shes going through a bad patch, but theres no doubt shell turn that around.
The mother told Judge Horgan she hoped to move out of her current area once finished rehabilitation. I want to start a new life, she said.
The judge said there had been a lot of good parenting as well as a bump in the road. The mother had identified her problems and put the welfare of her children first by agreeing to the care order. She made an order until September.
Rejected plan
In a separate case, Judge Horgan rejected an aftercare plan for a girl who is soon to turn 18 after her court-appointed guardian said she was in danger of becoming homeless.
The court heard the agency intended to move the teenager from a residential unit to a private apartment with 25 hours of support services a week.
The social work team leader gave evidence of difficulties the agency has finding private apartments. He said they top up rent above the social welfare rate, but even if they are prepared to pay 1,000 a month for a one-bedroom unit, they still have difficulty. He said the landlord of the teenagers apartment said if there was any anti-social behaviour, she would have to leave within seven days.
The teenagers guardian said, given her issue with drugs, which she denies, there was a possibility the teenager could be asked to leave the apartment.
I always find it hard to understand how we support the kids who are least vulnerable, but drop the kids who are most vulnerable, she said.
Judge Horgan said she wanted to see a robust plan for the teenager before adjourning the case for two weeks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>TD calls for facilities to allow elderly to live in their communities </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/td-calls-for-facilities-to-allow-elderly-to-live-in-their-communities-1.2278186</Link>
        <Description>Sixteen per cent of population will be aged over 65 in 10 years, deputy tells Dáil    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
TD calls for facilities to allow elderly to live in their communities
Sixteen per cent of population will be aged over 65 in 10 years, deputy tells Dil
A recent report by the Alone organisation showed more than a third of older people in long-term nursing homes had low to medium dependency needs. Photograph: John Stillwell/PA Wire
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Independent TD Tom Fleming called for the provision of supportive housing and nursing facilities to allow the elderly live in their communities.
By 2026 it is envisaged that 16 per cent of the population will be aged over 65, compared with the current figure of 11 per cent, said Mr Fleming.
While nursing home care is the only option for many high- dependency patients, the existing model of prioritising that type of care is not sustainable into the future.
He said it was vital to ensure sufficient funds were set aside in the budget for the Fair Deal scheme. In addition, there must be sufficient funding for the extra respite and acute hospital beds that were needed to solve overcrowding, he added.
These matters can be addressed in the short term but the demographic issue requires a long-term approach, he said.
Dependency needs
Mr Fleming said a recent report by the Alone organisation, which helps elderly people in need, showed more than a third of older people in long-term nursing homes had low to medium dependency needs.
This means they could live at home if provided with adequate home care, he added.
Taoiseach Enda Kenny said discussions around the budget were a matter for the Ministers for Finance and Public Expenditure and Reform.
All of that will take place, including public engagement with different sectors, over the next while, he added.
He said this years Health Service Executive service plan made reference to progressing the realignment of services to provide home and community care services to maximise the opportunity for older people to remain in their homes for as long as possible.
Currently, 10.3 million hours of home help services were provided, supporting 50,000 people. There were 13,800 people now in receipt of homecare packages, including 600 people who were supported under the delayed discharges initiative, said Mr Kenny .
He said 190 people were receiving intensive homecare packages at any time.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>RNLI releases videos for new drowning prevention campaign</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/rnli-releases-videos-for-new-drowning-prevention-campaign-1.2278240</Link>
        <Description>An average of 59 people die accidentally in Irish waters annually, RNLI figures shows   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
RNLI releases videos for new drowning prevention campaign
An average of 59 people die accidentally in Irish waters annually, RNLI figures shows
The Royal National Lifeboat Institution is releasing two videos as part of a new drowning prevention campaign. Photograph: Getty Images/Design Pics
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Dangerously unpredictable conditions in water and the impact of cold shock are themes of two hard-hitting film clips which the Royal National Lifeboat Institution (RNLI) is releasing on Thursday as part of a new drowning prevention campaign.
The two 60-second films are rated for audiences of 15 years and over, and will be screened in Irish cinemas over the summer months.
Figures released by the lifeboat organisation show an average of 59 people die accidentally in Irish waters annually, with 55 people dying last year.
Another 33 drowning deaths were attributed to suicide, while 25 were undetermined and one related to an assault  giving a total of 114 deaths by drowning here in 2014, according to Irish Water Safety .
RNLIs lifeboat crews rescued 1,133 people and saved 36 lives last year, and the organisation aims to halve the number of coastal deaths by 2024.
The first film , entitled Breathe is shown from the point of view of the casualty, played by an actor. The second film , also filmed from the perspective of the water, demonstrates how quickly conditions can change.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Banking Inquiry: guarantee was best option, says Cowen</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/banking-inquiry-guarantee-was-best-option-says-cowen-1.2278127</Link>
        <Description>Former taoiseach tells Oireachtas guarantee safer than nationalising Anglo Irish Bank   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Banking Inquiry: guarantee was best option, says Cowen
Former taoiseach tells Oireachtas guarantee safer than nationalising Anglo Irish Bank
Brian Lenihan  was not overruled by Brian Cowen on the night of the bank guarantee, the former taoiseach insisted. File photograph: Joe St Leger/The Irish Times
Former taoiseach Brian Cowen at the Dail for the banking inquiry. Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Previous Image
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
The blanket bank guarantee was the best option available to the government in September 2008, former taoiseach Brian Cowen has said.
Mr Cowen told the Oireachtas banking inquiry no decision was risk-free but the guarantee was safer than nationalisation of Anglo Irish Bank .
He insisted he did not overrule former minister for finance Brian Lenihan on the night in question.
Mr Cowen said he held a private meeting with Mr Lenihan and the two men agreed on the method chosen.
He said: We were grappling with a situation here which was very serious.
We came, ultimately, to a conclusion as to what we felt, on balance, with different degrees of enthusiasm as well  no one was enthusiastic, obviously  but different degrees of conviction what was going to be the best thing to do.
Mr Cowen said nationalisation of Anglo carried a weight of risk he was not prepared to take. He said it could have potentially brought on more nationalisations and may not have been the confidence boost the sector needed.
Best solution
He insisted it was not a question of overruling his minister for finance, and the two men were trying to find the best solution.
He said: Im sure he respected my position as well as I respected his, but, you know, at the end of the day, I had to chair the meeting, I had to pull it together based on all of these views that were being held.
It wasnt an atmosphere where I was overruling people.
We had a long discussion about it. It wasnt in any way acrimonious. Why would it be? We were both on the same side trying to do the best we could in a difficult situation.
Mr Cowen told the inquiry he did not have an agreed position when he entered the discussions. He said he spoke to only one person outside the room on the night the decision was made: former Central Bank director Alan Gray.
Pearse Doherty of Sinn Fin asked if Mr Cowen was told that Anglos then chairman, Sen FitzPatrick, and chief executive, David Drumm , had visited Mr Gray earlier that day.
Mr Cowen said he was not aware of that when he spoke to Mr Gray.
Mr Cowen told the committee that the government could have walked away on the night in question. We could have walked away from our responsibilities and abdicated our responsibilities saying: Im not big enough, we cant make this decision. Its too big.
With all the risks and all the pros and cons, youll find 20 arguments why you wouldnt do this and 20 arguments why you wont do that.
And if you lose the sight of the basic thing, that if you dont have a banking system tomorrow or next week, theres hundreds of thousands of people who are waiting for their wages who mightnt get them and all the rest of it.
No documentation
He said he was sorry there was no documentation of the night the guarantee was agreed. I am sorry there is not a full and accurate note of the night. It would be for the protection of all of us.
The former Fianna Fil leader also expressed regret for not holding a cabinet meeting on September 29th 2008.
Mr Cowen said there had been one on the Sunday evening, September 28th, and calling one the following morning was a judgment call.
He said: Im sorry to colleagues if any of them feel that we should have had that meeting.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brian Cowen says he was unaware  of  emails on future of Anglo Irish Bank</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/brian-cowen-says-he-was-unaware-of-emails-on-future-of-anglo-irish-bank-1.2278170</Link>
        <Description>Former taoiseach did not discuss ‘any issues of substance’ with bank, inquiry told   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Brian Cowen says he was unaware  of  emails on future of Anglo Irish Bank
Former taoiseach did not discuss any issues of substance with bank, inquiry told
Brian Cowen arriving at the Oireachtas bank inquiry in Leinster House   on Wednesday. Photograph: Collins
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Brian Cowen has insisted he was not aware of emails sent to his office about several possibilities for the future of Anglo Irish Bank on the night he met the board of the bank.
The former taoiseach was questioned at the Oireachtas banking inquiry yesterday about correspondence exchanged between officials in the Department of Finance .
The emails, which discussed the future of Anglo, were sent on the day Mr Cowen attended a board dinner at the banks headquarters in Dublin on April 28th, 2008.
Live blog: Banking inquiry
Mr Cowen said: Its an internal email that refers to some issue regarding the State Guarantees Act 1954.
That relates to work that was being done in the domestic standing group regarding the question of the guarantee, making sure there were sufficient powers available if you were ever to do a guarantee, as a contingency planning measure.
Significant
Mr Cowen said he had not seen the email and insisted he was not copied in on it. He said his private secretary would normally screen his correspondence and print off anything significant for him.
The former taoiseach added: My evidence here last week is the same today. I didnt discuss any issues of substance with Anglo Irish Bank officials then or subsequently.
When questioned by inquiry chairman Ciarn Lynch, Mr Cowen said he did not recall being briefed ahead of the function on April 24th 2008.
However, it may have been the case that some briefing material was given to me generally about Anglo Irish Bank on the basis that I was going down to a dinner there, but I dont recollect anything about it, to be honest, he said.
Truthful
The important point is this, in any event: a lot of this can be a distraction, the important point is the evidence I gave last week is truthful and accurate evidence. I didnt discuss anything with Anglo Irish Bank of any substance that day.
Mr Cowen was responding to a report in yesterdays Irish Times which detailed an email sent between Department of Finance officials outlining possible solutions to Anglos problems. Later, Mr Cowen was questioned about a golf game he attended in July 2008 with the then Anglo chairman Sen FitzPatrick, non-executive director Fintan Drury, board member Gary McGann and a director of the Central Bank Alan Gray.
Fine Gael TD Kieran ODonnell asked if he had shown poor judgment by attending the outing. Mr Cowen said all of the individuals concerned would have rather it hadnt happened considering the controversy surrounding it.
He said: I want to assure the Irish people that I didnt do anything untoward, or inappropriate, or discuss issues I shouldnt be discussing with any individual bank at the expense or cost of anyone else, at that time or ever.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Case study: The children of   undocumented migrant workers</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/case-study-the-children-of-undocumented-migrant-workers-1.2278155</Link>
        <Description>Amanthi (18): ‘We’d like to pay taxes properly and  want to progress. It’s wasted potential’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Case study: The children of   undocumented migrant workers
Amanthi (18): Wed like to pay taxes properly and  want to progress. Its wasted potential
Wed like to pay taxes properly and want to progress. Its wasted potential. File photograph: Getty Images
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Amanthi, a bright, chatty 18-year-old from the Indian subcontinent, is joking about how much she feels at home in Ireland .
I was away in Kilkenny for a few days. It was very nice and everything, but all I wanted to do was to get home. Home to Dublin, she says.
Its where I went to school since I was eight. Its where all my friends live . . . Its shaped how I think and view the world . . . If you ask me where home is, its here.
Ireland may be where she feels she belongs . But in the eyes of the law, shes an illegal immigrant.
Amanthi is one of an estimated 20,000-26,000 undocumented migrants living and working here.
Of these, about 6,000 are the children of migrants and have grown up here.
Amanthi came here more than a decade ago with her mother and father. They, like most undocumented workers, arrived on visas during the boom and ended up overstaying.
They are still living and working here, paying taxes and putting down roots. But life feels precarious. Thats because they face a range of obstacles in areas such as health, education and travel.
Just like the undocumented Irish in the US, they are cut off from visiting their extended families.
If they become unemployed, they arent entitled to social security. In the health system, they may face significant bills for treatment.
Many are reluctant to report crimes to garda.
Biggest obstacle
But the biggest obstacle of all, Amanthi says, is access to education. While she attended primary and secondary school here without any problem, third-level is effectively blocked off because the rules on access are citizenship-based.
Amanthi completed her Leaving Certificate in 2013 and would love to study biochemistry. But shes not an Irish citizen, so she isnt entitled to free fees.
Neither is she an EU citizen, which would entitle her to discounted fees.
Instead, shes regarded as an international student, so the cost of a college place is in the region of 15,000 a year.
We could never afford that, she says.
While her friends have progressed on to third-level, shes taken a part-time job in the shadow economy.
Shes also involved in a campaign group, Young, Paperless and Powerful, made up of undocumented young people who want to regularise their status.
The group recently made a powerful video on the anxieties, frustrations and resilience of young people stuck in limbo and hoping for change.
Were not looking for handouts, Amanthi says. We just want to get back into the system and work towards citizenship.
Proposals being considered by the Department of Justice recommend a one-off, timebound regularisation scheme.
The document, drawn up by the Migrant Rights Centre of Ireland, notes that 15 years of inward migration have occurred in the absence of a coherent legal framework.
It says regularisation has the potential to generate up to 185 million over five years in registration fees and an increased tax take.
Credibility
It would also add credibility to the Governments campaign to agree a regularisation programme for undocumented Irish in the US.
The department has traditionally opposed amnesties or programmes of this nature, preferring to deal with individuals on a case by case basis.
But the documents authors say that, unlike an amnesty, the proposals bar anyone with a criminal record from taking part and include a two-year probation period.
For people like Amanthi, the advantages of the proposals are simple. Failing to take action, she says, would simply be a waste of talent.
All these people who could benefit are already here. Wed like to pay taxes properly and we want to progress. Its just wasted potential if people like me arent able to work and study.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Extra funding and staff for organ donation, says Leo Varadkar</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/extra-funding-and-staff-for-organ-donation-says-leo-varadkar-1.2278164</Link>
        <Description>An extra €3m has been provided to facilitate 19 appointments, says Minister for Health    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Extra funding and staff for organ donation, says Leo Varadkar
An extra 3m has been provided to facilitate 19 appointments, says Minister for Health
Minister for Health Leo Varadkar: told the Seanad that an additional 3 million has been provided to facilitate the appointment of 19 staff. Photograph: Dave Meehan
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
An additional 3 million has been provided to facilitate the appointment of 19 staff dedicated to organ donation across the country, Minister for Health Leo Varadkar told the Seanad.
He said these included five organ procurement co-ordinators, who had been appointed, and six organ donation nurse managers who would be in their posts in each of the hospital groups by the end of next month.
I recognise all of the families who have facilitated the donation of the organs of their loved ones, often to the benefit of several recipients, he added. I reiterate my commitment to enhance organ donation and transplantation rates for the benefit of patients and their families.
Varadkar stands by his claim of lower hospital waiting times
Retired
Mr Varadkar was replying to Fine Gael Senator Colm Burke who said he understood Prof David Hickey , who provided an excellent service in carrying out transplants, had retired from Beaumont Hospital in Dublin. Another consultant had returned to his native country.
The number of transplant consultants has been reduced to four in total when it should be eight, Mr Burke added.
The Minister said given the limited number of surgeons who specialised in transplants, the filling of such vacancies posed a challenge. While Beaumont Hospital is making every effort to recruit a suitable replacement, it is also collaborating with St Vincents University Hospital on a combined approach to kidney and pancreas transplants, he added.
Mr Varadkar said the two hospitals, together with Organ Donation and Transplant Ireland and his department, were working to facilitate the commencement of that work as soon as possible.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tourist season sees fewer hotel rooms for Dublin’s homeless</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/tourist-season-sees-fewer-hotel-rooms-for-dublin-s-homeless-1.2278029</Link>
        <Description>Hotels turn down offers from homeless executive in favour of accommodating visitors   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Tourist season sees fewer hotel rooms for Dublins homeless
Hotels turn down offers from homeless executive in favour of accommodating visitors
Cathal Morgan of the Dublin Region Homeless Executive said: We have to find other solutions, we need to try to get away from using commercial hotels. File photograph: Dara Mac Dnaill/The Irish Times
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
Availability of hotel rooms for Dublins homeless is running out because of competition with tourists over the summer months, director of the Dublin Region Homeless Executive Cathal Morgan has said.
Hotel owners were turning down offers of full-rate payments for rooms from the executive Mr Morgan said, in favour of accommodating the summer tourist trade.
There will be a problem during the summer. We are making 200 placements to hotels a day, Mr Morgan said.
Mortgage arrears case study: I felt powerless
We are not getting a reduction in room rates, but often they are saying to us that they dont need our business.
He said the council needed to move away from using private hotels for emergency accommodation for homeless individuals and families.
We have to find other solutions, we need to try to get away from using commercial hotels.
The number of homeless children in Dublin reached 1,122 at the end of June and just under 800 of them are living in hotels.
Shortfall
The councils head of housing Dick Brady last Monday told councillors the city is facing a shortfall of 18.5 million in funding from the Department of the Environment for homeless services this year.
Mr Brady said he has been told by the department it would be allocating 37.1 million to fund homeless services in the city in 2015, despite the council having sought 55 million from central Government to run the service, which has a full cost of 68 million for the year.
Lord Mayor of Dublin Crona N Dhlaigh said she had contacted Minister for the Environment Alan Kelly after the meeting and he had agreed to meet her as well as other councillors and council officials to discuss the issue.
Fine Gael councillor Ray McAdam pointed out the letter from the department had been sent on June 2nd and asked why it was only bought to councillors last week.
He also asked whether more money might be released from the department later in the year and whether Mr Brady was playing politics.
Mr Brady said he had been in budget discussions with officials in the department since the letter was received in an attempt to bridge the gap.
The council would expect to receive an allocation of funds later in the year, but he said the council needed to have certainty that it would be able to fund the homeless service.
There was no attempt to play politics, this is too important to play politics with.
If we get to the end of the year and we get into the position where there isnt the money to run the service, it would be a poor reflection on us if we didnt make that clear now.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU leaks intended to bounce Ireland into bailout, says Cowen</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/eu-leaks-intended-to-bounce-ireland-into-bailout-says-cowen-1.2278086</Link>
        <Description>Patrick Honohan’s RTÉ interview ‘put us on back foot’, says former taoiseach   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
EU leaks intended to bounce Ireland into bailout, says Cowen
Patrick Honohans RT interview put us on back foot, says former taoiseach
Former taoiseach Brian Cowen said he did not believe Patrick Honohan was one of those briefing against Ireland. Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 01:00
EU institutions sought to bounce Ireland into a bailout programme in late 2010 by providing selective leaks to international media, former taoiseach Brian Cowen told the Oireachtas banking inquiry on Wednesday.
It became very clear to me, very quickly, that people were trying to bounce us into a programme in principle, he said. I have no doubt that there were elements within the EU institutions who were providing inspired leaks to the media with that agenda in mind.
However, Mr Cowen made it clear to the committee that he did not believe that Central Bank of Ireland governor Patrick Honohan , who was a member of the governing council of the European Central Bank (ECB), was one of those briefing against Ireland at the time.
Live blog: Banking inquiry
On November 18th, Mr Honohan went on to RTs Morning Ireland radio programme to tell the public that Ireland would probably apply for a bailout. Mr Honohans intervention came at a time when the Government was insisting that Ireland had not applied for a bailout from the EU and the International Monetary Fund (IMF), as had been reported by international media.
Unfortunate interview
Mr Cowen said Mr Honohans RT interview put us on the back foot.
It was very unfortunate that thats the way it came out, thats the way it was presented. That was a job for us to do, and it put us in a poor light, he said.
He said the government was trying to create some leverage in its early negotiations with the troika in advance of formally applying for a bailout.
He was also determined that the four-year national recovery plan that had been drawn up by the government to reduce Irelands deficit to 3 per cent would form the basis for the bailout adjustment.
Mr Cowen detailed how Ireland was placed under pressure by the ECB in November 2010 to enter a bailout programme.
On November 12th, the governing council of the ECB decided that it could not sustain its large exposure to Irish banks.
Some days later, EU finance ministers encouraged the then finance minister Brian Lenihan to seek access to a bailout programme. Mr Lenihan said he had no mandate from the government to do this.
On November 19th, the then ECB president Jean-Claude Trichet sent a letter to Mr Lenihan threatening the withdrawal of ECB funds in the absence of a formal bailout request.
This was not well received by us, Mr Cowen said.
However, Mr Cowen accepted that access to the EU-IMF bailout gave Ireland access to funds at a cost cheaper than was available on the markets at that time and into the future. On November 11th, Irelands bond yield had risen to 8.6 per cent.
It would provide, in that respect, funding certainty over a three-year period that therefore gave a better prospect to implement the plan that we were announcing, Mr Cowen said.
Burning bondholders once the original two-year bank guarantee was due to expire in September 2010 was not favoured by the National Treasury Management Agency (NTMA) as Ireland was still raising funds from capital markets, Mr Cowen said.
Once we were out there borrowing funds on bond markets from a limited pool of investors, the question of being allowed to burn senior bondholders was not something that the NTMA would be in favour of in terms of getting funds at the right price, he said.
Guarantee of bonds
Eoghan Murphy, of Fine Gael , noted that the guarantee of some 19 billion of unsecured senior bonds was due to expire, with 2.4 billion repaid between September 2010 and the time of the bailout negotiations two months later.
Mr Cowen said the ECB was also not in favour of burning bondholders in September 2010, though it hadnt made its position explicit by that stage.
When Ireland explored the possibility of burden-sharing by unguaranteed senior bondholders during subsequent discussions, the IMF were sympathetic, but when it was referred to a higher level there was total opposition to it.
US treasury secretary Timothy Geithner was opposed because he claimed it would totally undermine market access for those European countries, including ourselves, that were in trouble.
The ECB also opposed burden-sharing, Mr Cowen added. It was made clear to us that any attempt to burden-share with senior bondholders would mean no programme for Ireland.
In answer to a question about whether Mr Lenihan had kept him fully informed about his contacts with EU institutions, Mr Cowen described the late minister as very capable.
I was very happy to appoint him as minister for finance, and glad I did, he added. He would keep us [the cabinet] informed generally.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brian Cowen admits ‘miscalculation’ on bailout news</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/brian-cowen-admits-miscalculation-on-bailout-news-1.2278136</Link>
        <Description>  Former taoiseach says it was not his intention to mislead public over talks </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Brian Cowen admits miscalculation on bailout news
Former taoiseach says it was not his intention to mislead public over talks
Former taoiseach Brian Cowan arrives at the Dil before giving evidence to the banking inquiry. Photograph: Sara Freund/The Irish Times
Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 00:20
First published: Thu, Jul 9, 2015, 00:20
Former taoiseach Brian Cowen said it was not his intention to deceive the Irish public about its talks in November 2010 with the European Union and International Monetary Fund on accessing a bailout programme and accepted that it was a miscalculation on his part not to reveal this sooner.
The bottom line is that we should have been saying: Look, we have these people coming over, we havent applied yet, we are in discussions, well see where it takes us, we should come to a conclusion on it fairly soon one way or the other. That would have been the accurate, up-to-date situation as it was.
It wasnt our intention not to provide clarity, it was the timing of providing it, I suppose, where we fell down.
Theres no benefit in a government misleading its own people. We were simply trying to get as full a picture as we could before formally applying for a bailout.
Leverage
He said the government was trying to use as much leverage as it could to get as good a deal as we could get before formally applying for a rescue package.
Ireland applied for its bailout on November 21st, 2010, three days after Central Bank governor Patrick Honohan had gone on RT radio to inform the public the Government would probably be seeking a troika loan.
Mr Honohan told the committee in his evidence he had been responding to a sense of panic that had been building around the security of Irish banks.
His intervention followed earlier government denials of reports that Ireland was in talks about a bailout.
Mr Cowen said he was satisfied Mr Honohans radio interview didnt have a detrimental impact on the talks with the troika but it did have a detrimental impact politically for the government.
This is the first time Mr Cowen has spoken publicly about this matter. He spent 9 hours in front of the inquiry on Wednesday answering questions about his time as taoiseach from May 2008 to February 2011.
Mr Cowen stood over the decision to issue a blanket bank guarantee on the night of September 29th, 2008, saying it was the best option available at the time. He insisted he did not overrule former minister for finance Brian Lenihan on the night in question.
Weight of risk
Mr Cowen said nationalisation of Anglo Irish Bank , an option favoured by Mr Lenihan, carried a weight of risk he was not prepared to take.
Mr Cowen told the committee the government could have walked away from the guarantee decision on the night in question.
We could have walked away from our responsibilities and abdicated our responsibilities saying: Im not big enough, we cant make this decision. Its too big.
With all the risks and all the pros and cons youll find 20 arguments why you wouldnt do this and 20 arguments why you wont do that. And if you lose the sight of the basic thing, that if you dont have a banking system tomorrow or next week, theres hundreds of thousands of people who are waiting for their wages who mightnt get them and all the rest of it. People find it hard to understand how it can get that bad that quick.
Mr Cowen denied he had shown poor judgment by attending social functions with executives of Anglo in 2008, including playing golf with Anglos chairman Sen FitzPatrick in July that year.
He said nothing inappropriate had happened and there had been no discussions about the bank itself. As God is my witness, that is the truth, he said in reply to a question from Sinn Fins Pearse Doherty .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:50:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seanad reforms unlikely in current Government term</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/seanad-reforms-unlikely-in-current-government-term-1.2278262</Link>
        <Description>Taoiseach Enda Kenny suggests reform in EU legislation  and public policy consultation   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Seanad reforms unlikely in current Government term
Taoiseach Enda Kenny suggests reform in EU legislation  and public policy consultation
The Taoiseach suggested that some reforms in relation to the functions of the Seanad be proceeded with, as recommended by a working group chaired by former senator Maurice Manning. Photograph: Stephen Collins/Collins Photos
Wed, Jul 8, 2015, 22:50
First published: Wed, Jul 8, 2015, 22:50
Any reform of the Seanad looks increasingly unlikely during this Governments term, Opposition representatives have said following a meeting with Taoiseach Enda Kenny on the issue.
Mr Kenny, accompanied by Labour Minister Alex White , briefed Fianna Fil leader Michel Martin, Sinn Fin leader Gerry Adams and Independent Senators Jillian van Turnhout and Sean Barrett.
In the course of the hour-long meeting, the Taoiseach suggested that some reforms in relation to the functions of the Seanad be proceeded with, as recommended by a working group chaired by former senator Maurice Manning .
They included new roles in relation to scrutiny of North-South ministerial meetings, EU legislation, regulatory reports and public policy consultation.
However, little reference was made to other suggested reforms such as gender balance, extension of the franchise and Northern representation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:46:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>TDs concerned at ‘gross’  increases in pensions for former taoisigh </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/tds-concerned-at-gross-increases-in-pensions-for-former-taoisigh-1.2278256</Link>
        <Description>Bertie Ahern and Brian Cowen will benefit from Howlin’s new pay and pensions deal    </Description>
        <MainBody>Wed, Jul 8, 2015, 22:46
First published: Wed, Jul 8, 2015, 22:46
A group of Fine Gael TDs have raised concerns about increases in ministerial pensions which will be given to former office holders such as ex -taoisigh Brian Cowen and Bertie Ahern .
A number of backbenchers have also raised concerns about the operation of the National Asset Management Agency at a meeting of the Fine Gael parliamentary party on Wednesday night.
Mr Ahern and Mr Cowen will be among a number to benefit from the changes which will take effect because of a provision in the new pay and pensions deals struck by Minister for Public Expenditure Brendan Howlin .
The pair currently receive about 134,000 per year, but will see that rise by 2,000 annually over the next three years as a result of the recent deal. Former minister for finance Charlie McCreevy will see his pension increase from 108,000 to 110,000.
The issue was first raised at the Fine Gael meeting by Cork South-Central TD Jerry Buttimer, who described the increases as gross. Mr Buttimer was supported by Paul Connaughton of Galway East, Anthony Lawlor of Kildare North, Alan Farrell of Dublin North, Brendan Griffin of Kerry South and Gabrielle McFadden of Longford-Westmeath.
Sources said many of the deputies told Taoiseach Enda Kenny the public perception of giving the former office holders pension increases was extremely negative. Mr Buttimer told Mr Kenny it undermined the work of the Government and claimed many former politicians were in receipt of pensions similar in amount to the Taoiseachs salary.
Mr Griffin said the raises were disgusting in light of difficulties faced by people in recent years and added there is an onus on the Government to find a way to reverse the recent increases.
Mr Farrell suggested legislating to cap increases beyond a certain point, which was also pressed by Mr Griffin.
Mr Kenny told his parliamentary party there would be issues and difficulties in touching peoples pensions and is understood to have said moves to do so could interfere with constitutional rights.
The Taoiseach also said some of the pensions could be returned voluntarily. Sources said Dublin South Central TD Catherine Byrne, who was chairing the meeting, attempted to shut debate down, leading to further objections.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
