<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:45:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com |  Americans streaming to fight in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Americans-streaming-to-fight-in-Syria-20150708</Link>
        <Description>More than 200 Americans have travelled or attempted to travel to Syria to fight for Islamic militants, Federal Bureau of Investigation chief James Comey says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Americans streaming to fight in Syria
2015-07-08 23:45
Suspected al-Qaeda militants stand behind bars during a hearing at a court in the Yemeni capital Sanaa. (AFP)
American killed in Syria
Washington - More than 200 Americans have travelled or attempted to travel to Syria to fight for Islamic militants, Federal Bureau of Investigation chief James Comey said on Wednesday.
"We continue to identify individuals who seek to join the ranks of foreign fighters ... and also home-grown violent extremists who may aspire to attack the United States from within," Comey told lawmakers on the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence.
The radicalisation of Americans by ISIS is a top concern for the agency, and earlier on Wednesday Comey urged technology companies to allow law enforcement authorities access to encrypted communications to help combat the threat.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:56:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | British Airways flight diverted for unruly passenger</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/British-Airways-flight-diverted-for-unruly-passenger-20150708</Link>
        <Description>A British Airways flight to Texas has been diverted to Boston because of an unruly male passenger.</Description>
        <MainBody>British Airways flight diverted for unruly passenger
2015-07-08 21:56
British Airways (Supplied)
Mystery surrounds BA stowaways
Boston - Authorities say a flight from London was diverted to Boston after an English passenger allegedly assaulted a travelling companion.
Massachusetts state police said troopers arrested 48-year-old Darren Halliwell, of Aspull, after the Houston-bound British Airways flight landed at Logan International Airport around noon on Wednesday.
Halliwell was charged with interfering with a flight crew. Police said it took multiple passengers to restrain him.
Authorities say Halliwell allegedly assaulted a woman who was travelling with him. More charges could be filed.
A statement released by British Airways says customers and crew shouldn't have to suffer any form of abuse.
Authorities say the plane continued to Houston after Halliwell was arrested. He is expected to be arraigned on Thursday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:56:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | First London Underground strike since 2002 starts</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/First-London-Underground-strike-since-2002-starts-20150708</Link>
        <Description>The first London Underground strike shut down since 2002 is under way as drivers protest pay and plans for a new 24-hour service due to start in September.</Description>
        <MainBody>First London Underground strike since 2002 starts
2015-07-08 21:56
London tube strike causes chaos for millions
London - The first London Underground strike shut down since 2002 got under way on Wednesday, as drivers protested pay and plans for a new 24-hour service due to start in September.
Commuters rushed home ahead of the start of the strike at 18:30 (17:30 GMT), as unions mounted picket lines outside stations and Transport for London (TfL) began reporting delays.
A full shut down is expected on Thursday, and TfL has warned that disruptions to the British capital's public transport could continue into Friday.
Transport for London (TfL), the local government organisation responsible for most aspects of London's transport system, said it would lay on 200 extra buses and more bicycle rental hubs, although it also posted walking maps of London on its website.
"Londoners who own a bike are encouraged to cycle to work," the network administrator said in a statement.
To reach the Wimbledon tennis tournament, which ends this weekend, TfL said it was organising a taxi-sharing service from the nearest train station.
"We're very clear that it's unacceptable and unjustified. It's going to hit families, workers, businesses across the capital," Prime Minister David Cameron's spokesperson said at a daily briefing.
London Mayor Boris Johnson tweeted: "Tube strike politically motivated - union bosses need to explain why they refuse to put new offer to members - disgraceful - call it off!"
New all-night Underground services are due to start in September on several lines and staff have been offered an average 2% pay rise this year, inflation-linked rises for the next two years and a bonus for each driver on the new overnight service.
This offer was rejected by unions on Wednesday.
London Underground's managing director Mike Brown said an all-night Tube service would support jobs and boost the city's economy, adding that the offer had been "remarkably fair".
But Finn Brennan of the Aslef trade union accused managers of playing "foolish games of brinkmanship".
Read more on:  uk
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:56:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Netanyahu loses parliament vote for first time</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Netanyahu-loses-parliament-vote-for-first-time-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's ruling coalition lost a parliamentary vote for the first time since taking office with a knife-edge majority in May.</Description>
        <MainBody>Netanyahu loses parliament vote for first time
2015-07-08 21:56
(Ariel Schalit, AP)
Obama warning over Netanyahu unjustified - Israeli official
Jerusalem - Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's ruling coalition lost a parliamentary vote Wednesday for the first time since taking office with a knife-edge majority in May.
The vote, on a technical issue regarding jurisdiction of state bailiffs, did not directly challenge the government's survival but highlighted the challenge of governance with the coalition commanding just 61 seats in the 120-member legislature.
"Netanyahu's coalition of 61 is unable to function," MP Karin Elharrar of the opposition Yesh Atid party and sponsor of the private member's bill, said in a statement.
The draft must still pass three more readings before it can become law but it showed the government caught off guard by a united opposition ambush.
"Opposition members waited outside the chamber, burst in at the moment of truth and achieved a majority in the preliminary reading," Haaretz newspaper wrote of the 46-45 upset.
"We carried out a classic ambush," opposition leader Isaac Herzog told public radio. "We entered by surprise... Nobody suspected that there would be a majority or that we would even be present there."
Netanyahu's Likud party made no statement following the vote and the party's spokesperson could not immediately be reached for comment.
In the March 17 general election Likud won 30 seats, while Herzog's Zionist Union trailed with 24.
After weeks of political horse-trading Netanyahu announced formation of a coalition, seen as one of the most right wing in the country's history.
Read more on:  benjamin netanyahu | israel
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:57:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Trump: I'll win the Latino vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Trump-Ill-win-the-Latino-vote-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Republican Donald Trump says he will win the Latino vote if he gets his party's nomination for president  despite recent comments about immigrants that have cost him business.</Description>
        <MainBody>Venezuela's President calls Donald Trump a thief
Washington - Republican Donald Trump on Wednesday said he would win the Latino vote if he gets his party's nomination for president and claimed a "great relationship with the Mexican people," despite recent comments about immigrants that have cost him business.
"I'll win the Latino vote. I will win it," Trump said in an excerpt of an interview with NBC News released on Wednesday. He said he would be better able to create jobs as president than fellow Republican Jeb Bush or Democrat Hillary Clinton.
"I will create jobs, and the Latinos will have jobs that they don't have right now, and I will win that vote," Trump said.
A steady stream of Trump's business partners have broken ties with him since his June 16 announcement that he would seek the Republican nomination for the November 2016 election.
During his speech, Trump vented about illegal immigrants, claiming that many of the people crossing the border from Mexico are criminals. Republicans and Democrats alike have criticised his remarks.
Meanwhile, the Comcast-owned NBC television network , Macy's department store chain and others have ended relationships with Trump.
The PGA of America on Tuesday said it was moving a golfing event away from a Trump-owned course and was considering options for another event planned for the same venue.
On Wednesday, Trump said many of the people who work for him, including workers at the site of a planned hotel in Washington, are legal immigrants from Mexico.
"They love me, I love them," Trump told NBC.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:56:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | More Confederate flags to be lowered</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/More-Confederate-flags-to-be-lowered-20150708</Link>
        <Description>The House of Representatives has voted to ban the display of rebel Confederate flags at historic federal cemeteries in the deep South.</Description>
        <MainBody>More Confederate flags to be lowered
2015-07-08 21:56
Alabama lowers Confederate flag
Washington - The House of Representatives has voted to ban the display of rebel Confederate flags at historic federal cemeteries in the deep South.
Pressure has mounted to ban display of the Confederate battle flag on state and federal property in the wake of last month's murders at a historic black church in Charleston, South Carolina. The suspect was seen with the flag in photos.
The move in Congress came late on Tuesday after a brief debate on a measure funding the National Park Service, which maintains national cemeteries, most of which contain graves of Civil War soldiers.
The proposal would block the Park Service from allowing private groups from decorating graves of southern soldiers with Confederate flags in states that commemorate Confederate Memorial Day.
The cemeteries are in Georgia and Mississippi.
Read more on:  us | charleston shooting
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:03:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Pope Francis to tour prison where inmates rule</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Pope-Francis-to-tour-prison-where-inmates-rule-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis is set to visit Bolivia's most notorious prison, Palmasola, where guards only secure the perimeter, In each unit, murderers, drug traffickers and rapists make the rules.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis to tour prison where inmates rule
2015-07-08 21:03
Pope Francis. (AP)
Catholic Church should not have leaders for life - pope
Santa Cruz - Guards only secure the perimeter of Palmasola, Bolivia's most notorious prison. Inside each unit, murderers, drug traffickers and rapists make the rules and run a lucrative criminal economy.
Money can buy inmates everything: A cell, a shower, drugs, protection, prostitutes and prime "real estate" as large as two-storey houses, from which to run a business or simply live relatively well.
On Friday, Pope Francis will enter the sprawling maximum-security complex in Bolivia's largest city, Santa Cruz, continuing his practice of visiting prisons when he was Archbishop of Buenos Aires.
"We make sure things are quiet around here," said Leonardo Medina, facing murder charges, one cheek bulging with coca leaves. Sporting a red jacket emblazoned with the word "discipline", Medina, 48, belongs to a team of security officers selected by inmates.
Palmasola is infamous for violence between rival factions. In one of the worst incidents in 2013, at least 30 inmates were killed and dozens wounded in a turf war that spiralled out of control in the prison's PC3 section, which houses the most violent.
Medina, housed in the quieter PC4 section that Pope Francis will visit, said he was under instructions not to reveal the jail's dark underbelly to visitors.
"If we do something wrong you can go, but for us it's ugly. We have to stay behind and pay the price," he said, speaking in a fluent English learned while trafficking cocaine in the United States.
PC4 is more small town than prison wing. Laundry hangs from lines slung between ramshackle buildings, kiosks sell juices and tables from a cafeteria spill out into a square with a statue of Jesus Christ. The unit has alleys that lead from the muddy football field in the centre, and inmates elect their leader, like a mayor.
Young children live inside the jail with their incarcerated parents alongside the most dangerous prisoners who can avoid the worst-offender unit with a bribe to officials, said Ramiro Llanos, a former head of Bolivia's prison services.
And like Medina, many of Palmasola's inmates have not been convicted of any crime. Nationwide, nearly 90% of Bolivia's 12 000 prisoners are awaiting trial, trapped by the country's gridlocked justice system.
Lined up outside the facility, Irene Pinto, 36 said her elderly mother had been locked up for failing to pay her debts. She said her mother has diabetes and with not enough medicine in the prison, she brought it in from outside.
"She sleeps in a room with four people, drug traffickers and murderers. So she worries and can't sleep easily," Pinto said.
The national prison director and the government declined to comment for this story.
Entrenched corruption
When Medina is not on security detail he makes leather wallets and hammocks that can fetch up to 450 Bolivianos ($66). Without money, it is a punishing existence inside Palmasola.
Roberth Aquino, 38, said a friend locked up on charges of land theft had paid about 6 850 Bolivianos for a bed, 1 300 Bolivianos for access to outdoor areas and 25 Bolivianos to use the showers.
Those without cash sleep on the floor. Those with wads of pesos swiftly climb a hierarchy in the prisoner ranks. Prisoners with money get more respect and protection.
"The government just locks you up inside and leaves you here," said Enea Cardina, a 61-year-old Italian citizen accused of murder.
The Catholic Church runs primary and secondary education schools, while a sign outside the prison chapel offers Alcoholics Anonymous meetings. It even offers prisoners university-level law classes.
"Human rights are widely violated in prisons," said Zaida Romero, who provides legal counselling inside Palmasola on behalf of the church. "A large percentage are here without trial."
Corruption is so entrenched in Bolivia's prison system that prisoners and families complain they have to bribe officials just to get a trial hearing, in addition to lawyers fees.
In the visitors line, Pinto said she had already put down 800 Bolivianos for her mother's two hearings and knew of another inmate still in prison on drugs charges because she lacked the money for a trial.
"She went in pregnant and now she has an 8-year-old child with her," Pinto said.
Ahead of the pope's arrival, prisoners were laying a stone pathway along a muddy throughway, clearing huge piles of litter and building walls.
Even among Bolivia's most hardened criminals, inmates say the pope will be safe.
"His visit is a benediction for us," said Ambi Vaca, 24, who is serving a 15-year sentence. "So we will look after him."
Read more on:  pope francis | bolivia
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Israeli blockade makes Gaza recovery 'impossible'</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Israeli-blockade-makes-Gaza-recovery-impossible-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Israel's blockade of building materials for Gaza has created one of the highest levels of unemployment in the world and made it impossible for the small coastal enclave to recover from the war a year ago, aid agencies say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Israeli blockade makes Gaza recovery 'impossible'
2015-07-08 21:03
Magdalena Mis
(AP)
The Gaza Strip: The site of 3 wars in 6 years
London - Israel's blockade of building materials for Gaza has created one of the highest levels of unemployment in the world and made it impossible for the small coastal enclave to recover from the war a year ago, aid agencies said on Wednesday.
Less than one percent of the materials needed for reconstruction have been allowed into the enclave, the international charity Christian Aid said.
Israel has blockaded Gaza, placing restrictions on people and goods leaving the enclave and goods entering it, since the Islamist group Hamas won power in Gaza in elections in 2006.
The blockade has isolated Gaza from the rest of the world, "helped to create some of the highest unemployment and aid dependency levels in the world, and must be brought to an end", Christian Aid spokesperson William Bell said in a statement.
Israel launched "Operation Protective Edge" on July 8 2014 in response to rocket fire into Israel by militants in the Gaza Strip.
Israeli air strikes and shelling hammered the densely populated enclave for 50 days, causing widespread destruction of homes, schools and other buildings, and killing more than 2 100 Palestinians, mostly civilians.
Thousands of Gazans were made homeless, 100 000 homes were damaged and more than 12 000 destroyed, none of which have been rebuilt.
The aid agency Oxfam said Gaza's economy was increasingly reliant on international aid, on which 80% of its 1.8 million residents depend.
Unemployment is among the highest in the world, with almost 68% of those under 24 jobless, it said.
The lack of opportunities is forcing a growing number of young people to risk their lives or arrest by trying to climb the border fence into Israel to look for work, Oxfam said.
The slow pace of reconstruction - estimated to take more than 70 years - means teenagers in Gaza will be old by the time it is completed, the agency said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:03:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Russia vetoes UN draft resolution on Srebrenica</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Russia-vetoes-UN-draft-resolution-on-Srebrenica-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Russia has vetoed a draft UN resolution recognizing the Srebrenica massacre as genocide, branding the measure confrontational and a setback to reconciliation in the Balkans.</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia vetoes UN draft resolution on Srebrenica
2015-07-08 21:03
AP
Serbs apologise for Srebrenica massacre
New York - Russia on Wednesday vetoed a draft UN resolution recognizing the Srebrenica massacre as genocide, branding the measure "confrontational" and a setback to reconciliation in the Balkans.
Britain had put forward the draft text, hoping the Security Council would formally recognize Europe's worst atrocity since World War II as an act of genocide for the first time and condemning genocide denial.
Angola, China, Nigeria and Venezuela abstained from the vote on the draft resolution, days before Bosnia is due to mark the 20th anniversary of the murder of 8 000 Muslim boys and men by Bosnian Serb forces in July 1995.
Russian Ambassador Vitaly Churkin called the British-drafted text "not constructive, confrontational and politically-motivated" and argued that it unfairly singled out Bosnian Serbs for war crimes.
"The draft that we have in front of us will not help peace in the Balkans but rather doom this region to tension," Churkin told the council meeting that began with a minute of silence to remember the victims.
British Deputy Ambassador Peter Wilson accused Russia of siding "with those who are unwilling to accept the facts today."
"Genocide occurred at Srebrenica. This is a legal fact, not a political judgment. On this there is no compromise," he said.
Russia, the United States and Britain had been locked in intense negotiations over the past 24 hours to try to avoid a veto and agree on a text.
But Moscow refused to drop its insistence that references to the Srebrenica killings as an act of genocide be scrapped, diplomats said.
Bosnian Serb leaders had called on Russia to use its veto power to block the resolution, arguing that it was "anti-Serb" because it highlighted the killings in the town in the final months of the war.
Bosnian Serb forces commanded by General Ratko Mladic overran the UN-protected safe haven of Srebrenica on July 11, 1995 in what was to become one of the darkest chapters of the 1992-95 Bosnian war.
Mladic's troops brushed aside the lightly armed Dutch peacekeepers and loaded thousands of Muslim men and boys onto trucks before executing them in a nearby forest and burying them in mass graves.
Read more on:  un | russia | bosnia
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:01:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Italian police seize assets from mafia pensioners</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Italian-police-seize-assets-from-mafia-pensioners-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Italian authorities have seized assets worth more than €1.6 billion from a family of five Sicilian pensioners believed to have links to a prominent mafia clan.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italian police seize assets from mafia pensioners
2015-07-08 20:01
Italian police arrest mobster hiding in sofa
Rome - Italian authorities said on Wednesday they had seized assets worth more than 1.6 billion from a family of five Sicilian pensioners believed to have links to a prominent mafia clan.
The huge sweep of businesses, property and bank accounts "represents, in total value, one of the biggest seizures ever made", the anti-mafia department (DIA) said.
The haul belonged to Carmelo Virga, 66, his brothers Vincenzo, 78, and 71-year-old Francesco, and their sisters Anna, 76, and Rosa, 68.
The operation in Palermo was aimed at "known entrepreneurs from the Palermo area who belong to the Marineo mafia family, linked to the Corleone clan," the DIA said.
"Complex investigations have uncovered how the Virgas have benefited from the backing of the Cosa Nostra in the bidding for these works and public tenders in the construction sector," the DIA said.
The family "succeeded over time in developing and imposing their group of companies, by using the method known as 'Siino', which consists of organising cartels of entrepreneurs with a view to the 'directed' bidding for public tenders."
RaiNews reported that the family were all farm hands in the 1980s before becoming millionaires.
'Pizzo' mafia tax
Italian newspapers reported that the son of Carmelo Virga, Gaetano, has in recent years been a high-profile opponent of the Sicilian mafia's extortion of companies.
With the support of several anti-mafia groups, he strongly criticised the practice and evidence he gave has led to the arrest of several mafia chiefs in the region.
Gaetano Virga has told investigators that one of those mafia dons, Stefano Polizzi, came to the construction site where he worked in Marineo in 2010 to demand payment of the mafia tax known as "pizzo", telling him: "Remember that you have children."
Gaetano told investigators that the mafia chief went from his office to that of one of his uncles. But there was an altercation and Polizzi left, with the uncles claiming they had not paid a cent.
Assets seized from the mafia in Italy include farming land, luxury cars and bank accounts, trucks and chains of hotels.
After years of fighting the Cosa Nostra in Sicily, the Camorra in Naples and the 'Ndrangheta in Calabria, the Italian state now controls almost 3 000 companies and 12 000 property assets seized from the mafia.
The national agency that manages seized mafia assets also controls more than two billion euros in bank deposits and other assets.
Read more on:  mafia | italy
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:01:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Millions share story of US girl found dead in Boston Harbor</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Millions-share-story-of-US-girl-found-dead-in-Boston-Harbor-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Millions have shared the  story of US girl found dead in Boston Harbour as police search for her identity.</Description>
        <MainBody>Millions share story of US girl found dead in Boston Harbor
2015-07-08 20:01
This flyer released by the Suffolk County Massachusetts District Attorney includes a computer-generated composite image depicting the possible likeness of a young girl, whose body was found on the shore of Deer Island in Boston Harbour. (Suffolk Coun
Maddie: Alleged online troll found dead
Boston - In her computer-generated image, she is the picture of innocence: a 4-year-old girl with long brown hair, chubby cheeks and expressive brown eyes. The image has attracted a staggering 45 million views on Facebook as investigators try to identity the child whose remains were found on a Boston Harbour beach nearly two weeks ago.
The mystery of Baby Doe began on June 25, when a woman walking her dog reported finding a trash bag containing the girl's body. The child was wearing white leggings with black polka dots. Inside the bag with her remains was a zebra-print blanket.
Police immediately appealed to the public for help in identifying the girl. Using photos of her remains, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children created a composite image of what the girl may have looked like when she was alive.
After that image and photos of the leggings and blanket were posted on the Massachusetts State Police Facebook page, investigators were astonished by the number of views and shares the posting received. As of late on Tuesday, more than 45.4 million people had viewed the image.
But authorities still haven't identified the girl.
Adding to the mystery is that investigators still haven't been able to figure out how she died. There were no obvious signs of trauma to her body, and an autopsy performed by the state medical examiner's office did not determine the manner or cause of her death.
Prosecutor Daniel Conley said on Tuesday that authorities are awaiting the results of toxicology tests to determine if the girl was poisoned or ingested drugs.
Conley said the outpouring of support by people who have shared the girl's image on social media is gratifying and gives him confidence that her identity eventually will be determined.
During a news conference Tuesday, Conley spoke directly to the girl's parents or caretakers: "Please step forward, clear your conscience and help us identify this young child."
Her death and the mystery surrounding her identity have touched a chord in many people. People from the US, Canada and Puerto Rico have shared the posting, with many of them expressing sorrow or anger over the girl's death.
"How can someone just throw a child away?" wrote one woman from Arizona.
Read more on:  facebook | us
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:54:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 3 gunned down in hit near US university</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/3-gunned-down-in-hit-near-US-university-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen have killed three people and wounded one near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, in the latest killings in a city that has seen an upturn in homicides following the death of Freddie Gray in April.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 gunned down in hit near US university
2015-07-08 18:54
In this image taken from video, police investigate the scene of the shooting in Baltimore. (WMAR via AP)
Relief, celebrations in Baltimore as 6 officers charged
Baltimore - Gunmen killed three people and wounded one overnight near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, police said on Wednesday, the latest killings in a city that has seen an upturn in homicides following the death of Freddie Gray in April.
Two gunmen emerged from two vans and began shooting just before 23:00 on Tuesday (03:00 GMT on Wednesday), campus police said in a statement.
A man died at the scene, Baltimore police said, and a man and a woman died while receiving medical treatment. The fourth victim, a woman, was hospitalised.
"Three to four suspects are believed to be involved at this time. This was not a random act of violence, but was a targeted incident," police said in a statement.
The shooting was not related to the university, the statement said. The Baltimore Sun reported that shots had been fired into a vehicle travelling on the same block five days ago.
The shootings came as Baltimore is grappling with an upsurge in killings following the death of Gray, a 25-year-old black man, from an injury suffered in police custody.
His death triggered protests and a day of rioting and arson. Police said looting of pharmacies during the unrest and a subsequent drug turf war was behind a surge in killings in May.
Police had originally recorded 43 homicides in May, the highest number since 1972, but dropped the total to 42 when one killing was reclassified as justified. A police spokesperson on Wednesday put the May homicide number at 41, the highest monthly tally since August 1990, without explaining the new total.
Baltimore, a largely black city of about 620 000 people, has notched 155 homicides this year, compared with 105 for the same period last year, the spokesperson said.
Police said on Tuesday the Police Executive Research Forum, a non-profit policy group, would evaluate the department's performance during the April unrest.
Police had said the Forum and the International Association of Chiefs of Police would take part in the department's internal review. The Baltimore police union also released an after-action report on Wednesday.
Read more on:  us
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:39:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Democratic Clinton challenger draws big crowds</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Democratic-Clinton-challenger-draws-big-crowds-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Bernie Sanders a Democratic challenger to Hillary Clinton is drawing big crowds but still faces an uphill climb.</Description>
        <MainBody>Democratic Clinton challenger draws big crowds
2015-07-08 17:39
Democratic presidential candidate Senator Bernie Sanders, at a campaign rally, in Portland, Maine. (Robert F Bukaty, AP)
Jeb Bush ready to declare he is running for president
Portland - Democratic presidential candidate Bernie Sanders may be a long shot against favourite Hillary Clinton, but he is still drawing bigger crowds than any other presidential candidate, up to 10 000 people at one event.
The trick for the independent senator from Vermont and self-described democratic socialist is to turn all that excitement into something more than a summer fling. Will those supporters turn out in key states that hold the first nominating contests in next year's primary race?
"We've only been a declared candidate for two months," Sanders said recently in Iowa. "In a certain sense, our momentum is outpacing our infrastructure."
In presidential politics, infrastructure matters. For Sanders to turn his insurgent campaign into an honest challenge against an unquestioned front-runner like Clinton, he will need to convert those willing to come hear him speak in the summer of 2015 into volunteers, donors and - ultimately - voters in 2016.
For all the crowds that Sanders is attracting, and the attention he's getting for them, he remains far behind Clinton in the work of building a big campaign organisation. He has a few more than 50 paid staffers in all. Clinton has nearly 50 in Iowa alone, as well as at least one in every other state.
"The grassroots movement behind this campaign has been much faster than I think anyone could have anticipated," said Sanders' campaign manager Jeff Weaver. "The organisation is trying to catch up to where the people are."
More than 100 people crowded into the Better Day Cafe in Storm Lake to hear Sanders. A table at the front of the restaurant held clipboards with sign-up sheets, where people could fill in their name, email address and phone number - as well as a box to check if they planned to caucus for Sanders. By the end of the event, many had signed up, but few had checked the box indicating how they'll vote.
Weaver said the infrastructure needed to turnout supporters for the caucuses is coming soon. Sanders has more than 20 paid staffers in Iowa, with more scheduled to come aboard next month. In New Hampshire, he has four paid staffers, but the state will get a "big jump soon," Weaver said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:24:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Pakistani PM Sharif meets Malala in Oslo</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Pakistani-PM-Sharif-meets-Malala-in-Oslo-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif and Nobel Peace Prize laureate Malala Yousafzai held their first official meeting on Wednesday after both attended a UN education summit in Oslo.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistani PM Sharif meets Malala in Oslo
2015-07-08 16:24
Pakistani student Malala Yousafzai speaks before the UN Youth Assembly at UN headquarters in New York. (Stan Honda, AFP)
Pakistan Taliban slam Malala over Nobel prize
Oslo - Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif and Nobel Peace Prize laureate Malala Yousafzai held their first official meeting on Wednesday after both attended a UN education summit in Oslo.
The 17-year-old activist, who was shot and nearly killed by the Taliban in Pakistan in October 2012 for insisting girls had a right to an education, said Sharif told her his government would support her if she decided to visit the country.
"He said my country is always there for me. And I said that it is my responsibility as a Pakistani to return to Pakistan and help people there," Malala, who has made her home in Britain, told public broadcaster NRK, adding that any visit would have to coincide with her school holidays.
Pakistan's education system, child labour and child marriage were also among the issues discussed, she added.
The ruling Pakistan Muslim League-N (PML-N) party posted a picture of the meeting on its official Twitter account.
The prime minister and the teen met briefly on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly in September 2013, but this was their first official meeting.
Both were in Oslo after attending the two-day Oslo Summit on Education for Development, where Malala urged world leaders to cut "eight days of military spending" to give all children access to 12 years of free education.
Sharif and his Indian counterpart Narendra Modi last year declined to attend the Nobel Peace Prize awards ceremony, where she collected the prize she shared with Indian child rights activist Kailash Satyarthi.
Malala became a global icon after the Taliban attack in 2012.
She recovered after being flown for extensive surgery to Birmingham, central England, and has since continued both her education and activism.
But she remains a figure of hate for many Pakistanis who resent having the country's problems aired abroad.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:24:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Iraq sentences 24 to death</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Iraq-sentences-24-to-death-20150708</Link>
        <Description>An Iraqi court has sentenced 24 people to death over the killings of hundreds of mainly Shi'ite soldiers captured by ISIS during their offensive through northern Iraq last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraq sentences 24 to death
2015-07-08 16:24
Isis massacre. (AP)
ISIS publicly kills 6 in Iraq
Baghdad - An Iraqi court sentenced 24 people to death on Wednesday over the killings of hundreds of mainly Shi'ite soldiers captured by Islamic State militants (ISIS) during their offensive through northern Iraq last year.
As many as 1 700 soldiers were killed after they fled Camp Speicher, a former US military base just north of Saddam Hussein's home town of Tikrit, and were rounded up by the Sunni Islamist fighters.
Video footage of the soldiers being gunned down in their hundreds, posted online by jihadists, came to symbolise Islamic State brutality and could mark the deadliest single act of violence during a decade of intermittent sectarian war in Iraq.
Dispensing swift justice, the court issued the death sentences within hours of the start of the trial on Wednesday, based on what a spokesperson described as strong evidence and confessions from the convicted men.
"Today the Iraqi central criminal court issued a death sentence against 24 people convicted of the Speicher massacre," said Abdul-Sattar al-Birqdar, spokesperson for Iraq's Supreme Judicial Council.
He said all those tried and sentenced on Wednesday were Iraqi nationals. Another 604 suspects wanted in connection with the killings remained at large, he added.
Tariq Harib, a leading Iraqi criminal lawyer who attended the session, said the sentences would be sent automatically to a higher court within a month for approval.
Iraqi soldiers and Shi'ite militia fighters recaptured Tikrit from Islamic State militants three months ago, allowing the start of exhumations at 12 suspected mass graves thought to contain the bodies of the slain soldiers.
Video footage released a year ago showed bodies being dumped in the nearby Tigris river, suggesting that a definite death toll from the Speicher killings may never emerge.
Many families of victims accused military leaders and local Sunni tribespeople of not doing more to prevent the killings, saying senior officers told the men they could safely abandon Camp Speicher and head for their homes in Iraq's Shi'ite south.
Instead they were rounded up and led to their deaths.
Government officials disputed those accounts, saying there was no promise of safety, and that the soldiers had left the base unarmed despite being ordered to stay.
Read more on:  isis | iraq
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:03:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 3 dead in shooting near US university campus</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/3-dead-in-shooting-near-US-university-campus-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Police say four people have been shot, three fatally, near a university campus outside the US capital.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 dead in shooting near US university campus
2015-07-08 15:03
(Saul Loeb, AFP)
Arrests may trigger revenge attacks after US biker gang shootout
Baltimore - Police say four people have been shot, three fatally, near a university campus outside the US capital.
Detective Rashawn Strong said in a statement early on Wednesday that officers responded on Tuesday night to a shooting reported in a residential neighborhood blocks from the University of Maryland campus in Baltimore. Strong says officers found three people with gunshot wounds.
One man was pronounced dead and another man and a woman were taken to a hospital, where they died.
Strong says another woman who walked into a hospital with a gunshot wound is listed in stable condition.
A statement on the school's website says campus police reported that two gunmen in two vans fired into a group of people.
A spokesperson for the university says there's no indication students were involved.
Read more on:  us | us shooting
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:03:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Rights group condemns Myanmar bill on interfaith marriage</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Rights-group-condemns-Myanmar-bill-on-interfaith-marriage-20150708</Link>
        <Description>An international human rights group has accused Myanmar's parliament of playing with fire by passing a bill regulating the right of women from the country's Buddhist majority to marry men from outside their religion.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rights group condemns Myanmar bill on interfaith marriage
2015-07-08 15:03
A Myanmar girl takes part in a religious ceremony. (Gemunu Amarasinghe, AP)
Myanmar jails 20 suspected human traffickers
Yangon - An international human rights group has accused Myanmar's parliament of playing with fire by passing a bill regulating the right of women from the country's Buddhist majority to marry men from outside their religion.
Phil Robertson of New York-based Human Rights Watch said on Wednesday the bill was related to a campaign by extremist Buddhist groups that have incited anti-Muslim hatred.
Religious tensions have led to deadly violence, especially against Rohingya Muslims in western Myanmar, who have felt compelled to flee abroad.
The bill passed Tuesday is one of four known as the Protection of Race and Religion Laws, which have been criticised as discriminatory by rights groups.
It mandates that Buddhist women register their intent to marry outside their faith, and that they can be stopped if there are objections.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:01:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Calls for end to Israeli blockade a year after Gaza war</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Calls-for-end-to-Israeli-blockade-a-year-after-Gaza-war-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Israel and Palestinians have marked one year since last summer's war in Gaza, with a UN official calling for an end to the "inexcusable" blockade of the territory that has helped prevent rebuilding.</Description>
        <MainBody>Calls for end to Israeli blockade a year after Gaza war
2015-07-08 14:01
(File, AFP)
The Gaza Strip: The site of 3 wars in 6 years
Gaza City - Israel and Palestinians marked one year since last summer's war in Gaza on Wednesday, with a UN official calling for an end to the "inexcusable" blockade of the territory that has helped prevent rebuilding.
The ceasefire that ended the 50-day war has largely held, but few of the issues that led to the conflict have been resolved and tens of thousands of Gazans remain homeless in the besieged strip.
While there appears to be little appetite for conflict on either side for now, analysts say failing to address the misery of Gazans who have faced three wars in six years will only sow the seeds for future violence.
"The blockade remains in place and its crippling effect on Gaza is undeniable, inexcusable," Robert Turner, operations director in Gaza for UN relief agency UNRWA, told reporters.
He however referred to a small amount of Gazan goods being allowed through for sale in Israel and the occupied West Bank in recent months as a reason for hope.
Israel 'not doing enough'
"I see a real willingness on the part of Israel to address some of its worst impact," Turner said of the blockade, which Israel says is necessary to prevent the import of arms and material to make weapons.
"It is not yet enough. It is not what is required, which is a full lifting of the blockade."
The war took a heavy toll on Gaza, killing 2 251 Palestinians, including more than 500 children. Seventy-three people were killed on the Israeli side, including 67 soldiers.
A UN report released last month said both sides may have committed war crimes during the conflict in and around the impoverished enclave of 1.8 million people.
Hamas, the Islamist movement that runs the Gaza Strip, planned commemorations for later on Wednesday, but details were not yet clear.
Israel held a memorial on Monday for its 73 victims killed in the war, where Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu defended the military offensive.
"I say to all enemies of Israel - Hamas, Hezbollah, Iran and IS (Islamic State) - that those who attempt to attack our people will pay with their blood," he said.
Indirect talks on shoring up the ceasefire and easing Israel's blockade have taken place, but there have been no signs that a deal could be reached anytime soon.
The blockade, as well as a lack of financing from international donors, have been blamed for the slow pace of reconstruction in Gaza, where around 18 000 homes were destroyed or severely damaged.
A split between Hamas and the Palestinian Authority led by president Mahmud Abbas, which runs the Israeli-occupied West Bank, has worsened the situation. Reconciliation attempts have failed to heal the rift.
Meanwhile, Hamas has been challenged by Salafist extremists in Gaza claiming links to the Islamic State jihadist group and who have taken credit for recent rocket fire.
'No help'
Last year's war was sparked in part by the abduction and murder of three young Israelis near a Jewish settlement in the West Bank.
The kidnapping triggered a massive manhunt in which hundreds of Palestinians were arrested and at least five killed.
It also led to the grisly revenge slaying of a 16-year-old Palestinian, who was snatched in east Jerusalem and burned alive by Israelis.
A surge in rocket fire from Gaza into Israel followed, and Israel in response launched its offensive on 8 July. A ground offensive began on 17 July.
Air and naval bombardments on the coastal strip continued until an Egyptian-brokered truce was reached on 26 August.
Israel's aims in the war were to stop the rocket fire and destroy tunnels used by Palestinian militants to carry out attacks.
But rocket fire has started up again - although sporadically and not claimed by Hamas - and militants in Gaza have rebuilt tunnels.
Hamas claimed victory after the war, but that has been scoffed at by Gazans who have seen family members killed and who now live among the ruins of their former homes.
Mohammed Zaza, a 19-year-old nursing student, pointed to a vacant lot where his family's house once stood and said they now live in an overpriced, rented flat.
"All that comes out of our pocket because we are receiving absolutely no help," he said.
The UN's Turner said payments would be issued for the first time Wednesday for a limited number of families whose homes were destroyed, while repairs for damaged houses have occurred. Financing however remains lacking.
"We need to help rebuild over 7 000 refugee family homes," he said of his agency's programme. "We have funding only currently for 200 homes."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:01:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Afghans, Taliban to meet again after Pakistan talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Afghans-Taliban-to-meet-again-after-Pakistan-talks-20150708</Link>
        <Description>Pakistan says Afghan and Taliban representatives have agreed to meet again after landmark talks aimed at ending the militants’ 13-year insurgency.</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghans, Taliban to meet again after Pakistan talks
2015-07-08 14:01
File: AFP
Afghan officials: 11 police, army dead in Taliban attack
Islamabad - Pakistan on Wednesday said Afghan and Taliban representatives had agreed to meet again after landmark through-the-night talks aimed at ending the militants' 13-year insurgency.
A delegation of the Afghan High Peace Council (HPC), the body tasked with opening negotiations, met the Taliban in the town of Murree, a hill station north of Islamabad, the Pakistani foreign ministry said in a statement.
Few details were released about what was discussed, but a foreign ministry spokesman said the talks lasted through the night, concluding at sehri, the traditional pre-dawn meal Muslims eat during the fasting month of Ramadan.
"The participants exchanged views on ways and means to bring peace and reconciliation in Afghanistan," the statement said, adding that the two sides had agreed to approach the talks with "sincerity and... full commitment".
"The participants agreed to continue talks to create an environment conducive for [the] peace and reconciliation process."
Significant step
The next round of talks will be held at a "mutually convenient date" after Ramadan, which is due to end around July 18.
Several informal meetings have been held in recent months between Taliban representatives and Afghan officials and activists.
But the talks in Pakistan, led on the HPC side by deputy foreign minister Hekmat Khalil Karzai, are seen as a significant step.
It is the first time Kabul has publicly acknowledged that someone as senior as a government minister was talking directly to the Taliban - though some earlier meetings were shrouded in secrecy, so it was not entirely clear who took part.
The foreign ministry statement said US and Chinese representatives were present during Tuesday's meeting.
Concrete progress
There have been several informal meetings between the Taliban and Afghan officials at venues outside Afghanistan in recent months as Kabul seeks a negotiated end to the insurgents' 13-year fight, but little in the way of concrete progress.
The Taliban leadership have not officially confirmed, but a militant source told AFP on Tuesday that they would attend, saying the Islamabad round would be an extension of meetings held in China in May.
Official efforts to open negotiations with the Taliban have borne little fruit, but informal talks have taken place several times in the recent past, veiled in secrecy.
The Taliban have said they took part in informal talks in Norway with an Afghan delegation, reportedly including women, as well as meetings in Qatar in May.
The Taliban's annual summer offensive is in full swing, with twin suicide attacks in Kabul on Tuesday, one targeting a Nato convoy and one an Afghan intelligence office, highlighting the precarious security situation.
Read more on:  taliban | pakistan | afghanistan
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:02:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Female supreme court nominee rejected by Afghan Parliament</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Female-supreme-court-nominee-rejected-by-Afghan-Parliament-20150708</Link>
        <Description>The first-ever female nominee for the supreme court in Afghanistan has failed to garner enough votes of approval from the parliament.</Description>
        <MainBody>Female supreme court nominee rejected by Afghan Parliament
2015-07-08 14:02
Mauritius parliament approves first woman president
Kabul - The first-ever female nominee for the supreme court in Afghanistan has failed to garner enough votes of approval from the parliament.
Anisa Rasoli received 88 votes on Wednesday, nine short of the 97 needed for her nomination to pass. Zahir Qadir, the deputy parliament speaker who was chairing the session, asked President Ashraf Ghani to bring forth another nominee.
During the same session, Mohammad Yasuf Halim was approved for the supreme court and Khalilullah Sediq was approved as the governor of the central bank.
Pres @ashrafghani nominated a female judge, #AnisaRasoli , for #SupremeCourt for the first time in #Afghan history pic.twitter.com/zuPGRtrqTO
Read more on:  afghanistan | gender equality
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
