<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="NEWS">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chief suspect a hard nut to crack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/detroit-police-post-picture-of-suspect-squirrel-in-search-for-stolen-snack-nuts/story-fndir2ev-1227435036385?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>STOLEN: 1300kg of packaged nuts. SUSPECTED: Dastardly supervillain &amp;#8220;The Squirrel&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; or at least according to Detroit police.</Description>
        <MainBody>SHARKNADO is real, people. Well, it is for one grandma who found a shark in her backyard.
World
Detroit police post picture of suspect squirrel in search for stolen snack nuts
by:
Suspect squirrel ... Shelby Township police are seeking those behind the theft of a $173,000 cargo of snack nuts. Source: Facebook Source: Supplied
STOLEN: 1300kg of packaged nuts. SUSPECTED: Dastardly supervillain The Squirrel  or at least according to Detroit police.
The suburban Shelby Township Police Department displayed a fleeting glimpse of wit when it came to responding to an unusual theft earlier this month.
A semi trailer filled with 18 pallets of walnuts and other nut varieties was swiped from its parking lot on June 27.
It was found five days later elsewhere in Detroit  but its cargo of nuts was gone.
Thats $A173,000 worth of snack food, swiped.
Earlier this week the Shelby police issued a public appeal for information on the whereabouts of the nuts on its Facebook page .
To accompany the post, nutty police shelled-out for a composite mugshot  of a suspicious squirrel.
This blatant piece of police profiling has a bit of a backstory: The Macombe County community has endured a string of animal antics lately  including goats in parkinglots and window-shopping pigs.
Residents are keeping their eyes open for strangely bulging trees surrounded by empty wrappers  as well as offers of unusually cheap snacks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lifeless body found ‘face down’ in water</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/asia/families-hear-gruesome-details-as-trial-for-thailand-murders-of-two-british-tourists-begins/story-fnh81fz8-1227434677803?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>TEN months after two British tourists were killed on a Thai island, court witnesses have described the grim moments they discovered their bludgeoned bodies.</Description>
        <MainBody>SHARKNADO is real, people. Well, it is for one grandma who found a shark in her backyard.
Asia
Families hear gruesome details as trial for Thailand murders of two British tourists begins
by:
The trial of two Myanmar nationals accused of murdering two British holidaymakers is underway in Thailand. Paul Chapman reports.
Reuters
08 Jul 2015
News/World
Murder trial ... Myanmar nationals Win Zaw Tun and Zaw Lin look out from a prison transport van as they arrive at court for the start of their trial in Koh Samui. Source: AFP
TEN months after two British tourists were brutally killed on a resort island in Thailand, prosecutors have called their first witnesses in a case plagued by claims that the two accused were tortured into confessing.
Following widespread attention, the case has been deemed a test for Thailands justice system and its treatment of foreign labourers. The alleged attackers are migrant workers from Myanmar.
The battered bodies of David Miller, 24, and Hannah Witheridge, 23, were found on September 15 on the rocky shores of Koh Tao, sending shockwaves through the tourist haven in the Gulf of Thailand known for its scuba diving.
Tragic loss ... Hannah Witheridge and David Miller were found bludgeoned to death. Source: Supplied
Autopsies showed that the young backpackers, who had met while staying at the same hotel, had both suffered severe head wounds and that Witheridge had been raped.
The first policeman on the scene, Lt. Jakrapan Kaewkao, told the court that he received a call at 6.30am that morning about two tourists bodies found on the beach. He said he discovered a gruesome scene on arrival, with Miller face down in the shallow surf.
I found a mans body lying on the beach with seawater lapping his body, said Jakrapan, the prosecutions first witness. Then I found the womans body behind the rocks. The rocks were spotted with blood, he said.
He said the two bodies were several metres apart and both were mostly unclothed, with Witheridges body bearing signs of physical assault.
Millers father and brother and Witheridges mother and brother were in the courtroom, and there were about a dozen people from Myanmar, including a representative from its Bangkok embassy.
In the small courtroom on Koh Samui, an island near Koh Tao, the accused sat in orange prison uniforms with their legs shackled.
It begins ... Myanmar national Zaw Lin walks out of a prison transport van as he arrives at court. Source: AFP
The two men, Win Zaw Htun and Zaw Lin, both 22, were arrested in early October and initially confessed to the killings but then retracted their statements, saying they were extracted through beatings and threats, which police deny. Human rights groups repeatedly called for an independent investigation and raised concerns that the men might be scapegoats.
The accused were indicted on several charges related to the murders and to illegally working in Thailand. Prosecutors say they have a solid case against them that includes DNA evidence linking them to the crime. If found guilty they could face the death pnality.
Journalists were initially allowed into the courtroom, which seats about 30 people, but then ushered out to make room for relatives of the victims, diplomats and others attending the trial.
A second witness, Dr. Chasit Yoohad, gave testimony about his examination of the victims bodies on the beach.
He told the court that Witheridge had recently had sex and suffered traumatic head injuries while Millers body was found naked and had been struck, but without the same level of injury. He estimated the time of death for both was around 5.30am.
He said he also performed a medical check-up of the two accused, and found them in good health. He said he asked through a translator if they had committed the crime, and they replied that they had.
We hope the truth will be revealed, defence lawyer Nakhon Chompuchat said as he headed into the courtroom. We hope the mechanism of justice in Thailand ... will have the same standards of international countries.
High-profile case ... Myanmar national Win Zaw Tun walks arrives for the start of his trial. Source: AFP
Twelve days have been scheduled for prosecution witnesses, but it is unclear when the proceedings will be concluded.
From the start, the case raised questions about police competence. Investigators faced a variety of criticisms, including their failure to secure the crime scene and their releasing of several names and pictures of suspects who turned out to be innocent.
The defence again questioned yesterday why it took many hours for police to seal off the crime scene with rope and delay calling medical experts.
Under intense pressure to solve the case, which drew global attention, police went on to carry out DNA tests on more than 200 people on Koh Tao.
Concerns that the men were tortured by police originated with advocates for migrant workers, who are often abused and mistreated without the safeguard of rights held by Thai citizens. The British government also expressed concern to Thai authorities about the way the investigation was being conducted. As a result, British police were allowed to observe the case assembled by their Thai counterparts.
Bowed heads ... The brother and father of murdered Hannah Witheridg leave court. Source: AFP
The victims families issued a joint statement.
The Witheridges urged the media not to focus on the speculation, rumour and theory that has surrounded the case, making an unthinkable time harder to bear.
Hannah was a beautiful person, inside and out, she brought a room alive just being there, they wrote.
Her bright future was brutally ended leaving those who loved her broken with no answers.
Millers family said that just hours before he died, their son had called home and described the beauty of Koh Tao and the friendliness of the Thai people. Over the coming weeks we hope to gain a better understanding as to how such a wonderful young man lost his life in such idyllic surroundings in such a horrible way, they said.
About 2.5 million people from Myanmar work in Thailand, most as domestic servants or in low-skilled manual jobs such as construction, fisheries or the garment sector.
The gruesome killings tarnished the image of Thailands tourism industry, which has been struggling to recover after the army imposed martial law and staged a coup in May 2014
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 02:49:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Christian soldiers train to destroy ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/iraqs-dispossessed-christians-are-training-to-become-troops-in-the-fight-to-regain-their-homes/story-fndir2ev-1227434677677?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>WITH crosses and Kalashnikovs, Iraqi Christians are in training to form a new military force aimed at recapturing their homes from the Islamic State.</Description>
        <MainBody>SHARKNADO is real, people. Well, it is for one grandma who found a shark in her backyard.
World
Iraqs dispossessed Christians are training to become troops in the fight to regain their homes
by:
Where do they come from and what do they want? The Islamic State explained.
News Corp Australia
15 Jun 2015
News
In the firing line ... With wooden crosses around their necks and others tattooed on their arms, Iraqi Christians are training to recapture their homes overrun by the Islamic State jihadist group. Source: AFP Source: AFP
WITH wooden crosses around their necks and others tattooed on their arms, Iraqi Christians are in training to recapture their homes overrun by the Islamic State jihadist group.
A year ago, IS launched a fierce offensive in northern Iraq, quickly capturing second city Mosul, with its large Christian minority, and Christian-populated areas in the surrounding Nineveh province.
Residents were given the choice of converting to Islam, paying a tax to continue practising their faith, or death.
Thousands fled, but some want to fight back.
Christian soldier ... A tattoo of Jesus Christ is seen on the arm of an Iraqi volunteer from the northern embattled Mosul governorate. Source: AFP Source: AFP
They are now training at a military base near the Baghdad airport.
Shiite Muslim fighters are instructing them on how to use their Kalashnikov assault rifles and on the basics of combat manoeuvres, but they are vocal in their Christianity on parade, chanting Ya Mariam (O Mary) in cadence as they march in a salute to the mother of Jesus.
We heard that the Christians had an opportunity for jihad (holy war), and we all came and volunteered, said 17-year-old Chaldean Christian Frank Samir.
Freedom fighters ... Volunteer fighters attend a training session at a base in Baghdad airport. Source: AFP Source: AFP
Our children are dying; our Christian families were displaced. How do we ourselves accept that people say the Christians are not fighting? On the contrary, we want to fight everywhere, he said.
BACKGROUNDER: Understainding Islamic States success, one year on
Samir is from Baghdad, but most of the Christians in the Ketaeb Babylon unit are from Mosul.
The IS assault was the latest in a long series of disasters for Iraqi Christians, who have repeatedly been attacked by jihadists since the 2003 overthrow of dictator Saddam Hussein, pushing hundreds of thousands to flee abroad.
Crosses and Kalashnikovs ... An Iraqi Christian volunteer fighter. Source: AFP Source: AFP
Mark of faith ... A tattoo on the arm of an Iraqi Christian volunteer. Source: AFP Source: AFP
Two weeks of training
I did not hesitate to volunteer with my brothers to fight Daesh, said Fares Issa, 38, using an Arabic acronym for IS.
I will continue fighting (them) until the liberation of Mosul and their expulsion from all the areas of Iraq, said Issa, who sold cars in Mosul before the conflict began.
Both Christian and Muslim religious symbols are displayed at the training area. These include a large cross affixed to a concrete blast wall and banners reading God is greatest and There is no god but God, the first part of the Muslim testament of faith.
Banner of belief ... A flag reading in Arabic: "Christian Movement in Iraq" is seen as Iraqi Christian volunteer fighters from Baghdad. Source: AFP Source: AFP
The training courses  of which this is the ninth  last only two weeks. But this is far too little time to turn new recruits into competent fighters able to face the battle-hardened jihadists, many of whom have years of experience fighting in Iraq and neighbouring Syria.
The main aim of forming our forces is the liberation of Mosul, said Rayan al-Kaldani, the secretary-general of Ketaeb Babylon.
Holy warriors ... A training session in a base at Baghdad airport. Source: AFP Source: AFP
We took part in the operations to liberate the city of Tikrit and other operations, including Baiji, in Salaheddin province, he said, referring to major battles north of Baghdad.
According to Kaldani, the Christians fight under the command of Abu Mahdi al-Mohandis, one of the top commanders in the Popular Mobilisation forces, an umbrella organisation mainly made up of Shiite fighters.
Insignia ... The uniform wooden cross as worn by Iraqs Christian volunteer fighters. Source: AFP Source: AFP
Source: AFP Source: AFP
Source: AFP Source: AFP
Close-quarters combat
Baghdad turned to the Popular Mobilisation forces, which are dominated by Iranian-backed Shiite militias, after the security forces suffered a series of disastrous defeats by IS last year.
According to another Ketaeb Babylon commander, who declined to be named, there are hundreds of Christian fighters located now in various areas of Salaheddin ... in addition to others responsible for protecting churches in Baghdad province. Recruitment of other volunteers to fight the Daesh terrorist organisation is continuing, he said.
Battling for belief ... A flag from the Christian movement in Iraq flies from a cross over a Baghdad training facility. Source: AFP Source: AFP
A man who gave his name as Hajji Ali, a leader of one of the Shiite units overseeing the training, said it focuses on close-quarters combat, unconventional warfare and war inside the cities. Their eyes are on Mosul and the areas occupied by Daesh, Hajji Ali said of the Christian fighters.
The volunteers say Mosul is the main goal, but their fight is not limited to that city.
Mosul is our first aim, said 16-year-old Raymoun Salwan, who was displaced from the city.
But I will continue to fight terrorism wherever it goes in Iraq and every place, he said
Severe Clear 1:33:10
WARNING - Graphic Content: A first person account of the soldier's experience on the front lines of Iraq, a place of constant danger where nothing can be predicted but terror.
Oovvuu
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Close encounter of the humpback kind</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/technology/science/video-shows-pod-of-humpback-whales-surfacing-simultaneously-in-resurrection-bay-alaska/story-fnjwkt0b-1227434591838?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>TWO men out fishing on an Alaskan bay got the surprise of their lives when a pod of humpback whales surfaced simultaneously, just metres away from their boat. Watch the video.</Description>
        <MainBody>MEET Australias next assault rifle: The EF88 Austeyr. With 30,000 due to be delivered next year, well soon be seeing a lot more of them.
Science
Video shows pod of humpback whales surfacing simultaneously in Resurrection Bay, Alaska
by:
What are these?
Humpback encounter ... the whales were surfacing to feed. Picture: Brad Rich Source: YouTube
TWO men out fishing on a remote Alaskan bay could not contain their excitement when a pod of humpback whales breached simultaneously, just metres away from their boat.
Brad Rich and Tony Flanders were in Resurrection Bay, south of the state capital Anchorage, when they had the unique encounter.
The men told local TV station KTVA that they had spotted the whales at a distance before the pod suddenly surfaced to feed just by the boat.
I knew that humpbacks do this group feeding. So I knew what was happening as soon as it happened, Mr Rich told KTVA. But to be in the middle of that, to actually experience that as to just watching it, it was the most awe-inspiring thing, its the most amazing thing to have ever happened to me.
Whales surface
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Charles Manson might not be guilty</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/why-charles-manson-might-not-be-guilty/story-fnq2oad4-1227434598722?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>HE&amp;#8217;S been rotting in jail for decades, but have we been wrong about this madman mass murderer all along? One man says he has proof.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Charles Manson. Did the justice system get it wrong? Source: AP
CHARLES Manson  the charismatic cult leader convicted in the deaths of actress Sharon Tate and eight other victims  might not be guilty, according to New York journalist Daniel Simone.
Simone and co-author Heidi Ley are putting the finishing touches on a book that will lay out all the evidence that Manson, 80, was the victim of ruthlessly ambitious prosecutor Vincent Bugliosi , who died in June.
The reader will walk away with doubts, Simone says. Of Mansons 37 prior arrests, none involved violence. And [almost] every single witness who testified against him was a convicted felon or facing trial.
Manson wasnt even at the scenes of the Tate-LaBianca murders but was convicted because he told his co-conspirators to do it.
Manson, who gave the authors 12 hours of prison interviews, has authorised the tome.
He not only signed off on it, he placed his thumbprints beneath his signature in case someone questions its authenticity, Simone said. Hes quite clever.
But Manson wasnt clever when he insisted on representing himself at his 1971 murder trial. Simone says a good lawyer would have argued in a pre-trial motion that there was no proof Manson had directed his followers to kill.
He probably could have gotten the case dismissed based on the lack of evidence, Simone said.
As for Manson, who famously has a swastika scratched into his forehead, At times hes completely incoherent, Simone said. Other times, hes articulate and made a lot of sense ... I am sure he is using illegal narcotics.
Mansons engagement to a woman 53 years his junior was called off in February after Simone claimed the convicted killers fiancee, 27-year-old Afton Elaine Burton, known as Star, planned to profit from his death.
Manson apparently got cold feet after learning of Stars alleged plot to take ownership of his corpse and put it on display in a wild, money-making scheme.
Hes finally realised that hes been played for a fool, Simone said. Also, Manson believes he is immortal.
He feels he will never die. Therefore, he feels its a stupid idea to begin with.
Manson with ex-fiancee Star. He apparently broke up with her after discovering what she planned to do with his dead body. Source: Supplied
Are You Good Or Evil? 48:20
What would it take for things to fall out of balance in our normal brains? Could we all become natural born killers? Horizon finds out just how delicately balanced our brains are.
Oovvuu
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Disney World removes Cosby statue</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/walt-disney-world-in-orlando-florida-removes-bronze-bill-cosby-statue/story-fn907478-1227434425576?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>THE happiest place on Earth no longer includes Bill Cosby after Walt Disney World removed a bronze statue of the comedian and distanced itself from him.</Description>
        <MainBody>FROM Friends to Full House, we take you beyond the fourth wall to see what the TV sets of your favourite shows really looked like.
celebrity life
Walt Disney World in Orlando, Florida, removes bronze Bill Cosby statue
by:
Mathew Murphy and Network Writers
From:
Gone ... A bronzed bust of Bill Cosby has been removed from Walt Disney World. Picture: Supplied Source: News Limited
Cosby admits drugging woman 0:25
Court documents show Bill Cosby admitted having drugged at least one woman in order to have sex with her.
Sky News
07 Jul 2015
News/World
THE happiest place on Earth no longer includes Bill Cosby after Walt Disney World removed a bronze statue of the comedian and distanced itself from him.
The move comes after unsealed court documents from 2005 released on Monday showed that Cosby admitted giving a woman Quaaludes before sex.
Bill Cosby case
At least 40 women have come forward saying that Cosby drugged them with Quaaludes and then raped them.
In a statement, Walt Disney World told the Orlando Sentinel that the bronzed bust of Cosby was removed after the park closed on Tuesday night. The bust was among others including Lucille Ball and Oprah Winfrey who are recipients in the Television Academy Hall of Fame.
Conflicted ... Raven-Symone, seen here in 2011, says she feels indebted to Bill Cosby because he gave her her start on TV.  Picture:  Supplied Source: AP
Backflip ... Jill Scott says shes now completely disgusted by Bill Cosby.  Picture:  AP Source: AP
TV stations in the US have pulled re-runs of The Cosby Show, while his supporters including Jill Scott and former co-star Raven-Symone have also distanced themselves from him since the documents were revealed.
I dont really like to talk about it that much because hes the reason Im on this panel in the first place. He gave me my first job, Raven-Symone, 29, said. But at the same time, you need the proof, and then Ill be able to give my judgment here or there. And now there are real facts. More people can come up.
Scott said she was completely disgusted by the revelations.
Sadly his own testimony offers PROOF of terrible deeds, which is ALL I have ever required to believe the accusations, she tweeted. I stood by a man I respected and loved. I was wrong. It HURTS!!! When you get it ALL right, holla.
Whoopi Goldberg and former on-screen wife Phylicia Rashad appear to remain in Cosbys corner despite the latest revelations.
Cosby supporter ... Whoopi Goldberg says she believes that Bill Cosby should be innocent until proven guilty.  Picture:  AP Source: AP
Close ... Phylicia Rashad, who played Bill Cosbys wife on The Cosby Show, has stood by him.  Picture:  Supplied Source: Supplied
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stock exchange paralysed for hours</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/finance/markets/tech-glitch-halts-new-york-stock-exchange/story-e6frfm30-1227434469321?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>THE New York Stock Exchange halted trading on all stocks overnight because of a technical problem, as a system glitch forced United Airlines to ground all planes.</Description>
        <MainBody> NYSE (@NYSE) July 8, 2015
While NYSE, which is operated by InterContinental Exchange, is the symbol of American capitalism, there were at least 10 other exchanges including the Nasdaq as well as dark pools still actively trading was down, trading was still going on the roughly ten other exchanges, like Nasdaq.
We are in contact with NYSE and are closely monitoring the situation and trading in NYSE-listed stocks. While NYSE is working to resolve the situation, NYSE and NYSE stocks continue to trade normally through other trading venues. said Securities and Exchange Commission chair Mary Jo White.
It wasnt like from my seat that all of sudden you had to call the trading desk to get something executed manually, one broker said. Everything systems-wise is flawless.
Trader ... specialist William Bott works on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Picture: AP Photo/Seth Wenig Source: AP
After the NYSE halted stocks, the website for the Wall Street Journal homepage was also down for unconfirmed reasons. The webpage was restored by 12:30pm.
Stock trading continued on other exchanges and dark pools, with the Dow down 1.18 per cent by noon 17,548.95.
It wasnt the only glitch of the day.
United Airlines grounds flights worldwide
United Continental had grounded all their planes worldwide in the morning for more than an hour because of a network connectivity issue, the company said in a statement.
Trading volume on Uniteds stock was lower than normal during the outage, the broker said.
US officials said that there was no connection between the two.
We're recovering from a network connectivity issue &amp; restoring flight ops. Well have a waiver on http://t.co/ufFoKFTNNe to change flights.
The US Department of Homeland Security did not have an official statement about the computer outages.
However, the agency said there was no immediate indication of a coordinated cyberattack.
Grounded ... United Airlines passengers wait in line to check in for flights at San Francisco International Airport. Picture: Justin Sullivan/Getty Images/AFP Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baby shark falls from the sky</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/technology/science/family-stunned-after-baby-shark-falls-from-the-sky/story-fnjwkt0b-1227434503193?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>SHARKNADO is real, people. Well, it is for one grandma who found a shark in her backyard.</Description>
        <MainBody>Real-life Sharknado ... a baby shark fell from the sky, into a stunned familys backyard. Picture: wavy.com Source: Supplied
ITS a bird. Its a plane. Its ... Sharknado?
A US family was left stunned after a baby shark fell out of the sky and landed in their backyard.
Sue Bowser said her grandchildren found the dead dogfish shark near a pond at her Virginia Beach, Virginia home on June 26.
This could be the shark house, but hopefully not too many more will be falling from the sky, Ms Bowser told wavy.com.
The kids found it, and they came upstairs and they were all excited and said, We found a shark in the backyard.
Baby shark ... the 33cm dogfish shark landed near a pond in a familys backyard. Picture: wavy.com Source: Supplied
Surprised ... Sue Bowser said her grandchildren found the dead shark in her yard. Picture: wavy.com Source: Supplied
Ms Bowser said she thinks the 33cm smooth dogfish was killed and dropped by a large osprey, also known as a fish eagle or sea hawk.
Theres a little mark on his side where the talons probably went in, and its a little bloody on the side where the talons had poked him, she said.
Incredible find ... Sue Bowser has shown off the baby shark to family and friends. Picture: wavy.com Source: Supplied
Baby teeth ... Sue Bowser keeps the shark in her freezer. Picture: wavy.com Source: Supplied
The grandmother keeps the slimy creature in her freezer next to the pureed apples, but sometimes whips it out to show family and friends.
I would like to preserve the shark because a lot of people have asked about it and I think its just so unique, Ms Bowser said.
Sharknado 2: Yes, it happened
(Frame content direct link: https://www.youtube.com/embed/G5wf1f8Nmt8 .)
##
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:57:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dad killed shooting firework off chest</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/brekkie-wrap-justin-bartek-launched-firework-off-chest-and-was-killed/story-fndir2ev-1227434488888?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>BREKKIE WRAP: A FATHER has died after launching a firework off his chest, days after a man who lit a rocket over his head was killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>SHARKNADO is real, people. Well, it is for one grandma who found a shark in her backyard.
World
BREKKIE WRAP: Justin Bartek launched firework off chest and was killed
by:
Mathew Murphy and Network Writers
From:
What are these?
Tragic ... Justin Bartek leaves behind his girlfriend, Summer Jenkins. Picture: GoFundMe Source: Supplied
A 30-YEAR-OLD father who launched a firework off his chest has died, days after a man was killed when he lit a rocket over his head.
Police said Justin Bartek was setting off fireworks with friends at a fishing spot in Columbus, Texas, about 1.30am Tuesday when he lit a firework called Medieval Knight on his chest.
The US postman was rushed to hospital in a critical condition but succumbed to his injuries.
KTRK reports the precise cause of death is yet to be determined.
Bartek leaves behind his three-year-old son Braxton and girlfriend Summer Jenkins.
The tragic death comes after 22-year-old Devon Staples was killed after trying to launch a firework off the top of his head.
The US man was drinking and celebrating the Fourth of July holiday at a friends house in the Maine city of Calais when he placed a fireworks mortar tube on his head. He died instantly.
Bad interview ... A racism expert says the real problem with the Dawn Fraser interview where she told Nick Kyrgios, inset, to go back to his own country was that the comment slipped by without being picked up on by interviewer Karl Stefanovic. Picture: Supplied. Source: Supplied
IN NATIONAL NEWS
 SHE created a furore after a racist comment calling on Nick Kyrgios to go back to his own country but thats not the worst part of the Dawn Fraser interview .
 CONSUMER cops are moving to shut down an Australian website accused of ripping off parents and shattering the birthday wishes of children across the country.
 LABOR leader Bill Shorten walks away from his six-hour grilling today with a problem that is likely to jar with many Aussie voters.
 AN Australian mother who fell pregnant from a one-night stand has been reunited with the father of her child after she placed an ad on Gumtree .
 UTTERLY outclassed, NSW resorted to cheap shots and dangerous throws as Queensland romped to victory in State of Origin Game III . These are the talking points.
Suspended ... The New York Stock Exchange, pictured here, has ground to a halt due to a computer glitch. Picture: AP Source: AP
IN WORLD NEWS
 THE New York Stock Exchange halted trading on all stocks overnight because of a technical problem, sending markets into a spin.
 GREECE has told Europe they plan to immediately implement tax and pension related measures in a bid to reform their economy.
 AN Australian has been gored in the groin and the thigh during the second bull-run of Pamplonas San Fermin festival.
 FACEBOOK has just made a small, but important, change to its icons  and you probably didnt even notice.
Gone ... A bronzed bust of Bill Cosby has been removed from Walt Disney World. Picture: Supplied Source: Supplied
IN SHOWBIZ NEWS
 THE happiest place on Earth no longer includes Bill Cosby after Walt Disney World removed a bronze statue of the comedian and distanced itself from him.
 JURASSIC Park actor Jeff Goldblum has become a first-time father at 62 after his new wife, 32, gave birth on July 4.
 AC/DC drummer Phil Rudd is set to learn his fate after he was charged with threatening to kill and drug possession in New Zealand.
Semis ... Roger Federer will play Andy Murray at Wimbledon. Picture: Supplied Source: News Limited
IN SPORTS NEWS
 ROGER Federer and Andy Murray will face-off in the Wimbledon semis after straight sets victories on a day marred by rain and overzealous officiating.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dad fatally launches firework off chest</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/father-killed-after-launching-firework-off-his-chest/story-fnq2o7dd-1227434410864?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>A FATHER has died after launching a firework off his chest, days after a man who lit a rocket over his head was killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Fatal mistake ... Justin Bartek, 30, died after launching a firework off his chest. Picture: Facebook/Summer Bartek Source: Supplied
A 30-YEAR-OLD father who launched a firework off his chest has died, days after a man was killed when he lit a rocket over his head.
Police said Justin Bartek was setting off fireworks with friends at a fishing spot in Columbus, Texas, about 1.30am Tuesday when he lit a firework called Medieval Knight on his chest.
The US postman was rushed to hospital in a critical condition but succumbed to his injuries.
KTRK reports the precise cause of death is yet to be determined.
Tragic loss ... Justin Bartek leaves behind his girlfriend, Summer Jenkins. Picture: GoFundMe Source: Supplied
Bartek leaves behind his three-year-old son Braxton and girlfriend Summer Jenkins.
Family and friends described Bartek as generous and loving.
He just had an infectious spirit, whenever you met him you met a friend, Erica Jackson, who set up a GoFundMe account to raise money for Barteks family, told Click2Houston.
He was the light of many peoples lives and the world to the people that knew him, and he would give the world to any that asked.
Young dad ... Justin Bartek with his son, Braxton. Picture: GoFundMe Source: Supplied
The tragic death comes after 22-year-old Devon Staples was killed after trying to launch a firework off the top of his head .
The US man was drinking and celebrating the Fourth of July holiday at a friends house in the Maine city of Calais when he placed a fireworks mortar tube on his head. He died instantly.
Fourth of July tragedy ... Devon Staples died after trying to launch a firework off his head. Picture: Facebook/Devon Staples Source: Supplied
##
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
