<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="npr">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI Director Brings Silicon Valley Encryption Fight To Capitol Hill</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/08/421225069/fbi-director-brings-silicon-valley-encryption-fight-to-capitol-hill?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>FBI Director James Comey went to Capitol Hill on Wednesday to make a case for Silicon Valley companies to continue to let law enforcement monitor communications over encrypted devices.</Description>
        <MainBody>FBI Director Brings Silicon Valley Encryption Fight To Capitol Hill
July 08, 2015 5:39 PM ET
FBI Director James Comey went to Capitol Hill on Wednesday to make a case for Silicon Valley companies to continue to let law enforcement monitor communications over encrypted devices.
ROBERT SIEGEL, HOST:
FBI director, James Comey, was on Capitol Hill today, and he was talking about encryption. Comey wants Silicon Valley companies to allow law enforcement the ability to monitor communications with a court order. But companies have resisted, and they're building more and more encrypted devices that can only be opened by the user. That's called strong encryption, and the FBI director says that's a problem.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
JAMES COMEY: We cannot break strong encryption. I think people watch TV and think the Bureau can do lots of things. We cannot break strong encryption.
SIEGEL: NPR's Dina Temple-Raston joins me now with the latest in this debate. Hi, Dina.
DINA TEMPLE-RASTON, BYLINE: Hi there.
SIEGEL: Did James Comey make an effective case for law enforcement access to encrypted data?
TEMPLE-RASTON: I think he made a start. He provided senators on the Judiciary and Intelligence Committees with very specific examples - actual cases in which he said the FBI tried to obtain electronic information after getting a warrant but they couldn't get it because it was encrypted or scrambled. He said it came up in a recent case in Boston. A follower of the self-proclaimed Islamic State, or ISIL, was contemplating an attack, but the FBI couldn't see exactly what he was planning because they lost him in an encrypted site. That's something the Bureau calls going dark. And here's what he said happened.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
COMEY: In Boston, you had a guy who was in touch in an encrypted way with these ISIL recruiters and, we believe, was bent on doing something on July 4. He woke up one morning, June 2, and decided he was going to go kill somebody. He confronted our people with a knife, and unfortunately, they had to use their weapons. But that's an example of sort of the unpredictability of this.
SIEGEL: And he had examples that weren't just about terrorism.
TEMPLE-RASTON: Yes. He said the encryption technology actually affects everything from child pornography to kidnapping. He talked about a case of a long-haul trucker who had kidnapped his girlfriend last December. The trucker took her from state to state and sexually assaulted her, and she eventually escaped and pressed charges. And the trucker claimed it was consensual sex. As it turned out, he had videotaped his assaults on his smartphone. The FBI got a warrant, and they used that video against him in court.
SIEGEL: And how would that case have been different if the phone had this new encryption on it?
TEMPLE-RASTON: Well, Comey said if there had been one key encryption, or end-to-end encryption, on that phone, the truck driver would have refused to give them a password to open it. End-to-end encryption means that law enforcement has to go directly to a target instead of to, say, a company for a password or a key. If they had end-to-end encryption in place for that trucker case, they might not have had access to that incriminating video.
SIEGEL: And what about technical concerns? Does having passwords or encryption keys for law enforcement actually weaken the system overall?
TEMPLE-RASTON: Well, some elite security technologists released a paper last night that made pretty much that argument. They provided a technical analysis of the government's proposals for special access, and they think what the government wants could put the whole system at risk because, as they see it, if law enforcement could get that access, then maybe hackers could get that access too. The group - this particular group has some sway because it ended up derailing a plan in the 1990s to allow the government to unscramble communications. What's unclear this time is whether they have - they can have that kind of effect. Director Comey has said he's open to any ideas that technology companies might have to solve this encryption problem, and the solution, he suggested, might be something that hasn't even been discovered yet.
SIEGEL: Dina, just one question. I mean, if I'm not a terrorist or not a pornographer, what's my protection here that the FBI or other agencies of government won't go poking into my personal data?
TEMPLE-RASTON: Well, theoretically, the way this is supposed to work is they're supposed to go into a judge and actually get a warrant. What he's talking about now is even with a warrant, with these encrypted devices, the warrant doesn't do them any good.
SIEGEL: OK. Thank you, Dina. That's NPR's Dina Temple-Raston.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:31:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guatemalan Ex-Dictator Rios Montt Found Mentally Unfit For Genocide Retrial</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/08/421225062/guatemalan-ex-dictator-rios-montt-found-mentally-unfit-for-genocide-retrial?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>NPR's Kelly McEvers speaks with documentary filmmaker Pamela Yates about Guatemalan ex-dictator Efrain Rios Montt, who was declared mentally unfit for trial Tuesday by Guatemala's forensic authority.</Description>
        <MainBody>Guatemalan Ex-Dictator Rios Montt Found Mentally Unfit For Genocide Retrial
July 08, 2015 5:31 PM ET
NPR's Kelly McEvers speaks with documentary filmmaker Pamela Yates about Guatemalan ex-dictator Efrain Rios Montt, who was declared mentally unfit for trial Tuesday by Guatemala's forensic authority.
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
Former Guatemalan dictator Jose Efrain Rios Montt has been declared mentally unfit to stand trial for committing genocide. Rios Montt briefly ruled Guatemala in the 1980s, during one of the most deadly periods of that country's civil war. He and his former intelligence chief are accused of ordering the army to kill more than 1,700 indigenous people in northern Guatemala. Filmmaker Pamela Yates has been covering Rios Montt and Guatemala since the 1980s, and she joins us now. Welcome to the show.
PAMELA YATES: Thank you, Kelly.
MCEVERS: This is not the first time the case against Rios Montt has been thrown out, right? I mean, he was actually found guilty of genocide back in 2013, but then a high court threw that ruling out and ordered this new trial. What's happening here?
YATES: Well, he was found guilty, and 10 days later, the Constitutional Court - they annulled the verdict on technical grounds. The vote in the Constitutional Court was 3 to 2, and the two who dissented, dissented vociferously, questioning the legality of the other three's ruling. Since then, Rios Montt's lawyers have continued to obstruct the beginning of the new trial. And that has been their defense strategy all along - to never have this trial restart because what was exposed at the first two-month trial was so shocking and had been so hidden in Guatemalan history that they decided never to allow that to happen again.
MCEVERS: Well, tell us about that. What was exposed during that trial?
YATES: What was revealed was the extent of this systemic targeting of the Mayan Indians in the Maya Ixil region of the Guatemalan Highlands and how entire villages were wiped out, how women, children and men were killed and what racism had to play in the Guatemalan armed forces' attack on the civilian population. The genocide in Guatemala, which is the sole genocide of the Americas in the 20th-century, is not taught in Guatemala high schools. It's not taught in the colleges. And so many people don't believe the genocide happened. Now they can no longer believe that.
MCEVERS: You were there in Guatemala back in the early '80s. You actually met Rios Montt, and you interviewed him on tape. Can you just tell us about that time and what he said to you?
YATES: I had been petitioning to interview him for months and finally, in June 1982, I got the chance. And I kept asking him about all the things that I had been seeing in the Highlands, where the military was attacking the civilian population, and he kept denying it. And finally he got really angry, and he said, if I don't control the army, then what am I doing here? Meaning - what am I doing here as president of the country? And that was used in the genocide case to show command responsibility. Command responsibility is a really important element in the crime of genocide.
MCEVERS: Right, 'cause it's really difficult. People can always say, oh, I was just following orders, but then it's always hard to find that guy who was giving the orders. And this is somebody who's basically saying, I was in charge.
YATES: I gave the orders. I'm in charge here. I'm the president.
MCEVERS: And so knowing what you know about him - about Rios Montt - what has it been like for you to sit in that courtroom and watch this process unfold?
YATES: It was incredibly satisfying because, you know, the Guatemalans - the survivors of the genocide - have never given up on the quest for justice. And they, along with incredible human rights defenders and international allies, spent 13 years building this case. And this case was the first time in the Americas where someone was on trial for genocide against indigenous people.
MCEVERS: So it sounds like, to you, justice has prevailed, whether a high court allows this final trial to go through or not.
YATES: And not just to me - to many Guatemalans and especially to the Mayans in Guatemala. They have a saying - la sentencia esta vigente - the verdict is valid. He was judged to be a genocidaire, and in their minds, he is a genocidaire.
MCEVERS: Pamela Yates into the documentary filmmaker who's been working in Guatemala for decades. Her next film, "500 Years," explores how Guatemala is working to shape it's national narrative. Pamela Yates, thank you very much.
YATES: Thank you, Kelly.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:31:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China's Economic Downturn Needs To Happen To Boost Consumption</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/08/421225041/chinas-economic-downturn-needs-to-happen-to-boost-consumption?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>NPR's Robert Siegel talks with Patrick Chovanec, chief strategist with Silvercrest Asset Management group, about the Chinese stock market and the impact on the U.S. and global economy.</Description>
        <MainBody>China's Economic Downturn Needs To Happen To Boost Consumption
July 08, 2015 5:31 PM ET
NPR's Robert Siegel talks with Patrick Chovanec, chief strategist with Silvercrest Asset Management group, about the Chinese stock market and the impact on the U.S. and global economy.
ROBERT SIEGEL, HOST:
Now to the Chinese markets and what the crash there means for Americans. Chinese stock markets have lost nearly a third of their value in the past three weeks, despite intervention by the Chinese government to try to stop the slide. Patrick Chovanec has worked and taught in China. He's an investment strategist for a wealth management firm, and he also teaches part-time at Columbia University. Welcome to the program.
PATRICK CHOVANEC: Good to be with you.
SIEGEL: The White House announced today that the U.S. government - the treasury of White House is keeping an eye on the Chinese markets. Is what's happening there likely to affect typical American investors?
CHOVANEC: Well, few investors and few financial institutions in the United States have any direct exposure. The bigger question is whether it reflects some kind of turn in the Chinese economy that will impact the global economy. And there, I would say that China's stock market bubble and the bursting of that bubble is really more of a symptom of China's economic troubles then it is a cause. China's stock market became detached from its real economy, which has been deteriorating over the course of the past few years, and reality caught up to it.
SIEGEL: One measure of what you're saying is the Chinese stock prices, despite the big losses in the recent weeks, are still higher today than they were a year ago. So there really was quite a bubble.
CHOVANEC: They are higher, but this crash, I don't think, is over. And I think they're going right back down to where they started about a year ago. That would be consistent with what took place in 2007. China had a very similar bubble where the market tripled in the course of 12 months, and then in the next 12 months, it sold off right back to where was. So this is not something that's completely new for China.
SIEGEL: Do people who own mutual funds that say global markets or emerging markets or international markets - are they perhaps indirectly involved in this, in the Chinese stock markets?
CHOVANEC: They are exposed to the extent that they are invested in Hong Kong, and Hong Kong has also seen a sellout. But although Hong Kong prices rose in recent months, they did not skyrocket the way that domestic Chinese shares did.
SIEGEL: When the most recent Chinese bubble burst back in 2007, 2008, was the U.S. hurt by that?
CHOVANEC: It's hard to disentangle from the global financial crisis that then took hold. What's interesting is not only did it not really affect the U.S. economy very much, but it also really didn't affect the Chinese economy that much. The Chinese economy was still going like gang busters in the summer of 2008, even though the stock market had lost about two-thirds of its value.
SIEGEL: Are the Chinese markets irrational? I mean, is this - is this a rough place to invest?
CHOVANEC: They're very volatile, and they don't always trade based on fundamentals. And sometimes the government gives the impression that everybody can pile in and that it's risk-free and that the government will ensure that nothing happens. And this time around, the government has really pulled out all the stops in China to try to keep share prices from falling. They have gone in and actually bought very aggressively, but it hasn't stopped the falling prices.
SIEGEL: So you're saying, really, that if this is a dose of reality taking hold in the Chinese markets, there's something good about what's going on right now.
CHOVANEC: Well, look, China is undergoing a profound economic adjustment right now, away from one kind of growth model which relied on exports and investment towards another kind of growth model that is more balanced between domestic consumption and investment. And in the long run, that's going to be good. It's very disruptive. That being said, this is a transition that needs to happen. It's a transition that ultimately will be good for China, and it's a transition that's actually good for the rest of the world economy because it's really going to boost consumption from China.
That's - when the rest of the world looks at the Chinese economy, they shouldn't be so concerned about what the output levels or GDP levels are in China. They should care about whether China continues to consume. And China has produced more than it's consumed for years. It has all these reserves - $4 trillion worth of foreign exchange reserves. It can afford to consume more than it produces, so that's one thing that I think is actually going to be - this economic adjustment in China is actually ultimately going to turn China into a driver of consumer demand globally.
SIEGEL: Patrick Chovanec, thanks for talking with us.
CHOVANEC: You're welcome.
SIEGEL: Patrick Chovanec, chief strategist with Silvercrest Asset Management Group and also an adjunct professor at Columbia University School of International Public Affairs.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lead Prosecutor Brings Ghandi-Like Attitude To Brazil's Corruption Scandal</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/08/421225013/lead-prosecutor-brings-ghandi-like-attitude-to-brazils-corruption-scandal?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>In Brazil, one of the biggest corruption scandals in its history has an unlikely hero. He is a 35-year-old Harvard educated lawyer who says his inspiration is Gandhi.</Description>
        <MainBody>Lead Prosecutor Brings Ghandi-Like Attitude To Brazil's Corruption Scandal
July 08, 2015 5:31 PM ET
In Brazil, one of the biggest corruption scandals in its history has an unlikely hero. He is a 35-year-old Harvard educated lawyer who says his inspiration is Gandhi.
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
One of the biggest corruption scandals in Brazil's history has an unlikely hero. He's a 35-year-old, Harvard-educated lawyer who says his inspiration is Gandhi. NPR's Lourdes Garcia-Navarro went to meet him in a sleepy state capital that's become a beacon for fighting white-collar crime.
LOURDES GARCIA-NAVARRO, BYLINE: Like so many things that become really huge, it started small, with an email.
DELTAN DALLAGNOL: A simple email that was exchanged between one of the main characters of this case and a seller of vehicles.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: We'll hear more about that in a moment. First meet Deltan Dallagnol. He's the lead prosecutor in a case that has unprecedented scope. It's led to the arrests of the heads of some of Latin America's biggest companies. It's implicated leading political figures in Brazil, including the heads of both houses of Congress, and it sent the Brazilian economy into a tailspin. We sit down to talk in his office in Curitiba, the state capital of Parana in Brazil's south. He's clean-cut, brown hair, soft eyes, earnest, but he can laugh about all the attention he's been getting. He asks me what I want to talk about.
You're involved in - I don't what it is.
DALLAGNOL: I don't either.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: What is it? Oh. Oh, I know. There's something.
DALLAGNOL: Rich cars.
(LAUGHTER)
DALLAGNOL: Cars.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: The name of this vast investigation into corruption at the state oil company here is Lava-Jato, or carwash. So now back to that email. In it, a known money launderer wrote that he was buying a new car for a former executive at Petrobras, the state oil company.
DALLAGNOL: A famous money laundering agent giving a car for free for a guy. What was that? So we began investigating.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: That investigation turned into a thread that, when pulled, unraveled a vast scheme. The way it worked was some of Brazil's biggest contractors would overcharge Petrobras for work and then would funnel the extra money to politicians and others in bribes and kickbacks to the tune of billions. The sheer scale has shocked the country.
Did you imagine that this would go this far?
DALLAGNOL: No, we had no idea.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: Dallagnol says he become a prosecutor at 22, with dreams of transforming Brazil. This, in short, is his manifesto.
DALLAGNOL: We can have a better country with less corruption and punishing people that are powerful and rich who commit the same wrongs than the others. I believe that is possible and that we have to pursue this.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: But then he came up against cold Brazilian reality. Whatever the failings of the U.S. justice system, he says, Brazil is far worse. Most cases take over a decade to resolve. Politicians have immunity, so more than half the Congress has been charged with some kind of crime, but individuals are rarely punished. Disillusioned, he wanted to learn how to do things better, so he went to Harvard Law and became an admirer of American jurisprudence.
DALLAGNOL: The American point of view, I think - much more practical. They are much more effective.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: When he came back to Brazil, he decided to put what he learned into practice. He has a reverence for the law and for Gandhi, who was also a lawyer.
DALLAGNOL: He was only a lawyer who saw a very unjust system and who fighted in order to change that.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: Dallagnol doesn't see himself as Gandhi. He's kind of humble. In fact, since the case exploded, he worries people expect him to cure Brazil's many problems.
DALLAGNOL: We realize that we could not deliver that for the people, and we thought about how we could reach it.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: His answer - Hong Kong. It went from one of the most corrupt places in the world to one of the cleanest. He and his team have come up with 10 recommendations for Brazil based on what happened there. He sent the plan to the Congress, and he wants the public to get behind it, too. Dallagnol and his team have been compared by some to the Untouchable team, the reputedly incorruptible group that took down Al Capone in the 1920s.
Do you think things are changing in Brazil now? Do you think this is an example that things can actually change?
DALLAGNOL: I would describe ourselves as the stubborn guys, not the untouchable guys - the guys that don't give up what they believe.
GARCIA-NAVARRO: He says he's at the beginning of a very long road. Lourdes Garcia-Navarro, NPR News, Curitiba.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:49:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks Brace For Shortages At Home, Await Word On Fate From Abroad </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/07/08/421211424/greeks-brace-for-shortages-at-home-await-word-on-fate-from-abroad?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Greeks are increasingly worried as they confront an eighth day of closed banks and limited withdrawals. Meanwhile, people are running short of money for essentials.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greeks Brace For Shortages At Home, Await Word On Fate From Abroad
July 08, 2015 4:49 PM ET
People lined up on Wednesday to withdraw cash from a bank machine in central Athens. Banks remain shut this week and ATM withdrawals are limited to 60 euros (about $66) a day. Emilio Morenatti/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Emilio Morenatti/AP
People lined up on Wednesday to withdraw cash from a bank machine in central Athens. Banks remain shut this week and ATM withdrawals are limited to 60 euros (about $66) a day.
Emilio Morenatti/AP
Athenians gathered around a television screen at an outdoor caf this morning to watch their prime minister at the European Parliament in Brussels. Alexis Tsipras talked of the "austerity experiment" being conducted on Greece and said reforms could not be carried out on the backs of the poor.
Sixty-year-old sculptor Nikos Talepolos was pleased.
Greece By The Numbers
"I thought it was a very good speech, but I'm afraid the poor people will have to pay for the mistakes of the bankers and those in power," he says. "We have no power against this blackmail of the European Union."
Greek Prime Minister Tells EU Leaders He Wants A United Europe
While the future of their country plays out in Brussels, Greeks are bracing for the worst. The government today asked for a new three-year loan from the Eurozone's bailout fund, and has until Thursday night to present a concrete plan to reform its economy.
All 28 European Union nations will meet in Brussels on Sunday to decide on the country's fate. European leaders warn Greece this is its last chance to remain in the euro.
The attacks on Tsipras by some conservatives in the European Parliament might have angered the prime minister's supporters, but Sakis Georgiou, a 62-year-old Athens taxi driver, says he can understand the frustration of some of Greece's European partners.
"The main problems in Greece are tax evasion, smuggling and corruption in the state sector," he says. "And I was expecting that a left-wing government like Syriza and Tsipras will do something to change that. But after five months, I haven't seen anything moving. So eventually, the Europeans, they like to help us, but they're tired. If we don't do something for ourselves, nobody can do anything for you."
Greeks are becoming increasingly nervous as they struggle with an eighth day of closed banks and limited cash withdrawals. They can't send money, for example, to students studying abroad or pay bills from their accounts. The freezing of the financial system is creating massive problems in many parts of the economy.
Dmitris Makrivelios works for Greece's federation of filling station owners. He says pumps may soon run dry without the means to buy fuel from distributors.
Makrivelios says the gas station owners are being hit with a double whammy: The government is forcing them to accept credit cards they cannot redeem for cash. And the cash they do get from customers cannot be deposited in the bank.
They're now afraid of being robbed. Makrivelios says they're asking for police protection.
Inside a drugstore, pharmacist Isadora Papageorgiou says people are trying to stock up on medicines. She's convincing them to take a little at a time and says so far things are OK. But that could change, depending on what happens this weekend in Brussels.
"We try to give medicine to all the people," she says. But if the country bankrupts, she says, they're not going to have any more medicine.
There's one part of Athens that doesn't seem affected by the general sense of an impending collapse. That's in the tourist streets. The only Greek I met today who doesn't seem anxious is a tourist shop owner.
The Acropolis is still there, Costas Kokias tells me, pointing up the hill. And we have the sun.
"As long as it's there," he says, "I'm not afraid."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:30:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece's Tsipras Tells EU Leaders He Wants 'Socially Just' Solution To Crisis</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/08/421224992/greeces-tsipras-tells-eu-leaders-he-wants-socially-just-solution-to-crisis?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras appeared before European Parliament on Wednesday to propose what he called a "fair and viable solution" to the country's economic crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece's Tsipras Tells EU Leaders He Wants 'Socially Just' Solution To Crisis
July 08, 2015 4:30 PM ET
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras appeared before European Parliament on Wednesday to propose what he called a "fair and viable solution" to the country's economic crisis.
ROBERT SIEGEL, HOST:
Greece's prime minister, Alexis Tsipras, went before the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France, today. He said he wants a fair and viable solution to his country's debt crisis. The atmosphere in the chamber was heated.
(APPLAUSE, BOOS)
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
Tsipras called the crisis a European problem that needs European solutions. And he said he wants an agreement with a program for growth.
SIEGEL: He cited his country's recent referendum rejecting the latest bailout offer.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
ALEXIS TSIPRAS: (Speaking Greek).
SIEGEL: He said he'd been given a mandate to get a socially just solution for the problem.
MCEVERS: Among the members of Parliament criticizing Tsipras was former Belgian prime minister Guy Verhofstadt.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
GUY VERHOFSTADT: You are talking about reforms, but we never see concrete proposals of reforms.
(APPLAUSE)
VERHOFSTADT: And I'm angry why? I'm angry why? I'm angry because we are in fact sleepwalking towards a Grexit.
MCEVERS: Grexit - that's a Greek exit from the eurozone, the group of countries using the euro as currency. Verhofstadt continued.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
VERHOFSTADT: The choice that we have is very simple. How do you want to be remembered - as an electoral accident who made its people poorer in his country or want to be remembered, Mr. Tsipras, as a real revolutionary performer?
SIEGEL: Unlikely praise for the politically far-left Greek prime minister came from the far right. The leader of the U.K. Independence Party, Nigel Farage, praised Tsipras for standing up to European leaders. The fierce eurozone critic offered his own suggestion for Greece.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
NIGEL FARAGE: Frankly, if you've got the courage, you should lead the Greek people out of the eurozone with your head held high.
MCEVERS: For now, Greece is working to stay in the eurozone.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kurdish Forces Retake Ground From Self-Declared Islamic State In Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/08/421225076/kurdish-forces-retake-ground-from-self-declared-islamic-state-in-syria?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>With the help of U.S. airstrikes, Kurds in Syria have taken ground from the self-declared Islamic State. But that could alienate Arab rebel groups — wary of the Kurds — who the U.S. needs to take on the extremists.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kurdish Forces Retake Ground From Self-Declared Islamic State In Syria
July 08, 2015 4:30 PM ET
Deb Amos
With the help of U.S. airstrikes, Kurds in Syria have taken ground from the self-declared Islamic State. But that could alienate Arab rebel groups  wary of the Kurds  who the U.S. needs to take on the extremists.
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
U.S.-led forces in the Middle East are turning more attention to Syria. Recent days have seen some of the heaviest airstrikes in months in Syria. These strikes have helped Kurdish forces on the ground take back some territory from the so-called Islamic State or ISIS. NPR's Deborah Amos was recently near the Syrian border in Turkey reporting on the fighting and joins us now from Istanbul. And Deb, the U.S. has been conducting airstrikes on ISIS in Iraq, but it's also now increasing the attacks in Syria. Why do you think that happened?
DEBORAH AMOS, BYLINE: Well, I think we can look at two things. There's reports in the Turkish media that claim that Turkey urged the U.S. to strike ISIS targets - one around a key border town called Azaz and another near Aleppo. That's Syria's largest city in the north - because in the past week, rebels backed by Turkey have launched an offensive against the Syrian regime in Aleppo. So the U.S. strikes helped hold ISIS back. But the heaviest U.S. airstrikes are to support the Kurds. And the U.S. Secretary of Defense said that in public. The Kurds continue to press their momentum, and they look like the best bet to fight ISIS.
MCEVERS: So how much should we read into this Kurdish advance? I mean, does it mean that ISIS is on the ropes?
AMOS: You know, they delivered this surprising win in June in this key border town of Tal Abyad, backed by U.S. airstrikes. They pushed ISIS out in two days. And that was surprising because this town was really important to ISIS. It was their key crossing point into Turkey. They've pushed even further. They've driven ISIS out of about one third of the territory in their stronghold of Raqqa. That's a province that they control in northern Syria.
MCEVERS: Right. So the Kurds have made these advances with U.S. help against ISIS. But that is not pleasing all of the U.S. allies - right? - like the Turks and maybe, possibly the Arab allies in Syria. Why the backlash?
AMOS: Turkey is nervous over these Kurdish gains. Turkey struggles with its own Kurdish minority. Turkey is also an important U.S. ally. So this is more complicated than these wins on the ground that depends on only one partner. But the Turks also see why the Kurds are an attractive partner for the West. They're tough fighters. They're secular. We talked to a political science professor here, Hakan Yilmaz, and he said wars are won at the symbolic level. Turkey is losing, and the Kurds are winning. Here's what he said.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
UNIDENTIFIED MAN: Who is fighting ISIS?
HAKAN YILMAZ: The Kurds. And not just any Kurds, but the Kurds who have adopted the secular values of the West, you know, beautiful girls with Kalashnikovs in their hands killing the radical Islamists. It is the image which is being spread.
MCEVERS: Beautiful girls with Kalashnikovs - so meanwhile the Pentagon has said it would train some Syrian rebels. But so far very few have actually been trained. What's taking so long?
AMOS: Well, we now have a number - 60. That is the Pentagon's number in this multimillion dollar train-and-equip program. And the rebels tell us that the main problem is this signed pledge. They have to promise to only fight ISIS and not the Assad regime which is the point for many of them to be on the battlefield now. There are some pragmatic Syrian Arab rebels who are considering fighting with the Kurds because they know that's the only way they can get U.S. support. They are in awe of U.S. intel to the Kurds. And for example, they tell us that there is this heat detecting technology, and the U.S. can tell the Kurds how many ISIS fighters are still in an un-cleared building. So Syrian rebels who've been fighting for four years are considering fighting with the Kurds.
MCEVERS: Wow, Arab rebels.
AMOS: Yes.
MCEVERS: And still there's a battle going on for the Syrian city of Aleppo where we've seen in recent days that Christians are fleeing. What have you heard about that?
AMOS: Well, we confirmed today that European governments have set up these rescue missions. And what they're doing is they're facilitating an exodus of Syrian Christians from Aleppo. The Belgian government worked on one escape. They are flying Syrian families out of Lebanon after they cross the border. There are other Christian churches in Aleppo. Also, they have escape plans. Some 600 Christians have already left that city.
MCEVERS: That's NPR's Deborah Amos in Istanbul, Turkey. Deb, thanks so much.
AMOS: Thank you.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:24:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia Vetoes U.N. Proposal To Call Srebrenica 'Genocide'</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/08/421224999/russia-vetoes-u-n-proposal-to-call-srebrenica-genocide?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Twenty years ago, the international community failed to protect Bosnian Muslims in what was supposed to be a United Nations safe zone in Bosnia. Russia blocked a UN Security Council resolution on Wednesday that would have condemned the Srebrenica massacre as an act of genocide.</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia Vetoes U.N. Proposal To Call Srebrenica 'Genocide'
July 08, 2015 4:24 PM ET
Transcript
Twenty years ago, the international community failed to protect Bosnian Muslims in what was supposed to be a United Nations safe zone in Bosnia. Russia blocked a UN Security Council resolution on Wednesday that would have condemned the Srebrenica massacre as an act of genocide.
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
A grim anniversary this week - 20 years ago, the international community failed to prevent the massacre of Bosnian Muslims who were taking refuge in a U.N. safe zone at Srebrenica. Now U.S. officials say the U.N. has failed again, and that's after Russia vetoed a Security Council resolution today to commemorate the massacre and call it a genocide. NPR's Michele Kelemen reports.
MICHELE KELEMEN, BYLINE: The U.S. ambassador to the U.N., Samantha Power, was a reporter covering the war when Bosnian-Serb forces moved on Srebrenica. At first, she says, she couldn't believe the news of mass executions.
SAMANTHA POWER: No, was all I could say - no.
KELEMEN: She said she had the same reaction when she heard Russia would veto a resolution that described the 1995 massacre of 8,000 Muslim men and boys as a crime of genocide.
POWER: Today's vote mattered. It mattered hugely to the families of the victims of the Srebrenica genocide. Russia's veto is heartbreaking for those families. And it is a further stain on this council's record.
KELEMEN: Russia's ambassador, Vitaly Churkin, accused Power of distorting Russia's position.
VITALY CHURKIN: (Speaking Russian).
KELEMEN: He described the resolution as counterproductive, confrontational and politically motivated. China abstained, as did Venezuela, Angola and Nigeria. British ambassador, Peter Wilson, who drafted it, says the resolution was mean to promote reconciliation in Bosnia, but reconciliation, he adds, must be based on a shared acceptance of the facts. Michele Kelemen, NPR News, Washington.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caine Prize Winner: Literature Is Not A Competitive Sport</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/08/421134703/caine-prize-winner-literature-is-not-a-competitive-sport?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Namwali Serpell promised to split the award's winnings with her fellow nominees. For the Zambian writer, it's one step toward changing the structure of the prestigious prize for African authors.</Description>
        <MainBody>Close embed modal
&lt;iframe src="http://www.npr.org/player/embed/331681128/331681137" width="100%" height="290" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;
The questions, in some ways, are intrinsic to the prize itself. Named for British patron Sir Michael Harris Caine (no, not that Sir Michael Caine ) and awarded in Oxford University's Bodleian Library, the Caine Prize has occasionally attracted criticism  even from past winners  alternately for not representing the best of African writing, or for being expected to represent too much. As a prize born on an island, it faces the difficult task of recognizing just one story from an entire continent.
As another nominee for this year's prize, Elnathan John, put the matter in The Guardian last week: "I would prefer not to be a spokesperson at all. Whether for Africa or African writing."
"I think that tension is acknowledged by both the writers shortlisted and the Caine Prize itself. It's also a tension that, I have to admit, is kind of intrinsic to who I am because my father is British of origin," Serpell says. "I think that kind of conflict inside can be a source of criticism, but it can also be a source of productive and interesting clashes."
Though, she says, one step toward resolving some of these difficulties is by simply having more literary prizes on the continent. She lists several collectives and magazines  like South Africa's Chimurenga and Kenya's Kwani?  as proof of a publishing industry that's already thriving from the ground up.
"Having a prize next to the Caine Prize rather than one to displace it, I think, would be the ideal."
For now, though, she's thrilled with the prize  and, by laying down her newly earned winnings, splitting them up and diminishing the duel between writers, she says she's also taking steps toward that change herself.
That and, well, also creating a little insurance plan.
"I keep joking to the other shortlisted writers that if I'm ever unemployed," she laughs, "I will be calling them."
Read an excerpt of "The Sack," the Caine Prize-winning story, below. And read the full thing here.
Excerpt: 'The Sack'
July 08, 201510:22 AM ET
There's a sack.
A sack? A sack.
Hmm. A sack. Big?
Yes. Grey. Like old kwacha. Marks on the outside. No. Shadows. That's how I know it is moving.
Something is moving inside it?
The whole sack is moving. Down a dirt road with a ditch on the side, with grass and yellow fl owers. There are trees above.
Is it dark? Yes, but light is coming. It is morning. There are some small birds talking, moving. The sack is dragging on the ground. There is a man pulling it behind him.
Who is this man? I can't see his face. He is tallish. His shirt has stains on the back. No socks. Businessman shoes. His hands are wet.
Does he see you? I don't know. I'm tired now. Close the curtains. Yes, bwana.
***
J. left the bedroom and went to the kitchen. The wooden door was open but the metal security gate was closed. The sky looked bruised. The insects would be coming soon. They had already begun their electric clicking in the garden. He thought of the man in the bedroom, hating him in that tender way he had cultivated over the years. J. washed the plates from lunch. He swept. A chicken outside made a popping sound. J. sucked his teeth and went to see what was wrong.
The isabi boy was standing outside the security gate. The boy held the bucket handle with both hands, the insides of his elbows splayed taut. His legs were streaked white and grey.
How do you expect me to know you are here if you are quiet? J. asked as he opened the gate. The boy shrugged, a smile dancing upwards and then receding into the settled indifference of his face. J. told the boy to take off his patapatas and reached for the bucket. Groaning with its weight, J. heaved the unwieldy thing into the sink. He could just make out the shape of the bream, flush against the inside of the bucket, its fin protruding. J. felt the water shift as the fish turned uneasily.
A big one today, eh? J. turned and smiled.
The boy still stood by the door, his hands clasped in front of him. His legs were reflected in the parquet floor, making him seem taller.
Do you want something to eat?
The boy assented with a diagonal nod.
You should eat the fish you catch. It is the only way to survive, J. said.
***
I told him about the first dream but I did not tell him about the second. In the second dream, I am inside the sack. The cloth of it is pressing right down on my eyes. I turn one way, then the other. All I can see is grey cloth. There is no pain but I can feel the ground against my bones. I am curled up. I hear the sound of the sack, sweeping like a slow broom. I have been paying him long enough  paying down his debt  that he should treat me like a real bwana. He does his duties, yes. But he lacks deference. His politics would not admit this, but I have known this man since we were children. I know what the colour of my skin means to someone of our generation. His eyes have changed. I think he is going to kill me. I think that is what these dreams are telling me. Naila. I cannot remember your hands.
***
They lifted the bream out of the bucket together, the boy's hands holding the tail, J.'s hands gripping the head. The fish swung in and out of the curve of its own body, its gills pumping with mechanical panic. They flipped it on to the wooden board. Its side was a jerking plane of silver, drops of water magnifying its precise scaling. The chicken outside made a serrated sound.
Iwe, hold it down!
The boy placed his hands on either end of the body. J. slid a knife beneath the locking, unlocking gills. Blood eased over their hands. The fish bucked once, twice. Stopped.
I needed your help, J. smiled.
He deboned and gutted the fish. The boy wiped the chopping board, hypnotised by his own hand tracking thin loops of purple and yellow entrails across it. J. fried the fish in cooking oil with salt and onions and tomatoes. He served a piece of it to the boy, setting the plate on the floor. He set a portion of the fish aside for himself and took a plate with the rest of it to the man in the bedroom.
The room was dark but for an orange patch on the wall from the street lamp.
Who is here?
The isabi boy. J. put the plate on the side table and turned on the lamp.
The man began to cough, the phlegm in his chest rattling as he heaved and hacked. J. helped him sit up and rubbed his back until the fit ceased. When it was done, the man was tired.
Why is the fish boy still here? Did you not pay him?
I gave him supper.
As if I have food to spare, the man grunted. He took the plate on to his lap and began eating.
***
In the first dream, the sack is full and it is being dragged. In the second dream, I am inside it. What will the third dream reveal? You laugh. You say that dreams move forwards, not back. That I am imagining things. But that is why you chose me, Naila. Or at least that is what I fancied then. Now I am not so sure. Some days, I think you loved me for my hands. Other days, I think you threw stones to decide.
Excerpted from "The Sack" by Samwali Serpell, published in Africa39. This story can be found in full on the Caine Prize website and in the anthology Lusaka Punk , from New Internationalist.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>This Must Be A First: Alpacas Blessed In Nation's Capital</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/07/08/419823015/this-must-be-a-first-alpacas-blessed-in-nations-capital?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Peru brought its tradition of praying for alpacas to the U.S. And there's good reason to wish the animals well. Their fiber — softer and warmer than wool — provides a livelihood for many Peruvians.</Description>
        <MainBody>This Must Be A First: Alpacas Blessed In Nation's Capital
July 08, 2015 1:58 PM ET
Jessie Rack
The Peruvians blessed this delegation, from Whispering Meadows Alpaca Breeders and Flame Pool Alpacas, during the first week of the Smithsonian Folklife Festival. Lydia Thompson/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Lydia Thompson/NPR
The Peruvians blessed this delegation, from Whispering Meadows Alpaca Breeders and Flame Pool Alpacas, during the first week of the Smithsonian Folklife Festival.
Lydia Thompson/NPR
Here's something you don't see every day in Washington, D.C.
Standing just a couple of blocks from the U.S. Capitol, a group of Peruvian highlanders, draped in handwoven cloths and ponchos in all the colors of the rainbow, pray to Mother Earth, to the mountains, to the spirit of their ancestors. They offer wine, incense and flowers. Their wish is that their alpaca "cover the earth like the grains of sand by the ocean."
Alpacas, in case you don't know, are llama-like animals in the camel family. Their wool  called fiber  is prized for its softness and warmth. It's woven into textiles and garments. So the more alpacas, the better. That's why Peruvians hold a traditional blessing ceremony, performed since before Columbus discovered the New World and re-created at the national mall last Friday for the annual Smithsonian Folklife Festival .
The Peruvians kneel in front of the alpacas' pen to prepare their offering. Behind them, six alpacas, on loan from Sugarloaf Alpacas in Maryland, stand nervously. It's apparent they've never been blessed before.
A woven tassel signifies that an alpaca has received its blessing. Courtesy of PROMPERU hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of PROMPERU
A woven tassel signifies that an alpaca has received its blessing.
Courtesy of PROMPERU
A weaver named Timoteo, from the village of Chinchero, leads the ceremony. As he speaks, a translator echoes his words.
"Lightning storms, please, I supplicate you with this offering. Please be gentle with us, support us and allow our animals to be fruitful and multiply, don't be harsh."
Before the ceremony began, I spoke with Nilda Callaaupa Alvarez, a traditional weaver. Callaaupa is a cofounder of the Centro de Textiles Tradicionales del Cusco , a nonprofit formed to preserve the art of weaving. As we talk, her hands never stop moving as she spins alpaca fiber into yarn.
The alpaca ceremony, Callaaupa explains, takes place once a year during their rainy season, which in Peru lasts from November through April. The people ask Mother Earth  Pachamama in the Quechua language  and the spirits to look out for their animals.
"Spirit of our ancestors, angels that protect us, please take care of us. We offer to you this blessing."
Alpacas are native to South America, where they are sometimes raised for meat (which is low in calories, fat, and cholesterol ) but are primarily prized for their fleece, which grows naturally in over twenty colors . Alpaca fiber is not only soft, Callaaupa says, but warmer and finer than sheep's wool.
Ann Rowe, a researcher at the George Washington University Museum and Textile Museum in D.C. , says these attractive properties of alpaca fiber are due to its structure. "Alpaca is softer than wool because [the shaft of each fiber] has fewer surface scales," she says. "It is warmer because many of the fibers have a hollow core."
It also costs more than wool, Callaaupa says, an advantage for the farmer. Peru is reportedly home to 3.6 million alpacas  that's most of the world's population and produces 80 percent of the world's alpaca fleece. Those exports , however, are managed by large fiber mills.
i
Peru's alpacas are blessed once a year, during rainy season. The blessing declares: "Let there be a great abundance of alpacas, so that the alpacas should be like the condor and appear to fly from one mountain to another." Courtesy of the Center for Traditional Textiles of Cusco hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of the Center for Traditional Textiles of Cusco
Peru's alpacas are blessed once a year, during rainy season. The blessing declares: "Let there be a great abundance of alpacas, so that the alpacas should be like the condor and appear to fly from one mountain to another."
Courtesy of the Center for Traditional Textiles of Cusco
"The export industry is an entirely different thing than local use of alpacas" for textiles, says Rowe.
"Let the alpaca be as strong as can be because their bones are like steel. The mountains should run with alpacas like grains of sand, and their caretakers should be so overjoyed that their eyes run with tears."
It's a long road from animal to textile. It starts, Callaaupa says, with shearing the animals, which is done every year or two (in warmer climates, annual shearing is more common).
Next, the fiber is spun by hand into yarn on a traditional drop spindle  a wooden spike that is weighted at one end. The spinner fixes the fiber to the spike, then pulls and twists the fiber while holding the spindle between the legs. When the twisted fiber reaches a certain length, the spindle is dropped toward the floor, and its weight makes it rotate, twisting it into yarn.
The finished yarn is washed and can be dyed. The Cusco weavers use natural dyes made from leaves, flowers and insects.
When the yarn is ready, artisans use a backstrap loom to weave bright, intricate textiles. Each community, Callaaupa explains, has its own designs and style of weaving. "It's part of our identity," she says.
"Let there be a great abundance of alpacas, so that the alpacas should be like the condor and appear to fly from one mountain to another, and let them come in all the beautiful colors."
People sell their woven textiles. If they have a lot of alpaca, they'll sell the actual fiber as well. Callaaupa says that in many of these villages, raising alpaca is the basis for the economy. "In high altitudes where the alpacas are kept, there is not agriculture," she says. "So all the food will come through [sale of the] fiber."
Is it enough to make a living?
She doesn't look up from the creamy, pale fiber she is spinning into soft yarn. "Most people, that pays for living," she says. "The food, the education. No savings."
When the ceremony is over, necklaces of carnations and woven tassels are hung around each alpaca's neck to show it has been blessed. In Peru, the end of the ceremony marks the beginning of a festival, so right there on the National Mall, to the beat of drums and the whistle of flutes, the Peruvians dance their thanks to Mother Earth.
Back in their pen, the blessed alpacas pace, perhaps not yet aware of their good fortune.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Blog Ewe Didn't Know Ewe Needed: Google Sheep View</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2015/07/08/421140493/the-blog-ewe-didnt-know-ewe-needed-google-sheep-view?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>It's the year of the sheep, so it follows that a new blog would celebrate the woolly four-legged creatures. Readers submit sheep spottings from around the world, with the help of Google Street View.</Description>
        <MainBody>Is This A Goat Or A Sheep? It's Harder Than You Think
This might seem discriminatory and sheepist to some, but the zwartbles originate in the Netherlands, where both Ren and Karabinos currently live.
Google Sheep View has more than 10,000 followers, and over 100 posts of sheep across the world. Most of the posts are submitted by readers, and the photo captions bear the location of each sheep sighting so that anyone can explore the herds.
Ren and Karabinos don't want to pull the wool over your eyes  they fact-check the sheep submissions to ensure that only legitimate sheep make it on the blog. In the "Outtakes" section, there are photos of cases of mistaken sheep identity: a misleading goat, large lumps of hay in a field, a cow and some statues. This isn't just your average sheep blog  they have ethics over at Google Sheep View.
It's this sort of thing that makes ewe look at the Internet and think, "It's not such a baaaaaaaaaaad place."
Paige Pfleger is an intern with NPR Digital News.
Correction July 8, 2015
In a previous version of this post, we referred to Ding Ren as a man. Ren is a woman.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece By The Numbers</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/07/08/421137650/greece-by-the-numbers?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Forget about all the nebulous terms like "austerity," "bailout" and "capital controls." Here are the key numbers you need to know in the Greek financial crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>If The Mess In Greece Is All Greek To You, Then Read This
92: The actual income earned by a typical Greek citizen is 92 percent higher than the income reported to the government , according to a 2012 study. Tax evasion is endemic in Greece and a major contributor to the government's budget shortfalls. Creditors are demanding this be addressed in return for a new rescue package.
680: The number of Greeks on the island of Zakynthos who were receiving government benefits for blindness. It turns out that about 500 of them had decent vision. Some were still driving. One was a taxi driver. Critics say scams, like this one on the "island of the blind," are widespread in Greece.
60: The maximum number of euros that Greeks can withdraw from their bank accounts each day. That works out to about $66. However, ATMs are starting to run out of cash and the banks have now been closed for more than a week. It's still not clear when they will reopen, and even more importantly, whether Greeks will respond by making a run on the banks and withdrawing all of their money immediately.
240 billion: The euros that international lenders have provided to Greece in recent years as part of the bailouts (around $264 billion at the current exchange rates). That's a lot for a country of just 11 million people. But Greeks say much of the bailout money has simply gone to pay off earlier lenders and has not been used to rebuild the Greek economy. Hence the term "extend and pretend," that's often used to describe the process.
2: Percent of economic output that Greece contributes to the 19-country eurozone . Some European leaders and economists say that because Greece's economy is small and the troubles have dragged on for so long, the country's problems are unlikely to cause a broader contagion in Europe or beyond.
81: Percent of Greeks who say they want to remain in the eurozone, according to one recent poll . This may sound contradictory given Greece's vote in Sunday's referendum, where it rejected the terms proposed by its creditors. However, many Greeks say they want to keep close links to Europe but are tired of deals that inflict pain without leading to a solution. Critics say this shows Greece's desire to have it both ways  it wants large sums of aid from Europe and other lenders without meeting the same standards of others in the eurozone.
Greg Myre is the international editor of NPR.org. Follow him @gregmyre1 .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fact Check: 36 Percent Or Not? Inside Jeb Bush's Tax Math</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/itsallpolitics/2015/07/08/420909119/why-jeb-s-tax-returns-are-the-dog-that-didn-t-bark?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Did Bush really pay 36 percent over all those years of tax returns or not? Here's how the campaign got to that number.</Description>
        <MainBody>Republican presidential candidate Jeb Bush participates in a Fourth of July parade in Amherst, N.H., on Saturday. Kayana Szymczak/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Kayana Szymczak/Getty Images
Republican presidential candidate Jeb Bush participates in a Fourth of July parade in Amherst, N.H., on Saturday.
Kayana Szymczak/Getty Images
Jeb Bush released more tax returns than any other presidential candidate in history. Over 33 years, the former Florida governor's campaign said he paid an average effective tax rate of 36 percent.
... depending on how you calculate it.
That's a confusing number, and it obscures three decades in which Bush's income climbed slowly, then explosively.
Scrutinizing politicians' tax returns can be wonky, tedious business, but it matters because the documents are also used as political weapons. So understanding how candidates manipulate their tax figures becomes all the more important.
By portraying his effective tax rate as high, Bush not only gets to portray himself as a fair-and-square taxpayer, but also make a point about what he sees as the problems of the U.S. tax system. He also used it to compare himself with Hillary Clinton, the Democratic front-runner, whose 2014 tax returns showed she and her husband, former President Bill Clinton, paid a 30 percent rate.
The Math Behind The 36 Percent
To come up with Bush's 36 percent number, the Bush campaign did a straightforward calculation, adding up his total taxes from 1981 through 2013 and dividing it by all of the income he earned in those same years.
That's simple enough, but it makes that headline "36 percent" figure easy to misunderstand. For one thing, saying it was his "average tax rate" could suggest that he, in fact, paid an average of 36 percent each year  that is, that he paid something around 36 percent each year.
That's not close to true.
Really, he paid more than 36 percent in only eight of those years. (Meanwhile, in four earlier years, he had either zero or negative taxable income.)
Here's how that 36 percent number works, then: Bush made a huge share of his money in the last few years. Two-thirds of his taxable income came in just the last five years of returns, to be exact.
Not only that, but a new 39.6 percent bracket went into effect in 2013, as Yahoo contributor and financial planner Michael Kitces pointed out. Not only does that give the most recent years extra weight, but the campaign also isn't adjusting for inflation, so the earliest years get even less weight than they should.
Not to get too wonky, but one might more precisely call this figure Bush's total effective rate from 1981 to 2013. The average effective rate, simply adding together all the rates and then averaging them out, was more like 24.5 percent.
Kitces was the first to do something like this  using slightly different figures from the Bush tax returns, he came up with a 21 percent rate.
And that's how effective tax rates work  no one talks about or thinks about their total tax rate over time, because income changes year by year, as do tax brackets (not to mention the tax laws governing those brackets). Adding them up over time doesn't really say anything meaningful.
How Jeb Bush Is Like LeBron James  High Tax Rates
Still, there's no denying that in the past few years, Bush paid a lot of money to the government, relative to his fellow high earners. Bush earned $7.2 million in taxable income in 2013 and paid $2.7 million in income taxes, an effective income tax rate of 36 percent that year.
That year, the effective tax rate for people in the top 0.1 percent of earners (who had an average income of around $ 3.9 million ) was 26 percent. That puts him in stark contrast to another rich Republican political scion who recently ran for president. Mitt Romney took a lot of heat in the 2012 cycle for his 14 percent effective tax rate and the methods he took to get to that low number.
In light of these figures, many are asking why Bush didn't find a way to pay less.
"For me, what stands out is that he doesn't appear to have been aggressively trying to legally avoid his taxes," said Joe Thorndike, director of the Tax History Project at Tax Analysts. "Most people with a lot of money pay a lot of money to tax advisers to minimize their taxes. They pay a lot, but it saves them even more. It really doesn't look like he did much of that."
The Bush campaign also highlighted this with a statement from Abraham Shashy, former IRS chief counsel:
"All of the returns appear to me to have been prepared conservatively and timely," he wrote, adding, "There is no indication of aggressive or improper tax planning."
There is some explanation for why Bush's rate is so high for an uber-rich person  one is that a lot of his income was in self-employment. Bush only ("only") earned around $662,000 in capital gains in 2013  income from investments like stocks or real estate  making those a small share of his total income. Those capital gains are generally taxed at a lower rate than wage income. In this way, you can think of Bush (at least from a tax perspective) as more LeBron James than Mitt Romney.
"The short answer is that there is nothing he can do [to lower his rate on his self-employment income], because he is providing personal services," Lee Sheppard, contributing editor at Tax Analysts, said, adding, "Many people with those [high] incomes earn capital gains, but that is because they get their money from wealth, not personal services. But there are some people, like Bush, who earn their large paychecks from services, like sports figures."
There are other avenues Bush could have taken to lower his rate as well. As McClatchy's Lesley Clark and Amy Sherman point out , Bush has donated less to charity than even than the average American  he gave away 1.5 percent of his adjusted gross income in 2013, compared to the 3 percent average for other Americans. In contrast, fellow candidate Carly Fiorina gave away 13 percent in 2013.
Not only that, but he's including something the rest of us don't have in our income tax returns  payroll taxes.
When most workers get their paychecks, employers take out some taxes. They pay half of the payroll taxes, and workers pay the other half. Bush, however, is self-employed, so he pays his own self-employment taxes through his income-tax return.
Bush includes those in his effective tax-rate calculations. When he says he paid more than 40 percent last year, that's not just income tax  it's those Medicare and Social Security taxes, too. It's not a huge amount, accounting for around 3 percentage points in 2013, but that extra padding works to Bush's advantage, as part of his point he's sending with his tax returns is that he believes tax rates need to be lowered.
"This release will show voters how I earned a living over the past three decades and how much of that living I had to give back to Uncle Sam. (Spoiler Alert: A LOT)," he wrote in an essay accompanying the returns.
25 Percent, 36 Percent ... Why Do We Care?
It's a busy pre-election season, and making these sorts of distinctions about the math candidates are using on their taxes can seem like the smallest of matters.
But in a hard-fought election, tax returns can easily be weaponized. The Obama campaign used Romney's lower tax rate and high income to stoke voter resentment and play into a narrative about Romney as uncaring. That bore fruit. By Election Day, when asked in exit polls which candidate cared about "people like me," Obama won the question 81 to 18 percent.
As a result, many observers saw Romney's lack of foresight in preparing his pre-election tax returns as a major misstep. But what Bush seems to understand is that tax returns aren't private tallies of income and deductions  they're campaign documents.
"My impression of these returns is that they [the Bush campaign] are politically astute, like many people running for office, but more than some  certainly more than Mitt Romney," Thorndike said.
James Joseph, head of the Tax Group at law firm Arnold and Porter, agrees that it appears Bush prepared these returns with an eye toward caution.
"[Bush] seems to have just been very careful," he said, drawing a contrast to Romney. "Romney had so much going on even in what he disclosed that raised questions. It was almost as if he did no planning at all from a campaign perspective."
While being rich is rapidly becoming a requirement for seeking national office, the trappings of being rich  like a team of tax-dodging accountants  can turn voters off. The goal for Bush's team: Being able to tell voters that he, too, hates paying Uncle Sam. That may well make even a high earner like the candidate seem more relatable.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Toyota Executive Released From Custody In Drug Case</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/08/420826919/former-toyota-executive-released-from-custody-in-drug-case?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Last month Japanese customs officials discovered oxycodone pills in a package that the 55-year-old American had allegedly mailed to herself from Kentucky. She reportedly will not face charges.</Description>
        <MainBody>Former Toyota Executive Released From Custody In Drug Case
July 08, 201510:48 AM ET
Julie Hamp had recently been appointed head of public relations for Toyota Motor Corp. Kyodo/Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Kyodo/Reuters/Landov
Julie Hamp, the former Toyota executive arrested for allegedly mailing oxycodone pills to herself in Japan, was released from custody on Wednesday.
The Wall Street Journal reports that Tokyo prosecutors thought they had enough evidence to charge Hamp but didn't because they deemed justice had already been served:
" 'She has already gone through a certain level of social punishment,' an official from the Tokyo District Public Prosecutor's Office said, adding that prosecutors took her resignation into consideration. Ms. Hamp didn't comment when she left the police station in a silver Toyota van, and the identity of her lawyer wasn't known. ...
"Ms. Hamp is now free to return to the U.S. without a formal criminal record."
As the Two-Way has previously reported, Japanese customs officials discovered 57 pills in a package that Hamp had allegedly mailed to herself from Kentucky, in violation of Japanese narcotics law:
"Oxycodone is legal in the U.S. with a prescription.
" The Asahi Shimbun writes: 'When customs officials at Narita Airport checked an international parcel addressed to Julie Hamp, a 55-year-old American, they found pills, placed in bags, at the bottom of the parcel, Tokyo police said.'
"Hamp, who was arrested on Thursday, has denied the charges. A spokesman for Tokyo's Metropolitan Police Department said she told authorities that she did not think she had imported an illegal substance."
Hamp was Toyota Motor Corp.'s first senior female executive. She had recently been appointed head of public relations.
Toyota Motor Corp. announced in a press release that Shigeru Hayakawa, Senior Managing Officer and member of the Board of Directors, has been appointed to Chief Communications Officer, the position Hamp recently resigned from.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:46:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For A 3rd Straight Day, Chinese Markets Plunge </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/08/421097879/for-third-straight-day-chinese-markets-plunge?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The government tried to curb the panic by suspending some trade and also helping to buy stocks. The efforts, however, fell short. The Shanghai Composite fell by 5.9 percent Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>For A 3rd Straight Day, Chinese Markets Plunge
July 08, 2015 8:46 AM ET
A man walks past an electric board displaying stock prices at a brokerage house in Beijing, China, on Wednesday. Andy Wong/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Andy Wong/AP
A man walks past an electric board displaying stock prices at a brokerage house in Beijing, China, on Wednesday.
Andy Wong/AP
It was another turbulent day on the Chinese stock market on Wednesday. For a third day in a row, stocks tumbled as the government tried unsuccessfully to prop up the market.
Reporting from Beijing, NPR's Anthony Kuhn reports that over the past three weeks, the markets have lost some $4 trillion.
Anthony reports:
"Today, the Shanghai and Shenzhen markets fell by 5.9 percent and 2.9 percent, respectively, even as the government gave brokerages more money to buy up stocks. Nearly half of listed companies halted trading to try to wait out the market turbulence.
"Beijing University finance professor Michael Pettis says the current rout highlights the speculative nature of China's markets. He says they're speculative because investors lack reliable information on certain things:
" 'High-quality macroeconomic data, high-quality financial statements; a clear understanding of what managers are supposed to do  corporate governance  and they need to know that the rules are stable,' Pettis said.
"Without that information, Pettis says, it's hard for investors to calculate what companies are worth and how they'll perform in future."
Much of the talk on this side of the world has been about the possibility of contagion and also what exactly all these interventions by the Chinese government mean.
Bloomberg reports :
"The trading suspensions, which cast doubt on authorities' pledge to give markets a greater role in the world's second-largest economy, mean that the Shanghai Composite's drop was probably understated.
" 'It's absurd, stopping trading just because they don't want stocks to fall,' said Tsutomu Yamada, a market analyst at Kabu.com Securities Co. in Tokyo. 'They're going all out in trying to stop stocks from falling but it's not working.' ...
"Leshi Internet Information &amp; Technology (Beijing) Co., the biggest company in the ChiNext index of small-cap stocks, was suspended after plunging 42 percent from a record high two months ago. The company, which soared five-fold in the year through May, said in a statement that it plans to invest in a smart terminal."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
