<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:16:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ireland was 'bounced' into the Troika deal - Cowen</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713362-bank-inquiry/</Link>
        <Description>Former Taoiseach, Brian Cowen, has defended his government's decision to guarantee the banks and said Ireland was "bounced" into the Troika bailout in 2010.</Description>
        <MainBody>AS IT HAPPENED: BANKING INQUIRY
He denied that he overruled then minister for finance Brian Lenihan in their private conversation on the night, which he said was not adversarial or confrontational.
Mr Cowenalso detailed how conditions worsened for Ireland in 2010 and said they were eventually pushed into the bailout.
Off-the-record briefings tried to create a situation where a programme was a fait accompli, without prior agreement on conditions, he said.
He also insisted that banking was not discussed on an infamous golf outing in July 2008 with a group of Anglo Irish Bank directors and its chairman Sen FitzPatrick.
As God was his witness, Mr Cowensaid, they only discussed the economy.
MrCowensaidhe acceptedhis share of responsibility of what happened to the country.
Asilent run had begun by depositors on all Irish banks, he said.
Mr Cowen addedthat they knew over the weekend of 27-28 September 2008 that Anglo and Irish Life &amp; Permanent were going to find it hardto get through the following week in terms of having no cash to conduct day-to-day business.
Money continuedto leave the financial system at such a ratethat a meeting was scheduled at the Department of An Taoiseach after close of business on 29 September 2008 to review the situation.
He said GovernorHurleytold the meeting that a situation had developed at Anglo where it had lost 2bn in deposits that day.
Mr Cowen said Mr Hurley had been in contact with ECB president Jean-Claude Trichet and confirmed that there wasno euro-wide initiative in the offingand "it was clear that we were on our own".
The former taoiseachtold the inquiry that they were bounced into the bailout by anonymous briefings from ECB/EU sources in an unacceptable manner.
These off-the-record briefings were clearly trying to create a situation where a formal Irish approach for assistance was a fait accompli without prior agreement on conditions, he said.
The ECB also threatened to withdraw funding for banks if they did not accept the programme.
Sinn Fin's Pearse Doherty asked Mr Cowen when he had first become aware that the wholesale borrowing situation represented a systemic risk to the banking sector.
The issue would have come up in relation to the Northern Rock situation, Mr Cowen said,and the government had been watching how that was working out.
He said in relation to wholesale borrowings September of 2008 was a trigger, and that the government had been managing the situation up to then.
Mr Cowen said he had no recollection of anyone coming to him and suggesting a guarantee as a potential solution. He said he had never discussed this with anyone in any of the banks at any time.
He was aware of what the multitude of solutions might be from early on, he said.
The first time he became aware of the need to prepare legislation for the potential State guarantee of institutions was April/May, he said.
Cowen says he wanted to look at all angles
Mr Cowen said on the night of the guarantee he did not have his mind made up beforehand and did not know what they were going to do.
He said he had wanted to be briefed, that he wanted a discussion and he wanted to look at all the angles.
Mr Cowen was asked if, when he spoke to economist andCentral Bank board member Alan Gray, Mr Gray mentioned that Sen FitzPatrick and David Drumm had called to his office a couple of hours beforehand.
Mr Cowen said Mr Gray did not mention that.
Inquiry chairman Ciarn Lynch asked Mr Cowen about the possibility of a different approach being taken if the true financial position of the banks had been known on the night of the guarantee.
Mr Lynch asked if a different approach might have reduced the losses ultimately sustained by the Irish taxpayer given the apparent insistence of the ECB that no bank should fail.
Mr Cowen said there had to be a decision about whether it was important to have a domestic banking system, and he said he had no doubt the answer was yes.
The question of pressing a nuclear button or saying let it fall where it may, he said, would have had devastating effects on the Irish economy.
Mr Cowen said one person had said to him it would have meant going back a generation, 25 years.He said the country went back five or six years but not 25.
It was his opinion that you could not allow a bank to close.
Mr Cowen said there was no cost free solution to the problem. The guarantee bought time, he said, and without it they would have had to recapitalise much more quickly.
'Banking not discussed at golf game'
Mr Doherty asked Mr Cowen about how a game of golf in Druids Glen in July 2008 with a group of individuals, including Sen FitzPatrick, came about.
Mr Cowen said he had suggested to formerAnglo directorFintan Drurythat a few people should get together to discuss how the economy was going after the Dil broke up for the summer recess.
He said he did not believe it should stretch credibility that issues around banking were not discussed as this was the truth.
Mr Cowen said discussions there were about economic issues and were nothing to do with Anglo Irish Bank.
Fianna Fil's Michael McGrath asked Mr Cowen about the night the decision was taken for the bank guarantee.
Mr Cowen said based on the information available that night the government had to avoid a run on the banking system in Ireland.
He said he believed the decision they made provided them with the best prospect of achieving that.
Further information the government received following analysis by PWC within six weeks of the guarantee reaffirmed the fact that the basis on which the decision was made was correct, he said.
He said the immediate problem was to get money into the system.
'National interest that they had to protect'
Mr McGrath asked Mr Cowen about a phone conversation he had with then British Prime Minister Gordon Brown in September 2008.
Mr Cowen said that Gordon Brown had been putting forward British concerns, andthey obviously had a concern in relation to the possibility of extending the bank guarantee to UK banks with operations in Ireland.
Mr Cowen said at the end of the day the banks concerned made a decision not to come in on the guarantee scheme because of the conditions the Government would have had to set for them to do so.
Mr Cowen said he had said to Mr Brown that they would continue to work with those who had concerns, but that they had a national interest that they had to protect.
Fine Gael TD Kieran O'Donnell asked about warnings on the exposure of banks to the property market and the liquidity of banks in the months coming up to the bank guarantee.
He asked Mr Cowen what type of instructions he had given on taking up office as taoiseach to deal with the impending crisis.
Mr Cowen said for the previous 12 months prior to the guarantee the Government was managing the situation, and the Central Bank was working with the various institutions.
He said the regulatory authorities were informing the Government that they were doing stress tests, and all of that was indicating that while there were difficulties in the banks we were getting through this.
Mr Cowen said a trigger moment happened in September with the collapse of Lehman Brothers in the US.
He said a plan was in place, and there was a nationalisation bill ready to go if that was what they wanted to do, there had been arrangements made to have a fighting fund established if that was needed, and the legislation was ready to go if they were going the guarantee route.
Mr O'Donnell asked Mr Cowen about the game of golf at Druid's Glen in July 2008.
Mr Cowen said he thought all of the individuals concerned now would probably rather it had not happened if only for the optics.
However, he said he did not do anything untoward, or inappropriate, or discuss issues with any individual bank at the expense or cost of anyone else at that time or ever.
Senator Marc McSharry asked Mr Cowen about his relationship with Brian Lenihan and how they came to a decision on the night of the guarantee.
Mr Cowen said he had a very good relationship through the years with Mr Lenihan, and it was clear to colleagues, that in relation to economic and budgetary matters,he had his full support.
Mr Cowen said on the night of the guarantee they had to come to a conclusion then andMr Lenihan's position was different to his, and they "chatted it out".
He said they came ultimately to a conclusion as to what they felt, on balancewith different degrees of conviction, was what was going to be the best thing to do.
Mr Cowen said when the final position was put to those present there was no dissent.
He said it was not an atmosphere where he was overruling people.
Mr Cowen said it was in thebest national interest to listen to the ECB's advice that no bank could fail.
It would have been very hard to fund the banks in the future without the co-operation of the ECB. It was clear that as a eurozone member, no bank of systemic importance could fail.
On banks' solvency on the night of the guarantee, they were dependent on the advice they were given at that time, he said.
Fine Gael's Eoghan Murphy asked why they trusted the Regulator's information at such a turbulent time.
Mr Cowen said you had to trust somebody and they put it to the Regulator and the Central Bank governor.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:18:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Irishman dies in Thailand drowning incident</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713523-irishman-dies-in-thailand-drowning-incident/</Link>
        <Description>A 24-year-old Irishman has died in what is thought to have been a drowning incident in Thailand.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Wednesday 08 July 2015 23.18
The chairman of Dungarvan GAA Club descricbed David Houlihan as one of the most popular men in the community
A 24-year-oldIrishman has died in what is thoughtto have been a drowning incident in Thailand.
The man has been named locally asDavid Houlihan fromthe Dungarvan area of Co Waterford.
The Department of Foreign Affairs is providing consular assistance to the family.
Mr Houlihan was an active member ofDungarvan GAA Club. This evening the chairman of the club described the 24-year-old as"one of the most popular men in the club and in the community".
Mr Ryan saidMr Houlihanwas very close to a lot of the players who are very upset at the news of his death and added that the club would probably arrange for counsellingover the coming days.
"He had this way about him, he just didn't stay within his own club, he had friends all over, in different parishes. He played soccer with Lismore, he enjoyed golf this past year, he was just one of these people that enjoyed everybody's company," Mr Ryan said.
MrHoulihanwas working locally for GlaxoSmithKline.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:55:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Labour TD criticises changes to one-parent payment</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713567-emmet-stagg/</Link>
        <Description>Labour party Chief Whip Emmet Stagg has confirmed that he wrote a letter to a constituent in which he criticised recent changes to the One-Parent Family Payment.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 23.55
Emmet Stagg has said he stands over his remarks and does not regret making them
Labour party chief whip Emmet Stagg has confirmed that he wrote a letter to a constituent in which he criticisedrecent changes made to theOne-Parent Family Payment.
In an email Mr Stagg describes the changes as "a bad decision" and said he will continue to press for their reversal.
The Kildare TD said he "fails to see how cutting the income of the very ones who are making a real effort to improve the lot of their family and themselves helps in some way to get out of a poverty trap".
He said the cut "clearly has the opposite effect".
When contacted by RT news Mr Stagg said he is aware that the letter has made it into the public domain, and he has no problem with this. He said he stands over his remarks and does notregret making them.
A copy of the email was tweeted by theFianna Fil TD Colm Keaveneywho accused Mr Stagg of "appalling duplicity".
About 30,000 families across the country received their final One-Parent Family Payment last month.
They were moved to different payments, mainly to the newly-introduced Job Seekers Transitional Allowance or to Job Seekers Allowance, because their youngest child has reached the age of seven.
The Government has acknowledged that at least 4,000 of the 30,000 parents in part-time work will suffer an income loss as a result of the changes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:32:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tsipras tells EU parliament Greece will reform</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713376-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras has said that a detailed plan is being drawn up aimed at resolving the country's debt crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Alexis Tsiprastoday addressed the European Parliament after EU leaders gave him five days to come up with convincing reforms.
With its banks closed, cash withdrawals rationed and the economy in freefall, Greece has never been closer to a state bankruptcy that would probably force it to print an alternative currency and leave the euro.
Mr Tsipras appeared before EU politicians in Strasbourg to cheers and scattered boos.
He was speaking hours after eurozone leaders, at another emergency summit in Brussels, set Greece a deadline of the end of the week to come up with far-reaching reform proposals.
Mr Tsipras said Greeks had no choice but to demand a way out of "this impasse".
"We are determined not to have a clash with Europe but to tackle head on the establishment in our own country and to change the mindset which will take us and the eurozone down," he said to applause from the left.
He promised to deliver detailed reform proposals tomorrow and mostly avoided the angry rhetoric that has alienated many European partners.
However, he criticised attempts to "terrorise" Greeks into voting for "never-ending austerity".
In its loan application letter, Athens promised to implement a set of tax and pension measures "as early as the beginning of next week", promising more details within 48 hours.
Tusk says this week is final deadline for Greece
Speaking before Mr Tsipras, European Council President Donald Tusk repeated that the final deadline for Greece to submit convincing reform plans and start implementing them was this week.
"Our inability to find an agreement may lead to the bankruptcy of Greece and the insolvency of its banking system," Mr Tusk said.
"And for sure it will be most painful for the Greek people.
"I have no doubt that this will affect Europe, also in the geopolitical sense. If someone has any illusion that it will not, they are naive," he said.
In the turbulent chamber, some politicians held up "Oxi" (No) signs to back Greek voters' rejection of more austerity, while far-right speakers praised the radical leftist government for standing up to what several called the European "oligarchy".
If experts from the European Commission, European Central Bank and International Monetary Fund deem the Greek proposals viable, eurozone finance ministers would meet on Saturday to recommend opening negotiations with Athens.
A special summit of the 28-nation EU would then meet on Sunday to approve an aid plan.
Before then, Greece is supposed to rush a first wave of measures through parliament, eurozone sources said.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel has said she would ask parliament in Berlin to authorise the opening of loan negotiations provided the Greek measures are deemed satisfactory.
Eurozone sources said one key question is whether the Greek reform package will be more ambitious than the spending cuts, tax increases and modest reforms that Greek voters rejected on Sunday in a referendum on a previous bailout plan.
"The numbers have to add up, and the numbers have become vastly more unfavourable since the banks were shut and the economy seized up in the last ten days," one eurozone finance official said.
Meanwhile,Greece's finance ministry has dismissed a newspaper report that the country was preparing to issue a second currency to pay state pensions and wages atthe end of July.
Citing unidentified sources, Kathimerini newspaper reported that Greece's General Accounting Office was preparing IOUs, known as warrants, to pay the wages and pensions of state workers at the end of the month if there was no deal between Greece and its lenders by then.
"The report is totally baseless. Such reports are directed against the country and considered dangerous at a time when negotiations with creditors partners are at a crucial point," the finance ministry said in a statement.
Meanwhile,Tnaiste Joan Burton has said she believes that a deal can be done to "reappraise or reschedule" the obligations that Greece has committed to.
She said she wanted to see everyone sitting round a table and negotiating a deal that would be good for the people in Greece and in the rest of Europe.
Analysis: Paul Cunningham
It appears that the defining moment of the Greek debt crisis beckons this Sunday - when all 28 EU leaders will consider proposals from the Syriza government in Athens for a third bailout.
Commission President Jean Claude Juncker said he wanted Greece to remain in the eurozone but his team was prepared for everything.
We have a Grexit scenario prepared, he said.
By tomorrow at the latest, the Greek government must publish its bailout plans; these will first be assessed by international creditors,then by eurozone finance ministers on Saturdaybefore a full EU leaders' summit on Sunday.
Taoiseach Enda Kenny said: "Time is now of the essence". For his part, the Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said he wanted a "socially just and economically viable agreement".
In reality, the Greek government has been given a final ultimatum, after months of stormy negotiation. As one Greek newspaper put it this morning -it's the euro or drachma this Sunday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:06:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PSNI to investigate 'Project Eagle' claims</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713397-nama-northern-ireland/</Link>
        <Description>The PSNI has launched a criminal investigation regarding concerns over the sale of Nama's Northern Ireland property portfolio and the recent claims made by Independent TD Mick Wallace under Dáil privilege.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 18.06
The PSNI is engaging with a number of law enforcement partners as part of the investigation
The PSNI has launched acriminal investigationregarding concerns over thesale of Nama's Northern Ireland property portfolio and the recent claims made by Independent TD Mick Wallace underDil privilege.
Last year a US Investment company, Cerberus Capital Management, bought a NAMA portfolio of Northern Ireland-based debtors.
During Leaders'Questions in the Dil on 2 July, Mr Wallace made a number of serious allegations about the deal, which he said was called Project Eagle.
Mr Wallace claimeda routine auditshowed7m in funding ended up in an Isle of Man account.
He said the moneywas "reportedly earmarked for a Northern Ireland politician".
Assistant Chief Constable Will Kerr, who is head of crime operations at the PSNI, said: "We believe that there is sufficient concern in relation to potential criminal activity, surrounding this property deal, to instigate an investigation.
"PSNI are now engaging with a number of other national and international law enforcement partners to consider how best to take forward this investigation" he said.
Stormont's finance committee and the Dils Public Accounts Committee are also examining Mr Wallace's allegations about the project eagle deal.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:35:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NTA reports mixed response to bicyle rental scheme</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713531-nta-reports-mixed-response-to-bike-rental-scheme/</Link>
        <Description>New data from the National Transport Authority shows mixed results for bicycle rental schemes outside of Dublin.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 19.35
Public hire initiatives were rolled out in Galway, Limerick and Cork at the end of 2014
New data from the National Transport Authority shows mixed results for bicycle rental schemes outside of Dublin.
Public hire initiatives were rolled out in Galway, Limerick and Cork at the end of last year.
Almost 5,000 people have registered for the bike rental scheme in Cork, with a total of 90,000 journeys made since the launch.
By contrast, there have been just over 11,200 journeys in the first six months of the Galway bike rental scheme, with 17,300 recorded in Limerick.
The data was provided following a parliamentary question from Galway West Fine Gael TD,Sen Kyne.
Users must subscribe in advance to hire bikes. The first half hour is free, with charges applying after 30 minutes, if the bike is not returned to a rental station.
The NTA says the possibility of extending the scheme to other urban centres will be looked at later this year. The success or otherwise of the initiative in Galway, Cork and Limerick will inform that decision.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:15:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>300 years of Catholic parish registers go online</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713448-catholic-parish-registers/</Link>
        <Description>The National Library say over 50,000 unique users have visited its website today, after it made almost 300 years of Catholic parish records available.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 22.15
The records cover the entire island of Ireland
Almost 300 years of Catholic parish registers, containing information on births and marriages, held by the National Library of Ireland have been made available online.
The National Library says over 50,000 unique users have visited the website since its launch at 1pm today.
Thousands of baptismal and marriage certificates, dating fromthe 1740s to the 1880scan now be accessed online,for free.
The dedicated website has over 390,000 digital images of parish registers.
The parish register records are considered the single-most important source of information on Irish family history prior to the 1901 Census.
Covering more thana 1,000 parishes throughout the island of Ireland, the registers consist primarily of baptismal and marriage records.
They typically include information such as dates of baptisms and marriages, and the names of key people involved, such as witnesses or godparents.
For most genealogy researchers, parish registers provide the earliest direct source of family information as they can provide evidence of direct links between one generation and the next .
The documents can be accessed online atregisters.nli.ie.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:36:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vodafone plans to create 200 jobs in Dublin</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713401-vodafone-jobs/</Link>
        <Description>Telecoms operator Vodafone is to create 200 jobs in Dublin.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 22.36
Enda Kenny at Vodafone HQ in Westport, Co Mayo today
Telecoms operator Vodafone is to create 200jobs in Dublin when it opens a newtechnology driven European sales centre in Carrickmines.
The news was announced by Taoiseach Enda Kenny today, who visited Vodafone HQ in Westport, Co Mayo.
The venture, which was pilotedlast year, will involve an investment of 60mover five years.
It will bring to 2,000 the number of people employed by Vodafone in Ireland.
The new facility, called Vodafone Red Edge,will act as a sales centre for the company's business customers in Ireland, the Netherlands and the UK.
Two other support hubs will be located in central and southern Europe.
The centre will use a mixture of smart communication tools, predictive analytics and data to drive remote sales with customers.
Vodafone has saidits Irish operation won the investment mainly because of the pool of highly-skilled graduates available in the country.
The company saidrecruitment for the new jobshas already begun.
The expansion is supported by the Department of Jobs, Enterprise and Innovation through IDA Ireland.
Vodafone's chief executive in Ireland Anne O'Learysaid the centre would bring the latest in innovation including advanced sales tools and data analytics to determine customer needs and attitudes.
New recruits are to get specialist business analytics and sales training, which the company says will provide them with career development opportunities across the wider group.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:24:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Parents face back-to-school costs of €400</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713365-credit-union-survey/</Link>
        <Description>A survey has found that parents will spend an average of almost €400 per child on uniforms and books this September.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 22.24
Over two-thirds of those surveyed said the costs impact their ability to pay household bills
A survey has found that parents will spend an average of almost 400 per child on uniforms and books this September.
A study by the Irish League of Credit Unions found that almost a third of parents find themselves in debt covering back to school costs.
The survey found that uniforms can cost an average of 166 for primary school children and 258 for secondary school students.
School books for primary school childrencost anaverage of 106and 213 for secondary school students.
Over two-thirds of those surveyed said the costs will impacttheir ability to pay household bills or afford a holiday.
The survey found that 20% of parents surveyed said they will need to borrow to meet the costs of going back to school.
Financial expert and founder of the Irish Financial ReviewFrank Conwaydescribed the findings as worrying.
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, Mr Conway said those who are most financially vulnerable will end up paying the most when it comes to covering the costs.
Mr Conway said parents who might turn to moneylenders, as well as parents sacrificing food, are just some of the most worrying aspects of the survey.
He said when families who have children in primary and secondary schools tot up all their costs, they could be faced with a bill of around 1,000; money, he said, many people do not have.
Mr Conway said the main cost burdens are uniforms, books, lunches and transport.
He is urging families to plan ahead and to try to "keep a rainy day fund".
If parents have to borrow, he said, they should pay off the debt quickly to avoid paying late fees and charges.
Families should also give themselves enough time to shop around for deals, he said.
Mr Conway called on the Government to roll out a more robust solution than the book rental scheme, as families with multiple children will see costs mounting in this area.
Minister for Education Jan O'Sullivan said she noted the burden of costs on families andthe Government would continue to support parents to bring costs down.
The minister added thatthe book rental scheme has been rolled out to 95%of schools andthe Government will continue to invest in this scheme as it is a practical way of helping parents.
Ms O'Sullivan said there has been considerable pressure put on publishers recently to try to combat the changing of books every couple of years due to small changes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:50:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clerys liquidation to cost taxpayer 'millions'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713459-ictu-conference/</Link>
        <Description>Tánaiste and Minister for Social Protection Joan Burton has confirmed that the cost to the taxpayer of the Clerys liquidation is set to run into millions.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 21.50
Tnaiste Joan Burton described the actions of the owners of Clerys as "predator capitalism"
Tnaiste and Minister for Social Protection Joan Burton has confirmed that the cost to the taxpayer of the Clerys liquidation is set to run into millions.
Speaking as she arrived at the ICTU conference in Ennis, she described the actions of the owners of Clerys as "predator capitalism".
She said it was not right that the owners had left workers in the lurch and left the State facing the redundancy bill.
The State had better things to do with its money than bail them out, she said.
Given that the effect of the owners' actions was to place its private obligation to pay redundancy onto the State, she said she will use every legal avenue to vindicate the State and taxpayers'rights in this regard.
Ms Burton also said she expects aLow Pay Commission report, due this month, to recommend a rise in the national minimum wage.
The minimum wage, currently at 8.65 an hour, was the minimum value put on work, she said.
However, she acknowledged that while it was a protection against exploitation, it was not a guarantee of fair or even adequate wages.
The Tnaiste signed the new ICTU charter on workers'rights, which includes a commitment to pursue theintroduction of the living wage calculated at 11.45.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:10:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Appeal for 12-year-old missing from Co Kilkenny</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713546-appeal-for-12-year-old-missing-from-co-kilkenny/</Link>
        <Description>Gardaí are seeking the public's assistance in tracing 12-year-old Thomas Delaney.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 21.10
Thomas Delaney was last seen at approximately 12pm today in Glenmore, Co Kilkenny
Garda are seeking the publics assistance in tracing 12-year-old Thomas Delaney.
He was last seen at approximately 12pm today and is from Glenmore, Co Kilkenny.
He is described as being 1.22m (4) tall, of slim build, with blue eyes and short mousy brown hair.
Mr Delaney was last seen wearing a grey-blue Addidas tracksuit and black-grey runners.
Anyone with information is asked to contact Thomastown Garda Station on 056-7754157, the Garda Confidential Line 1800 666 111 or any garda station.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:45:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Call for inclusion of Cork home in investigation</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713516-mother-and-baby-home/</Link>
        <Description>Survivors of Protestant residential institutions have urged the Mother and Baby Home Commission to ask the government to include a Cork rescue home in its terms of reference.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 18.45
The Commission of Investigation into Mother and Baby Homes between 1922 and 1998 was established last February
Survivors of Protestant residential institutions have urged the Mother and Baby Home Commission to ask the Government to include a Cork rescue home in its terms of reference.
The survivors have also asked the Commission's chairperson, Judge Yvonne Murphy, to clarify why the majority of former residents of the Westbank Home in CoWicklow are excluded from the investigation despite indications to the contrary from Tnaiste Joan Burton.
The Commission of Investigation into Mother and Baby Homes between 1922 and 1998 was established last February following an outcry over the treatment - including the burial - of residents in an institution in Tuam, CoGalway which closed in the 1960s.
In a letter to Judge Murphy, Griffith College academicNiall Meehanhighlights the exclusion of the now defunct Braemar Rescue Home for Protestant Girls in Cork City from the Commission's terms of reference.
Dr Meehan says this has happened despite Braemar being the first recorded source of babies who were sent from here for adoption in the United States after tWorld War 2.
Recalling that the Commission is tasked with investigating adoption practices affecting residents of homes, hecontrasts Braemar's exclusion with the inclusion of Manor House in Catlepollard, a Catholic institution from which some of the other earlier American adoptees were taken.
Dr Meehan says the Government cannot entertain discriminating against Protestant women in this way.
Turning to the controversial former Westbank Home in Greystones, Co Wicklow, Dr Meehan says most residents will not be allowed to tell the Commission their stories.
He recalls that when it was excluded from the the list of 14 named institutions in the Government's terms of reference for the Commission, the Tnaiste Joan Burton, told the Dil that Judge Murphy had confirmed that cases from it and other such institutions would not be excluded from the Commission's Confidential Committee and that anybody with anything of relevance to contribute could do so.
A spokesperson for the Commission has told RT News that Braemar and Westbank had already come to its attention and that they would probably be looked at in their capacity as exit routes for residents from the homes included in the terms of reference.
The spokesperson added that the Commission would investigate them fully if they were included in the terms, and that it was up to the Government to amend them if it wanted to.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:50:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Remains of US Marines found in Pacific</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713367-marines-pacific-island/</Link>
        <Description>The bodies of 36 US Marines have been found on a remote Pacific island more than 70 years after they died in a bloody World War II battle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 13.50
An exhibit depicts Marines in the Battle for Tarawa in the Central Pacific during World War II
The bodies of 36 US Marines have been found on a remote Pacific island more than 70 years after they died in a bloody World War II battle.
A member of the recovery team said the remains were discovered after a four-month excavation on Betio Island in Kiribati.
Director of US charity History Flight, Mark Noah, told Radio New Zealand that the men were killed during the Battle of Tarawa in 1943.
The organisation had worked with the US Defense Department on the project.
While the remains have not been formally identified, Mr Noah said they almost certainly include those of Lieutenant Alexander Bonnyman, who posthumously received America's highest military accolade, the Medal of Honor, for conspicuous gallantry.
Bonnyman's citation says he led a series of assaults when Marines stormed the island, finally falling when he attacked a bombproof installation that was hampering the advance.
A statement on History Flight's website said Bonnyman's daughters had decided to have his remains interred in a family plot in Knoxville, Tennessee, next to his parents, with a public funeral service planned.
Overall, more than 1,000 Americans died at Tarawa, while the entire Japanese garrison of 4,800 was wiped out.
Mr Noah said the remains would be repatriated this month and identified using a combination of dental records and DNA comparison with surviving relatives.
He said the bodies of several hundred American soldiers still lay in makeshift, unrecorded graves where they were buried after the battle.
Mr Noah said efforts would continue to ensure that the bodies were returned home.
"There's a lot of work to be done on the island," he said.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:56:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Microsoft to reduce global workforce by 7,800</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713501-microsoft-to-reduce-global-workforce/</Link>
        <Description>Computer giant Microsoft has announced that is to reduce its global workforce by 7,800.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 16.56
The computer giant company is to reduce its global workforce primarily in its phone business
Computer giant Microsoft has announced that is to reduce its global workforce by 7,800.
The reductions will primarily be in the company's phone business which it bought from Nokia in 2013 for $7.2bn and will take place over the next few months.
A spokesperson for Microsoft in Ireland had no comment to make when asked what the potential impact could be on its almost 2,000 permanent and contract staff here.
However, the company's Irish operations are primarily focused on cloud services, software development and operations, and so it is likely any job cuts here would be minimal and limited to a small number of people.
The news was conveyed to staff via an email to staff from Microsoft CEO, Satya Nadella.
The company will also take a $7.6bn impairment charge on the assets it acquired when it bought Nokia's Devices and Services business.
It will also take a restructuring charge of approximately $750mto $850m.
"I don't take changes in plans like these lightly, given that they affect the lives of people who have made an impact at Microsoft," Mr Nadella said. "We are deeply committed to helping our team members through these transitions."
Microsoft has struggled to turn around the Nokia handset division it purchased, and to make inroads into the market with its Windows mobile operating system
Mr Nadella said that he is committed to its devices business, including phones, but added that efforts in that area need to be focused in the short term to three customer segments.
These include business customers, value phone buyers and Windows fans.
"We are moving from a strategy to grow a standalone phone business to a strategy to grow and create a vibrant Windows ecosystem that includes our first-party device family,"he said.
The job cuts announced today are in addition to the 18,000 job cuts announced at the company last year.
The layoffs had been expected, following an email sent to staff by Mr Nadella last month which warned it would have to "make some tough choices in areas where things are not working and solve hard problems in ways that drive customer value."
Microsoft currently employs 118,000 around the world.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:39:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two-thirds favour decriminalising abortion - poll</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713485-abortion-poll/</Link>
        <Description>Two-thirds of the Irish public favour decriminalising abortion, according to the results of a new poll for Amnesty International.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 17.39
Colm O'Gorman said Irish views on abortion have undergone a major transformation
Two-thirds of the Irish publicfavour decriminalising abortion, according to the results of anew poll for Amnesty International.
It also says the majority of people in Ireland are not aware that abortion is a criminal offence when a woman's life is not at risk.
The human rights organisation arguesthe Government is under increasingpressure to reform its anti-abortion law, one of the most restrictive in the world.
Over 1,000 people were interviewed in May as part of the poll,carried outby RED C Research and Marketing.
Asked whether the Government should decriminalise abortion, 67% agreed and 25% disagreed. 81% are in favour of significantly widening the grounds for legal abortion access in Ireland.
Key figures:
- 64% of people did not know it is a crime to get an abortion in Ireland when a woman's life is not at risk
- 71% agreed that classifying abortion as a crime contributes to the distress and stigma felt by women who have had abortions
- 68% agree that Ireland's abortion ban does not stop most women who want an abortion from having one
-70%agreed that women have aright to an abortion when their pregnancy is a result of rape or incest, where their life or health is at risk, or in cases of fatal foetal impairment
Executive Director of Amnesty International Ireland Colm O'Gorman said:"It is clear that Irish views on abortion have undergone a major transformation. People in Ireland are now, on the whole, more understanding of the situations women find themselves in and firmly believe that women should not be criminalised for having an abortion.
"This poll demonstrates that on the issue of abortion Ireland's people are clearly way ahead of their government leaders. The conversation we urgently need in Ireland on abortion is a challenging one, but it must happen.
"The Irish Government should put this issue to the people as a matter of priority. Decriminalising abortion is not only a human rights obligation - it is what people in Ireland want. And this means repealing the 8th Amendment," he added.
Sherlock takes issue with Amnesty poll findings
However, the Pro-Life Campaign has taken issue with the poll and said Amnesty's reputationhas been greatly undermined by its "decision to adopt such a one-sided position on the abortion issue".
Deputy Chairperson of the Pro-Life Campaign Cora Sherlock referred to Amnesty's report 'My Body: My Rights' saying:"It's now abundantly clear that Amnesty's recent report on Ireland's abortion laws was selective and skewed in pushing a pro-choice agenda. There wasn't even the slightest attempt made to ensure balance.
"In compiling the report, Amnesty failed to consult with women who regret their abortions or those who came under intense pressure from State funded agencies to abort their children with life-limiting conditions.
She added: "Almost identical results to today's Red C poll findings were published as far back as 1997 but when the public had an opportunity to vote on the issue in 2002 the outcome of the referendum was entirely different and a clear pro-life majority was evident.
"I am confident that as the current debate develops it will become much clearer that the Eighth Amendment, which provides the last remaining legal protection for the unborn, remains a force for good and is responsible for saving many lives and for creating an ethos of care that respects and protects both mother and baby in pregnancy."
The Pro-Life Campaignclaimed today's poll is undermined because one of a number of groups that were interviewed in compilingAmnesty's 'She is not a criminal' report , published on 9 June, is a group that advises women on abortions in countrieswhere abortions are illegal.
Amnesty has refuted this claim saying the recent report and today's poll are completely independent.
It said it"spoke to a plethora of health service providers, politicians, women affected, doctors, midwives etc" in compiling its 'She is not a criminal report'and the online advice group was one of those.
This group "had nothing to do with the Red C poll published today, which was commissioned by Amnesty International but done entirely byRed C", Amnesty said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:47:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK budget for the 'working people' - Osborne</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0708/713394-uk-budget/</Link>
        <Description>British Chancellor George Osborne has pledged to create a "higher wage, lower tax, lower welfare" Britain as he unveiled the first Tory-only Budget for nearly 20 years.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 14.47
UK Finance Minister says Britain still spends too much and borrows too much
British Chancellor George Osborne has pledged to create a "higher wage, lower tax, lower welfare" Britain as he unveiled the first Tory-only Budget for nearly 20 years.
The Chancellorannounced plans to introduce aa new "living wage" of9 an hour by 2020.
"Britain deserves a pay rise", he said."The Low Pay Commission will recommend future rises that achieve the Government's objective of reaching 60% of median earnings by 2020".
The Chancellor pointed to the Greek crisis as evidence that a "bold new settlement" is needed, saying Britain was still "borrowing too much and spending too much".
"This is the new settlement from a one nation government," he said. "This is a big budget for a country with big ambitions."
Mr Osborne said the UK economy today is "fundamentally stronger than it was five years ago", with living standards rising strongly.
He said higher tax receipts meant he could implement a "smoother" path to recording a surplus in the government finances, but stressed that he would not back away from tackling the deficit.
"You only have to look at the crisis unfolding in Greece as I speak to realise that if a country's not in control of its borrowing, the borrowing takes control of the country," Mr Osborne said.
"Britain still spends too much, borrows too much, and our weak productivity shows we don't train enough or build enough or invest enough."
"This will be a Budget for working people. A Budget that sets out a plan for Britain for the next five years to keep moving us from a low-wage, high-tax, high-welfare economy; to the higher-wage, lower-tax, lower-welfare country we intend to create."
The UK's official growth forecast for 2015 was revised slightly downwards today. Growth for this year was forecast to be 2.4%, down from a forecast of 2.5% made in March, Osborne told parliament.
"That is faster than America, faster than Germany and twice as fast as France," he said.
Growth in 2016 was expected to be 2.3%, unchanged from the March forecast made by Britain's Office for Budget Responsibility.
For the rest of the decade, growth would be 2.4% a year, Osborne said.
The Bank of England has previously predicted Britain's economy will grow by 2.5% this year and by 2.6% in 2016.
Mr Osborne said the Government would record an absolute surplus of 0.5% of national income in 2019-20 - a year later than previously predicted.
He stressed that no year would see departmental cuts as deep as those imposed in the last parliament.
"Many difficult but necessary decisions are required to save money and this will be done with moderation but determination," Mr Osborne said.
The Chancellor said 37 billion of fiscal consolidation was needed during this parliament, including 12 billion of welfare cuts. He confirmed that he was looking to raise another 5 billion from cracking down on tax avoidance.
Acknowledging a well-received Labour policy from the election campaign, Mr Osborne announced that permanent non-dom tax status was being abolished.
"British people should pay British taxes in Britain, and now they will," he said.
The UK finance minister is to reduce a bank levy charged on the assets of financial institutions and replace with it with a surcharge on bank profits.
"I will, over the next six years, gradually reduce the bank levy rate - and after that make sure it no longer applies to worldwide balance sheets," he said.
      
"But to maintain a fair contribution from the banks, I will introduce a new 8% surcharge on bank profits from January next year."
      
The bank levy was introduced in 2011 in response to the financial crisis and applies to the global balance sheet assets of British banks as well as assets belonging to the UK operations of foreign banks. HSBC has said the levy will be a factor in whether it decides to keep its headquarters in Britain.
On corporation tax, the Chancellor said the rate will be cut from 20% to 19% in 2017 and to 18% by 2020.
Mr Osborne also announced reforms to UK vehicle excise duty, reducing the number of bands to three - zero, standard and premium. He said "every single penny" of revenue will be ringfenced for road projects.
Fuel duty will remain frozen this year, he said.
And in a controversial move, Mr Osborne confirmed that student grants will be replaced by loans to save 1.6 billion.
"We have removed the artificial cap on student numbers so we don't have to turn away people from our universities who want to go and have the right grades," he said.
"But we can't afford to do this unless we tackle the cost of student maintenance grants - that is set to almost double to 3 billion over this decade", he added.
The main announcements in today's UKBudget include:
- a new compulsory National Living Wage for working people aged 25 and over, starting in April 2016 at 7.20 an hour and reaching 9 an hour by 2020.
- the Office for Budget Responsibility downgraded growth forecast for 2015 from 2.5% to 2.4%, then 2.3% in 2016, then revised it up to 2.4% in 2017 and for rest of decade.
- forecast for paying down the national deficit and running a surplus knocked back by a year from 2017/18 to 2018/19.
- new Fiscal Charter committing the country to running an overall budget surplus in normal economic times - when real GDP growth is lower than 1% a year.
- UK corporation tax to be cut from 20% to 19% in 2017 and 18% by 2020.
- tax-free personal allowance at which 20 pence income tax rate is payable raised from 10,600 to 11,000 next year, while, rates of income tax remain unchanged.
- higher rate 40 pence income tax threshold to rise from 42,385 to 43,000 from next year.
- rises in public sector pay restricted to 1% per year for the next four years.
- package of welfare reforms cutting 12 billion from the system, including four-year freeze for working-age benefits.
- reduction from 6,420 to 3,850 in income level at which tax credits begin to be cut, with increase in taper rate at which the benefit is removed.
- support for children through tax credits and universal credits to be limited to two children, affecting children born after April 2017.
- benefits cap to be reduced from 26,000 per household to 23,000 in London and 20,000 in the rest of the country.
- rate of Employment and Support Allowance aligned with Jobseekers' Allowance for new claimants deemed able to work.
- permanent non-dom tax status to be abolished.
- inheritance tax reform to allow estates worth up to 1m to be tax-free if they include a home.
- new bands for vehicle excise duty for brand new cars from 2017 - with most cars paying 140 standard charge. No change to VED for existing cars. All income from VED to go into new Roads Fund to pay for investment in the network.
- climate change levy exemption for renewable electricity to be removed
- counties and elected mayors to gain power to set Sunday trading hours in their areas.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:08:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As it happened: Banking Inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713403-live-banking-inquiry/</Link>
        <Description>Brian Cowen appears before the banking inquiry for the second time, the session focused on the period covering the bank guarantee and the bailout in detail.</Description>
        <MainBody>CONTACT RT NEWS
HOW TO GET IN TOUCH
If you have any views on our stories or would like to share any information you can get in touch with us on Facebook , Twitter or email newsonline@rte.ie
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:00:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Figures show drop in prices paid to dairy farmers</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713461-milk/</Link>
        <Description>New figures from the Central Statistics Office show the price farmers are receiving for milk is down 24% compared to this time last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 17.00
Milk production figures for April and May were 12% higher than for the same period last year
New figures from the Central Statistics Office show the price farmers are receiving for milk is down 24%compared to this time last year.
The reduction is being driven by lower milk prices in the global market place.
Despite the drop in prices, the amount of milk being produced is at an all-time high as farmers have increased their output in response to the abolition of EU milk quotas at the start of April.
Milk production figures for April and May were 12%higher than for the same period last year.
Today's figures show that despiteoptimism about the potential of the Irish dairy sector to expand production and to deliver a very significant boost to our rural economy, dairy farmers are making significantly less money than they were this time last year although they are producing and investing a lot more.
President of the Irish Creamery Milk Suppliers AssociationJohn Comer said there is a lot of anxiety among his members, particularly those who have a lot of borrowings, who are finding themselves constrained because of a lack of profitability.
That has a serious effect not only on the members but also on the economy, he said.
Every one once cent drop in the milk price paid to farmers takes 60mout of the rural economy, Mr Comer said.
Milk, he said, has currently dropped by 10 cents since this time last year, which means there is 600m lessin the rural economy.
He said all the euphoria about milk quotas being abolished has been dampened greatly due to the harsh reality of supply and demand.
He also called for a serious "root and branch" examination of the milk supply chain before it gets to the consumers table.
Consumer prices have not come down even though prices being paid to farmers have dropped 30%.
Mr Comer said we need more transparency in the food supply chain.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:43:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Efforts to 'professionalise the civil service'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713472-civil-service/</Link>
        <Description>The first progress report on the Civil Service Renewal Plan since its publication in October 2014 has been published.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 14.43
Brendan Howlin said that they were moving away from the 'crude' recruitment embargo
The first progress report on the Civil Service Renewal Plan since its publication in October 2014 has been published.
Minister for Public Expenditure and Reform Brendan Howlin has said that at the heart of public service reform is civil service reform.
The minister said that on taking office he has said that not only had Ireland a broken economy, but it had broken oversight. It would take time to restore people's trust in the way public administration works, he said.
He said part of that was to have a much more integrated and people-focused civil service.
Minister Howlin said that focusing on performance "makes a good headline" but he was also trying to maintain moral within the civil service.
"Of course we need to have accountability, and we need to have clarity in relation to accountability and a new disciplinary code is an integral part of this process, but much more important is ensuring that we have a world class civil service," the minister said.
According to the report, work has commenced on 23 out of 25 proposed objectives set out in the plan.
Among the 23 are six so-called priority actions, and the report described work on these as "under way and on track".
One of the reforms where work has yet to begin is to re-design organisational and grade structures.
Effortsto 'professionalise the civil service'
An accountability board, which has a number of external members, has been established and will meet for the first time next week.
The external members are Paul Farrell from IBM Europe, Bernie Gray from Better Boards, Shane Bissett from The Royal Mint and Dorathy Scally from The Top Level Appointments Committee.
The board will publish an annual report.
A 21-member "all-Government" civil service management board has been set up.
The minutes of all the boards meetings will be published and all board members will be assigned responsibility to lead one ormore of the plan's proposed reforms.
A performance review process for secretaries general has been approved and will be in place by January 2016.
A revised disciplinary code has been drafted and will now be subject to the normal consultation procedures.
Open recruitment campaigns have been held for a number of grades in the civil service.
These are for principal, assistant principal, administrative officer, executive officer and clerical officer grades.
Department of Public Expenditure and Reform official Dr Orlaigh Quinn said that a number of new graduates had also been taken on, and 80 graduates were going through a new graduate development programme.
Minister Howlin said that they were moving away from the "crude" recruitment embargo and that would be wound down entirely this year.
The minister said that one of the things they were trying to do was to "professionalise the civil service".
He gave the example that in the case of a human resource manager, it would not be a case that someone would be promoted into that role, rather someone with the relevant qualifications and training would be recruited to that position.
A civil service wide employee engagement survey was piloted by more than 700 staff and this will be issued to all civil servants by the end of September.
Other areas where there have been changes include the development of a common corporate governance standard for all government departments and offices.
This is being finalised following public consultation.
New performance reviews developed
A new performance review for assistant secretaries has been developed and will be piloted by four government departments this year.
The first mobility policy for senior managers at principal level has been agreed and the first moves are expected to take place within the next three months.
It is already in place at the assistant secretary grade and 12 people have availed of it.
Minister Howlin said he did not think it was healthy that some civil servants only ever work in the department they started in, and he said it was important that there is movement across the civil service generally.
Since the Irish National Economic Evaluation Service was established three years ago, 90 graduate economists have been recruited.
According to department official Robert Watt, the plan is to increase this number to up to 400 in the coming years.
Mr Watt said at the moment a large number of the graduate economists were based in the Departments of Public Expenditure and Reform and in the Department of Finance where they were being trained, but that they would be allocated to other departments.
Minister Howlin described how under the service all government departments would have "a cadre of trained economic thinkers to stress test policy in its formation".
"One of the criticisms at the time of the economic collapse was that there wasn't enough economic analysis of policies," Mr Howlin said.
"An important innovation in this is that they [Irish National Economic Evaluation Service] can produce their own policies away from Government and produce their own independent papers, which might not be in agreement with government strategy."
A civil service customer satisfaction survey was completed by 2,000 participants in the months from April to June.
According to the media briefing, 77% said they were satisfied with the customer experience, 83% said the service "exceeded expectations".
An Informations and Communications Technology strategy to deliver better outcomes and efficiency has been published and is currently being implemented.
A chief human resources officer for the civil service has been appointed.
Eleven open policy debates were held on a number of policy issues including education reform, the labour market and future investment in early years of education.
Nine more open policy debates are scheduled for 2015.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:14:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cowen's answers 'unconvincing' says Ross</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0708/713468-banking-inquiry-brian-cowen-reaction/</Link>
        <Description>Independent TD Shane Ross has said the evidence seems to suggest that there is some sort of a contradiction and Brian Cowen's answers at the Banking Inquiry are somewhat "unconvincing".</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday 08 July 2015 23.14
Brian Cowen has been before the Banking Inquiry today covering his time as taoiseach
Independent TDShane Ross has said theevidence seems to suggest that there is some sort of a contradiction and former taoiseachBrian Cowen's answers at the Banking Inquiry are somewhat "unconvincing".
Mr Ross told RT'sNews At One that Mr Cowen's answers were "opaque" andit will be left to the committee to judge.
He said MrCowen's performance was different from last week, saying he came out fighting then, but, today, was more subdued and less convincing.
Mr Ross said that it will never be possible for anyone to contradict whether he overruled, or persuaded Brian Lenihan and he questioned why they had not agreed anything in advance.
Meanwhile, Fianna Fil's Timmy Dooley defended Mr Cowen's performance before the Banking Inquiry.
Speaking on the same programme. Mr Dooley said MrCowen and other members of the former government had made it clear they are preparted to participate in this inquiry to the fullest extent possible.
However, he said in his view this had been a politically motivated inquiry from the very start, which was orchestrated to allow for "political point scoring."
MrDooley said he believed MrCowen had answered questions fully and to his satisfaction and had indicated from the very start he was prepared to come before the committee and deal with it openly and honestly.
He said he detected a change in tone in the committee this week, with the attempt by certain members "to make political charges and present them as fact" less evident.
Speaking on RT's Six One News, Mr Dooley said that the former Taoiseach is setting out the context in which decisions were made, adding that he gave a good explanation around the guarantee and the limited nature of it.
He said thatBrian Cowen is never too worried about optics, or outer spin and it is clear from his evidence that he was trying to manage the situation at the time, rather than focusing on the political impact.
Mr Dooley said that Mr Cowen made it very clear that when issues around governance at Anglo were made at a later stage he had no problem, then, moving towards nationalism.
Conor Lenihan, who was a Fianna Fil TD and Minister of State at the time of the events being considered at the inquiry, has said that today's evidence is broadly in line of what we understand of that period.
He toldRTthere is no doubtthere was a difference of opinion about the nationalisation versus the broad guarantee that was given in relation to Anglo, buthe does not believeit was a serious dispute of opinion.
Mr Lenihan saidPatrick Honohan introduced the idea of Brian Lenihan being overruled by the then- taoiseach Brian Cowenbutdiscussions between ministers are often a great deal more subtle than a case of one person overruling another.
He said Mr Cowen is correct when he saidthe least injurious option was entertained in relation to the guarantee, saying it was not an ideal solution to the difficulties being faced at that time, but it was the only one that could effectively be used to protect the public and protect the depositors.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
