<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sciencedaily">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:55:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First real-life trial finds oral cholera vaccine protects against endemic disease, could speed up global control efforts</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/NlDfQhIuBsM/150708205538.htm</Link>
        <Description>An oral cholera vaccine (Shanchol) given as part of routine health services is safe and protects against severe cholera in children and adults in urban Bangladesh where the disease is endemic, according to the first real-life trial of this vaccine. The findings lend support to the use of the vaccine in routine mass vaccination programs to help to control cholera in endemic countries.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:55:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mothers who smoke, give birth preterm more than triple their CVD risk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/D4lWwzK3ssY/150708205528.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mothers who smoke and have a preterm birth more than triple their risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD), according to research in more than 900,000 mothers. The researchers also discovered that CVD risk was even greater in smoking mothers with more severe or recurrent preterm births.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:18:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A little jolt helps the brain get back on track</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/K1UQ7DwKUPM/150708181836.htm</Link>
        <Description>Applying mild electrical stimulation to an area of the brain associated with cognitive control helps people with schizophrenia recognize errors and adjust their behavior to avoid them.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:17:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spawning frequency regulates species population networks on coral reefs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YrS4982h1L0/150708181719.htm</Link>
        <Description>Releasing larvae more often is beneficial for a species' network, new research on tropical coral reef ecosystems shows. The study on reproductive strategies is critical to assess the conservation of coral reef ecosystems worldwide.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:17:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cost of low-risk childbirth varies widely among hospitals</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ng4_lFS97hw/150708181717.htm</Link>
        <Description>The cost of having a baby can vary by almost $10,000 in the United States, depending on which hospital is chosen, researchers have found. Childbirth is the leading cause of hospital admission in the United States.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:17:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Surfer-shaped waves found in near-Earth space</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Tb-7b72KHJ8/150708181714.htm</Link>
        <Description>The universe overflows with repeating patterns. From the smallest cells to the largest galaxies, scientists are often rewarded by observing similar patterns in vastly different places. One such pattern is the iconic surfer's waves seen on the ocean - a series of curled hills moving steadily in one direction. The shape has a simple cause. A fast fluid, say wind, moving past a slower one, say water, naturally creates this classic shape. Named Kelvin-Helmholtz waves in the late 1800s after their discoverers, these waves have since been discovered all over the universe: in clouds, in the atmospheres of other planets, and on the sun. Now two recently published articles highlight these shapely waves at the boundaries of near-Earth space.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 01:17:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New psoriasis drug is more effective than current treatment</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/eFothI66tN8/150708181711.htm</Link>
        <Description>A phase II clinical trial shows that a new psoriasis drug called guselkumab has greater efficacy than the current standard of care for the chronic skin condition. Psoriasis is an immune-mediated disease that causes itchy, dry and red skin. It also increases a patient's risk for depression, heart disease and diabetes, among other conditions. The disease affects nearly 3 percent of the world's population.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:05:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Countries have boundaries, but fish do not</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/zk3MwgSA9L8/150708160534.htm</Link>
        <Description>Many species transcend political boundaries, so countries must work together on environmental management practices, marine science researchers argue in a new paper.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:05:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Phthalates: 'Safer' replacements for harmful chemical in plastics may be as risky to human health</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Gse7_9jYggM/150708160531.htm</Link>
        <Description>According to a new series of studies, two chemicals increasingly used during manufacturing to strengthen plastic wrap, soap, cosmetics, and processed food containers have been linked to a rise in risk of high blood pressure and diabetes in children and adolescents.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:05:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Long-term effects of type 2 diabetes on the brain, thinking</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YTIov6_Gx3c/150708160528.htm</Link>
        <Description>In just two years, people with type 2 diabetes experienced negative changes in their ability to regulate blood flow in the brain, which was associated with lower scores on tests of cognition skills and their ability to perform their daily activities, according to a new study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:04:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why social workers aren't discussing religion, spirituality with clients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/bzy5Tdc5ti0/150708160449.htm</Link>
        <Description>Licensed clinical social workers, who account for the largest number of clinically trained helping professionals, believe that discussions about their clients' religion and spirituality can often lead to improved health and mental health, but practitioners are not integrating these conversations into their counseling sessions.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:12:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stratospheric accomplice for Santa Ana winds and California wildfires</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/vEZ8X0G16Y0/150708151231.htm</Link>
        <Description>Southern Californians and writers love to blame the hot, dry Santa Ana winds for tense, ugly moods, and the winds have long been associated with destructive wildfires. Now, a new study finds that on occasion, the winds have an accomplice with respect to fires, at least: Natural atmospheric events known as stratospheric intrusions, which bring extremely dry air from the upper atmosphere down to the surface, adding to the fire danger effects of the Santa Anas, and exacerbating some air pollution episodes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:12:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Disrupting cells' 'powerhouses' can lead to tumor growth, study finds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/9JbM0zBcuGA/150708151227.htm</Link>
        <Description>A study implicates defects in mitochondria, the energy-production centers of cells, as playing a key role in the transition from normal to cancerous. In their report, researchers note that looking for defects in cytochrome oxidase C could be a biomarker for cancer screening.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:12:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Male koalas raise their voices to avoid conflict</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/JiaEunLmzgc/150708151225.htm</Link>
        <Description>A team of international scientists has tracked the love lives of koalas, uncovering some curious behaviors and finding that male koalas make their distinct bellows to avoid confrontation with competitors.The researchers have mapped what they believe to be the first-look inside the social system of a large group of wild koalas at St. Bees Island near Rockhampton, Queensland, Australia.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:10:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New horned dinosaur reveals evolution of nose horn in Triceratops family</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ISb9Ah9MEIQ/150708151035.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have discovered a striking new species of horned dinosaur based on fossils collected from a bone bed in southern Alberta, Canada. Wendiceratops pinhornensis was approximately 6 meters long and weighed more than a ton. It lived about 79 million years ago, making it one of the oldest known members of the family of large-bodied horned dinosaurs that includes the famous Triceratops, the Ceratopsidae.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:10:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gene therapy restores hearing in deaf mice</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ypggOBircQs/150708151031.htm</Link>
        <Description>Using gene therapy, researchers have restored hearing in mice with a genetic form of deafness. More than 70 different genes are known to cause deafness when mutated. The scientists focused on a gene called TMC1 because it is a common cause of genetic deafness, accounting for 4 to 8 percent of cases, and encodes a protein that plays a central role in hearing, helping convert sound into electrical signals that travel to the brain.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:10:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Social engagement aids disaster preparedness</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-IUGmHCOHu8/150708151025.htm</Link>
        <Description>Community participation and strong social networks can aid preparedness to natural disaster such as tsunamis in vulnerable regions, shows new research conducted in the south of Thailand.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:10:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crowdsourcing brain data</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/b4sHFf2cwhQ/150708151020.htm</Link>
        <Description>Crowdsourcing brain data with hundreds of adults in a short period of time could be a new frontier in neuroscience and lead to new insights about the brain, neuroscientists have shown.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:43:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wearable electronics: Tiny wires could provide a big energy boost</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/jWXIh28ON4Y/150708144346.htm</Link>
        <Description>Wearable electronic devices for health and fitness monitoring are a rapidly growing area of consumer electronics; one of their biggest limitations is the capacity of their tiny batteries to deliver enough power to transmit data. Now, researchers have found a promising new approach to delivering the short but intense bursts of power needed by such small devices.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:15:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deaths attributed to low levels of education: Lack of education as deadly as smoking</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/KPLk0V7Jqns/150708141559.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study estimates the number of deaths that can be linked to differences in education, and finds that variation in the risk of death across education levels has widened considerably.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:15:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Remediating abandoned, inner city buildings reduces crime, violence in surrounding areas</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/4KRS76ecI_I/150708141556.htm</Link>
        <Description>Fixing up abandoned buildings in the inner city doesn’t just eliminate eyesores, it can also significantly reduce crime and violence, including gun assaults, researchers report in the first study to demonstrate the direct impact of building remediation efforts on crime.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:15:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Targeting bacteria in the gut might help burn, trauma patients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/041D5prHO3s/150708141552.htm</Link>
        <Description>Burn patients experience dramatic changes in the 100 trillion bacteria inside the gastrointestinal tract, research shows. The findings of a new study has now shown that there was an increase in potentially harmful bacteria, and decrease in beneficial bacteria. The findings suggest that burn patients might benefit from treatment with probiotics.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:14:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drug candidate significantly reduces HIV reactivation rate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/kexES_ppj58/150708141446.htm</Link>
        <Description>Unlike other antiretroviral therapies, a natural compound called Cortistatin A reduces residual levels of HIV virus from infected dormant cells, establishing a near-permanent state of latency and greatly diminishing the virus' capacity for reactivation, scientists report.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:39:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seafloor hot springs a significant source of iron in the oceans</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/wsaIswLwP2s/150708133904.htm</Link>
        <Description>A two-month voyage tracking a deep current flowing from one of the most active underwater volcanoes on Earth proves that iron released from hydrothermal vents travels thousands of miles, providing a significant source of iron to support life in the broader oceans.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Biggest explosions in the universe powered by strongest magnets</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/3Dn2oe5MpNk/150708133900.htm</Link>
        <Description>Observations have for the first time demonstrated a link between a very long-lasting burst of gamma rays and an unusually bright supernova explosion. The results show that the supernova was not driven by radioactive decay, as expected, but was instead powered by the decaying super-strong magnetic fields around an exotic object called a magnetar.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:38:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Volcanic eruptions that changed human history</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/KHVguppoOvs/150708133858.htm</Link>
        <Description>It is well known that large volcanic eruptions contribute to climate variability. A new study uses new evidence found in both ice cores and corresponding tree rings to show the timing and associated radiative forcing of nearly 300 individual volcanic eruptions extending as far back as the early Roman period.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:16:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Panel outlines new diagnostic criteria for central nervous system disorder</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/UEuk1v17OJg/150708131643.htm</Link>
        <Description>New diagnostic criteria have been introduced for neuromyelitis optica, now called neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder, which is an inflammatory disease of the central nervous system that is sometimes mistaken for multiple sclerosis.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:16:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blood test could identify diabetes decades before it develops</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/kFMi134al8A/150708131640.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists show for the first time that a small molecule circulates in the blood of people who are in the early stages of type 1 diabetes. A simple blood test could detect this biological marker years, maybe decades, before symptoms develop.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:16:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Treating breast cancer with progesterone could aid survival</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/JheSZUlMPtY/150708131638.htm</Link>
        <Description>A special technique where breast cancer cells are “rescued” for research has been developed by researchers. Coupled with advanced scientific technologies, this has provided a unique insight into the hormone regulation of breast cancers, which is expected to lead to new treatments for the disease.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:14:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bonelike 3-D silicon synthesized for potential use with medical devices</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/DyqHDMeZ3pI/150708131448.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new approach for better integrating medical devices with biological systems has been developed by scientists with the first skeleton-like silicon spicules ever prepared via chemical processes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:14:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brain activity changes after cognitive rehabilitation, TBI study shows</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/neJB-jMoq_8/150708131446.htm</Link>
        <Description>Results of a trail demonstrate for the first time significant changes in cerebral activation after memory retraining in individuals with TBI.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:46:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Probiotics - for plants</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/RExL-5CSzfU/150708124612.htm</Link>
        <Description>In plants, beneficial bacteria and fungi are endophytes. Scientists have known for decades that plants like legumes (peas, beans, and lentils) have beneficial bacteria in nodules attached to their roots. These bacteria "fix" vital nitrogen, turning it into a form the plant can easily use. However, researchers have recently found some nitrogen-fixing bacteria actually live inside plant tissue--in the leaves, stems, and roots -- with impressive results.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:41:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Intrahepatic cholestasis of pregnancy linked to liver cancer, other diseases later in life</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/TpKq1JI16R4/150708124130.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a new study of more than 125,000 pregnant women, researchers found that the risk of hepatobiliary cancer and immune-mediated and cardiovascular diseases later in life is higher in women with intrahepatic cholestasis of pregnancy (ICP) than in women without this condition.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:33:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Patent filings by women have risen fastest in academia, finds study</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/KqYyI4hssEM/150708123336.htm</Link>
        <Description>The number of women across the globe filing patents with the US Patent and Trade Office over the past 40 years has risen fastest within academia compared to all other sectors of the innovation economy, according to a new study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:33:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lymphoma: How the tumor escapes the immune response</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ST3H4OkKeqc/150708123334.htm</Link>
        <Description>Natural killer cells of the immune system can fend off malignant lymphoma cells and thus are considered a promising therapeutic approach. However, in the direct vicinity of the tumor they lose their effect. Scientists have now elucidated which mechanisms block the natural killer cells and how this blockade could be lifted.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:33:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Reform to resident physicians' work hours does not improve surgical patient safety</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/k0c9CsQjSlA/150708123332.htm</Link>
        <Description>Work-hour restrictions for resident physicians, revised nationally four years ago largely to protect patients against physician trainees' fatigue-related errors, have not had the desired effect of lowering postoperative complication rates in several common surgical specialties, according to new study results.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:33:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why do puddles stop spreading?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ZzkbQC7AI5c/150708123326.htm</Link>
        <Description>When you spill a bit of water onto a tabletop, the puddle spreads -- and then stops, leaving a well-defined area of water with a sharp boundary. There's just one problem: The formulas scientists use to describe such a fluid flow say that the water should just keep spreading endlessly. Everyone knows that's not the case -- but why? This mystery has now been solved -- and while this phenomenon might seem trivial, the finding's ramifications could be significant.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:33:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Messages of individual blame for black Americans perpetuate racial inequality</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1iQEi87TOls/150708123323.htm</Link>
        <Description>Why is it that messages about black absentee fathers, such as Obama's 2008 Father's Day address, are so pervasive in society? A new article suggests that such messages align with broader beliefs that black Americans place too much blame on 'the system' and instead need to hear messages that encourage individual responsibility. A consequence of that, the researchers say, is that they perpetuate structural racial inequalities.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:33:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Glimmer of hope for patients with leukodystrophies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Li2JMabe4Bg/150708123321.htm</Link>
        <Description>Leukodystrophies are deadly neurodegenerative diseases that affect one in 7,000 children and remain incurable. These genetic diseases attack myelin or the 'insulating rubber sheath' surrounding neurons, which leads to deteriorating health for affected children. Today, nearly 20 types of leukodystrophies have been characterized, but many other forms remain undefined, leaving nearly 40 percent of families awaiting a diagnosis. Montreal researchers discovered a new crucial gene associated with these orphan diseases.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:33:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hybrid cells cause chaos around cancers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/FftuqVmQnIw/150708123319.htm</Link>
        <Description>Like all cells, those in tumors need access to the body's fine network of blood vessels to bring them oxygen and carry away waste. Tumors have learned to game the process called angiogenesis in which new vessels sprout from existing ones, like branches from a tree. Now, researchers have built a simulation to understand how cancerous tumors manipulate blood-vessel growth.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:33:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Army suicide attempts, risk profiles for enlisted soldiers, officers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ZpTU7yhyNHI/150708123317.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new analysis of US Army data details rates of suicide attempts during the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq, and researchers have identified risk factors for suicide attempts by enlisted soldiers and officers, according to an article.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:15:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hastening the dawn of hybrid rocket engines</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/sYynJxB93cU/150708111544.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hybrid rocket fuel research by mechanical engineers could hasten the day when a simpler, safer hybrid engine propels space missions.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:14:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bricks to build 'an Earth' found in every planetary system</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/7U6mNwq-Dug/150708111441.htm</Link>
        <Description>Earth-like planets orbiting other stars in the Milky Way are three times more likely to have the same type of minerals as Earth than astronomers had previously thought. In fact, conditions for making the building blocks of Earth-like rocks are ubiquitous throughout the Milky Way. </Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:12:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Medication could improve gastric bypass results, study suggests</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gO_aEpoDBO0/150708111255.htm</Link>
        <Description>New findings about the mechanisms involved -- or not involved -- in the effects of the most common form of bariatric surgery suggest that combining surgery with a specific type of medication could augment the benefits of the procedure.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:12:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Learning categorical information gives children a feeling of deja vu</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/mi1dowa7qgg/150708111253.htm</Link>
        <Description>During development, children must learn both broad facts about the world (that dogs have four legs, for example) and information that is more specific (that the family dog is scared of snow). While research in developmental psychology suggests that young children should have an easier time learning specific, concrete facts, a new study reveals that they learn general facts so effortlessly that they often can't tell that they learned anything new at all.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:12:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cost-saving ultrasound degassing now possible in continuous processing of aluminum melt</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/XkfpNYzuJsI/150708111251.htm</Link>
        <Description>Having proved that ultrasound degassing of molten aluminum alloys is cleaner, greener and cheaper than current methods, a team of scientists has now taken the breakthrough a step further.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:12:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Production of iPS cells: Discovery of the fifth element</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YCPeCKYdT14/150708111248.htm</Link>
        <Description>Since 2006, research has succeeded in generating, from specialized adult cells, induced pluripotent cells (iPS cells), with huge potential applications, particularly for regenerative medicine. However, the process has still not been completely mastered. Now a molecule that may favor the production of these induced stem cells has been discovered by researchers.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:12:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A black hole under the gravitational lens</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/0VoNX-RGgp4/150708111244.htm</Link>
        <Description>Turbulent processes take place close to supermassive black holes, which lurk in the centers of nearly all galaxies. They swallow up matter flowing in from the outside while at the same time producing so-called gas jets which shoot out into space in two opposite directions. Researchers have now succeeded in localizing the origin of the high-energy gamma radiation in such a jet: it apparently originates very close to the black hole. This discovery was made possible by a micro-gravitational lens effect that occurs by chance and selectively amplifies the light from different regions close to the black hole like a magnifying glass. An unusual observation method uncovers processes near the event horizon of a distant, massive monster.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:12:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Keeping the smells of onions, garlic and other stinky foods under wraps</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/hioaPVozrwc/150708111242.htm</Link>
        <Description>Some of the world's most popular foods and seasonings can also be the smelliest -- think garlic, onions, certain cheeses and the notoriously stinky Asian durian fruit. No amount of plastic wrap seems to contain their stench, but now scientists have developed a new film that could finally neutralize the odors of even the most pungent fare.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:10:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Impact of smoking on California's economy in decline at $18.1 billion per year</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/jJMeAk1GCTA/150708111015.htm</Link>
        <Description>Results of a study on the cost of smoking in California, one of the first US states to implement a comprehensive tobacco control program, have been released. Researchers estimated expenditures for smoking-attributable costs (healthcare, lost productivity from illness, and lost productivity from premature mortality) for the year 2009. The total cost came to $18.1 billion, amounting to $487 per California resident and $4,603 per smoker.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:10:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Examining the neonicotinoid threat to honey bees</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/IevxJ5DwpQA/150708111012.htm</Link>
        <Description>The decline of honey bees has been a major concern globally for the past decade. One of the factors that could be contributing to the decline is the use of insecticides -- specifically neonicotinoids -- that persist in rivers and streams. Researchers now report that although sunlight plays an important role in degrading pollutants, its effects on neonicotinoids can diminish dramatically even in shallow water.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:10:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Peppermint oil and cinnamon could help treat and heal chronic wounds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/vRVakAC9nAg/150708111009.htm</Link>
        <Description>Infectious colonies of bacteria called biofilms that develop on chronic wounds and medical devices can cause serious health problems and are tough to treat. But now scientists have found a way to package antimicrobial compounds from peppermint and cinnamon in tiny capsules that can both kill biofilms and actively promote healing. The researchers say the new material could be used as a topical antibacterial treatment and disinfectant.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:10:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>3-D views reveal intricacies in intestines that could lead to discoveries for IBD</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/S27LYMj23ik/150708111006.htm</Link>
        <Description>A technology whose roots date to the 1800s has the potential to offer an extraordinary new advantage to modern-day medicine. Scientists detail how stereomicroscopy can provide physicians an invaluable diagnostic tool in assessing issues within the gastrointestinal tract.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 18:10:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vaccines: Practices, hesitancy among general physicians in France</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/mOIAQzLQVsk/150708111003.htm</Link>
        <Description>Authors present and analyze the attitudes and practices of over 1,500 general physicians in France, in a context of distrust toward vaccines.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:07:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New method to develop more efficient drugs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/UsHU5NMjQlw/150708100738.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new approach to develop highly-potent drugs has been uncovered by researchers, which could overcome current shortcomings of low drug efficacy and multi-drug resistance in the treatment of cancer as well as viral and bacterial infections, a new report suggests.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:07:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Recent agricultural pest stems from one fly generation's big genetic shift, evolution study finds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/3ruwbTIBPtk/150708100734.htm</Link>
        <Description>The genes of a fruit fly that has plagued American apple producers for more than 150 years is the result of an extremely rapid evolutionary change, a new study reveals.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:07:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Think twice before ordering your next steak</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/8MyBxX0wSYA/150708100701.htm</Link>
        <Description>High consumption of livestock products could have serious consequences for people and the environment, according to a recent article. The article emphasizes that the demand for livestock-based foods has soared over the last few decades. The article’s authors emphasize that, if left unchecked, worldwide meat consumption and production could lead to species loss, climate risks, poverty, and even social breakdown as large meat-producing companies continue to displace small-scale farmers.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:06:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IT-based concepts for effective coordination of public authorities, general population</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/W1VzqtwNFL0/150708100658.htm</Link>
        <Description>To get a handle on crisis situations you need volunteers from the general population. A new project investigates how volunteers’ help can be incorporated into the crisis management efforts of public bodies. Research is focusing on IT supported and systematic integration of existing structures such as associations, companies and citizens’ initiatives.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:06:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Potential treatment identified for a rare but deadly form of lymphoma in HIV patients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/EZBr11w9t80/150708100622.htm</Link>
        <Description>A potential treatment for a rare but previously incurable form of lymphoma that is observed primarily in patients with HIV/AIDS infection has been identified by researchers.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:06:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Record-breaking heavy rainfall events increased under global warming</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/C7MpLQub2n0/150708100619.htm</Link>
        <Description>Heavy rainfall events setting ever new records have been increasing strikingly in the past thirty years. While before 1980, multi-decadal fluctuations in extreme rainfall events are explained by natural variability, a team of scientists detected a clear upward trend in the past few decades towards more unprecedented daily rainfall events.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
