<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Guinea ex-junta leader indicted over stadium massacre</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/Guinea-exjunta-leader-indicted-over-stadium-massacre</Link>
        <Description>CONAKRY (Reuters) - Guinean authorities have indicted former military leader Moussa Dadis Camara over a massacre at a stadium in the capital in 2009 in which soldiers are accused of killing at least 157 people, a spokesman for his party said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
CONAKRY (Reuters) - Guinean authorities have indicted former military leader Moussa Dadis Camara over a massacre at a stadium in the capital in 2009 in which soldiers are accused of killing at least 157 people, a spokesman for his party said on Thursday.
Camara's indictment could throw into doubt his participation in elections set for Oct. 11 at which he is set to run for the newly created Patriotic Forces for Democracy and Development (FPDD) party against President Alpha Conde.
Camara ruled the West African country for almost a year after seizing power in a coup in 2008 and remains popular in his native Forest region of southeastern Guinea.
His reputation was tarnished, however, by the massacre in September 2009 against protesters who opposed his candidacy for presidential elections in 2010. Human rights groups and witnesses say at least 100 women were raped.
"The president of our party has in fact been indicted. He confirmed this to me during a telephone conversation that I had with him this afternoon," Maxime Monimou, spokesman for the FPDD, told Reuters.
"He told me that he had a first audience with the judges who read out the charges against him," he said. "Dadis himself said that he is ready to respond to the judges convocation. He is very calm as we are in the FPDD."
A source close to Camara's family said he had met two judges from Guinea.
Camara was charged in Burkina Faso where he has lived in exile since resigning the presidency. He is recovering from an assassination attempt. Prosecutors in Burkina Faso could not be reached for comment.
Two Guinean magistrates travelled to the Burkina Faso capital Ouagadougou on Monday. Last week, the prosecutor of the International Criminal Court Fatou Bensouda visited Guinea in connection with the affair.
(Additional reporting by Mathieu Bonkoungou in Ouagadougou; Writing by Matthew Mpoke Bigg; Editing by Lisa Shumaker)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>China suspends trains, closes schools as typhoons approach</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/China-suspends-trains-closes-schools-as-typhoons-approach</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - Chinese authorities have suspended train services, closed schools and bought trawlers back to port before two typhoons in the south and east of the country make landfall later this week, state media said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 9:30:03 AM
Updated:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 9:30:10 AM
China suspends trains, closes schools as typhoons approach
to win cash or gadget!
BEIJING (Reuters) - Chinese authorities have suspended train services, closed schools and bought trawlers back to port before two typhoons in the south and east of the country make landfall later this week, state media said.
Typhoon Linfa is expected to make landfall in the southern province of Guangdong on Thursday. The more powerful Typhoon Chan-Hom could land further up the coast in Fujian or Zhejiang province late on Friday, Xinhua news agency said.
China's commercial capital, Shanghai, will stop all passenger trains running south along the coast on Friday and Saturday, the report said.
Guangdong province has closed primary and middle schools in 15 counties, it said.
Typhoons are common at this time of year in the South China Sea, picking up strength from the warm waters before dissipating over land.
(Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Paul Tait)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Banks face closures, bailout or not - sources</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/Banks-to-remain-closed-until-Monday--state-television</Link>
        <Description>(Reuters) - Following is the latest news on Greece&amp;#39;s debt crisis after euro zone leaders set Athens a deadline of the end of the week to come up with convincing reform proposals. All times are in BST.</Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
(Reuters) - Following is the latest news on Greece's debt crisis after euro zone leaders set Athens a deadline of the end of the week to come up with convincing reform proposals. All times are in BST.
0142 - Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe says he will work with Group of Seven countries and other Asian countries to ensure economic and finance market stability as the euro zone grapples with Greece's debt crisis.
2144 - Some large Greek banks may have to be shut and taken over by stronger rivals as part of a restructuring of the sector that would follow any bailout of the country, European officials tell Reuters.
2008 - IMF chief Christine Lagarde reiterates that Greece's massive debt will need restructuring, something Germany is resisting. "Greece is in a situation of acute crisis, which needs to be addressed seriously and promptly," she tells the Brookings Institution think-tank in Washington.
2003 -  Greek banks will remain closed for the rest of the week and a 60-euro per day ATM withdrawal limit will remain in force, Greek state television reported.
1941 - Greece's government will be encouraged to deliver a "precise plan" for its finances to inspire confidence among euro zone currency partners, says French President Francois Hollande
1900 - Fed officials need more signs of strengthening U.S. economy before raising interest rates, according to minutes of June Fed meeting, cite Greece's debt crisis as serious concern
1710 - The European Stability Mechanism asks EU experts and the IMF to review Greece's request for a loan
1707 - Luxembourg Finance Minister Pierre Gramegna tells parliament that euro zone finance ministers would ask the European Commission and European Central Bank to review Greece's bailout request
1653 - European Central Bank policy setters keep the level of emergency assistance to Greek banks steady, a person familiar with the matter says
1536 - French Prime Minister Manuel Valls says basics of a Greek deal have been laid out, a deal is within grasp
1434 - Reuters polling shows for first time economists saying Greece's exit from euro zone is more likely than not
1423- U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew says Greek meltdown would be geopolitical mistake
1314- Greece will issue a ministerial decree later on Wednesday to extend a bank holiday that has already lasted for eight working days, a government official says
1310 - Spanish Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy says the mood music coming from Greece concerning its debt negotiations is more positive than before
1304- Russian Economy Minister Alexei Ulyukayev says financial aid for Greece is not a subject for the BRICS summit
1247 - German finance ministry spokesman rejects measures that reduce the current value of Greek debt such as debt reprofiling
1239 - European Banking Authority says remains vigilant but markets coping well so far with Greek uncertainty
1230 - Greece proposes to implement as early as next week tax and pension reform measures, letter shows
1225 - Greece requested a three-year loan from the European Stability Mechanism bailout fund but didn't specify volume of financing sought, a euro zone source tells Reuters
1225 - European Council President Donald Tusk says without unity on Greece we will in four days wake up in a different Europe
1222 - If Greece and its creditors don't agree by Sunday to start talks on third bailout, it will be necessary to think about other options, a spokesman for the German finance ministry says
1217 - Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras tells EU Parliament he will come up with very specific proposals on Thursday
1115 - Technical experts will review Greece's request for an ESM loan on Wednesday but there will be no conference call among euro zone ministers, a spokesman says
1056 - Russia is not in a position to help solve the Greek debt crisis, and the EU should resolve it on its on, the chief executive of Russia's second largest bank VTB says
1047 - Greece lodges formal request for bailout loan with the euro zone's special support fund, a spokesman for the European Stability Mechanism says
1020 - European Central Bank Governing Council member Ewald Nowotny says hard to imagine that ECB council could increase emergency liquidity for Greece
1004 - Bank of Italy and ECB member Ignazio Visco says ECB will do what it can to contain financial and economic consequences of Greek crisis.
1003 - Greece successfully rolls over T-bills to refinance a maturing six-month issue
0920 - Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras tells European Parliament says will present details proposal to EU in next 2-3 days.
0912 - Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras tells European Parliament the referendum gave him a mandate to find a socially just and economically sustainable solution to end the crisis.
0847 - EU Economics Commissioner Pierre Moscovici tells BBC radio an agreement between Greece and its euro zone partners is still possible.
JULY 7
0047 - Euro zone members give Greece until the end of the week to come up with a proposal for sweeping reforms in return for loans
2235 - Merkel says she hopes to have sufficient reform proposals from Greece this week to be able to ask the German parliament to approve negotiations on a new long-term aid programme for Athens. If the reform list was adequate and Greece took some prior actions to enact first measures, she says she is sure that short-term finance can be provided to help Athens over its immediate funding needs.
2130 - Austria's finance minister says Greece's request for financial aid from the European Stability Mechanism (ESM) is so far very vague.
2120 - Summit over; Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi says a final meeting on Greece, involving all 28 EU leaders, will take place on Sunday.
2032 - Greek banks could start to run out of cash over the next two days if creditors do not agree to a new aid deal, two sources familiar with the country's financial system say.
1853 - Euro zone leaders could hold a further emergency summit on Sunday to approve a plan to aid Greece if creditor institutions are satisfied with a Greek loan application and reform plan, two senior EU sources say.
1815 - A Greek government official says Greece is asking its euro zone partners for an interim solution to its funding needs that would cover the rest of July while a long-term deal is sought.
1814 - Irish finance minister says the main elements of an agreement on Greece need to be in place by next Monday, and that the general impression is that a reprofiling of Greek debt would be acceptable.
1804 - White House says Obama has spoken to Tsipras and Merkel.
1745 - Prominent economists have called on German Chancellor Angela Merkel in an open letter to change her policy course and stop "force-feeding" the Greek people "never-ending austerity".
1732 - German bond yields fall by as much as 15 basis points to their lowest in nearly five weeks amid a rout in commodity markets and mounting doubts about Greece's future in the euro. Greek fears drive the biggest UK bond rally in over three years.
1718 - Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi says a deal with Greece can be found in the coming hours.
1654 - A Greek government official says proposals Athens made to creditors last week to unlock bailout funds still stand, although some improvements have been made.
1636 - French President Francois Hollande says immediate aid is available for Greece, but the onus is on Athens to make proposals. "Greece must make serious, credible proposals. We are waiting for them and they have already been announced. They must be fleshed out now. That's the issue for tonight."
1621 - A Greek government official says PM Tsipras spoke to U.S. President Barack Obama on Tuesday and briefed him on Greece's request for a rescue loan from its euro zone partners.
1613 - German Chancellor Angela Merkel says Greece must commit to reforms to secure new loans, and stresses that only days are left to secure a deal. "Without solidarity and reforms it's not possible to go where we want to go," she says. "It's not a matter of weeks but of a few days. We will see what the Greek prime minister will tell us."
1605 - Dutch PM Rutte says if Greece doesn't come up with a proposal soon, euro zone leaders won't be able to help.
(Compiled by Toby Chopra)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Japan&amp;#39;s Abe - will work with G7, other countries on Greece crisis</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/Japans-Abe--will-work-with-G7-other-countries-on-Greece-crisis</Link>
        <Description>TOKYO (Reuters) - Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe said on Thursday he will work with Group of Seven countries and other Asian countries to ensure economic and finance market stability as the euro zone grapples with Greece&amp;#39;s debt crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
TOKYO (Reuters) - Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe said on Thursday he will work with Group of Seven countries and other Asian countries to ensure economic and finance market stability as the euro zone grapples with Greece's debt crisis.
Abe, speaking at a seminar, also said excessive yen strength has been corrected due to economic policies he put in place when he took office in late 2012.
(Reporting by Stanley White; Editing by Kim Coghill)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>South African universities trail other BRICS</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/South-African-universities-trail-other-BRICS</Link>
        <Description>JOHANNESBURG (Reuters) - South Africa has eight of the top 15 universities in Africa but its higher learning institutions are rated as the worst performing among the BRICS emerging market nations, two separate reports released this week said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:23 AM
Updated:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:23 AM
South African universities trail other BRICS
to win cash or gadget!
JOHANNESBURG (Reuters) - South Africa has eight of the top 15 universities in Africa but its higher learning institutions are rated as the worst performing among the BRICS emerging market nations, two separate reports released this week said.
A study released by Times Higher Education rated the University of Cape Town as Africa's premier institution followed by University of Witwatersrand in Johannesburg.
But South Africa was ranked last in the World Economic Forum's 2015 report on the quality of maths and science education and 139th out of 143 countries in the overall quality of its education system.
The Times Higher Education report put Uganda's oldest and largest institution of higher learning, Makerere University, in third place in Africa, in a statement released on Thursday.
The Times rankings assess universities on their published research, reviews and academic papers between 2009 and 2013.
In a separate study released by QS University Rankings, South Africa did not rank highly among the top 10 institutions when compared to the other BRICS countries, Brazil, Russia, India and China.
Of the 404 BRICS institutions that were evaluated, the University of Cape Town was ranked 14th, five places lower than in 2014, and the University of Witwatersrand was 28th, with only four South African universities making it to the top 50.
(Reporting by Peroshni Govender; Editing by Ruth Pitchford)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Czech Republic willing to take in 1,500 migrants by 2017</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/Czech-Republic-willing-to-take-in-1500-migrants-by-2017</Link>
        <Description>PRAGUE (Reuters) - The Czech Republic is willing to accept 1,500 migrants by 2017, the government said on Wednesday, as European Union countries prepare more talks over how to share the growing influx.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:20 AM
Updated:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:21 AM
Czech Republic willing to take in 1,500 migrants by 2017
to win cash or gadget!
PRAGUE (Reuters) - The Czech Republic is willing to accept 1,500 migrants by 2017, the government said on Wednesday, as European Union countries prepare more talks over how to share the growing influx.
The number of migrants seeking protection in the EU soared by 68 percent in the first five months of 2015 compared with the year-earlier period, the bloc said on Wednesday.
The Czech Republic is one of several EU member states that have rejected a mandatory scheme to share migrants proposed by the European Commission, the EU executive.
Tomas Prouza, the Czech state secretary for EU affairs, said on Twitter the cabinet had agreed the Central European country would take in 1,100 migrants currently in Greece and Italy as well as another 400 from refugee camps outside the EU.
In June, EU leaders endorsed ways to counter the migration crisis in the Mediterranean by sharing 60,000 refugees and asylum seekers over the next two years, but failed to decide precise national commitments to take people in.
According to a plan to be considered at a meeting in Luxembourg on Thursday, 20,000 refugees would be resettled in Europe directly from their countries of origin or transit, such as Syrians escaping war or displaced in Lebanon or Jordan.
Another 40,000 asylum seekers already in Italy and Greece would be transferred to other EU countries.
(Reporting by Jason Hovet, editing by G Crosse)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>U.S. Air Force leader sees Russia as &amp;#39;biggest threat&amp;#39;</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/US-Air-Force-leader-sees-Russia-as-biggest-threat</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Russia is the biggest threat to U.S. national security and America must boost its military presence throughout Europe even as NATO allies face budget challenges and scale back spending, U.S. Air Force Secretary Deborah James said on Wednesday. </Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:15 AM
Updated:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:19 AM
U.S. Air Force leader sees Russia as 'biggest threat'
to win cash or gadget!
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Russia is the biggest threat to U.S. national security and America must boost its military presence throughout Europe even as NATO allies face budget challenges and scale back spending, U.S. Air Force Secretary Deborah James said on Wednesday.
"I do consider Russia to be the biggest threat," James told Reuters in an interview after a series of visits and meetings with U.S. allies across Europe, including Poland.
James said Washington was responding to Russia's recent "worrisome" actions by boosting its presence across Europe, and would continue rotational assignments of F-16 fighter squadrons.
"This is no time to in any way signal a lack of resolve in the face of these Russian actions," she said.
James said she was disappointed that only four of NATO's 28 members had thus far met the NATO target of spending 2 percent of gross domestic product on defence.
"This is not something that came up out of thin air. This is something that we as NATO members agreed to do. All of us need to be advocates," she said.
The top Air Force civilian leader acknowledged that Europe was facing difficult immigration and economic challenges at the moment, but said the NATO military alliance and associated commitments should be a clear priority.
Britain on Wednesday said it would commit to the 2 percent spending pledge for the next five years, which will raise the number of NATO allies meeting the spending goal to five in 2015.
Given the tensions, the Air Force is continuing its effort to reduce U.S. reliance on Russian RD-180 rocket engines for military and intelligence satellite launches, James said.
She said there were huge demands on U.S. Air Force assets now, given the tensions with Russia and the fight against Islamic State, but the Air Force was also working hard to defend its weapons systems and networks against growing cyber attacks.
James said her records were among those involved in a massive breach of personnel records held by the Office of Personnel Management that some U.S. officials have blamed on China. China denies any involvement in hacking U.S. databases.
James said the Air Force took a hard look at its cyber security immediately after the revelations and decided to redouble its efforts, although no new actions were needed.
She said the service was cataloguing weapons and IT systems to detect any possible vulnerabilities, while also working to set up 39 cyber security teams around the country.
(Reporting by Andrea Shalal; Editing by Leslie Adler)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Pope drinks tea mix including coca leaf on flight to Bolivia</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/Pope-drinks-tea-mix-including-coca-leaf-on-flight-to-Bolivia</Link>
        <Description>LA PAZ, Bolivia, July 8 (Reuters) - Pope Francis drank a tea of coca leaves, chamomile flower and anise seeds on the plane to Bolivia from Ecuador to ward off  altitude sickness upon arrival at the highest international airport in the world.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:13 AM
Updated:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:14 AM
Pope drinks tea mix including coca leaf on flight to Bolivia
to win cash or gadget!
LA PAZ, Bolivia, July 8 (Reuters) - Pope Francis drank a tea of coca leaves, chamomile flower and anise seeds on the plane to Bolivia from Ecuador to ward off  altitude sickness upon arrival at the highest international airport in the world.
Coca is the main ingredient for cocaine but people in the Andean region have chewed coca leaves or drank coca tea for centuries for its medicinal properties.
The flight attendant said the pope drank a mix called "Trimate," with the three ingredients. It was also offered to journalists on the flight.
The pope did not appear to have any difficulties when he walked off the plane and while he was reading his welcoming address. Francis is visiting three of the poorest countries in Latin America on a trip that will also include Paraguay.
A Bolivian minister said 10 days ago that Francis had told government officials that he would like to chew coca leaves when he visits. A Vatican spokesman said, however, that the Argentine pontiff would decide for himself.
At just over 4,000 meters (13,000 feet) above sea level, La Paz airport is actually located in the appropriately named El Alto ("The High One"), a satellite city perched on the plateau above La Paz.
Indigenous people, including Bolivia's first indigenous president Evo Morales, defend the use of coca and consider it a sacred plant.
For health reasons, the 78-year-old Francis, who lost part of one lung to disease when he was a young man, will be in La Paz - 3,650 meters (11,975 feet) above sea level - for only about four hours before moving on to Santa Cruz.
(Reporting by Philip Pullella; Writing by Sarah Marsh; Editing by Grant McCool)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Pope praises Bolivia&amp;#39;s reforms, pays tribute to slain priest</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/Popes-homecoming-tour-moves-from-Ecuador-to-Bolivia</Link>
        <Description>LA PAZ, Bolivia (Reuters) - Pope Francis arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday, praising the government of leftist President Evo Morales, the country&amp;#39;s first indigenous leader whose frosty relationship with the Catholic Church has begun to thaw under the Argentine pontiff&amp;#39;s papacy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:11 AM
Updated:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:13 AM
Pope praises Bolivia's reforms, pays tribute to slain priest
to win cash or gadget!
LA PAZ, Bolivia (Reuters) - Pope Francis arrived in Bolivia on Wednesday, praising the government of leftist President Evo Morales, the country's first indigenous leader whose frosty relationship with the Catholic Church has begun to thaw under the Argentine pontiff's papacy.
Morales has nationalized key industries such as oil and gas to finance social programmes that have slashed poverty in the Andean country, where animal sacrifices and pagan worship remain widely cherished. [ID:nL8N0ZI3I6]
Francis, Latin America's first pope, arrived from Ecuador at La Paz's El Alto airport, at over 4,000 meters (13,000 feet) above sea level, the highest international airport in the world.
Oxygen tanks are always at the ready for passengers to deal with altitude sickness brought on by the thin air.
Locals chew coca leaves and drink coca tea. Coca is the main ingredient for cocaine.
Aboard the plane, the pope drank a tea made of a mix of coca leaves, chamomile and anise seeds to ward off illness, a flight attendant said. [ID:nL1N0ZO2QF]
The pope, who lost part of one lung to an infection when he was a young man, will spend only about four hours in the La Paz, the seat of government, before moving on to the provincial city of Santa Cruz for the rest of his two-day stay.
He did not appear to have any difficulties as he left the plane, while he read his arrival speech, and on the ride to the center of the city for a private meeting with Morales.
"Bolivia is making important steps towards including broad sectors in the countrys economic, social and political life," Francis said in his arrival address, wearing a white poncho over his white cassock to warm him against the Andean wind.
Morales, an Aymara native and former coca grower, came to power in 2006 promising to govern in favor of the poor indigenous majority, marginalized by the ruling elite.
In his address to the pope, Morales, who had frequently clashed with Church officials in Bolivia before relations improved when Francis was elected in 2013, welcomed the pope as a homecoming hero.
"In many historic moments, the Church was used for domination, subjugation and oppression. Now the Bolivian people receive you with joy and hope," said Morales, wearing a dark suit with indigenous pattern embroidered around the lapels.
"We welcome you as the chief representative of the Catholic Church coming to support the liberation of our Bolivian peoples."
TRIBUTE TO SLAIN PRIEST
On his way into the center of La Paz, which lies in a bowl beneath mountain peaks, the pope was due to stop at a spot where the body of Jesuit Father Luis Espinal Camps was found in 1980. The priest, who was a strong supporter of the rights of miners, was tortured and murdered by paramilitaries.
"Let us pray for this brother of ours who was a victim of interests," the pope said, asking the roadside crowd to join him in a minute's silence.
Under Morales' brand of "indigenous socialism," Bolivia has vastly expanded the role of the state in the economy, nationalizing key industries and introduced socialist reforms to spread the wealth from a boom in gas exports.
  Bolivia's economy has tripled in size during the nine years under Morales, a prominent member of South America's leftist bloc, and the number of Bolivians living in extreme poverty has fallen to one in five from more than a third of the population of 10 million in 2006.
It remains, however, one of the poorest countries in the Americas. Francis urged Morales to be sure to blend economic growth with social justice.
"A growth which is merely material will always run the
risk of creating new divisions, of the wealth of some being built on the poverty of others," he said.
Morales, who was elected to a third term last October, has been more pragmatic than some of his closest Latin American allies on economic policy at home, winning him praise from some of the world financial institutions he has excoriated, such as the International Monetary Fund (IMF).
The pope, who has made defense of the poor and the planet major planks of his papacy, also praised the fact that the Bolivian constitution "recognizes the rights of individuals, minorities and the natural environment."
Francis flew into Bolivia from Quito, Ecuador, where he showed his sense of humor during the last few hours of his trip to that country, where he drew crowds totaling nearly 2 million people.
"I have a prepared script but I don't want to read it," said the 78-year-old pope to laughs from the crowd, before asking them to pray for him so that he would never forget where he came from.
"Do not fall into a spiritual Alzheimer's, do not forget!" Francis added in a totally improvised speech.
(Additional reporting Sarah Marsh in Santa Cruz, and Diego Ore in La Paz.; Editing Grant McCool, Richard Lough and Lisa Shumaker)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Despite peace talks breakthrough, Afghan leader under pressure at home</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/09/Despite-peace-talks-breakthrough-Afghan-leader-under-pressure-at-home</Link>
        <Description>KABUL (Reuters) - If Afghan President Ashraf Ghani was savouring inaugural peace talks with Taliban insurgents held in Pakistan on Wednesday, celebrations of the milestone he has worked so hard to reach may be short-lived.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:03 AM
Updated:                 Thursday July 9, 2015 MYT 8:30:06 AM
Despite peace talks breakthrough, Afghan leader under pressure at home
to win cash or gadget!
KABUL (Reuters) - If Afghan President Ashraf Ghani was savouring inaugural peace talks with Taliban insurgents held in Pakistan on Wednesday, celebrations of the milestone he has worked so hard to reach may be short-lived.
Back in Kabul, the 66-year-old faces growing discontent from lawmakers who are making life difficult on several fronts nine months after he took office.
The lower house of parliament is threatening to impeach Ghani's interior minister over his failure to stem violence by Islamist militants. Last week lawmakers rejected the president's third nominee for defence minister.
Casualties among Afghanistan's fledgling armed forces are on the rise, they are losing pockets of territory to insurgents and there are less than 10,000 foreign troops left to support them after most NATO soldiers withdrew last year.
Little wonder the president calls his "the most difficult job in the world."
Ghani's deputy spokesman, Sayed Zafar Hashemi, downplayed the political turmoil.
"There are problems in Afghanistan, and the environment can never be ideal for a leader," he said.
The Senate upper house of parliament has been on strike since Sunday, protesting that the government has failed to respond to members' concerns.
Another problem for Ghani is the lack of cohesion in his unity government, so-called because he and rival presidential candidate Abdullah Abdullah were convinced to share power after months of wrangling over a contested election last year.
"This government is absolutely lacking national unity," said Mohammad Mohaqiq, an influential figure representing the Hazara ethnic minority.
Leaders of Afghanistan's various ethnic groups, including Abdullah's powerful Tajik faction of "mujahideen", complain that Ghani favours his own Pashtun kin when it comes to filling key posts, an issue that has dogged Afghan politics for decades.
A senior diplomat in Kabul said that he had reached "a pessimistic low" over the government's survival prospects.
FEW REAL ALTERNATIVES
For now, a growing number of critics saying Ghani should go have few legal options other than blocking his agenda.
Removing an Afghan president is constitutionally complicated and would require new elections that few would relish after last year's political crisis that threatened to spill into violence.
But in Afghanistan, where some power brokers command well-armed factions, deep discontent is worrying.
Influential northern governor Atta Mohammad Noor, who last year issued veiled threats of a breakaway government, this week issued a list of "suggested" defence ministers after parliament rejected Ghani's latest nominee, Mohammad Masoom Stanekzai.
Atta's loyalists in parliament led a campaign against Stanekzai's nomination, joined by Uzbek lawmakers who are reportedly seeking a member of their own ethnicity as defence minister, said pro-Ghani parliamentarian Qader Zazai.
"The Tajiks and former mujahideen MPs did not vote because they think all security sectors are occupied by Pashtuns and power must be shared," he said.
On Wednesday, parliament also voted down Ghani's nomination for the first woman to the Supreme Court.
Next on its hit list could be Interior Minister Noor ul Haq Ulomi, likely to be called for questioning before lawmakers, some of whom are threatening to remove him.
"We are going to summon the interior minister and will likely dismiss him," said lawmaker Allah Gul Mujahid, citing spiralling violence that included a Taliban attack on the parliamentary compound last month.
However, it was unclear whether Ghani's opponents in parliament have enough votes to remove Ulomi.
Ghani has pushed for peace talks with the Taliban to end the war, and achieved a rare breakthrough when his government met militants formally for the first time this week.
COMPLAINTS TAKE ON ETHNIC HUE
Afghanistan's fledgling democracy set up after the U.S.-sponsored military intervention that toppled the Taliban in 2001 has been hampered by power struggles and corruption throughout.
Ghani campaigned on promises to tackle graft and create a professional administration based on merit.
But he has struggled to balance the competing interests in Afghanistan's labyrinthine politics, described by one diplomat as a "constellation of egos".
Disagreements between Ghani and Abdullah's camps delayed cabinet nominations for months, and the two are still deadlocked over who should lead the electoral reform commission.
Increasingly, complaints against Ghani have taken on an ethnic hue, a worrying trend in a country that fought an ethnic-based civil war in the 1990s.
Hazara protesters last month accused the government of failing to come to the aid of 30 Hazara police massacred by Taliban fighters in Jalrez district, west of Kabul. Ghani ordered an investigation.
Mohaqiq, the Hazara political leader, said he pleaded for hours during the battle for reinforcements that were never sent.
"All I received were fake promises and lies," he said.
(Additional reporting by Jessica Donati; Writing by Kay Johnson; Editing by Mike Collett-White)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
