<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Times of India">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>DNA test couples before marriage: UK Asian peer</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f545d1/sc/14/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CDNA0Etest0Ecouples0Ebefore0Emarriage0EUK0EAsian0Epeer0Carticleshow0C479969210Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Britain's first Asian woman peer - Baroness Flather - has raised a storm by telling the House of Lords that couples who are getting married should be forced to have a DNA test first to ensure they are not cousins.</Description>
        <MainBody>My Saved articles
RELATED
LONDON: Britain's first Asian woman peer - Baroness Flather - has raised a storm by telling the House of Lords that couples who are getting married should be forced to have a DNA test first to ensure they are not cousins.
Raising serious concern around how first cousin marriages in Pakistani communities in the UK were leading to disability among the children born out of such unions, Baroness Flather said during a debate that the practice is rampant among Pakistanis who come from the Pakistan occupied Kashmir.
She said, "We know so much about DNA now, but there is so much disability among the children, which is absolutely appalling. You go to any such family and there will be four or five children, at least one or two of whom will have some disability. That is absolutely unacceptable, and if we cannot do anything about it, is it fair to the children?" house She added, "Never mind the parents  it is not fair to the children that they should be allowed to become disabled because of a social practice. It is a social practice which does not belong in today's age. There should at least be some rule which says that you must have a DNA examination before your marriage can be registered."
Reacting to the debate, the parliamentary under-secretary of state for communities Baroness Williams of Trafford said "My Lords, I can confirm that first-cousin marriages are against the law in this country and the church does not condone them."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:17:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No evidence of JuD's links with LeT: Pak</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f5ab8d/sc/14/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cpakistan0CNo0Eevidence0Eof0EJuDs0Elinks0Ewith0ELeT0EPak0Carticleshow0C479968230Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pakistan has ruled out possibility of banning Jamaat-ud-Dawa (JuD), claiming there was no evidence to prove it is an offshoot or a front for Lashkar-e-Taiba (LeT), the terrorist group involved in the November 2008 attacks on Mumbai.</Description>
        <MainBody>READ MORE LeT | Jamaat-ud-Dawa
Pakistan has ruled out possibility of banning Jamaat-ud-Dawa (JuD), claiming there was no evidence to prove it is an offshoot or a front for Lashkar-e-Taiba (LeT), the terrorist group involved in the November 2008 attacks on Mumbai.
RELATED
ISLAMABAD: Pakistan has ruled out possibility of banning Jamaat-ud-Dawa (JuD), claiming there was no evidence to prove it is an offshoot or a front for Lashkar-e-Taiba (LeT), the terrorist group involved in the November 2008 attacks on Mumbai.
Federal minister Abdul Qadir Baloch told Pakistan's parliament on Tuesday that the UN Security Council had in a resolution mentioned JuD as LeT's new name "without sharing any supporting evidence'' with Islamabad to establish the connection.
India had maintained JuD is an LeT front and provided Pakistan evidence proving its involvement in the Mumbai attacks. The US has named the JuD as a foreign terrorist organization.
Baloch said the JuD had been under observation since Nov 15, 2003 and all provinces had been asked to keep a watch on its activities.
"The JuD will be proscribed under Anti-Terrorism Act if the federal government has reasons to believe that it is linked to terrorism," the minister said.
The government can place any organization under observation for six months if it is suspected of being involved in terrorist activities. The period can be extended only after providing the organization a hearing.
Baloch said JuD's offices were closed between 2008 and 2010 before the Lahore high court ruled against it.
"Presently, JuD is engaged in charity and social work, operating hospitals, clinics, schools, ambulance service and religious institutions," he claimed.
Baloch said the UN Security Council had listed Falah-i-Insaniat Foundation as a suspected charity having links with LeT as well.
But he did not say whether it too was under observation. He was responding to Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP) Senator Farhatullah Babar question whether banned outfits were not allowed to work under different names or as charity organizations. Babar specifically asked whether a banned organization had renamed itself as JuD.
Baloch added any organization proscribed under the Anti-Terrorism Act is prohibited from all activities, including charity work.
Another PPP lawmaker Taj Haider opposed deployment of paramilitary Rangers to provide security to JuD's congregations in Karachi.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=LeT,Jamaat-ud-Dawa
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:08:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chinese, US &amp; Pak officials participated in Taliban talks</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f5ab8c/sc/11/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cpakistan0CChinese0EUS0EPak0Eofficials0Eparticipated0Ein0ETaliban0Etalks0Carticleshow0C479967630Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US, Chinese and Pakistani officials were present as observers at the meeting between Afghan government and Taliban representatives at Murree near Islamabad on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Pakistan
Breaking News:
Chinese, US &amp; Pak officials participated in Taliban talks
Omer Farooq Khan Omer Farooq Khan,TNN | Jul 9, 2015, 06.38 AM IST
READ MORE Taliban | afghanistan
Beijing had recently hosted a meeting between top Afghan peace envoy,MasoomStanakzai, and Taliban representatives atUrumqiin Western China with Islamabad's help.(Representative Image)
RELATED
ISLAMABAD: US, Chinese and Pakistani officials were present as observers at the meeting between Afghan government and Taliban representatives at Murree near Islamabad on Tuesday.
Pakistan's foreign office spokesman Qazi Khalilullah confirmed this on Wednesday, highlighting China's increasing role in the Afghan peace process.
Beijing had recently hosted a meeting between top Afghan peace envoy, Masoom Stanakzai, and Taliban representatives at Urumqi in Western China with Islamabad's help.
Khalilullah said the two sides agreed to meet again after Ramazan ends in two weeks and to continue talks to create an environment conducive for peace and reconciliation.
"Both major parties (Afghanistan and Taliban) agreed that for lasting peace in the region, each side would approach the process with sincerity and full commitment.''
Mullah Abbas Akhund, who served as health minister when the Taliban ruled Afghanistan from 1996 to 2001, led the three-member insurgent delegation in talks with Afghan deputy foreign minister Hekmat Khalil Karzai.
The two sides have held informal meetings several times. But it was the first time that Kabul had sent an official team to Pakistan for talks with the Taliban.
It was unclear whether the Taliban fully backed the meeting. Taliban spokesman Zabiullah Mujahid said he was unaware of any talks.
The talks coincided with escalation of violence in Afghanistan.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Taliban,afghanistan
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:03:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lithuania sees huge rise in Indian students</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f5845f/sc/33/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CLithuania0Esees0Ehuge0Erise0Ein0EIndian0Estudents0Carticleshow0C479967310Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Indian students have started to explore new parts of Europe for higher education and many are headed to Lithuania.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Lithuania sees huge rise in Indian students
Kounteya Sinha Kounteya Sinha | Jul 9, 2015, 06.33 AM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
Kazlauskaitesaid that Indians are coming to the country to study because "the quality of education is among the top in Europe while living costs and tuition fees are tremendously cheap compared to UK".(Representative Image)
RELATED
VILNIUS: Indian students have started to explore new parts of Europe for higher education and many are headed to Lithuania.
Lithuania has recorded a massive increase in the number of Indian students heading to its universities with the latest data showing that the number of Indian students studying full time in the Baltic country have increased from 37 in 2011 to 357 in 2014.
In 2012, there were 57 students from India enrolled in Lithuanian colleges which increased to 224 in 2013.
This year, the numbers are expected to breach the 500 mark.
From January to June of 2015 "Study in Lithuania" website was visited 64,931 times. The most visitors came from the following five countries: India - 7.695 sessions, Ukraine - 5.789 sessions, United States - 4.944 sessions, Russia - 3.996 sessions and Belarus - 3.393 sessions.
In 2014, the most popular Lithuanian university amongst Indians was the Kaunas University of Technology with 248 students enrolling there
The second in terms of popularity was Vilnius Gediminas Technical University which recorded 36 students from India.
According to statistics gathered by the Study in Lithuania department, in 2014 the only country which surpassed India in the number of students in Lithuania was Belarus (1617 students).
In 2015, the QS World University Rankings published a list of the best universities in emerging Europe and central Asia. Four Lithuanian universities made it to the top 100. Vilnius University was placed 32nd, Vilnius Gediminas Technical University - 47th, Kaunas University of Technology was placed within the 61-70th rank and Vytautas Magnus University - 81-90th places.
Ilona Kazlauskaite, head of higher education programs unit in Lithuania told the TOI, "Indian students are sincere, diligent and very hard working. Their presence in our universities is raising the bar of excellence. Lithuania is known worldwide for its expertise in laser technology, agricultural and medical sciences, engineering and courses in art. Indians are now among the top 5 countries as far as the origin of our international students is concerned."
Kazlauskaite said that Indians are coming to the country to study because "the quality of education is among the top in Europe while living costs and tuition fees are tremendously cheap compared to UK".
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:56:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>That sinking feeling: 4th smallest nation sends out SOS</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f58461/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CThat0Esinking0Efeeling0E4th0Esmallest0Enation0Esends0Eout0ESOS0Carticleshow0C479966840Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The PM of Tuvalu Islands, the fourth smallest nation, has appealed for help from European leaders to stop it disappearing from the face of the Earth.</Description>
        <MainBody>READ MORE Tuvalu Islands | PM | European leaders
RELATED
The PM of Tuvalu Islands, the fourth smallest nation, has appealed for help from European leaders to stop it disappearing from the face of the Earth.
Enele Spoaga arrived in Brussels on Monday to call on leaders of the European Union for support ahead of the next United Nations climate change summit in Paris in December.
The Tuvalu islands, home to just 10,000 people, is under direct threat by rising sea levels due to climate change as it is no more than 4m above sea le Tuvalu Islands, under threat from rising sea levels, has sought Europe's help for survival vel at its highest level.
Spoaga called on Europe to reduce greenhouse gas emissions to keep global warming down to 1.5 degrees Celsius, which scientists say is a safer limit than the current goal of 2 degrees Celsius, the Brussels Times reports.
He said, "We need to save Tuvalu to save the world. If this island disappears under the world. If this island disappears under water, it is not the end of climate change.And I ask you what future do we hold? We need to collaborate as one human face to save human kind. We are told that even 2 degrees global warming is too dangerous as it would mean Tuvalu would disappear under the water. Yes, we can move the Tuvalu in habitants to other peoples' lands, but it wil not stop climate change."
Tuvalu is one of several island chains in the Pacific which are vulnerable to ris ing sea levels. In pictures: Climate Change Protests Around the World In 2009, the president of Maldives staged an underwater meeting of his cab inet to high the threat countries like his face from climate change.
Six metres below the surface, the ministers ratified a treaty calling on other countries to cut their greenhouse gas emissions.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Tuvalu Islands,PM,European leaders
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:42:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berlusconi sentenced to 3 years for bribing Italian senator</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f57101/sc/16/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CBerlusconi0Esentenced0Eto0E30Eyears0Efor0Ebribing0EItalian0Esenator0Carticleshow0C47996630A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A court in Naples today sentenced former Italian premier and media tycoon Silvio Berlusconi to three years in prison for bribing a senator as part of a plot to destabilise a 2006-08 centre-left government.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Berlusconi sentenced to 3 years for bribing Italian senator
AFP | Jul 9, 2015, 06.12 AM IST
A court in Naples today sentenced former Italian premier and media tycoon Silvio Berlusconi to three years in prison for bribing a senator as part of a plot to destabilise a 2006-08 centre-left government.
RELATED
ROME: A court in Naples today sentenced former Italian premier and media tycoon Silvio Berlusconi to three years in prison for bribing a senator as part of a plot to destabilise a 2006-08 centre-left government.
Berlusconi, 78, will not however have to serve the sentence as the case's statute of limitations expires later this year, well before any final ruling will have been reached on appeal.
"It was a good trial, passionate, but in terms of consequences the imminent expiration date takes all the pathos out of the verdict," said prosecutor Henry John Woodcock.
The case centred around bribes totalling three million euros (USD 3.3 million) that were paid, through an intermediary, to Senator Sergio De Gregorio in order to get him to leave the coalition of then premier Romano Prodi.
The idea was to further weaken an already fragile coalition and the defection was widely seen as hurting Prodi's government, which collapsed in 2008, two years after it was elected. Berlusconi's centre-right Forza Italia party won the resulting election and he served a third term as Italian premier until 2011.
The senator has admitted accepting the money.
The case marks the latest in a string of legal woes for Berlusconi.
Earlier this year, he completed a community service order for corporate tax fraud but was cleared of having sex with an under-age dancer after judges ruled he could not have known she was a minor.
Berlusconi would have gone to prison for the tax fraud had he been younger but was allowed to serve his time by helping out once a week with dementia sufferers at an old people's home.
In summing up the bribery case, prosecutor Vincenzo Piscitelli had told the court the three million euros paid to the senator were "a colossal economic investment made with the aim of achieving the sole goal that interested Berlusconi, who was obsessed by his desire to kick Prodi out and take his post".
The case will reach its statute of limitations in October or November at the latest, according to Italian media. (AFP)
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Silvio Berlusconi,Bribery Case
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 03:29:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia vetoes UN resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f57100/sc/11/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CRussia0Evetoes0EUN0Eresolution0Ecalling0ESrebrenica0Ea0Egenocide0Carticleshow0C479965860Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Russia vetoed a U.N. resolution Wednesday that would have condemned the 1995 massacre of Muslims at Srebrenica during the Bosnian war as a "crime of genocide," saying that singling out the Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division in the Balkans.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World US
Breaking News:
Russia vetoes UN resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide
AP | Jul 9, 2015, 05.59 AM IST
Two international courts have called the slaughter by Bosnian Serbs of some 8,000 Muslim men and boys who had sought refuge at what was supposed to be a U.N.-protected site genocide.
RELATED
UNITED NATIONS: Russia vetoed a U.N. resolution Wednesday that would have condemned the 1995 massacre of Muslims at Srebrenica during the Bosnian war as a "crime of genocide," saying that singling out the Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division in the Balkans.
Two international courts have called the slaughter by Bosnian Serbs of some 8,000 Muslim men and boys who had sought refuge at what was supposed to be a U.N.-protected site genocide.
But Russia's U.N. Ambassador Vitaly Churkin objected to focusing only on Srebrenica, calling the resolution "confrontational and politically motivated" and stressing that Bosnian Serbs and Croats had also suffered during the 1992-95 war that killed at least 100,000 people.
Britain drafted the resolution to mark the 20th anniversary of the Srebrenica massacre on Tuesday, but the vote was delayed to address Russian concerns.
The defeated resolution states that acceptance of "the tragic events at Srebrenica as genocide is a prerequisite for reconciliation" and "condemns denial of this genocide as hindering efforts towards reconciliation."
Britain's U.N. deputy ambassador Peter Wilson stressed that the resolution "did not point fingers of blame, score political points nor seek to reopen political divisions." It also didn't link the crimes at Srebrenica to the Serb people and recognized there were victims on all sides, he said.
The vote was 10 countries in favor, Russia casting a veto, and four abstentions _ China, Nigeria, Angola and Venezuela.
Leaders of the Bosnian Serbs and Serbia, who have close religious and cultural ties to Russia, have lobbied President Vladimir Putin to vote "no.'
Serbia's pro-Russian President Tomislav Nikolic said Russia's veto "not only prevented the throwing of guilt against the whole Serbian nation, trying to show it as genocidal, but it also proved that Russia is a real and sincere friend."
Wilson said Britain was "outraged" by Russia's veto.
"Russia's actions tarnish the memory of all those who died in the Srebrenica genocide," he said. "Russia will have to justify its behavior to the families of over 8,000 people murdered in the worst atrocity in Europe since the Second World War."
Bosnians reacted bitterly to the veto.
"This is a defeat of justice," said Camil Durakovic, the mayor of Srebrenica. "The world has lost. The world _ and especially Serbia _ will have to face the truth sooner or later," he said.
Fadila Efendic, a Srebrenica woman who lost her son and husband in the Srebrenica massacre, called the veto "another humiliation of the victims."
"Today's vote mattered," said U.S. Ambassador Samantha Power, who was a 24-year-old journalist in Bosnia at the time of the Srebrenica massacre. "It mattered hugely to the families of the victims of the Srebrenica genocide. Russia's veto is heartbreaking for those families, and it is a further stain on this council's record."
Russia's Churkin began his speech before the vote asking for a minute of silence in memory of the victims of Srebrenica and everyone in the Security Council stood, many bowing their heads.
Instead of Srebrenica, he said the council should commemorate the 20th anniversary of the 1995 peace agreement signed in Dayton, Ohio that ended the Bosnian war later this year, and make every effort to implement it and normalize relations in the Balkans.
"Our vote against ... will, however, not mean that we are deaf to the suffering of victims of Srebrenica and other areas of Bosnia and Herzegovina," Churkin said.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=UN,Srebrenica,Serbia,Russia,Genocide
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:44:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f2e893/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CBoko0EHaram0Eoffers0Eto0Eswap0Ekidnapped0Egirls0Efor0Edetainees0Carticleshow0C47993910A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Nigeria's Boko Haram extremists are offering to free more than 200 young women and girls kidnapped from a boarding school in the town of Chibok in exchange for the release of militant leaders held by the government, a human rights activist has told The Associated Press.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees
AP | Jul 8, 2015, 11.14 PM IST
READ MORE Boko Haram
Boko Haram extremists are offering to free more than 200 girls kidnapped from a school in the town of Chibok in exchange for the release of militant leaders held by the govt.
RELATED
LAGOS: Nigeria's Boko Haram extremists are offering to free more than 200 young women and girls kidnapped from a boarding school in the town of Chibok in exchange for the release of militant leaders held by the government, a human rights activist has told The Associated Press.
The activist said Boko Haram's current offer is limited to the girls from the school in northeastern Nigeria whose mass abduction in April 2014 ignited worldwide outrage and a campaign to "Bring Back Our Girls" that stretched to the White House.
The new initiative reopens an offer made last year to the government of former President Goodluck Jonathan to release the 219 students in exchange for 16 Boko Haram detainees, the activist said.
The man, who was involved in negotiations with Boko Haram last year and is close to current negotiators, spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to talk to reporters on this sensitive issue.
Fred Eno, an apolitical Nigerian who has been negotiating with Boko Haram for more than a year, told the AP that "another window of opportunity opened" in the last few days, though he could not discuss details.
He said the recent slew of Boko Haram bloodletting -- some 350 people killed in the past nine days -- is consistent with past ratcheting up of violence as the militants seek a stronger negotiating position.
Presidential adviser Femi Adesina said on Saturday that Nigeria's government "will not be averse" to talks with Boko Haram.
"Most wars, however furious or vicious, often end around the negotiation table," he said.
Eno said the 5-week-old administration of President Muhammadu Buhari offers "a clean slate" to bring the militants back to negotiations that had become poisoned by the different security agencies and their advice to Jonathan.
Two months of talks last year led government representatives and Eno to travel in September to a northeastern town where the prisoner exchange was to take place, only to be stymied by the Department for State Service intelligence agency, the activist said.
At the last minute, the agency said it was holding only four of the militants sought by Boko Haram, the activist said.
It is not known how many Boko Haram suspects are detained by Nigeria's intelligence agency, whose chief Buhari fired last week.
The activist said the agency continues to hold suspects illegally because it does not have enough evidence for a conviction, and any court would free them.
Nigerian law requires charges be brought after 48 hours.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Boko Haram
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 20:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>High-level talks between Afghan govt officials and Taliban</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f338e0/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cpakistan0CHigh0Elevel0Etalks0Ebetween0EAfghan0Egovt0Eofficials0Eand0ETaliban0Carticleshow0C4799330A10Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Afghan government officials and Taliban representatives concluded their first officially recognized peace talks in Pakistan with a promise to meet again after the Islamic holy month of Ramazan, Pakistan’s foreign office said on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>My Saved articles
RELATED
ISLAMABAD: Afghan government officials and Taliban representatives concluded their first officially recognized peace talks in Pakistan with a promise to meet again after the Islamic holy month of Ramazan, Pakistan's Foreign Office said on Wednesday.
The talks, which were held on Tuesday in Murree, a hill station on 60-minute drive from Islamabad, was the first highest-level official contact between the two warring parties since Taliban were ousted from power in the wake of terrorist attacks on US by al-Qaeda on 11 September 2001.
Pakistan's Foreign Office said that US, Chinese and Pakistani officials were present at the meeting as observers. China has become more influential in Afghanistan in recent months. With Islamabad's help, it hosted a meeting between Afghanistan's top peace envoy Masoom Stanakzai and ex-Taliban officials in the city of Urumqi, in Western China.
The eight-member Afghan delegation had arrived in Islamabad on a UN flight on Monday. Deputy Foreign Minister Hekmat Khalil Karzai led the delegation. Other participants included adviser to the Afghan president Haji Din Mohammad, governor of Afghanistan's Parwan province Mohammad Asem and members of the country's High Peace Council, a body constituted for talks with militants.
Mullah Abbas Akhund, who served as health minister when the Taliban ruled Afghanistan from 1996 to 2001, led the three-member Taliban delegation in talks.
The FO said the two sides would meet again after the Islamic holy month of Ramazan ends in two weeks. "The participants agreed to continue talks to create an environment conducive for peace and reconciliation process," Qazi Khalilullah, FO spokesman, said in a short statement early Wednesday.
"Both major parties agreed that for lasting peace in the region, each side would approach the process with sincerity and full commitment," he added.
Afghan government and Taliban representatives had held informal meetings several times in the past but it was the first time that Kabul had sent an official team to Pakistan for talks with Taliban. It was unclear, however, whether the meeting was fully backed by Taliban leadership. Zabiullah Mujahid, a Taliban spokesman, said he was unaware of any talks.
The new peace overtures in Pakistan came as Afghan forces face the most violent fighting season since the Taliban launched their insurgency. On Tuesday, a car bomb in Kabul targeted a convoy of the US-led military mission, causing damage to the vehicles.
Hours later, militants tried to storm a compound of Afghanistan's intelligence agency in eastern Kabul but were repelled by security forces. At least one member of the Afghan security forces was killed and another was injured in that attack, the Afghan intelligence agency said. Taliban had claimed responsibility for both the attacks.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:12:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Philippines warns China flouting UN maritime laws</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f1ca9b/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cchina0CPhilippines0Ewarns0EChina0Eflouting0EUN0Emaritime0Elaws0Carticleshow0C47990A8120Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Philippines has appealed to an international tribunal to declare China's claims to most of the South China Sea illegal, warning the integrity of United Nations' maritime laws is at stake.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World China
Breaking News:
Philippines warns China flouting UN maritime laws
AFP | Jul 8, 2015, 07.42 PM IST
File aerial photo taken though a glass window of a Philippine military plane shows the alleged on-going land reclamation by China on Mischief Reef in the Spratly Islands, South China Sea. (Reuters Photo)
RELATED
THE HAGUE: The Philippines has appealed to an international tribunal to declare China's claims to most of the South China Sea illegal, warning the integrity of United Nations' maritime laws is at stake.
In opening comments to the tribunal in the Hague on yesterday, foreign secretary Albert del Rosario said the Philippines had sought judicial intervention because China's behaviour had become increasingly "aggressive" and negotiations had proved futile.
Del Rosario said the UN's Convention on the Law of the Sea, which the Philippines and China have both ratified, should be used to resolve their bitter territorial dispute.
"The case before you is of the utmost importance to the Philippines, to the region, and to the world," del Rosario told the tribunal.
"In our view, it is also of utmost significance to the integrity of the convention, and to the very fabric of the legal order of the seas and oceans."
China insists it has sovereign rights to nearly all of the South China Sea, a strategically vital waterway with shipping lanes through which about a third of all the world's traded oil passes.
Its claim, based on ancient Chinese maps, reaches close to the coasts of its southern neighbours.
The Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia, Brunei and Taiwan also have claims to parts of the sea, which have for decades made it a potential military flashpoint.
Tensions have risen sharply in recent years as a rising China has sought to stake its claims more assertively.
Following a stand-off between Chinese ships and the weak Filipino Navy in 2012, China took control of a rich fishing ground called Scarborough Shoal that is within the Philippines' exclusive economic zone.
China has also undertaken giant reclamation activities that have raised fears it will use artificial islands to build new military outposts close to the Philippines and other claimants.
China has rejected all criticism over its actions, insisting it has undisputed sovereign rights to the sea.
However del Rosario told the tribunal in the Hague that China's argument of claiming the sea based on "historic rights" was without foundation.
"The so-called nine dash line (based on an old map used by China) has no basis whatsoever under international law," he said.
The Philippines submitted its case to the Hague-based Permanent Court of Arbitration, a 117-state body that rules on disputes between countries, in early 2013.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=UN maritime laws,South China Sea
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:03:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New constitution in two months: Nepal deputy PM</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f1a85c/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Csouth0Easia0CNew0Econstitution0Ein0Etwo0Emonths0ENepal0Edeputy0EPM0Carticleshow0C47990A720A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Nepal's deputy Prime Minister Bamdev Gautam has expressed confidence that a new constitution will be promulgated in the country in two months and said the devastating earthquake on April 25 brought the quibbling political parties together in finalizing the much-delayed document.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal's deputy Prime MinisterBamdevGautam. (PTI photo)
RELATED
KATHMANDU: Nepal's deputy Prime Minister Bamdev Gautam has expressed confidence that a new constitution will be promulgated in the country in two months and said the devastating earthquake on April 25 brought the quibbling political parties together in finalizing the much-delayed document.
"We would be able to declare the constitution in two months from now," Gautam told IANS in an interview at his residence here last week. Gautam said the new constitution will be secular and the state will not create any obstacle in the practise of religion.
He said people who had lost their houses during the devastating April earthquake and the aftershocks that followed were being provided temporary shelters during the monsoon and the task of reconstruction will be taken up in full swing once the rains get over.
"We have reached the last stage of relief work. After this, we will engage in rebuilding and rehabilitation. A plan has been made and it will be implemented. It (the earthquake) is a national calamity and one needs courage to fight an adversity. We have sought to boost the morale of the people," Gautam told IANS.
Over 8,500 people were killed and more than 23,000 injured in Nepal's devastating earthquake that also flattened numerous villages in central and western regions of the Himalayan nation rendering hundreds of thousands of people homeless.
Asked about the ongoing constitution-making process in the country, Gautam said 90 percent of the political parties were in favour of promulgating the new constitution soonest but there had been some disturbances by the dissenting minority during meetings of the Constituent Assembly recently.
He said that after Nepal's four major political parties gave their nod to a federal model following a 16-point agreement in June, there was hope that the Constitution will be promulgated in a month. The hurdles that cropped up from time to time were being sorted out through discussions, he added.
The 16-point agreement was signed by the Nepali Congress, Communist Party of Nepal (Unified Marxist-Leninist) [CPN-UML], Unified Communist Party of Nepal (Maoist) [UCPN-Maoist] and the terai-based Madhesi Janadhikar Forum-Loktantrik (MJF-L) with the objective of speedily resolving the key contentious issues in formally proclaiming the new Constitution.
The deal came after several years of protracted negotiations.
Nepal's Maoist rebels had in 2006 agreed to lay down arms after more than a decade-long insurgency and join the democratic process.
A constituent assembly was elected in 2008 to a two-year term to frame a secular democratic federal constitution for the former Hindu kingdom. The first CA, however, suffered several extensions with the political parties failing to find consensus on various contentious issues including the number of federal provinces, the form of government, electoral system and judiciary.
In 2012, a second house was elected and this, too, initially suffered the same malaise that had affected the first -- protracted wranglings and continued differences over the form and content of the much-awaited document.
Finally, jolted by the devastating temblor of July 25, the squabbling politicians in the CA sprung to cobbling a document that met the aspirations of the majority among them -- the four major political parties agreed on June 8 on the modus operandi to be adopted to speedily finalise a new constitution.
Asked if the agreement was propelled by the need to show political unity at a time of crisis for the country in the wake of the earthquake, Gautam said the quake united the people of the country like never before.
"It brought together political parties. This should have happened earlier. And using this, we made a proposal to all parties to get united to finalise the constitution. Four major political parties joined it... We are hopeful that we will succeed," he said.
Gautam, who belongs to the CPN-UML and is also the country's home minister, said Nepal cannot be without a Constitution for long. "No country in the world can stay without a Constitution in the 21st century. We have faith that we will be able to declare the new constitution shortly," he said.
Gautam affirmed that Nepal wanted to take forward its relationship with India.
"India is emerging as an economic centre not only in south Asia, but in Asia. We express happiness that our neighbour is a big country. In the north, China has also emerged as an economic centre. We also want to develop as an economic centre between India and China," Gautam said.
He said the people of Nepal were grateful over the way Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the people of India supported Nepal following the April 25 earthquake.
"We hope that in the future also, the Indian people will support us in our development effort, and stand by us in our pain, in our happiness, in our prosperity," Gautam said.
He said all religions find freedom in Nepal. "But asking people to leave their religion on the basis of allurements would be declared illegal. We have written it down in the draft Constitution," he said.
Over 80 percent of Nepal's population is estimated to be Hindu, while nine percent are Buddhists -- the remaining are Muslims, Christians and animists.
Asked how much the draft Constitution has adopted from the Indian Constitution, Gautam said the draft has gained from the constitutions of various countries.
"We have learnt the parliamentary system from India, but there will be first-past-the-post system (based on getting maximum votes) and proportional representation while electing representatives to parliament," he said.
According to the agreement signed by the four major political parties, the lower house will have 275 seats with 60 percent (165 seats) directly elected and 40 percent (110 seats) elected through the proportional representation system.
The Constituent Assembly will be turned into a central legislature parliament after the promulgation of the new constitution.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Nepal deputy PM,Bamdev Gautam
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:53:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India's stand at UNHRC a qualitative leap in ties, Israel says</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f1a42b/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CIndias0Estand0Eat0EUNHRC0Ea0Equalitative0Eleap0Ein0Eties0EIsrael0Esays0Carticleshow0C47990A50A90Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Israel on Wednesday hailed India's abstention at the UNHRC vote on Gaza war as a "qualitative" leap in bilateral ties that made it a "normal relation without hangups", even as India maintained that the vote does not mark any shift in its policy on the Palestinian cause.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home India
Breaking News:
India's stand at UNHRC a qualitative leap in ties, Israel says
PTI | Jul 8, 2015, 07.16 PM IST
(ET photo)
RELATED
JERUSALEM: Israel on Wednesday hailed India's abstention at the UNHRC vote on Gaza war as a "qualitative" leap in bilateral ties that made it a "normal relation without hangups", even as India maintained that the vote does not mark any shift in its policy on the Palestinian cause.
The remarks came as India and Israel held foreign office consultations (FOC), days after the highly publicized vote.
Watch: India abstains from voting on resolution against Israel in UNHRC
The consolations were led by secretary (east) at ministry of external affairs (MEA), Anil Wadhwa, and his Israeli counterpart, director general Dore Gold.
Israel is said to have expressed its appreciation for India's stand during the vote at the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC).
The FOC is a routine dialogue between the two sides to review bilateral relations and not related to the vote.
Mark Sofer, the deputy director-general at Israel's ministry of foreign affairs who is currently heading the division for Asia and the Pacific at the ministry, later told The Jerusalem Post that the dialogue came at a particularly "auspicious moment".
READ ALSO: In a first, India refuses to vote against Israel at UN
The relationship, which has been steadily improving over the years, has taken a "qualitative" leap forward since (Prime Minister Narendra) Modi's election, he said.
Now the relationship has transformed into a "completely normal relationship, without hangups," Sofer, who has served as Israel's ambassador in New Delhi, told the daily.
"The qualitative change in the relationship is palpable in every single sphere, and that is important to note," he said adding that India represents "a quarter of the world population and everyone is running to be there".
Sofer attributed a part of the improvement in ties to a "chemistry" that exists between Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Prime Minister Modi.
The two leaders had met in New York last September on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly and since have constantly kept in touch.
Sources at the PMO here said that Netanyahu had reached out to Modi before the UNHRC vote as well.
READ ALSO: Gaza war 2014  Israel, Hamas may have committed war crimes, UN report says
Wadhwa, speaking to PTI, however, said that India has already clarified its position on the UNHRC vote which was a "principled" one in connection to the ICC (International Criminal Court) which was referenced in the resolution.
"We have communicated to the Israeli side about our position and I am also going to convey the same to the Palestinian side when I meet their leadership later today and tomorrow," Wadhwa said.
"The FOC covers the whole gamut of bilateral relations and we focused on strengthening and expanding our engagement in various fields, especially agriculture and science and technology".
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=United Nations Human Rights Council,UNHRC vote on Gaza war,UNHRC vote,israel,Gaza war
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:52:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraq court sentences 24 to hang over Tikrit massacre</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f1a429/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CIraq0Ecourt0Esentences0E240Eto0Ehang0Eover0ETikrit0Emassacre0Carticleshow0C47990A5710Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An Iraqi court sentenced 24 men to death by hanging today over the June 2014 massacre by jihadist and allied militants of hundreds of mostly Shiite military recruits in Tikrit.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
Iraq court sentences 24 to hang over Tikrit massacre
AFP | Jul 8, 2015, 07.22 PM IST
READ MORE Tikrit massacre | Iraq court
Mothers hold up posters of their sons, Iraqi soldiers who were killed, at a courtroom in Baghdad, Iraq, Wednesday, July 8, 2015. An Iraqi court has issued death sentences to 24 militants for their role in killing hundreds of soldiers last year. (AP Photo)
RELATED
BAGHDAD: An Iraqi court sentenced 24 men to death by hanging today over the June 2014 massacre by jihadist and allied militants of hundreds of mostly Shiite military recruits in Tikrit.
The central criminal court in Baghdad handed 24 of 28 defendants the maximum sentence over the "Speicher" massacre, named after the base from which the victims were captured before being executed.
"After deliberations, the court finds that the evidence collected is sufficient to convict 24 defendants," said the judge. "The court decided they will be executed by hanging."
All 24 denied any involvement in the massacre, committed during the first days of the Islamic State group's broad offensive in Iraq last year.
Around 600 bodies of victims have been exhumed from burial sites in the Tikrit area. Footage released by IS last year shows some of the captured recruits were shot and pushed into the Tigris river.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Tikrit massacre,Iraq court
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:40:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>30 soldiers killed in mutiny at Yemen army base</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f073d6/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0C30A0Esoldiers0Ekilled0Ein0Emutiny0Eat0EYemen0Earmy0Ebase0Carticleshow0C4798890A30Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 30 Yemeni soldiers were killed in coalition air raids and clashes after troops attempted to defect to Iran-backed rebel ranks near the border with Saudi Arabia, a military source said on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
30 soldiers killed in mutiny at Yemen army base
AFP | Jul 8, 2015, 05.10 PM IST
People check a car damaged by a car bomb attack near a mosque in Yemen's capital Sanaa. (Reuters Photo)
RELATED
ADEN: At least 30 Yemeni soldiers were killed in coalition air raids and clashes after troops attempted to defect to Iran-backed rebel ranks near the border with Saudi Arabia, a military source said on Wednesday.
Saudi-led coalition jets, which have bombed Yemeni rebel positions since March, intervened when "dozens of soldiers defected and announced their support" for Shia Huthi rebels yesterday, prompting clashes with pro-government troops, the military source said.
The incident took place at the 23rd Mechanised Brigade, stationed near the border with Saudi Arabia and left "at least 30 soldiers killed and dozens wounded" on both sides, he told AFP.
"Armoured vehicles and troop carriers were destroyed or damaged" in the air raids and clashes between rival units before the situation was brought under control, the source added.
Troops loyal to former president Ali Abdullah Saleh have joined forces with the Huthi rebels, who seized the capital almost unresisted in September before advancing southwards in the impoverished Gulf country.
Saudi Arabia fears the Huthis are trying to bring Yemen under the influence of Shia Iran.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Yemeni soldiers,Yemen army base
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:09:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World’s 4th smallest nation is disappearing</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47f06bbe/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CWorlds0E4th0Esmallest0Enation0Eis0Edisappearing0Carticleshow0C4798840A20Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The prime minister of the world’s fourth smallest nation has appealed for help from European leaders to stop it disappearing from the face of the Earth.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
Worlds 4th smallest nation is disappearing
Caroline MortimerCaroline Mortimer,The Independent | Jul 8, 2015, 04.39 PM IST
The Funafuti atoll on Tuvalu, seen here from the air, is threatened by a rise in sea level. (Getty Images photo)
RELATED
The prime minister of the world's fourth smallest nation has appealed for help from European leaders to stop it disappearing from the face of the Earth .
Enele Spoaga arrived in Brussels on Monday to call on EU leaders for support ahead of the next UN climate change summit in Paris in December.
The group of islands, home to just 10,000 people, is under direct threat by rising sea levels due to climate change as it is no more than 4m above sea level at its highest level.
He called on Europe to reduce greenhouse gas emissions to keep global warming down to 1.5C, which scientists say is a safer limit than the current goal of 2C, the Brussels Times reports.
He said: "We need to save Tuvalu to save the world.
"If this island disappears under water, it is not the end of climate change. And I ask you what future do we hold? We need to collaborate as one human face to save human kind.
READ ALSO: Climate change turning male dragon lizards into females
"We are told that even 2 degrees global warming is too dangerous as it would mean that Tuvalu would disappear under the water. Yes we can move the Tuvalu inhabitants to other peoples' lands but it will not stop climate change."
Tuvalu is one of several island chains in the Pacific which are vulnerable to rising sea levels.
READ ALSO: Scientists point to narrowing gap to avert climate disaster
In 2009, the president of Maldives staged an underwater meeting of his cabinet to high the threat countries like his face from climate change.
Six metres below the surface, the ministers ratified a treaty calling on other countries to cut their greenhouse emissions.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Worlds 4th smallest nation,smallest nation disappearing,Climate Change
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 12:43:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Myanmar to hold general election on November 8: Poll officials</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47ef859c/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CMyanmar0Eto0Ehold0Egeneral0Eelection0Eon0ENovember0E80EPoll0Eofficials0Carticleshow0C479870A750Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A president will be chosen later by parliament, but Suu Kyi is barred by the constitution from taking the top job.</Description>
        <MainBody>ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
A president will be chosen later by parliament, butSuuKyiis barred by the constitution from taking the top job.
RELATED
YANGON: Myanmar officials on Wednesday announced November 8 as the date for a historic general election set to be the first contested by Aung San Suu Kyi's opposition in a quarter of a century.
The announcement fires the starting gun for the much-anticipated poll in the former junta-run nation, which has launched a series of reforms since the end of outright military rule in 2011.
"The general election will be held on November 8. The Union Election Commission will announce further details later," Thant Zin Aung, deputy director of Yangon's election commission, told AFP of the vote, which will select MPs for both houses of parliament.
A president will be chosen later by parliament, but Suu Kyi is barred by the constitution from taking the top job.
The Nobel laureate's National League for Democracy did not immediately confirm it would participate in the polls.
"We cannot say whether we will take part right now. We need to hold a meeting to make a decision," spokesman Nyan Win told AFP.
The party won nationwide polls in 1990, while Suu Kyi was under house arrest, but was prevented from taking power by the military.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 12:27:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No evidence of Jamaat-ud-Dawa's links with LeT</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47ef8597/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cpakistan0CNo0Eevidence0Eof0EJamaat0Eud0EDawas0Elinks0Ewith0ELeT0Carticleshow0C479868720Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pakistan has ruled out the possibility of declaring Jamaat-ud-Dawa (JuD) as a proscribed organization in the near future, saying that there was no evidence to prove that JuD was an offshoot or a front for the designated terror organization Lashkar-e-Taiba.</Description>
        <MainBody>READ MORE united nations | Lashkar-e-Taiba | Jamaat-ud-Dawa | Anti-Terrorism Act | Abdul Qadir
RELATED
ISLAMABAD: Pakistan has ruled out the possibility of declaring Jamaat-ud-Dawa (JuD) as a proscribed organization in the near future, saying that there was no evidence to prove that JuD was an offshoot or a front for the designated terror organization Lashkar-e-Taiba.
Gen (retired) Abdul Qadir Baloch, Minister for States and Frontier Regions, told the upper house on behalf of Interior Minister Chaudhry Nisar Ali Khan on Tuesday that the United Nations Security Council had in a resolution listed the JuD as LeT with a new name, but no supporting evidence had been shared with Pakistan to establish the connection.
He said the organization had been under observation since Nov 15, 2003 and all provinces had been asked to keep a watch on its activities. "The JuD will be proscribed under Anti-Terrorism Act if the federal government has reasons to believe that it is linked to terrorism," the minister said.
Under the law, the government can place any organization under observation for six months if it is suspected of being involved in terrorist activities. The period can be extended only after providing the organization an opportunity of being heard.
The minister said that JuD's offices remained closed between 2008 and 2010 but the Lahore High Court gave the relief to the organization. "Presently, JuD is engaged in charity and social work, operating hospitals, clinics, schools, ambulance service and religious institutions," he said.
Baluch said that Falah-i-Insaniat Foundation (FIF) had also been listed by the UNSC as a suspected charity having links with LeT, but did not say if it was also under observation.
In response to a question by Senator Farhatullah Babar of Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP), the minister said that any organization proscribed under provision of the Anti-Terrorism Act, 1997 was prohibited from any and all activities, including charity work under a different name. Babar had asked whether it was fact that banned militant outfits were not allowed to work under a different name or as charity organisation. He also asked was it a fact that JuD was a resurrection of a banned organization.
Senator Taj Haider, another PPP senator, revealed that JuD was holding congregations at 18 different places in Karachi and the Rangers, a paramilitary force, provided it security. He objected to the services being rendered by the Rangers to JuD.
The US and India have always considered JuD as front for Lashkar-e-Taiba, a militant group accused for 2008 Mumbai terror attacks which left 166 people dead. Last year the US state department had named JuD as a "foreign terrorist organization".
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=united nations,Lashkar-e-Taiba,Jamaat-ud-Dawa,Anti-Terrorism Act,Abdul Qadir
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 11:07:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen kill 3, wound 1 near Baltimore university: Police</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47eec267/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CGunmen0Ekill0E30Ewound0E10Enear0EBaltimore0Euniversity0EPolice0Carticleshow0C4798580A30Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Three people were killed and one was wounded when gunmen opened fire on a group of people on a street near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, police said on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Two gunmen emerged from two separate light-colored vans and began shooting people.
RELATED
Three people were killed and one was wounded when gunmen opened fire on a group of people on a street near the University of Maryland, Baltimore, police said on Wednesday.
Two gunmen emerged from two separate light-colored vans and began shooting people just before 11pm on Tuesday (0300 GMT Wednesday), campus police said in a statement.
A male was pronounced dead at the scene and a male and a female died while receiving medical treatment, the police said. The fourth victim, a woman, was hospitalized.
Police urged people in the area to exercise caution while the gunmen were sought.
The Baltimore Sun reported that shots were fired into a vehicle traveling on the same block five days ago.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Gunmen
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 10:53:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British tourists' high profile murder trial opens in Thailand</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47ee9da8/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Csouth0Easia0CBritish0Etourists0Ehigh0Eprofile0Emurder0Etrial0Eopens0Ein0EThailand0Carticleshow0C479856440Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Thai policeman described the harrowing moments he discovered the bodies of two British holidaymakers on Koh Tao island as the high-profile trial of two Myanmar migrants charged over their deaths opened Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World South Asia
Breaking News:
British tourists' high profile murder trial opens in Thailand
AFP | Jul 8, 2015, 01.23 PM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
READ MORE Thailand's reputation as a tourist haven | rape and robbery | Murder | high profile murder trial | could face the death penalty
Zaw Lin and Win Zaw Tun have both pleaded not guilty to the murder last September of 24-year-old David Miller and the rape and murder of Hannah Witheridge, 23, in a case that has tarnished Thailand's reputation as a tourist haven. (Reuters photo)
RELATED
KOH SAMUI, Thailand: A Thai policeman described the harrowing moments he discovered the bodies of two British holidaymakers on Koh Tao island as the high-profile trial of two Myanmar migrants charged over their deaths opened Wednesday.
Zaw Lin and Win Zaw Tun have both pleaded not guilty to the murder last September of 24-year-old David Miller and the rape and murder of Hannah Witheridge, 23, in a case that has tarnished Thailand's reputation as a tourist haven.
The two men, who have been in custody on neighbouring Koh Samui since October, arrived at court in a prison van with their feet shackled. They face several charges  including murder, rape and robbery  and if found guilty could face the death penalty.
Family members of the two British backpackers were also present as the trial began and the prosecution questioned their first witness, a policeman who found the tourists' bruised and battered bodies.
The officer described the awful scene as he discovered the lifeless Miller "face down" on the shallow surf followed by the body of Witheridge further up the beach. Police have said she was raped as well as beaten.
Their murders, just a few hundred yards from the main tourist drag in Koh Tao, sent shockwaves across the sleepy idyll in the Gulf of Thailand immensely popular with backpackers and divers.
But the prosecution has been marred by allegations of a bungled investigation with the defence team claiming the migrants, who worked for low wages in the tourism trade, were scapegoated by an under-pressure police force.
One of their key demands has been the opportunity to independently test controversial forensic evidence against their clients.
After the opening of the trial the judge said a decision on this would be made Thursday, according to an activist for a migrants group helping to fund the defence case, as journalists were asked to leave the small courtroom to make room for family members.
Earlier Wednesday the families of both victims released statements confirming they would attend the trial's opening at the imposing courthouse perched on a hill overlooking Samui's lush palm trees and white beaches.
"Just hours before he died David was talking to us with his usual enthusiasm, describing the beauty of Koh Tao and the friendliness of the Thai people," Miller's family said in their statement, adding that they hoped to "gain a better understanding" of how the young Brit died.
"Hannah was a beautiful person, inside and out, she brought a room alive just being there," the Witheridge family wrote in their statement.
"Her bright future was brutally ended leaving those who loved her broken with no answers."
Miller's parents and brother were present at court Wednesday as well as Witheridge's father and brother.
Both families have appealed for privacy from the press for the duration of the trial, which is expected to take place over 18 staggered days between now and September with a verdict due in October.
The killings came as the country's vital tourism industry was beginning to recover from months of violent street protests that culminated in the May 2014 military coup.
The case also shone a light on Thailand's many underpaid and often exploited Myanmar migrant workers who fill the lucrative tourist sector.
The pair's defence team have long criticised the police investigation, claiming the crime scene was contaminated and that their clients were tortured into admitting guilt.
Both men retracted their initial confessions, saying they were coerced into making them.
The defence team had also complained about not being given access to the forensic evidence, despite the court initially ruling in April that they could run their own independent tests.
Andy Hall, an activist for the Migrant Worker Rights Network helping to fund the pair's case, told AFP he felt "confident" the judge would "allow" the tests the defence team have been demanding for months.
"There's a real lack of adequate disclosure by the prosecution and that worries us about whether there will be a fair trial," Hall had said before the judge confirmed a decision on the matter would be reached Thursday.
The forensic material from the crime scene has been used by Thai police and prosecutors to insist they have charged the right men, saying it strongly points to the Myanmar pair as the perpetrators.
The victims' families have also previously said they have confidence in the case after British investigators reported back to them following a visit to Thailand late last year.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Thailand's reputation as a tourist haven,rape and robbery,Murder,high profile murder trial,could face the death penalty
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 10:52:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US to cut 40,000 soldiers from army: Official</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47eeef33/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CUS0Eto0Ecut0E40A0A0A0A0Esoldiers0Efrom0Earmy0EOfficial0Carticleshow0C47985630A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The US army is to cut 40,000 soldiers from its ranks over the next two years at home and abroad, a defense official said on Tuesday, in a move that will raise doubts about its ability to fight wars.</Description>
        <MainBody>ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
The paper quoted a document it had obtained and said the cuts are being made to save money.
RELATED
WASHINGTON: The US army is to cut 40,000 soldiers from its ranks over the next two years at home and abroad, a defense official said on Tuesday, in a move that will raise doubts about its ability to fight wars.
Under the cost-cutting plan, the Army will be down to 450,000 soldiers at the end of the 2017 budget year, even though in 2013 it argued in budgetary documents that going below 450,000 troops might mean it could not win a war, USA Today said.
By comparison, the army swelled to 570,000 men and women during the peak of fighting in Iraq and Afghanistan, the newspaper said.
Some 17,000 civilians working for the Army will also be laid off, the official told AFP, confirming the USA Today report.
The paper quoted a document it had obtained and said the cuts are being made to save money.
It will affect virtually every Army post domestically and abroad, USA Today said
The defense official told AFP that the Army plans to announce the cuts soon, with USA Today adding that the matter would be addressed this week.
Across-the-board government budget cuts are due to kick in in October and if Congress does not avert these the Army will have to lay off another 30,000 soldiers on top of the 40,000, according to the document quoted by USA Today.
It comes just a day after President Barack Obama said that the US-led coalition fighting the Islamic State group would step up its campaign in Syria, while cautioning a long battle remained.
Brigades stationed at Fort Benning in Georgia and Joint Base Elmendorf-Richardson in Alaska will be among those downsized, USA Today said.
Senator Dan Sullivan, a Republican from Alaska, told the paper that the cutdown "makes no strategic sense."
More than a year after ISIS fighters overran much of Iraq and Syria, the United States and its allies are struggling to turn the tide against the extremists in an air campaign known as Operation Inherent Resolve.
The Pentagon last month said it was sending 450 additional US troops to act as advisers to help Iraqi forces seize back control of the western city of Ramadi from jihadist fighters.
Speaking to reporters after a briefing at the Pentagon on Monday, Obama warned the war "will not be quick. This is a long-term campaign."
He added that more needed to be done to train government forces and Sunni tribal fighters in Iraq, as well as moderate Syrian rebels.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
