<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="USATODAY">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99933308/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Boko-Haram-offers-to-swap-kidnapped-girls-for-detainees/</Link>
        <Description>Boko Haram's offer is limited to the girls taken in April 2014.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees
Boko Haram's offer is limited to the girls taken in April 2014.
Post to Facebook
Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees Boko Haram's offer is limited to the girls taken in April 2014. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mf22CM
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Boko Haram offers to swap kidnapped girls for detainees
Michelle Faul, Associated Press 12:23 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
The parents of children abducted by Boko Haram attend an event linked to the "Bring Back Our Girls" campaign at the presidential residence in Abuja, Nigeria, on July 8, 2015.
(Photo: Olamikan Gbemiga, AP)
12 CONNECT 56 TWEET LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
LAGOS, Nigeria (AP)  Nigeria's Boko Haram extremists are offering to free more than 200 young women and girls kidnapped from a boarding school in the town of Chibok in exchange for the release of militant leaders held by the government, a human rights activist has told The Associated Press.
The activist said Boko Haram's current offer is limited to the girls from the school in northeastern Nigeria whose mass abduction in April 2014 ignited worldwide outrage and a campaign to "Bring Back Our Girls" that stretched to the White House.
The new initiative reopens an offer made last year to the government of former President Goodluck Jonathan to release the 219 students in exchange for 16 Boko Haram detainees, the activist said. The man, who was involved in negotiations with Boko Haram last year and is close to current negotiators, spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to talk to reporters on this sensitive issue.
Fred Eno, an apolitical Nigerian who has been negotiating with Boko Haram for more than a year, told the AP that "another window of opportunity opened" in the last few days, though he could not discuss details.
He said the recent slew of Boko Haram bloodletting   some 350 people killed in the past nine days  is consistent with past ratcheting up of violence as the militants seek a stronger negotiating position.
Presidential adviser Femi Adesina said on Saturday that Nigeria's government "will not be averse" to talks with Boko Haram. "Most wars, however furious or vicious, often end around the negotiation table," he said.
Eno said the 5-week-old administration of President Muhammadu Buhari offers "a clean slate" to bring the militants back to negotiations that had become poisoned by the different security agencies and their advice to Jonathan.
Two months of talks last year led government representatives and Eno to travel in September to a northeastern town where the prisoner exchange was to take place, only to be stymied by the Department for State Service intelligence agency, the activist said.
At the last minute, the agency said it was holding only four of the militants sought by Boko Haram, the activist said.
It is not known how many Boko Haram suspects are detained by Nigeria's intelligence agency, whose chief Buhari fired last week.
The activist said the agency continues to hold suspects illegally because it does not have enough evidence for a conviction, and any court would free them. Nigerian law requires charges be brought after 48 hours.
Thousands of suspects have died in custody, and some detainees wanted by Boko Haram may be among them. Amnesty International alleges that 8,000 detainees have died in military custody  some have been shot, some have died from untreated injuries due to torture, and some have died from starvation and other harsh treatment.
In May, about 300 women, girls and children being held captive by Boko Haram were rescued by Nigeria's military, but none were from Chibok. It is believed that the militants view the Chibok girls as a last-resort bargaining chip.
In that infamous abduction, 274 mostly Christian girls preparing to write science exams were seized from the school by Islamic militants in the early hours of April 15, 2014. Dozens escaped on their own in the first few days, but 219 remain missing.
Boko Haram has not shown them since a May 2014 video in which its leader, Abubakar Shekau warned: "You won't see the girls again unless you release our brothers you have captured."
In the video, nearly 100 of the girls, who have been identified by their parents, were shown wearing Islamic hijab and reciting the Quran. One of them said they had converted to Islam.
International indignation at Nigeria's failure to rescue the girls was joined by U.S. first lady Michelle Obama. In a radio address in May 2014, she said she and President Barack Obama are "outraged and heartbroken" over the abduction.
Jonathan's government initially denied there had been any mass abduction and delays of a rescue that might have brought the girls home became a hallmark of his other failures. He steadfastly refused to meet with the Bring Back Our Girls campaigners, charging they were politicizing the issue.
On Wednesday, President Buhari welcomed those campaigners at the presidential villa in Abuja and pleaded "We only ask for your patience." He said "The delay and conflicting reaction by the former government and its agencies is very unfortunate."
Campaign leader Oby Ezekwesili said, "The rescue of our Chibok girls is the strongest statement that this government could make to showg respect for the sanctity and dignity of every Nigerian life."
There have been unconfirmed reports that some of the girls have been taken to neighboring countries, and that some have been radicalized and trained as fighters. At least three were reported to have died  one from dysentery, one from malaria and one from a snake bite.
Last year, Shekau said the girls were an "old story," and that he had married them off to his fighters.
Lawan Zanna, whose daughter is among the captives, said this week that 14 Chibok parents have died since the mass kidnapping, many from stress-related illnesses blamed on the ordeal.
Some of the Chibok girls who managed to escape have been rejected by their community and now live with family friends, tired of hearing taunts like "Boko Haram wives."
The assumption that all girls and women held by the group have been raped is a difficult stigma to overcome in Nigeria's highly religious and conservative society.
Shekau had threatened in 2013 to kidnap women and girls if Nigeria's military did not release detained Boko Haram wives and children. The government freed them in May of that year as a goodwill gesture ahead of failed peace talks.
Boko Haram has kidnapped hundreds more  girls, boys, women and young men. Some have become sex slaves, while others are used as fighters, according to former captives.
Nigerian opinion on negotiating with the extremists is mixed. Some say the group's crimes are too heinous to be forgiven: The 6-year-old Islamic uprising has killed more than 13,000 people and forced about 1.5 million from their homes.
"A lot of people take a hard-line stance that you must never negotiate with a terrorist," said Sen. Chris Anyanwu. She called it a "very complex" issue, balancing the lives of more than 200 girls against the dangers of freeing extremists.
The militants last year seized a large swath of northeast Nigeria and declared an Islamic caliphate. Nigeria and its neighbors deployed a multinational army that forced them out of towns and villages this year, but the bloodshed has risen at a fierce rate since Buhari's May 29 inauguration amid pledges to crush the insurgency.
Associated Press writer Bashir Adigun contributed to this report from Abuja, Nigeria.
12 CONNECT 56 TWEET LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1Mf22CM
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:36:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>El-Nino Fuelled Drought Hits Thailand's Economy</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99998402/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~ElNino-Fuelled-Drought-Hits-Thailands-Economy/</Link>
        <Description>July 9 -- After reaping unsustainable levels of rice from Shinawatra years, Thailand is facing another struggle. Water restrictions are in place in almost a third of provinces and economists are warning of a severe impact on growth. Bloomberg's Sher</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
El-Nino Fuelled Drought Hits Thailand's Economy
July 9 -- After reaping unsustainable levels of rice from Shinawatra years, Thailand is facing another struggle. Water restrictions are in place in almost a third of provinces and economists are warning of a severe impact on growth. Bloomberg's Sher
Post to Facebook
El-Nino Fuelled Drought Hits Thailand's Economy July 9 -- After reaping unsustainable levels of rice from Shinawatra years, Thailand is facing another struggle. Water restrictions are in place in almost a third of provinces and economists are warning of a severe impact on growth. Bloomberg's Sher Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MgjVBf
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
El-Nino Fuelled Drought Hits Thailand's Economy
July 9 -- After reaping unsustainable levels of rice from Shinawatra years, Thailand is facing another struggle. Water restrictions are in place in almost a third of provinces and economists are warning of a severe impact on growth. Bloomberg's Sher Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 04:15:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Opening Uganda's closet</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99997154/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Opening-Ugandas-closet/</Link>
        <Description>Can Uganda's gay-rights activists stop the government from  enacting another homophobic law?</Description>
        <MainBody>Can Uganda's gay-rights activists stop the government from  enacting another homophobic law?
Post to Facebook
Opening Uganda's closet Can Uganda's gay-rights activists stop the government from  enacting another homophobic law? Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IKwjuo
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Opening Uganda's closet
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:16:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What a 'Grexit' could mean for Greece and the U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99968970/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~What-a-Grexit-could-mean-for-Greece-and-the-US/</Link>
        <Description>USA TODAY economics reporter Paul Davidson sits down with Shannon Rae Green to discuss what Greece leaving the Eurozone could mean for both Greeks and Americans.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
What a 'Grexit' could mean for Greece and the U.S.
USA TODAY economics reporter Paul Davidson sits down with Shannon Rae Green to discuss what Greece leaving the Eurozone could mean for both Greeks and Americans.
Post to Facebook
What a 'Grexit' could mean for Greece and the U.S. USA TODAY economics reporter Paul Davidson sits down with Shannon Rae Green to discuss what Greece leaving the Eurozone could mean for both Greeks and Americans. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IK24ns
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
What a 'Grexit' could mean for Greece and the U.S.
USA TODAY economics reporter Paul Davidson sits down with Shannon Rae Green to discuss what Greece leaving the Eurozone could mean for both Greeks and Americans. Paul Davidson, Shannon Rae Green, Jasper Colt, USA TODAY
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 23:02:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pete Peterson: America can't afford Greek complacency</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99953724/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Pete-Peterson-America-cant-afford-Greek-complacency/</Link>
        <Description>As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pete Peterson: America can't afford Greek complacency
As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest.
Post to Facebook
Pete Peterson: America can't afford Greek complacency As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MfpShQ
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Pete Peterson: America can't afford Greek complacency
Peter G. Peterson 4:02 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest.
Pensioners line up at the main gate of the national bank of Greece in Athens on July 7, 2015.
(Photo: Emilio Morenatti, AP)
17 CONNECT 25 TWEET 6 LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
The world watches as the Greek tragedy unfolds, as pensioners continue to line up at shuttered banks, desperately attempting to withdraw some of their life savings.  These heartbreaking images show us what a debt crisis really looks like, as Greece's economy is in free fall and its most vulnerable citizens are so profoundly affected.
As a first-generation Greek American, I have more than a passing interest in Greece's condition (my father changed his name to Peterson from Petropoulos, which means "son of Peter").  But I also care deeply about the enduring opportunity for every citizen of the United States to live out the American Dream that I have been so blessed to live.
With more than 60% voting a resounding "no" on a proposed European financing offer, Europe and Greece face fundamental questions about where they go from here.  Greece has unfortunately left itself with few good options.
The world is focused on critical near-term questions, but it is important to remember that the seeds of this despair were planted long before the recent crisis began.  Although austerity measures and currency limitations made matters worse, Greece has faced imbalances between spending and revenues over many years, and the resulting high level of debt gave the Greeks little flexibility for dealing with the current fiscal and economic crisis once it began.
EU technocrats bleed Greece dry: Other views
Unfortunately, now there are no quick fixes or painless paths forward.  The country is left with limited and poor options to stabilize the economy and provide relief, potentially relying on other nations to dictate the terms of their future.  Indeed, the better time to act was well before the crisis.
There are countless differences between the circumstances of the U.S. and Greece. We are in a fundamentally better position and are nowhere near this kind of economic crisis.
Nonetheless, there are important lessons to be learned about the benefits of long-term planning and maintaining fiscal health and flexibility.
Without question, the United States remains on a fiscal path that is unsustainable and dangerous by any international standard.  Last month's non-partisan Congressional Budget Office analysis projects that by 2040, federal debt will climb to more than 100% of gross domestic product based on current laws, and would reach 175% of GDP under less optimistic assumptions. Debt at that level, CBO warns, would significantly harm our economy, reduce incomes and increase the chances of a fiscal crisis.
As just one staggering data point, interest costs alone will reach $5.5 trillion over the next decade , and are on a path to exceed all federal revenues. That's an absurd fiscal trajectory for any country to put itself on  including and especially a strong nation such as America.
While American debt can inflict pain on its citizens the same way that Greece's has, one critical comparative advantage we have is time.  This time gives us a wider range of options to choose from, and to make decisions on our own terms.  Because a major fiscal crisis is not right in front of us, we can implement reforms that are sensible, gradual and compassionate.
Europe must back away from Greek austerity cliff: Joseph Stiglitz
There are major benefits of putting the U.S. on a stable fiscal path.  A strong fiscal foundation is key to increasing incomes, prosperity and opportunity.  With lower interest costs, we will have more resources available for important private and public investments that improve productivity and competitiveness.  And fiscal strength is essential to maintaining a safety net for the most vulnerable, and to our ability to respond to unforeseen crises, foreign and domestic.
It is often hard for the U.S. to make politically difficult choices in the absence of an immediate crisis.  But complacency carries a cost.  A growing debt burden hurts our economy well in advance of any crisis.  And sadly, the situation in Greece is showing us how high the costs of a full crisis can be.
My father often reminded me of the Greek concept of  or "economia"  the importance of saving for the future.  I am sure he is looking down on Greece with great concern, but with the hope that his beloved America will take advantage of the opportunity it has to solve its own fiscal challenges.
Peter G. Peterson is the founder and chairman of the Peter G. Peterson Foundation , the chairman emeritus of the Council on Foreign Relations, the former secretary of Commerce and the co-founder of the Blackstone Group.
In addition to its own editorials, USA TODAY publishes diverse opinions from outside writers, including our Board of Contributors . To read more columns like this, go to the Opinion front page .
17 CONNECT 25 TWEET 6 LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MfpShQ
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 22:10:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia vetoes U.N. resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99952308/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Russia-vetoes-UN-resolution-calling-Srebrenica-a-genocide/</Link>
        <Description>Russia says singling out Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Russia vetoes U.N. resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide
Russia vetoed a U.N. resolution Wednesday that would have condemned the 1995 massacre of Muslims at Srebrenica during the Bosnian war as a "crime of genocide," saying that singling out the Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division in the Balkans.
Post to Facebook
Russia vetoes U.N. resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide Russia vetoed a U.N. resolution Wednesday that would have condemned the 1995 massacre of Muslims at Srebrenica during the Bosnian war as a "crime of genocide," saying that singling out the Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division in the Balkans. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MfmBiI
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
4
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Russia vetoes U.N. resolution calling Srebrenica a genocide
Edith M. Lederer, Associated Press 3:10 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Bosnian people visit graves at memorial center in Potocari near Srebrenica, Bosnia, on July 8, 2015.
(Photo: Amel Emric, AP)
24 CONNECT 40 TWEET LINKEDIN 4 COMMENTEMAILMORE
UNITED NATIONS (AP)  Russia vetoed a U.N. resolution Wednesday that would have condemned the 1995 massacre of Muslims at Srebrenica during the Bosnian war as a "crime of genocide," saying that singling out the Bosnian Serbs for a war crime would create greater division in the Balkans.
Two international courts have called the slaughter by Bosnian Serbs of some 8,000 Muslim men and boys who had sought refuge at what was supposed to be a U.N.-protected site genocide.
But Russia's U.N. Ambassador Vitaly Churkin objected to focusing only on Srebrenica, calling the resolution "confrontational and politically motivated" and stressing that Bosnian Serbs and Croats had also suffered during the 1992-95 war that killed at least 100,000 people.
Britain drafted the resolution to mark the 20th anniversary of the Srebrenica massacre on Tuesday, but the vote was delayed to address Russian concerns.
The defeated resolution states that acceptance of "the tragic events at Srebrenica as genocide is a prerequisite for reconciliation" and "condemns denial of this genocide as hindering efforts towards reconciliation."
Britain's U.N. deputy ambassador Peter Wilson stressed that the resolution "did not point fingers of blame, score political points nor seek to reopen political divisions." It also didn't link the crimes at Srebrenica to the Serb people and recognized there were victims on all sides, he said.
The vote was 10 countries in favor, Russia casting a veto, and four abstentions  China, Nigeria, Angola and Venezuela.
Leaders of the Bosnian Serbs and Serbia, who have close religious and cultural ties to Russia, have lobbied President Vladimir Putin to vote "no.'
Serbia's pro-Russian President Tomislav Nikolic said Russia's veto "not only prevented the throwing of guilt against the whole Serbian nation, trying to show it as  genocidal, but it also proved that Russia is a real and sincere friend."
Wilson said Britain was "outraged" by Russia's veto.
"Russia's actions tarnish the memory of all those who died in the Srebrenica genocide," he said. "Russia will have to justify its behavior to the families of over 8,000 people murdered in the worst atrocity in Europe since the Second World War."
Bosnians reacted bitterly to the veto.
"This is a defeat of justice," said Camil Durakovic, the mayor of Srebrenica. "The world has lost. The world  and especially Serbia  will have to face the truth sooner or later," he said.
Fadila Efendic, a Srebrenica woman who lost her son and husband in the Srebrenica massacre, called the veto "another humiliation of the victims."
"Today's vote mattered," said U.S. Ambassador Samantha Power, who was a 24-year-old journalist in Bosnia at the time of the Srebrenica massacre. "It mattered hugely to the families of the victims of the Srebrenica genocide. Russia's veto is heartbreaking for those families, and it is a further stain on this council's record."
Russia's Churkin began his speech before the vote asking for a minute of silence in memory of the victims of Srebrenica and everyone in the Security Council stood, many bowing their heads.
Instead of Srebrenica, he said the council should commemorate the 20th anniversary of the 1995 peace agreement signed in Dayton, Ohio that ended the Bosnian war later this year, and make every effort to implement it and normalize relations in the Balkans.
"Our vote against ... will, however, not mean that we are deaf to the suffering of victims of Srebrenica and other areas of Bosnia and Herzegovina," Churkin said.
Associated Press writers Aida Cerkez in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Dusan Stojanovic in Belgrade contributed to this report.
24 CONNECT 40 TWEET LINKEDIN 4 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MfmBiI
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 21:14:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WikiLeaks: NSA targeted German chancellery, Merkel aides</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99946246/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~WikiLeaks-NSA-targeted-German-chancellery-Merkel-aides/</Link>
        <Description>There was no immediate comment from the German government.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
WikiLeaks: NSA targeted German chancellery, Merkel aides
WikiLeaks on Wednesday published a new list of German phone numbers it claims showed the U.S. National Security Agency targeted phones belonging to Chancellor Angela Merkel's close aides and chancellery offices for surveillance.
Post to Facebook
WikiLeaks: NSA targeted German chancellery, Merkel aides WikiLeaks on Wednesday published a new list of German phone numbers it claims showed the U.S. National Security Agency targeted phones belonging to Chancellor Angela Merkel's close aides and chancellery offices for surveillance. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MffFlD
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
WikiLeaks: NSA targeted German chancellery, Merkel aides
AP 2:14 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Visiting German Chancellor Angela Merkel speaks during a news conference after meeting with Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama, on the first stop of her Balkan tour in Tirana on July 8, 2015.
(Photo: Hektor Pustina, AP)
8 CONNECT 47 TWEET LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
BERLIN (AP)  WikiLeaks on Wednesday published a new list of German phone numbers it claims showed the U.S. National Security Agency targeted phones belonging to Chancellor Angela Merkel's close aides and chancellery offices for surveillance.
Wednesday's publication came a week after WikiLeaks released a list of numbers it said showed the NSA targeted officials at various other German ministries and elsewhere. That rekindled concerns over U.S. surveillance in Germany after reports two years ago that Merkel's own cellphone was targeted.
Merkel's chief of staff last week asked the U.S. ambassador to a meeting and told him that German law must be followed.
There was no immediate comment from the German government on the latest publication.
The list includes a cellphone number attributed to Ronald Pofalla, Merkel's chief of staff from 2009-13; a landline number that appears to belong to the leader of Merkel's parliamentary caucus; various other connections at Merkel's office; and a cellphone number for the chancellor that WikiLeaks says was used until 2013.
It was unclear when exactly the partially redacted list of 56 German phone numbers dates from and it wasn't immediately possible to confirm the accuracy of that and other documents released by WikiLeaks.
Those documents, WikiLeaks said, are NSA reports based on interceptions  including one from 2009 that details Merkel's views on the international financial crisis and another from 2011 summarizing advisers' views on plans for the eurozone's rescue fund.
According to the secret-spilling site, the list of phone numbers was updated for more than a decade after 2002 and a "close study" of it shows it evolved from an earlier target list dating back into the 1990s.
8 CONNECT 47 TWEET LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MffFlD
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:26:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Voices: Like post-earthquake Nepal, Red God is in limbo</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99941880/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Voices-Like-postearthquake-Nepal-Red-God-is-in-limbo/</Link>
        <Description>The god, stalled in the midst of its pilgrimage, symbolizes the plight of Nepal.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Voices: Like post-earthquake Nepal, Red God is in limbo
Like more than 3 million Nepalis, the Red God is homeless. Since the 7.8 magnitude earthquake on April 25, his enormous wooden chariot, with its towering jute and vine spire, has been
Post to Facebook
Voices: Like post-earthquake Nepal, Red God is in limbo Like more than 3 million Nepalis, the Red God is homeless. Since the 7.8 magnitude earthquake on April 25, his enormous wooden chariot, with its towering jute and vine spire, has been Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MfaH8u
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Voices: Like post-earthquake Nepal, Red God is in limbo
Donatella Lorch, Special for USA TODAY 5:26 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Like more than 3 million Nepalis, the Red God is homeless. Since the magnitude-7.8 earthquake on April 25, 2015, his enormous wooden chariot, with its towering jute and vine spire, has been parked, or rather stopped, in the middle of a street just up the road from where I live. The spire, leaning precipitously even before the earthquake, is secured with two heavy ropes tied to nearby trees.
(Photo: Donatella Lorch)
19 CONNECT 63 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
LALITPUR, Nepal  Like more than 3 million Nepalis, the Red God is homeless. Since the magnitude-7.8 earthquake on April 25, his enormous wooden chariot, with its towering jute and vine spire, has been parked, or rather stopped, in the middle of a street just up the road from where I live. The spire, leaning precipitously even before the earthquake, is secured with two heavy ropes tied to nearby trees.
The god, known as the Rato Machhendranath, is never alone.  There is always a Hindu or Buddhist priest sitting next to him in his tiny alcove, perched 10 feet above the street, and always two shotgun-toting police officers to guard him as well. Worshipers light butter lamps on the road below him and passersby on motorcycles slow down, touching their foreheads and then the huge carved and brightly painted wooden wheels, demonstrating 'puja' or prayer.
The symbolism of this stalled chariot is not lost on many people in the Kathmandu Valley. In growing competition with a fast-encroaching modern world, this is a land of deep and complex religious rituals, an intricate mix of Hinduism and tantric Buddhism practiced by the Newars, the original inhabitants of the valley. Their traditional villages of brick and mud homes, dotting the area around Kathmandu, were hit hardest by the earthquake.
The Red God's home is in Bungamati, a Newar village just south of Patan, Kathmandu's twin city.  In just over 40 seconds, the April earthquake destroyed or badly damaged almost the entire village. The god's home, a temple in the main square, turned into a pile of rubble.
"We have been stopped here for two months," said Shaunu Shakya, 65, a priest who is accompanying the Red God. "Never in the history of the festival has an earthquake come. The astrologers say we must complete our trip, but that we also cannot move until the aftershocks stop for at least four days."
Machhendranath's limbo is very much Nepal's as it struggles to rebuild, its past damaged and its future uncertain. More than two months since the quake, it is slowly becoming clearer that the tremors, which continue on a daily basis, did more than just destroy homes. They are continuously influencing a way of life and thinking. For many, especially outside Kathmandu, it is a day-to-day struggle for food and shelter. Heavy monsoon rains are destabilizing the earthquakecracked mountains, and landslides have already begun to sweep away villages in the north and east of the country. The international community has committed more than $4 billion to help rebuild Nepal, but that complex work will only begin in early September.
I've lived in Nepal for two years, and for much of that time, I had planned to be in Kathmandu for April 2015.  This April was one of Nepal's most unique festivals, the storied Rato Machhendranath jatra, which occurs only once every 12 years. It is not only one of the largest and longest chariot festivals in the world, lasting two to four months depending on the determinations of local astrologers, but also a massive spectacle involving months of priestly rituals, many animal sacrifices, the construction of the chariot (by hand) and tens of thousands of spectators.
The Red God isn't really much to look at. He is a smallish enigma, just over 3 feet tall, wrapped in shapeless cloth. Every year, a priest gives his flattish wide face a bright new coat of red paint. He is worshiped by both Hindus and Buddhists. He is all powerful, but humans can summon him at will.
The event begins in Bungamati, about 8 kilometers south of Patan, where carpenter clans build the 6-foot-high wooden wheels from scratch, without nails, and vine lashers hand-tie a complex and thick weave of tree trunks, cane and vines into a 60-foot-high spire, called a 'rath.' The chariot is hand-pulled with thick ropes by hundreds of youths.
On April 25, the rath  was about 500 yards from our house. My son Lucas and I were invited to watch the afternoon pulling from the rooftop of a nearby house. An hour later, the earthquake hit Nepal.
There are those who believe that the earthquake happened because the Red God's chariot was built without fully observing construction rituals. Many Nepalis do not believe in these superstitions. Yet there is a link between this festival and life in Nepal. The complexities involved in building and moving the chariot are emblematic of an old world of risk and contingency, where ancient rituals must be observed in an effort to ensure stability, if not progress, and where the line between triumph and disaster is often very fine.
The earthquake brought communities together. Neighbors are helping neighbors. Many are living in transitional shelters, trying to get through the monsoons and the upcoming winter, until they have the means to rebuild their houses.  The Red God's permanent temple will also need to be rebuilt, and he will need to live elsewhere while that happens. But he is not alone, and like many Nepalis, he and his devotees also show the tremendous resilience for which Nepal is famous.
Lorch is a writer based in Nepal
19 CONNECT 63 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MfaH8u
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 19:38:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99933312/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~White-House-ready-to-let-Iran-talks-continue-indefinitely/</Link>
        <Description>GOP lawmakers say getting a good deal is more important than meeting  a deadline.</Description>
        <MainBody>White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely
An interim agreement in November 2013 required Iran to scale back its nuclear activities.
Post to Facebook
White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely An interim agreement in November 2013 required Iran to scale back its nuclear activities. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mf1tco
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
17
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
White House ready to let Iran talks continue indefinitely
Oren Dorell , USA TODAY 12:38 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
White House press secretary Josh Earnest answers a question on the Iran nuclear talks during the daily press briefing on July 7, 2015.
(Photo: Evan Vucci, AP)
45 CONNECT 78 TWEET LINKEDIN 17 COMMENTEMAILMORE
After missing two deadlines in a week, the White House may allow Iran nuclear talks to continue indefinitely under an interim agreement that already limits Iran's nuclear program.
While the pressure of deadlines set for June 30 and Tuesday succeeded in squeezing important concessions from Iran, "we haven't gotten everything that we wanted yet," White House spokesman Josh Earnest said.
"What we want to make sure of is that we continue to keep in place, an agreement that freezes Iran's nuclear program, rolls it back in some key areas, while we continue to have these conversations," he said.
The negotiations in Vienna between Iran and six world powers  the United States, Britain, France, Russia, China and Germany  aim to curb Iran's nuclear program in return for lifting crippling U.S. and international sanctions on Tehran. Envoys now seek a conclusion by Friday.
Secretary of State John Kerry, left, meets with his counterparts from world powers and Iran at nuclear talks in Vienna on July 6, 2015.
(Photo: Joe Klamar, AFP/Getty Images)
Each time a deadline for the talks is extended,  the negotiators must agree to extend the date of the terms of the interim agreement reached in November 2013 .
Iran's deputy foreign minister, Abbas Araqchi, told reporters in Vienna that Iran is not bound by any deadline and will stay in Vienna as long as it takes, but that there will be no months-long extension to the talks, according to Tasnim News Agency.
Negotiators have made progress on several major sticking areas where the sides seemed far apart two weeks ago. These include tentative agreements by Iran to answer questions by the U.N. nuclear watchdog agency about past nuclear research, and to participate in a process for granting inspectors access to suspected civilian and military nuclear sites.
Diplomats have also reached a tentative agreement on the timing for the lifting of sanctions, which Iran wants eliminated immediately and the United States wants lifted in stages as an agreement is implemented.
Differences remain, however, on whether those sanctions will be suspended, as Western nations want, so they can be reimposed if Iran fails to meet terms of the agreement, or eliminated for good, as Iran would like.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:59:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The day in pictures</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/95533850/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~The-day-in-pictures/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Children play in a fountain on the banks of the Manzanares river in Madrid.
Post to Facebook
The day in pictures Children play in a fountain on the banks of the Manzanares river in Madrid. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1SbnRa4
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
The day in pictures
Children play in a fountain on the banks of the Manzanares river in Madrid.
Dani pozo, AFP/Getty Images
Afghanistan's National Army soldiers stand guard during a visit by Afghanistan's Chief Executive, Abdullah Abdullah, in a military camp in Kelagai, Afghanistan.
Massoud Hossaini, AP
Fullscreen
A gull flips a herring to swallow it whole while flying away with a meal robbed from a delivery truck in Rockland, Me. Herring is primarily used for lobster bait, with a small percentage of it going to the sardine industry.
Robert F. Bukaty, AP
People watch as El Tajo y La Reina fighting bulls and revelers run during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival, in Pamplona, Spain.
Andres Kudacki, AP
A Palestinian family sits outside their house, damaged during the 2014 Israel-Gaza conflict, while fasting during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan.
Mohammed Saber, epa
Lightning strikes during a heavy storm over Poznan, Poland.
Lukasz Ogrodowczyk epa
Fullscreen
A young Filipino buys food from a vendor on a flooded street in Malabon, Philippines.  According to the Philippines State weather forecast, heavy rainfall is expected in metro Manila and nearby provinces due to an enhanced Southwest monsoon and tropical storm.
Francis R. Malasig, epa
This young girl enjoys sledding at the Snow Town park in Bangkok, Thailand.  Amid the heat, humidity and high temperatures of Bangkok, the newly opened Snow Town themed park attracts local and foreign tourists.
Rungroj Yongrit, epa
A boy jumps from a bridge into the Dnipro River in Kiev, Ukraine. The area is experiencing high summer temperatures.
Roman Pilipey, epa
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 09 00:51:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kids who survived Gaza war are living a nightmare, report finds</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99919656/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Kids-who-survived-Gaza-war-are-living-a-nightmare-report-finds/</Link>
        <Description>For Gaza's children, last year's war was the third conflict here they have seen.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Kids who survived Gaza war are living a nightmare, report finds
For Gaza's children, last year's war was the third conflict here they have seen in their short lives.
Post to Facebook
Kids who survived Gaza war are living a nightmare, report finds For Gaza's children, last year's war was the third conflict here they have seen in their short lives. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MeLSt8
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
15
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Kids who survived Gaza war are living a nightmare, report finds
Laura Dean, GlobalPost 5:51 p.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Israel and the Palestinians mark one year since last summer's devastating war in the Gaza Strip on Wednesday, with a ceasefire still largely holding but few of the issues that led to the conflict resolved. For Robert Turner, UNRWA's Director of Oper Newslook
Palestinian children play in the rubble of houses destroyed during the 50-day war last year between Israel and Hamas militants in the village of Khuzaa, east of Khan Yunis, in the southern Gaza Strip on July 7, 2015.
(Photo: Said Khatib, AFP/Getty Images)
138 CONNECT 65 TWEET LINKEDIN 15 COMMENTEMAILMORE
GAZA CITY, Gaza Strip  "Out of my five daughters, the only one uninjured in the war was Nada, and now she doesn't talk," a mother in Gaza says of her young child in a a new Save the Children report. "She cries a lot. She is exhausted all the time, suffers nightmares."
For Gaza's children, last year's war with Israel wasn't just a horrific summer of violence. It was the third conflict here children 7 and older have seen in their short lives.
They live with the effects every day.
Seven out of 10 children in the hardest hit areas of the Gaza Strip experience nightmares, according the report, which doesn't provide the names of those it interviewed. Three-quarters of them regularly wet their beds  a common issue for children that trauma can make worse. In al-Shoka, a neighborhood in the southern part of the Strip, half of the children interviewed wet the bed every night.
Save the Children collected data in April and May looking at the mental health of children ages 6 to 15. They found that those living in the hardest hit areas showed "unexpectedly high levels of continued severe emotional distress and trauma."
A total of 2,205 Palestinians were killed during the fighting last summer, most of them civilians and 521 of them children, according to the United Nations. Seven civilians and 66 Israeli soldiers were killed in Israel.
Some children now say they are afraid to leave their homes; others feel unsafe in school buildings. Some who moved to new areas after their homes were bombed say they feel too anxious to try to make friends in their new schools.
At the start of the academic year, schools across Gaza spent the first few weeks providing psychosocial support to students who had endured 51 days of bombing. They were also learning to cope with the empty desks in their classrooms and deaths in their families.
Save the Children figures say 551 Gazan children were killed in the fighting and 3,436 were injured. Around 10% of the injured will be disabled for the rest of their lives. An estimated 1,500 lost parents.
About 100,000 people remain homeless in Gaza. Significant reconstruction of health facilities, water networks and schools has not yet started because of the ongoing blockade, which restricts access to materials, and funding shortfalls.
For many children in Gaza, the war never ended. They continue to experience it "in their nightmares, their games, silently, in quiet corners, in their memories," the report said.
Many young people saw things that would be hard for even seasoned adults to recover from.
"My children were in the street (during the war) and saw the body pieces on the street after a shelling. My son is now traumatized, and my daughter has nightmares and wakes up frightened. I don't know how to help them," one mother told Save the Children.
In some areas children still play atop rubble that hasn't been cleared. Parents say their games are often violent and reflect scenes from wars they have seen. A particularly popular one is "Israelis and Palestinians"  which is a lot like "Cowboys and Indians" of the 1950s United States.
Even during peaceful times, the specter of bombardment lurks close by. Drones and F-16s buzz overhead  children can tell you the difference between the sounds  and the Israeli security forces frequently shoot into border areas.
More than 70% of the children interviewed said they are afraid there will be another war. Some reported feeling trapped, unable to escape. "Our future is gone," one 14-year-old said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 17:23:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Can China stop the stock rout?</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99916686/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Can-China-stop-the-stock-rout/</Link>
        <Description>July 8  -- China's securities regulator banned major shareholders, corporate executives and directors from selling stakes in listed companies for six months, the latest effort to stop a $3.5 trillion rout in the nation's equity market.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Can China stop the stock rout?
July 8  -- China's securities regulator banned major shareholders, corporate executives and directors from selling stakes in listed companies for six months, the latest effort to stop a $3.5 trillion rout in the nation's equity market.
Post to Facebook
Can China stop the stock rout? July 8  -- China's securities regulator banned major shareholders, corporate executives and directors from selling stakes in listed companies for six months, the latest effort to stop a $3.5 trillion rout in the nation's equity market. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MeI0sm
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Can China stop the stock rout?
July 8  -- China's securities regulator banned major shareholders, corporate executives and directors from selling stakes in listed companies for six months, the latest effort to stop a $3.5 trillion rout in the nation's equity market. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:18:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bolivia's indigenous Catholics believe in Pope, and mother earth</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99909408/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Bolivias-indigenous-Catholics-believe-in-Pope-and-mother-earth/</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of indigenous Catholics will greet Pope Francis when he lands in Bolivia, but most of them continue to worship pagan spirits.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Bolivia's indigenous Catholics believe in Pope, and mother earth
Thousands of indigenous Catholics will greet Pope Francis when he lands in Bolivia, but most of them continue to worship pagan spirits.
Post to Facebook
Bolivia's indigenous Catholics believe in Pope, and mother earth Thousands of indigenous Catholics will greet Pope Francis when he lands in Bolivia, but most of them continue to worship pagan spirits. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MeyDIU
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
3
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Bolivia's indigenous Catholics believe in Pope, and mother earth
Thousands of indigenous Catholics will greet Pope Francis when he lands in Bolivia, but most of them continue to worship pagan spirits. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 16:15:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope delivers environment message in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99909410/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Pope-delivers-environment-message-in-Ecuador/</Link>
        <Description>During a meeting with social organizations at San Francisco Church in Quito, Pope Francis talks about Amazonia, an "area that requires particular care due to its huge importance to the world ecosystem".</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Pope delivers environment message in Ecuador
During a meeting with social organizations at San Francisco Church in Quito, Pope Francis talks about Amazonia, an "area that requires particular care due to its huge importance to the world ecosystem".
Post to Facebook
Pope delivers environment message in Ecuador During a meeting with social organizations at San Francisco Church in Quito, Pope Francis talks about Amazonia, an "area that requires particular care due to its huge importance to the world ecosystem". Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IJ5abk
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Pope delivers environment message in Ecuador
During a meeting with social organizations at San Francisco Church in Quito, Pope Francis talks about Amazonia, an "area that requires particular care due to its huge importance to the world ecosystem". Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 15:32:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>There's still hope for a nuclear deal with Iran</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99903126/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Theres-still-hope-for-a-nuclear-deal-with-Iran/</Link>
        <Description>Peter Sluglett, director of the Middle East Institute of the National University of Singapore, discusses the prospects for a nuclear deal with Iran. He speaks with Bloomberg's Angie Lau on "First Up."</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
There's still hope for a nuclear deal with Iran
Peter Sluglett, director of the Middle East Institute of the National University of Singapore, discusses the prospects for a nuclear deal with Iran. He speaks with Bloomberg's Angie Lau on "First Up."
Post to Facebook
There's still hope for a nuclear deal with Iran Peter Sluglett, director of the Middle East Institute of the National University of Singapore, discusses the prospects for a nuclear deal with Iran. He speaks with Bloomberg's Angie Lau on "First Up." Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MesE74
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
There's still hope for a nuclear deal with Iran
Peter Sluglett, director of the Middle East Institute of the National University of Singapore, discusses the prospects for a nuclear deal with Iran. He speaks with Bloomberg's Angie Lau on "First Up." Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:40:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Flood of Londoners take to boats to escape housing costs</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99897564/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Flood-of-Londoners-take-to-boats-to-escape-housing-costs/</Link>
        <Description>Rocketing housing costs in Britain's capital have fuelled a surge in Londoners seeking cheaper accommodation on boats, with increased numbers putting pressure on the city's network of rivers and canals.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Flood of Londoners take to boats to escape housing costs
Rocketing housing costs in Britain's capital have fuelled a surge in Londoners seeking cheaper accommodation on boats, with increased numbers putting pressure on the city's network of rivers and canals.
Post to Facebook
Flood of Londoners take to boats to escape housing costs Rocketing housing costs in Britain's capital have fuelled a surge in Londoners seeking cheaper accommodation on boats, with increased numbers putting pressure on the city's network of rivers and canals. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IIUnOm
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Flood of Londoners take to boats to escape housing costs
Rocketing housing costs in Britain's capital have fuelled a surge in Londoners seeking cheaper accommodation on boats, with increased numbers putting pressure on the city's network of rivers and canals. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:37:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rare white Humpback seen off New Zealand coast</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99897570/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Rare-white-Humpback-seen-off-New-Zealand-coast/</Link>
        <Description>Bloomberg's Vonnie Quinn highlights photos that illustrate top stories from around the world. She speaks on "Bloomberg Surveillance."</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Rare white Humpback seen off New Zealand coast
Bloomberg's Vonnie Quinn highlights photos that illustrate top stories from around the world. She speaks on "Bloomberg Surveillance."
Post to Facebook
Rare white Humpback seen off New Zealand coast Bloomberg's Vonnie Quinn highlights photos that illustrate top stories from around the world. She speaks on "Bloomberg Surveillance." Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mem7td
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Rare white Humpback seen off New Zealand coast
Bloomberg's Vonnie Quinn highlights photos that illustrate top stories from around the world. She speaks on "Bloomberg Surveillance." Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:33:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly car bomb hits Shiite mosque in Yemen capital</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99896304/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Deadly-car-bomb-hits-Shiite-mosque-in-Yemen-capital/</Link>
        <Description>A car bomb explodes outside a mosque in the Yemeni capital of Sanaa on Tuesday, killing at least one person and wounding five, in a fresh attack on Shiite rebels claimed by the Islamic State group.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Deadly car bomb hits Shiite mosque in Yemen capital
A car bomb explodes outside a mosque in the Yemeni capital of Sanaa on Tuesday, killing at least one person and wounding five, in a fresh attack on Shiite rebels claimed by the Islamic State group.
Post to Facebook
Deadly car bomb hits Shiite mosque in Yemen capital A car bomb explodes outside a mosque in the Yemeni capital of Sanaa on Tuesday, killing at least one person and wounding five, in a fresh attack on Shiite rebels claimed by the Islamic State group. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IITQvS
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Deadly car bomb hits Shiite mosque in Yemen capital
A car bomb explodes outside a mosque in the Yemeni capital of Sanaa on Tuesday, killing at least one person and wounding five, in a fresh attack on Shiite rebels claimed by the Islamic State group. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:27:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Merkel seemingly at peace post Greece negotiations</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99896306/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Merkel-seemingly-at-peace-post-Greece-negotiations/</Link>
        <Description>Bloomberg's Hans Nichols discusses the ongoing crisis in Greece and the possible change in Angela Merkel during current negotiations.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Merkel seemingly at peace post Greece negotiations
Bloomberg's Hans Nichols discusses the ongoing crisis in Greece and the possible change in Angela Merkel during current negotiations.
Post to Facebook
Merkel seemingly at peace post Greece negotiations Bloomberg's Hans Nichols discusses the ongoing crisis in Greece and the possible change in Angela Merkel during current negotiations. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mel3pb
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Merkel seemingly at peace post Greece negotiations
Bloomberg's Hans Nichols discusses the ongoing crisis in Greece and the possible change in Angela Merkel during current negotiations. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:16:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A year on from conflict, has Gaza recovered?</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99895094/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~A-year-on-from-conflict-has-Gaza-recovered/</Link>
        <Description>Today marks one year since the war between rocket-firing militants in Gaza and Israel began. Yet reconstruction has barely begun. According to the UN, it would take 30 years for Gazans to rebuild the Strip at the current rate.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
A year on from conflict, has Gaza recovered?
Today marks one year since the war between rocket-firing militants in Gaza and Israel began. Yet reconstruction has barely begun. According to the UN, it would take 30 years for Gazans to rebuild the Strip at the current rate.
Post to Facebook
A year on from conflict, has Gaza recovered? Today marks one year since the war between rocket-firing militants in Gaza and Israel began. Yet reconstruction has barely begun. According to the UN, it would take 30 years for Gazans to rebuild the Strip at the current rate. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MejDej
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
A year on from conflict, has Gaza recovered?
Today marks one year since the war between rocket-firing militants in Gaza and Israel began. Yet reconstruction has barely begun. According to the UN, it would take 30 years for Gazans to rebuild the Strip at the current rate. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 13:56:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>It's in Vietnam's interest to not be alone</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99893980/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Its-in-Vietnams-interest-to-not-be-alone/</Link>
        <Description>July 8 -- Loyola Marymount University Distinguished Scholar and Asia Pacific Media Center Founder Tom Plate discusses President Obama meeting Nguyen Phu Trong, the head of Vietnam's Communist party at the White House and what it means for relations.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
It's in Vietnam's interest to not be alone
July 8 -- Loyola Marymount University Distinguished Scholar and Asia Pacific Media Center Founder Tom Plate discusses President Obama meeting Nguyen Phu Trong, the head of Vietnam's Communist party at the White House and what it means for relations.
Post to Facebook
It's in Vietnam's interest to not be alone July 8 -- Loyola Marymount University Distinguished Scholar and Asia Pacific Media Center Founder Tom Plate discusses President Obama meeting Nguyen Phu Trong, the head of Vietnam's Communist party at the White House and what it means for relations. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IIR4Xn
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
It's in Vietnam's interest to not be alone
July 8 -- Loyola Marymount University Distinguished Scholar and Asia Pacific Media Center Founder Tom Plate discusses President Obama meeting Nguyen Phu Trong, the head of Vietnam's Communist party at the White House and what it means for relations. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 14:17:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israeli tensions still high 1 year after Gaza war</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99885716/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Israeli-tensions-still-high-year-after-Gaza-war/</Link>
        <Description>Israelis living along the border with Gaza say it's only a matter of time before next war.</Description>
        <MainBody>Israeli tensions still high 1 year after Gaza war
Israelis living along the border with Gaza say it's only a matter of time before next war.
Post to Facebook
Israeli tensions still high 1 year after Gaza war Israelis living along the border with Gaza say it's only a matter of time before next war. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MdYHnH
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
58
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Israeli tensions still high 1 year after Gaza war
Michele Chabin, Special for USA TODAY 7:17 a.m. EDT July 8, 2015
Today marks one year since the war between rocket-firing militants in Gaza and Israel began. Yet reconstruction has barely begun. According to the UN, it would take 30 years for Gazans to rebuild the Strip at the current rate. Bloomberg
During Israel's war with Hamas last summer the Israel Defense Forces discovered 34 underground cross-border tunnels. Israel has not destroyed this 1.8-mile tunnel, discovered two years ago, because it wants to show the danger such tunnels pose to Israelis.
(Photo: Michele Chabin)
167 CONNECT 116 TWEET 8 LINKEDIN 58 COMMENTEMAILMORE
KIBBUTZ NIRIM, Israel  Determined to give their children a real summer vacation after last year's war with Hamas, the administrators of this communal village a mile from the Gaza border organized a July 1 beach day for the kids.
Just before boarding the bus, "we heard a terrible explosion and the children began running and crying," Anat Heffetz, mother of two of the children, recalled the next day. The  parents, fearing that yet another mortar or rocket had hit the kibbutz, ran to the bus.
It turned out  the explosion occurred about 18 miles away in the Sinai Peninsula, where Egyptian army and Islamic State fighters were fighting. Yet it triggered a traumatic reminder of how close this community is to Islamic militants.
Israelis mourn next to flower wreaths covering the grave of Shahar Melamed, 43, who was killed the previous day by Palestinian mortar fire in Kibbutz Nirim near Israel's border with the Gaza Strip, on August 27, 2014. Melamed  and another Israeli civilian were killed and another two were wounded when a mortar round struck the kibbutz close to the Gaza border, shortly before a permanent ceasefire came into force. Their deaths raised to 70 the total number of people killed on the Israeli side since the conflict with Hamas began on July 8, medics said.
(Photo: Menahem Kahana, AFP/Getty Images)
As residents in rocket range of Gaza mark Wednesday's  anniversary of the start of the war with Hamas last summer, they are bracing for the next conflict.
During a tour along Israel's border with Gaza, Israel Defense Forces spokesman Maj. Aryeh Shalicar said the military uses state-of-the-art technology to monitor the militants' activities in the air, at sea, on the ground and below ground.
Last summer, the IDF discovered and destroyed 34 underground cross-border tunnels. Hamas, the U.S.-designated terror group that rules Gaza, spent years building them in order to send terror squads into the farm communities and IDF positions that hug the border, Shalicar said.
Standing 75 feet underground in a dank but sophisticated 1.8-mile-long, Hamas-built tunnel that the IDF discovered two years ago, Shalicar pointed to the tunnel's solid concrete construction and electrical and communications wiring. The army takes visitors on tours of the tunnel to underscore the dangers they pose to Israel's border communities.
The tunnel, located less than a mile from Kibbutz Ein Hashlosha, "cost $2 million to $3 million to build," the spokesman said. "This is Hamas' top priority."
Ori Raz, who heads Nirim's emergency response team, said the community's kibbutz members live between hope and fear.
"Since the war not one rocket has hit the kibbutz and there was only one false alarm," he noted. From that perspective, he said, Israel's ground and air offensives in Gaza were a tactical success. During the last hour of the war, a mortar that landed in Nirim killed two kibbutz residents and maimed a third.
Raz said the government already has plans to evacuate the region's children should a new round of hostilities break out, even though every home has a room reinforced against rockets.
Children play at kindergarten surrounded by decorated concrete blast walls designed to protect from rocket and mortar fire, on June 24, 2015, in the southern Israeli Kibbutz of Nahal Oz, located near the border with the Gaza Strip. Shelters and blast walls have become a part of life for Israelis living near the Gaza Strip, and the war that broke out a year ago this week between Israel and Hamas, which rules the coastal enclave, has only increased such concerns.
(Photo: Menahem Kahana, AFP/Getty Images)
He said Nirim and other communities had to scramble a year ago to find children temporary homes, and many were forced to remain in the war zone.
Heffetz said the regional council, schools and communities have gone to great lengths to ensure all children and adults have access to psychological counseling.
"After every war the children have trouble falling asleep. They wet their beds, insist on sleeping with their parents. Initially many were afraid to go outside," she said.
Like many Israelis living near the Gaza border, Heffetz is politically left-of-center. She wants the  government to pursue a long-term cease-fire with Hamas, even though its leaders call for Israel's destruction.
"If you look at the government's policy over the past five to six years, you see no real attempt to deeply change the reality," Heffetz said. "More security means more soldiers and safe rooms, but not a cease-fire."
Follow Chabin at @michelechabin1
167 CONNECT 116 TWEET 8 LINKEDIN 58 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MdYHnH
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 06:01:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Euro zone gives Greece until sunday for debt deal</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99856422/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Euro-zone-gives-Greece-until-sunday-for-debt-deal/</Link>
        <Description>Euro zone members have given Greece until the end of the week to come up with a proposal for sweeping reforms in return for loans that will keep the country from crashing out of Europe's currency bloc and into economic ruin.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Euro zone gives Greece until sunday for debt deal
Euro zone members have given Greece until the end of the week to come up with a proposal for sweeping reforms in return for loans that will keep the country from crashing out of Europe's currency bloc and into economic ruin.
Post to Facebook
Euro zone gives Greece until sunday for debt deal Euro zone members have given Greece until the end of the week to come up with a proposal for sweeping reforms in return for loans that will keep the country from crashing out of Europe's currency bloc and into economic ruin. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Md6zpp
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Euro zone gives Greece until sunday for debt deal
Euro zone members have given Greece until the end of the week to come up with a proposal for sweeping reforms in return for loans that will keep the country from crashing out of Europe's currency bloc and into economic ruin. USA TODAY
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 04:00:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis holds mass in Ecuador's capital Quito</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99844366/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Pope-Francis-holds-mass-in-Ecuadors-capital-Quito/</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis celebrates his second open air mass in as many days in Ecuador on Tuesday, this time in Quito, the capital city roiled for the past month by anti-government protests.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Pope Francis holds mass in Ecuador's capital Quito
Pope Francis celebrates his second open air mass in as many days in Ecuador on Tuesday, this time in Quito, the capital city roiled for the past month by anti-government protests.
Post to Facebook
Pope Francis holds mass in Ecuador's capital Quito Pope Francis celebrates his second open air mass in as many days in Ecuador on Tuesday, this time in Quito, the capital city roiled for the past month by anti-government protests. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IHYv0S
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Pope Francis holds mass in Ecuador's capital Quito
Pope Francis celebrates his second open air mass in as many days in Ecuador on Tuesday, this time in Quito, the capital city roiled for the past month by anti-government protests. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 02:25:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope presses environment message in bio-diverse Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99786160/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Pope-presses-environment-message-in-biodiverse-Ecuador/</Link>
        <Description>Fans in Ecuador toss confetti as Francis zooms by in his popemobile.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Pope presses environment message in bio-diverse Ecuador
QUITO, Ecuador (AP)  Pope Francis kicked off a whirlwind final full day in Ecuador on Tuesday with an open-air Mass in the capital sandwiched between meetings with bishops, indigenous groups and students and
Post to Facebook
Pope presses environment message in bio-diverse Ecuador QUITO, Ecuador (AP)  Pope Francis kicked off a whirlwind final full day in Ecuador on Tuesday with an open-air Mass in the capital sandwiched between meetings with bishops, indigenous groups and students and Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IH7srs
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
8
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Pope presses environment message in bio-diverse Ecuador
Nicole Winfield, The Associated Press 7:25 p.m. EDT July 7, 2015
Pope Francis is greeted by a crowd as he rides through the Ecuadorean capital, Quito, on July 7, 2015.
(Photo: Juan Cevallos, AFP/Getty Images)
19 CONNECT 120 TWEET LINKEDIN 8 COMMENTEMAILMORE
QUITO, Ecuador (AP)  Pope Francis challenged Latin America's youth to take up his environmental protection campaign Tuesday, saying the defense of God's creation isn't just a recommendation but a requirement.
Francis' appeal, delivered at Quito's Catholic University, is particularly relevant for Ecuador, a Pacific nation that is home to one of the world's most species-diverse ecosystems in the Galapagos Islands and Amazon rain forest, but is also an OPEC country heavily dependent on oil extraction.
Francis told students and professors that God gave humanity the Earth to not only cultivate, but to care for  a message he framed earlier this month in his headline-grabbing encyclical on the environment.
"It is no longer a mere recommendation, but rather a requirement because of the harm we have inflicted on it by our irresponsible use and abuse of the goods with which God has endowed it," he said.
He challenged universities to ensure that students' educations aren't aimed only at profitable careers but also at helping the poor and the environment.
"There is a relationship between our life and that of mother Earth, between the way we live and the gift we have received from God," he said.
Pope issues urgent appeal to fight climate change
Francis' environmental message has been cheered by indigenous groups, who have complained of being increasingly marginalized by Ecuadorean President Rafael Correa as he pushes mining and oil drilling in the Amazon. That push, coupled with high crude prices, allowed Correa to lift 1.3 million people out of poverty in his eight years in office.
Pope Francis walks with his pastoral staff to celebrate Mass at Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on Tuesday, July 7, 2015.
(Photo: Gregorio Borgia, AP)
Francis has called for environmentally responsible development, one that is aimed at helping the poor without sacrificing the planet.
It was a message he was likely to repeat at a meeting with indigenous groups, and then later this week in Bolivia, the next stop on his three-nation South American tour. Bolivian President Evo Morales has been hailed as an environmental hero to many for demanding rich nations do more to halt global warming, but he has been assailed by conservationists at home who say he puts oil and gas extraction ahead of clean water and forests.
Francis began his last full day in Ecuador with an open-air Mass that drew more than 1 million people and featured readings in Quichua, the native language mostly spoken in Ecuador, and Ecuadorean vestments for the pope.
In his homily, Francis urged Latin Americans to channel the same urgency that brought them independence from Spain two centuries ago into spreading the faith on a continent where Catholicism is losing souls to evangelical movements.
The Mass location, at Quito's Bicentennial Park, was appropriate given that Ecuador was where the first cries of independence against Spanish rule arose in Latin America in 1809.
Pope Francis is surrounded by faithful as he arrives in his popemobile to celebrate Mass at Bicentennial Park in Quito, Ecuador, on Tuesday, July 7, 2015.
(Photo: Gregorio Borgia, AP)
"There was no shortage of conviction or strength in that cry for freedom which arose a little more than 200 years ago," Francis said. "But history tells us that it only made headway once personal differences were set aside."
He urged Latin Americans to channel that same purpose and unity into spreading the faith. Latin America counts 40% of the world's Catholics, but the church is losing out to Protestant evangelical ministries that have focused on the continent's poorest communities with real-life guidance on employment and education.
While the drop-off in Spanish-speaking South America hasn't been as sharp as it has been in Brazil, it is notable: Some 95% of Ecuador's population was Catholic in 1970, and now the figure is down to 79%, according to the Pew Research Center.
In a bid to counter the trend and return the Catholic Church to its evangelizing origins, Francis has called for the church to return to being a missionary church that looks out particularly for society's poorest and most marginalized. It's a message he crafted for the entire Latin American church when he played a leading role in a 2007 conference of bishops in Aparecida, Brazil.
"Evangelization doesn't consist in proselytizing, but in attracting by our witness to those who are far off, in humbly drawing near to those who feel distant from God and the church, those who are fearful or indifferent," Francis told the crowd. "Proselytism is a caricature of evangelization."
Pope Francis' schedule for U.S. visit released
Francis arrived at Bicentennial Park to cheers of people who camped out overnight for a good spot. They were rewarded with a pre-dawn deluge that sent some 20 people to paramedics with hypothermia, said city operations director Cristian Rivera. But the sun broke out as Francis arrived in his popemobile, with fans tossing confetti on him as he zoomed by.
"The joy at seeing the pope gives us the warmth we need," said seafood vendor Abel Gualoto, 59, as he rubbed his cold hands together to try to stay warm.
Tuesday was expected to end with a visit to the Church of the Society of Jesus, known locally as Iglesia de la Compania. The Jesuit church, a gem of Spanish Baroque, is one of the oldest and most well-known in Ecuador. It houses a painting of the Virgin Mary that was said to shed tears in 1906.
19 CONNECT 120 TWEET LINKEDIN 8 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1IH7srs
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:25:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What to know about running with the bulls in Pamplona</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99824466/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~What-to-know-about-running-with-the-bulls-in-Pamplona/</Link>
        <Description>Wear red, don't drink and other things to know about the Spanish festival.</Description>
        <MainBody>What to know about running with the bulls in Pamplona
Pamplona, Spain, hosts the traditional Encierro (running with the bulls) each July.
Post to Facebook
What to know about running with the bulls in Pamplona Pamplona, Spain, hosts the traditional Encierro (running with the bulls) each July. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IHFOdG
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
What to know about running with the bulls in Pamplona
Christine Rushton and Jennifer Calfas , USA TODAY 6:25 p.m. EDT July 7, 2015
People watch as Jandilla fighting bulls and revelers run during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
A reveler falls while others run with a Jandilla's ranch fighting bull during the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
A reveler is tossed by a cow with dull horns during a celebration held at the bullring after the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
Revelers wearing a local traditional outfit march during the San Fermin procession in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Revelers gather to watch Jandilla fighting bulls running at the San Fermin festival, in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Fullscreen
Revelers run with fighting bulls during the running of the bulls at the Fiestas de San Fermin in Pamplona, Spain, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The festival, locally known as Sanfermines, is held annually from July 6-14 in commemoration of the city's patron saint.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
People from around the world gather for the event.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
The 'Toro de Fuego' (flaming bull) chases revelers through the streets during the opening day.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez)
Revelers gathered on City Hall Square celebrate after the firing of the txupinazo rocket, which marks the official beginning of the festival.
(Photo: Daniel Fernandez, EPA)
Fullscreen
A band performs during the opening day or 'Chupinazo.' Hundreds of thousands of visitors from all over the world attend the nine-day fiesta. Many of them participate in the highlight event: The running of the bulls - or encierro - where they attempt to outrun the bulls along an approximately half-mile-long route through the narrow streets of the old city.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Revelers hold their red scarves as mark the kickoff at noon sharp of the San Fermin Festival.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Not for the claustrophobic! Revelers squeeze through Pamplona's City Hall Square.
(Photo: Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images)
A man gets some air as he's tossed about during the  launch of the chupinazo rocket.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A reveler wearing a bull earring enjoys the atmosphere during the opening day of the Running of the Bulls fiesta.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Festival goers soak each other with wine.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Ivy Mix from Brooklyn, N.Y., is given a drink of sangria.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, EPA)
Revelers throw a bucket of water from a balcony onto the crowd.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
And below the balcony, the water lands on party goers.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A red-and-white-clad sea of revelers soaked each other with wine in a packed Pamplona square Monday.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Revelers from around the world kick off the festival. Tuesday is the first of eight days of the running of the bulls.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A woman is sprayed with water as she celebrates.
(Photo: Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images)
A sea of participants hold red scarves as they celebrate.
(Photo: MIGUEL RIOPA, AFP/Getty Images)
A reveler jumps from a fountain onto the crowd below.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
A  reveler drinks wine during San Fermin Fiestas. Many others wore it, as their formerly white T shirts attest.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
People enjoy the atmosphere during the opening day of the Running of the Bulls festival.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Streets too much? Some people choose to witness the celebration from balconies.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Sangria is the drink of choice, taken from a plastic bottle as partying continues.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, EPA)
People-surfing/people-tossing is just part of the atmosphere.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
As long as you wear red and white, anything goes.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
Last Slide Next Slide
Revelers run with fighting bulls during the running of the bulls at the Fiestas de San Fermin in Pamplona, Spain, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The festival, locally known as Sanfermines, is held annually from July 6-14 in commemoration of the city's patron saint.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
316 CONNECT 84 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Thousands of adrenaline junkies risk their lives each year at the running of the bulls in Spain, which started this week in Pamplona. The nine-day San Fermin Festival gives runners eight chances to do the Encierro (running of the bulls). The first day is devoted to wine.
Before joining the masses, read up on the rules and history of this ancient tradition.
Why are we doing this?
Herding the bulls through the streets of Pamplona dates back as far as the 13th century. The method was used as a way to corral the bulls to a bullfighting ring from Pamplona's corral. The animals would run through a similar half-mile stretch as they do today as kids and adults chased after them with sticks.
People from around the world gather for the event.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
What should we wear?
Participants traditionally wear all white with a red scarf  a Pauelico  to honor San Fermin. Religious customs show priests would dress in red to honor saints. Red is also the color associated with charging bulls in bullfights.
Revelers wearing a local traditional outfit march during the San Fermin procession in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
How far is the run?
The run begins on Pamplona's Santo Domingo street, and finishes in the Plaza de Toros, where the bullpen is located. The run is a little over half a mile. For speedy runners, the course should only take a few minutes to complete. If participants make it to the bullpen, they can continue to run around the arena with the bulls.
How does the race begin?
Two rockets go off from the bull ring to inform runners the six bulls are released. The first indicates the bull pen has been opened, and the second tells runners the bulls have been released. Six steers are also released to help keep the pack together. After the half-mile run, two more rockets go off to announce all bulls have entered the bullring and that the ring is closed, respectively.
Can anyone participate?
Men and women 18 years and older can run with the bulls. Runners must be sober and cannot take photos while inside the barriers. Until a rule change allowing women in 1974, only men could participate. There are festivities for children, too. Each night at 10 p.m., children have their own Encierro where they can run with a fake bull stuffed with fireworks.
Revelers and children are 'chased' by the 'Toro de Fuego' (Flaming bull) as it runs through the streets during the opening day of the San Fermin Running of the Bulls fiesta on July 6, 2015, in Pamplona, Spain.
(Photo: David Ramos, Getty Images)
How dangerous is the event?
Fifteen people have died since festival officials started keeping track in the 1900s. Almost all of were Spaniards. One American from Illinois died from goring injuries in 1995. Still, hundreds are injured from being gored or trampled each year. Two Americans and one Briton were gored on the first day this year.
Mike Webster, a 38-year-old occupational therapist from Gainesville, Fla., was gored in the armpit while running with the bulls in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
What's the significance of San Fermin?
In 1591, the first official festival took place, making the official start date July 7. The festival combines religious and celebratory components, as festival-goers honor San Fermin, or Saint Fermin. Before 1591, an annual event to honor the saint took place each September.
Before the bulls are released, festival-goers chant, in Spanish, "We ask San Fermin, being our patron saint, to guide us in the bull run and give us his blessing." The chant is followed by yells of "Viva San Fermin! Gora San Fermin," or "long live San Fermin."
Learn about the greatest runner in Pamplona's 'Running of the Bulls' festival http://t.co/QcUmJ25yE3 via @truedotink pic.twitter.com/UZP4hLDfLt
 Huckberry (@Huckberry) July 7, 2015
Who are the matadors?
Matadors fight the bulls in the ring after the steers and runners corral the animals in the morning. The fighters kill the bulls by stabbing them with a sword between the shoulder blades. They get close to the animal using the cape to distract and divert the direction of the horns for sport. They typically wear a fitted ornate suit.
Spanish bullfighter Juan del Alamo fights against his second bull in Pamplona, on July 9, 2014.
(Photo: Javier Lizon, epa)
Why is it the festival so famous outside of Spain?
Ernest Hemingway's 1926 novel The Sun Also Rises depicted a group of Americans and Britons who travel to Spain for the annual running of the bulls. This story drew international attention to the festivities.
The Sun Also Rises by Ernest Hemingway
(Photo: Original book cover)
What are the festival traditions besides the Encierro?
Before the eight days of running, the festival begins with a celebratory shooting of a firework worked, called the "Chupinazo." Festival-goers dose themselves in wine and sing in honor of St. Fermin. Though wine and sangria are part of the celebration, participants are not allowed to run while drunk. Each morning also begins with a Parade of Giants , who represent four pairs of kings and queens from four different places.
Ivy Mix from Brooklyn, N.Y., is given a drink of sangria.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, EPA)
But what about the bulls?
Animal rights groups like PETA argue that prodding and chasing the bulls constitutes abuse. The matador fights also include stabbing and killing the bulls. People protest in the form of Running of the Nudes, which started in 2002 when a group of protesters ran through the streets of Pamplona wearing red scarves, plastic horns and nothing else.
All this violence is in the name of a tradition that most Spanish people do not want to preserve. #Pamplona #SF15 pic.twitter.com/ag4Wh0prFz
316 CONNECT 84 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1IHFOdG
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 00:12:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian police publish guide to taking selfies without killing yourself</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99820108/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Russian-police-publish-guide-to-taking-selfies-without-killing-yourself/</Link>
        <Description>Recent string of selfie-induced accidents led to new Information campaign.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Russian police publish guide to taking selfies without killing yourself
KIEV, Ukraine  Police in Russia might be known for cracking skulls and taking bribes, but now they're taking on a truly civic-minded task: teaching you how to properly take selfies. Citing a recent string of
Post to Facebook
Russian police publish guide to taking selfies without killing yourself KIEV, Ukraine  Police in Russia might be known for cracking skulls and taking bribes, but now they're taking on a truly civic-minded task: teaching you how to properly take selfies. Citing a recent string of Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IHBKub
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Russian police publish guide to taking selfies without killing yourself
Dan Peleschuk, GlobalPost 5:12 p.m. EDT July 7, 2015
Two women pose for a selfie on Red Square with St. Basil's Cathedral, left, and the Spasskaya Tower, right in Moscow in this file photo from Oct. 6, 2014. Alarmed by the number of Russians who have been killed while taking photos of themselves with smartphones, Russian police have started a new campaign called "Safe Selfies." The instructions issued Tuesday, July 7, 2015, warn against standing on railroad tracks, climbing onto roofs or posing with a gun or a tiger.
(Photo: Alexander Zemlianichenko, AP)
265 CONNECT 77 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
KIEV, Ukraine  Police in Russia might be known for cracking skulls and taking bribes, but now they're taking on a truly civic-minded task: teaching you how to properly take selfies.
Citing a recent string of selfie-induced accidents  some of them deadly  the Russian Interior Ministry on Tuesday launched an information campaign to instruct citizens on the safest ways to get those memorable shots.
It includes an infographic guide, crowdsourcing tools for safe selfie techniques and a hashtag in Russian meaning #safeselfie.
"When a person is trying to photograph themselves, their attention is scattered, they lose their balance, they don't look look around and feel no danger," the Interior Ministry said in a statement.
Some of the tips  such as advising against selfies with wild animals, firearms or at significant heights  may seem like no-brainers. But Russians have proved there's little they won't do for a solid selfie.
Among the more memorable cases was an incident last month when a drunk Siberian man accidentally toppled a statue of Vladimir Lenin while trying to photograph himself with the Communist leader.
Then there were the two fishermen  also in Siberia  who wound up in the hospital after reportedly attempting to take a selfie with a snake, their hands swollen from venom.
But the practice has also had far more tragic consequences.
A worker takes a selfie before removing a yellow and blue Ukrainian flag attached by protesters atop a Stalin-era skyscraper in Moscow in this file photo taken Aug. 20, 2014. Alarmed by the number of Russians who have been killed while taking photos of themselves with smartphones, Russian police have started a new campaign called "Safe Selfies."
(Photo: Ilya Varlamov, AP)
Just last weekend, a 21-year-old Muscovite fell to her death from a city bridge during a selfie attempt. In May, another 21-year-old woman accidentally shot herself in the head with a non-lethal pistol, causing severe injury, while trying to strike a pose.
Other grim incidents involving selfie-takers have included electrocutions and even deadly grenade explosions. In fact, police reported that about 100 people have been injured and at least 10 killed since the beginning of the year while attempting selfies.
It's not just the police who are worried.
A civic group called For Security recently petitioned the Education and Science Ministry to introduce lessons in Russian schools  featuring psychologists, cops and professional photographers  on how to take safer selfies.
"It's necessary to impress from childhood that such an easy path to accomplishment is dangerous," Dmitry Kurdesov, the group's director, told the Izvestiya newspaper this week.
This article originally appeared on the website of GlobalPost . Its content was created separately from USA TODAY.
MORE FROM GLOBAL POST
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:59:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uber under assault around the world as taxi drivers fight back</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99808606/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Uber-under-assault-around-the-world-as-taxi-drivers-fight-back/</Link>
        <Description>Service meets resistance from established cabbies complaining of unfair competition.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Uber under assault around the world as taxi drivers fight back
Smartphone-driven Uber is revolutionizing taxi service around the world, and in so doing has unleashed a global backlash that includes violent protests in France, legal barriers in Germany, a criminal investigation in New Delhi and police raids in China.
Post to Facebook
Uber under assault around the world as taxi drivers fight back Smartphone-driven Uber is revolutionizing taxi service around the world, and in so doing has unleashed a global backlash that includes violent protests in France, legal barriers in Germany, a criminal investigation in New Delhi and police raids in China. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IHucaO
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
18
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Uber under assault around the world as taxi drivers fight back
Gregg Zoroya and Angela Waters, USA TODAY 6:59 p.m. EDT July 7, 2015
Riot police in Paris stand near a car set on fire during demonstrations against Uber on June 25, 2015.
(Photo: Michel Euler, AP)
1650 CONNECT 95 TWEET 10 LINKEDIN 18 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Smartphone-driven Uber is revolutionizing taxi service around the world, and in so doing has unleashed a global backlash that includes violent protests in France, legal barriers in Germany, a criminal investigation in New Delhi and police raids in China.
The common anti-Uber battle cry has been unfair competition, largely from established cab companies that claim Uber's business model evades regulations to ensure safety and uniform fares.
Last month,   French taxi drivers unleashed massive protests across the nation, blocking highways, torching cars and even taking hostages. Two Uber executives were arrested and accused of running an "illicit" business.
While conceding France is a worst-case scenario, Uber says that focusing on a relatively few number of tough global markets obscures growing success stories.
"What we're starting to see," said spokeswoman Nairi Hourdajian, "as policy makers get to know the service better, as they hear from constituents, riders and drivers ... we really start to see some momentum."
The 5-year-old privately-held Uber now operates in 58 countries and in all but four U.S. states.
In an attempt to restore order to the streets of Paris, French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve ordered a new ban on uncertified drivers and said Uber drivers found breaking the law would have their cars impounded. Uber said last week it was suspending its low-cost UberPop service in France.
Another Uber spokesman, Thomas Meister, said the San Francisco-based business anticipated a certain level of push back and planned accordingly.
He  said the broad pattern is the company enters a market, meets opposition from taxi drivers, loses initial court cases and then works with authorities to find a way to regulate and tailor services to the location. The company offers several services through its app including food delivery, professional chauffeurs and the best known operation: drivers who ride-share with their own vehicles.
"The situation in France is the worst across Europe," Meister said. "We are facing a taxi community that is very reluctant to accept any kind of change."
Even on U.S. soil, Uber is not spared headaches. New York seized nearly 500 cars affiliated with Uber this spring for allegedly picking up fares illegally. On Tuesday, the company offered free UberPool rides to and from City Hall to protest a bill that would cap the number of drivers the company can deploy there.
The firm recently suspended operations in South Florida's Broward County after complaining that regulations on its drivers there were too onerous.
Uber even faces issues in its home state. The California Labor Commission ruled in June that an Uber driver was an employee and not an independent contractor, a decision that could complicate Uber's business model. The company is appealing.
Here is a look at some of the other battles waged against Uber as it expands around the world:
BRAZIL. The governing council of So Paulo, one of the world's largest cities with 20 million people, voted overwhelming to block the use of smartphone-based ride hailing. The city council in the capital of Brasilia did the same. The move by So Paulo requires a second vote and mayoral approval. The Brasilia city council vote goes before a federal judge.
CANADA. An effort by the city of Toronto to obtain an injunction banning Uber operations was rejected by a court last week.
CHINA. A different kind of fight is playing out in China where a local competitor is taking on Uber. Taxi app Didi Kuaidi boasted in a letter to shareholders last week that it has three times the number of daily car trips as Uber in the country. An email by CEO Travis Kalanick said Uber has nearly a million trips a day in China, the company's most important global market.
ENGLAND. London Mayor Boris Johnson announced last month that he wants Uber drivers to pass geography and English tests in order to operate in the city. Johnson said the measure would help level the playing field for drivers of London's iconic black cabs who spend up to four years trying to qualify to drive clients around the city. Uber says such restrictions are not a problem.
GERMANY. A Berlin court last year restricted Uber drivers by ruling that non-cabbies who were not carrying a passenger were barred from waiting for passengers. They must instead return to a central dispatch station. Other legal complaints have been filed alleging improper certification or unfair competition.
INDIA. New Delhi police are considering criminal charges against Uber if they find evidence it misrepresented that its service is safe. A top government official called for the company to be banned nationwide after an Uber driver in New Delhi was accused of rape. The service has already been banned in New Delhi, although an Uber spokesperson said drivers are still operating there.
MEXICO. Taxi drivers have protested and vowed to "hunt down" Uber drivers. But the ride-sharing app may soon get some good news in that nation's capital after receiving endorsements from Federal Commission on Economic Competition and Mexico City's Human Rights Commission.
SPAIN. A judge has temporarily blocked Uber from operating in the country after concluding its services constituted unfair competition.
SOUTH AFRICA. Uber has asked for police protection of drivers and passengers in Johannesburg from taxi drivers angry about the service cutting into their business.
1650 CONNECT 95 TWEET 10 LINKEDIN 18 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1IHucaO
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Battling Islamic State militants</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/87524922/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Battling-Islamic-State-militants/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Battling Islamic State militants
Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq.
Post to Facebook
Battling Islamic State militants Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1ChmkJu
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Battling Islamic State militants
Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters fire at Islamic State positions during a battle near the Baiji oil refinery.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters advance near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Shiite fighters hold a position near the Baiji oil refinery.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters hold a position against Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Sunni fighters battle Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Shiite fighters from the Popular Mobilization Units display an Iraqi national flag in front of an Islamic State mural on April 1 outside a presidential palace in Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government security forces celebrate in Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government soldiers battle Islamic State militants in Tikrit.
European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi counterterrorism forces patrol a street.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces deploy in the city.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi soldier guards a checkpoint.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi army tank advances in Tikrit on March 31 during a battle against Islamic State militants.  Iraqi Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi announced that Iraqi troops, supported by U.S.-led airstrikes, have recaptured most of the town from the Islamic State.
European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke rises during fighting in Tikrit.
European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi security forces conduct a house-to-house search for Islamic State militants on March 30 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces attack Islamic State extremists in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government troops watch an area outside the city. Islamic State militants have booby trapped streets and buildings in Tikrit with explosives.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi officer shouts orders.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces launch a rocket at Islamic State extremists.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security force soldiers run to a position as they surround Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi forces fire rockets at Islamic State positions in Tikrit on March 28.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government vehicles are positioned outside western Tikrit on March 27 during a military operation to retake the city from Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke billows from an air strike as Iraqi government troops hold a position outside Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government vehicles maneuver outside the city.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Explosions rock Tikrit as Iraqi security forces fire rockets against Islamic State militants.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi government vehicle drives to a position.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi security troops fire a mortar at positions held by Islamic State militants.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Smoke rises from buildings during a bombardment in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces fire a rocket at Islamic State militants on March 26 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi helicopter attacks Islamic State positions in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
A member of the Iraqi Shiite militant group the Imam Ali Brigades patrols in Tikrit on March 25.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
A volunteer fighter with the Shiite militant group Jihad Brigades fires his weapon at Islamic State militants on March 21 outside Tikrit, Iraq.
AP
Iraqi fighters with the Saraya al-Salam Brigade, a group formed by Iraqi Shiite Muslim cleric Moqtada al-Sadr, wave their weapons as they leave Najaf to join the fight against Islamic State militants on March 20.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi police leave Najaf to join government and coalition forces battling Islamic State militants in Tikrit.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A U.S. Navy jet takes off on March 19 from the aircraft carrier Carl Vinson on March 19 in the Persian Gulf. The Carl Vinson and French military jets from the French aircraft carrier Charles de Gaulle are flying missions over Iraq against Islamic State militants.
Hasan Jamali, AP
Iraqi security forces and allied Shiite militiamen battle Islamic State fighters in the Qadisiyah neighborhood in Tikrit on March 15.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Members of the group Soldiers of Imam Ali Brigade launch rockets against Islamic State extremists on March 15 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi army armored vehicle prepares to attack Islamic State positions on March 12 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government security forces patrol in Tikrit
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces and allied Shiite militiamen prepare to attack Islamic State extremists at Camp Speicher.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Shiite militiamen prepare to attack Islamic State extremists at Camp Speicher.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Shiite militiamen prepare to fire a mortar at Islamic State extremists in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi government soldier fires at Islamic State militants on March 11 in Tikrit.
AP
Iraqi government soldiers attack Islamic State militants as they attempt to recapture Tikrit. Iraqi soldiers and Shiite militiamen have entered Tikrit, the largest city controlled by the extremists.
AP
Iraqi government forces deploy during a military operation against Islamic State militants near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi government vehicle fires at Islamic State positions near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi pro-government fighters celebrate as they advance into Tikrit. Government forces are conducting a major military operation against Islamic State militants to recapture the city from the jihadist group.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi medics treat wounded fighters at a field hospital.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi fighter from the Popular Mobilization Unit holds a position as pro-government forces advance into Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
A member of a tribal group fighting alongside Iraqi government forces fires at Islamic State militants during a battle in the Hosh district in Ramadi.
Azhar Shallal, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi police officer aims a rocket-propelled grenade during clashes with Islamic State militants in the Hosh district of Ramadi.
Azhar Shallal, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the Popular Mobilization Unit celebrate with a captured Islamic State flag on March 9 after recapturing Albu Ajil village near Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces advance on Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government troops conduct a military operation against Islamic State militants in Albu Ajil village near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces drive toward Al-Alam village on March 8.
Younis Al-Bayati, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi soldier fires at Islamic State positions near Tikrit on March 4.
Iraqi Ministry of Defense via AP
Volunteer pro-government Shiite fighters with the Popular Mobilization Unit fire a howitzer at Islamic State militants on Feb. 28 at Awaynat near Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Egyptian military jet takes off from an undisclosed base on Feb. 16 to strike Islamic State targets in Libya. Egyptian warplanes bombed Islamic State positions in retaliation for the beheading of 21 Egyptian Coptic Christian hostages.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
A video image from an Egyptian warplane shows an airstrike on an Islamic State target in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
A video image shows a bomb hit on an Islamic State position in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
An image from Egypt's television station Al-Masriya shows a Egyptian F-16 fighter jet preparing to take off from an undisclosed location to conduct an airstrike on Islamic State targets in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A United Arab Emirates pilot prepares to take off in an F-16 on Feb. 10 at a base in Jordan. The United Arab Emirates launched airstrikes against Islamic State militants, marking the nation's return to combat operations after it halted flights in late 2014.
WAM via AP
A United Arab Emirates F-16 jet prepares for an airstrike against Islamic State targets at a base in Jordan.
WAM via AP
A Jordanian air force pilot writes a message to Islamic State militants on a missile at Mowafak Al-Salti airbase in Azraq on Feb. 6.
Roya TV via AP
Kayla Mueller speaks to a group on May 30, 2013, in Prescott, Ariz. The White House and her family confirmed the death of Mueller, who was being held by Islamic State militants, on Feb. 10.
Matt Hinshaw, The Daily Courier, via AP
Fullscreen
An image posted by the Islamic State on jihadist forums on Feb. 6 shows a heavily damaged building in Raqa, Syria, after it was allegedly targeted by a coalition airstrike. In a statement posted on jihadist websites the Islamic State group claims a female American hostage had been killed in a raid by coalition warplanes.
AFP/Getty Images
Thousands of people participate in a mass demonstration after Friday prayers near Al Hussein Mosque in Amman, Jordan, to express their solidarity with a Jordanian pilot murdered by the Islamic State group.
Jordan Pix, Getty Images
An image from the Jordanian television on Feb. 5 shows flames erupting from a building hit by an airstrike against Islamic State militants.
AFP/Getty Images
A Jordanian fighter jet takes off from an airbase.
Jordan News Agency via European Pressphoto Agency
A miltary officer writes a message on a missile. The Arabic words reads, "Will show them hell, from the Jordanian air force."
Jordan News Agency via European Pressphoto Agency
Fullscreen
Members of the Kurdish peshmerga forces and the Iraqi security forces patrol on a road as smoke billows from the Khubbaz oil field, some 15 miles west of the northern city of Kirkuk a few days after peshmerga forces and police retook the area from Islamic State group. 
Marwan Ibrahim, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
Members of the Yazidi minority search for clues that might lead them to missing relatives among the remains of those killed by the Islamic State jihadi group, a day after Kurdish forces discovered a mass grave near the Iraqi village of Sinuni, in the northwestern Sinjar area.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
Iraqi Shiite fighters celebrate in al-Mansuriya, in Iraq's Diyala province, after government forces retook the area from Islamic State group's control. Iraqi forces have "liberated" Diyala province from the Islamic State jihadist group, retaking all populated areas of the eastern region.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A Syrian Kurdish sniper sits among the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, Syria. The Islamic State group has acknowledged for the first time that its fighters were defeated there, but vowed to attack the town again.
AP
Fullscreen
A Syrian Kurdish sniper sits among the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, Syria. The Islamic State group has acknowledged for the first time that its fighters were defeated there, but vowed to attack the town again.
AP
Kurdish peshmerga fighters surround extremists inside a hotel near police headquarters in the oil-rich city of  Kirkuk, 180 miles north of Baghdad. 
AP
A Syrian Kurdish man walks among the rubble in Kobani.
AP
Rubble and damaged buildings are seen in the devastated Syrian city of Kobani.
AP
Fullscreen
Members of the Yazidi minority search for clues that might lead them to missing relatives among the remains of those killed by the Islamic State jihadi group, a day after Kurdish forces discovered a mass grave near the Iraqi village of Sinuni, in the northwestern Sinjar area.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units stand on the back of a homemade armored vehicle as they patrol Kobani, Syria.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A member of Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units walks through rubble on a street in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A member of Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units walks through rubble in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A Kurdish peshmerga fighter aims his weapon as other fighters cross a bridge on Nov. 30 near Kirkuk, Iraq.
Marwan Ibrahim, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi soldier inspects destroyed trucks used by Islamic State militants near Amerli.
Ali Mohammed, European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi army soldiers deploy in front of a court building run by the Islamic State militants in Sadiyah on Nov. 24.
AP
A Kurdish People's Protection Units fighter looks at damage from a Nov. 19 truck bomb attack in Kobani, Syria.
Jake Simkin, AP
Islamic State militants stand on Tilsehir Hill near the Turkish border before an Oct. 23 airstrike in Yumurtalik village.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A bomb explodes on Tilsehir Hill.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
People in Turkey watch an explosion following an airstrike carried out by coalition forces.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A Kurdish refugee woman from Kobani, Syria, holds a child in a camp in Suruc.
Kutluhan Cucel, Getty Images
People warm themselves on a hilltop outside Suruc, Turkey. They've gathered to watch fighting across the border in Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises from an airstrike in Kobani, Syria. Kobani and its surrounding areas have been under assault by extremists of the Islamic State group since mid-September and are being defended by Kurdish fighters.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
U.S.-led coalition aircraft strike at Islamic State targets on Oct. 20 in Kobani, Syria.
AP
Kurdish people observe smoke rising from the Syrian town of Kobani following an explosion as seen from the southeastern Turkish village of Mursitpinar in the Sanliurfa province on Oct. 20.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A explosion during an allied airstrike rocks Kobani.
AP
People watch from a hill in Turkey as Syrian Kurdish fighters battle militants from the Islamic State in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Allied warplanes strike Islamic State positions.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
Shiite fighters loyal to Grand Ayatollah Ali al-Sistani fire missiles at Islamic State militants on Oct. 19 in Karbala, Iraq.
Mohammed Swaf, AFP/Getty Images
People gather on a hill outside Suruc, Turkey, to watch fighting between Syrian Kurds and Islamic State militants in Kobane, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
U.S. Navy Aviation Boatswain Mate Jessica Brown directs an aircraft on the flight deck of the aircraft carrier USS Carl Vinson as the ship conducts strike operations in Iraq and Syria.
U.S. Navy via European Pressphoto Agency
Syrian refugees walk through a camp in Suruc, Turkey.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A man uses the scope from a sniper rifle to watch fighting in Kobani, Syria, on Oct. 19.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty Images
Islamic State militants fight in Kobani on Oct. 19.
Aamaq News Agency via AFP/Getty Images
Kurdish fighters detonate an Islamic State land mine in Gwer district, northern Iraq.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
A bomb explodes during an Oct. 18 allied airstrike on Islamic State targets in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
A U.S. Air Force B1-B bomber flies above Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Shiite volunteers participate in a training session in Hillah.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
An explosion rocks Kobani, Syria, on Oct. 18 during an allied strike on Islamic State militants.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
An Islamic State fighter fires a heavy machine gun in Kobani on Oct. 17.
Aamaq News Agency via AFP/Getty Images
Thick smoke rises following an airstrike by the US-led coalition in Kobani, Syria as fighting continued between Syrian Kurds and the militants of Islamic State.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Iraqi federal policemen search a car at a checkpoint in Baghdad.
Karim Kadim, AP
A woman in Mursitpinar, Turkey, reacts as smoke rises from explosions after an Oct. 13 allied airstrike on Islamic State targets in Kobani, Syria.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Coalition aircraft bomb Islamic State positions in Kobani, Syria.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
Heavy smoke rises following an airstrike by allied aircraft.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty images
A vendor sells bread to people watching the ongoing bombing campaign in Kobani, Syria, on a hilltop outside Suruc, Turkey.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
People watch fighting between YPG Kurdish fighters and Islamic State militants in Kobani.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke rises from the Syrian town of Kobani after airstrikes on Islamic State fighters.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty Images
Rabia Ali mourns at the grave of her son, Seydo Mehmud, a Kurdish fighter, who was killed during a battle with Islamic State militants.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Civilians and Turkish military personnel watch fighting between Kurds and militants from the Islamic State group.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish Kurds watch fighting in Kobani.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty images
Smoke rises from Kobani near the Turkish-Syrian border.
Stringer, Getty images
Turkish armored vehicles hold a position on a hill above Kobani on Oct. 9.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
A Kurdish man watches fighting in Kobani, Syria, from a hill in Turkey.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke rises from an allied airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
A Turkish Kurd watches an airstrike in Kobani on Oct. 8.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Personnel on a Turkish army tank watch allied warplanes attack Islamic State targets in Kobani, Syria.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A  plume of smoke rises after an airstrike in eastern Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish Kurds watch an airstrike in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises after an allied airstrike against an Islamic State target in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Turkish Kurds in Mursitpinar, Turkey, watch fighting between Kurdish forces and Islamic State militants in Kobani, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
An allied airstrike hits Islamic State targets in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Turkish armored vehicles patrol the Turkish-Syrian border in Sanliurfa province.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke rises after an airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Turkish Kurds in Turkey watch fighting in Kobani, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish troops watch the results of an airstrike in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Fullscreen
Smoke rises after an airstrike by allied forces against Islamic State targets on Oct. 7 in the Syrian town of Kobani near Suruc district, Turkey. Airstrikes targeted three groups of Islamic State militants in the first daytime action in Syria by U.S.-led coalition forces.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke from an explosion after an allied airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Turkish soldiers stand near their armored vehicles as they hold a position outside Suruc, near the Turkey-Syria border.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises from an explosion in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
An Iraqi military vehicle burns after an Islamic State attack in western Anbar province on Oct. 5.
AP
A photograph from the British Ministry of Defense shows the result of a Brimstone missile strike on an armed Islamic State truck on Sept. 30 in Iraq. The Brimstone missile is circled in red moments before impact.
Ministry of Defense via AP
A British Ministry of Defense photograph shows the result of a missile attack on an Islamic State truck in Iraq.
Ministry of Defense via AP
A British Royal Air Force Tornado GR4 aircraft lands after a mission over Iraq at the Akrotiri airbase in Cyprus.
Cpl. Neil Bryden, Royal Air Force, via AP
Iraqi Shiite militiamen battle Islamic State militants on Sept. 29 in Jurf al-Sakhar.
AP
A Department of Defense photograph released on Sept. 29 shows a pair of U.S. Air Force F-15E Strike Eagles flying over northern Iraq on Sept. 23.
Matthew Brusch, U.S. Air Force, via European Pressphoto Agency
A Sept. 26 photograph released by the U.S. Air Force shows a KC-10 Extender refueling an F-22 Raptor fighter aircraft before a strike operation against Islamic State targets in Syria.
Tech. Sgt. Russ Scalf, U.S. Air Force, via AP
Two photographs provided by the Pentagon on Sept. 25 shows before and after images of an airstrike on the Jerible Modular oil refinery in Syria.
Department of Defense via AP
Two photographs provided by the Pentagon shows before and after images of an allied airstrike on the Gbiebi Modular oil refinery.
Department of Defense via AP
A U.S. Navy F-18E Super Hornet receives fuel from a U.S. Air Force KC-135 Stratotanker over northern Iraq after conducting airstrikes on Islamic State targets in Syria.
Staff Sgt. Shawn Nickel, U.S. Air Force, via AP
A formation of U.S. Navy F-18E Super Hornets leaves after receiving fuel from a U.S. Air Force KC-135 Stratotanker over northern Iraq.
Staff Sgt. Shawn Nickel, U.S. Air Force, via AP
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Sat May 23 21:24:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ireland legalizes gay marriage</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/92962503/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Ireland-legalizes-gay-marriage/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Ireland legalizes gay marriage
Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum.
Post to Facebook
Ireland legalizes gay marriage Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Stu56b
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
9
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Ireland legalizes gay marriage
Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Irish Sen. Katherine Zappone, left, kisses her partner, Ann Louise Gilligan, as supporters for same-sex marriage wait for the result of the referendum at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
A man blows bubbles as supporters for same-sex marriage waited for the result of the referendum at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Supporters wait for the final result in the Irish referendum at Dublin Castle.
Peter Morrison, AP
Supporters wait for the final result in the Irish referendum at Dublin Castle.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Peter Morrison, AP
Michael Barron, right, and Jamie Nanci, who were married in Cape Town, South Africa, kiss at the RDS count center in Dublin.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
